<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Compost tea effects on soil fertility and plant growth of organic tomato (Solanum Lycopersicum Mill) in comparison with different organic fertilizers.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>EL HANAFI SEBTI, Kawtar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Over the last years, organic agriculture has attracted much attention in the Mediterranean countries for both environmental reasons and market opportunities. Composts and derived materials match closely with the organic farming approaches because of the beneficial effects on soil properties and functions, on plant nutrition and pathogens suppression and on several environmental concerns. This study compares the effects of compost tea (applied through fertigation and foliar application) on soil fertility, plant growth and food quality of two varieties of tomatoes (Vespro and Multiplo) in comparison with the effect of compost and commercial biofertilizer (Guanito) according to a split plot design. Compost, compost tea and Guanito revealed significant positive effects on yield, biomass, number of fruits and root weight in comparison to the control. On the other hand, compost tea increased vitamin C content for both varieties, while a limited nitrates fruit accumulation was induced by compost applications in Multiplo and by compost tea in Vespro.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7009/1/KawtarHanafi05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>EL HANAFI SEBTI, Kawtar   (2005) Compost tea effects on soil fertility and plant growth of organic tomato (Solanum Lycopersicum Mill) in comparison with different organic fertilizers.  [Effets du jus de compost sur la fertilité du sol et la croissance de la plante chez la tomate biologique (Solanum Lycopersicum Mill) par rapport aux différents fertilisants. biologiques.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 405. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7009/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>