<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An overview on the role and potential of forage production on lowland organic livestock farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weller, Richard F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Evan L</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
This paper outlines some of the factors influencing the level of forage production on organic lowland farms. Optimal forage production is achieved by maintaining soil fertility, providing a balance between N-fixing and N-demanding crops and producing sufficient quantities of quality feed to meet the requirements of the organic livestock enterprise. A key objective for organic systems is to increase the efficiency of forage production by improving the nutrient input/output balance of the wholefarm system. Improving forage quality reduces the requirement for external feed sources, leading to increased self-sufficiency in the wholefarm system. Legumes provide the main source of nitrogen for forage production with energy shortage and an erratic supply of protein the main limiting factors in the provision of balanced diets from home-grown crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8297/1/weller_Forage_lowland_farms.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weller, Richard F and Jones, Evan L    (2002) An overview on the role and potential of forage production on lowland organic livestock farms.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 81-84.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8297/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>