<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SOCIO-ECONOMIC AND ENVIRONMENTAL ASPECTS OF FARMING PRACTICES IN THE PERI-URBAN HINTERLANDS OF NEPAL</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bhatta, G.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Doppler, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Spatial location of the farm households shapes farming  practices and livelihoods of the farmers. Many socio-economic variables have strong spatial relations that would otherwise be missed by data aggregation at household level. Geographic Information System (GIS)provides display and analysis of socio-economic data that may be fundamental for many social scientists to understand socio-economic reality influenced by geographical position of the farm households. Present article aims at integrating socio-economic data into GIS environment to examine spatial relation in the resource availability and use employing spatial and random sampling techniques. Result demonstrates the variation in the socioeconomic attributes along the spatial gradient which is mainly related to the infrastructures such as road, market and improved agro-inputs. While households with better access to these infrastructures have tendency to use more agro-chemicals, have larger family, land holding and livestock units, better off-farm opportunities, commercial farming orientation and hence higher family income; opposite is true for the households with poor access to these infrastructures. Peri-urban farmlands, wherever agro-chemicals are applied imprudently, faces the problems of agro-ecological degradation while rural subsistence farming faces the problem of spatial poverty.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19205/4/19205.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bhatta, G.D. and Doppler, W.   (2010) SOCIO-ECONOMIC AND ENVIRONMENTAL ASPECTS OF FARMING PRACTICES IN THE PERI-URBAN HINTERLANDS OF NEPAL.   Journal of Agriculture and Environment, 11, pp. 26-39.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19205/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>