<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economic aspects of the application of different organic materials as N-sources in organic production of lettuce</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cabilovski, dipl ing Ranko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manojlovic, Prof Maja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bogdanovic, Prof Darinka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bavec, Prof Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a field experiment on a farm registered for organic production, we studied the effect of the application of different organic materials (OM): farmyard manure (FYM), guano (G), soybean seed (S), forage pea seed (P) on lettuce yield. Besides yield, we also analyzed the economic profitability of the application of different OM. Fresh lettuce yield was significantly higher with OM treatments than with the treatments without fertilization. The highest yield was obtained with the FYM treatment (43.7 t ha-1), and the lowest with the application of P (42.0 t ha-1). The highest additional profit was obtained with the FYM treatment (1123 EUR ha-1) and the lowest with the application of P (475 EUR ha-1).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12085/1/Cabilovski_12085_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Cabilovski, dipl ing Ranko; Manojlovic, Prof Maja; Bogdanovic, Prof Darinka and Bavec, Prof Martina    (2008) Economic aspects of the application of different organic materials as N-sources in organic production of lettuce.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12085/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>