<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Thermal and photochemical degradation of myoglobin pigments in relation to colour stability of sliced dry-cured Parma ham and sliced dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adamsen, Christina E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Møller, Jens K.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hismani, Ramadan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skibsted, Leif H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lipophilic and hydrophilic extracts of the red pigments from Parma ham and nitrosylated pigment of dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt were prepared with acetone/water (75/25 v/v %) solution and aqueous phosphate buffer, respectively. The spectral characteristics differed for both the lipophilic and the hydrophilic Parma ham pigment compared with the dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt. The red lipophilic pigment(s) extractable from Parma ham was(were) found to be very stable towards thermal degradation in acetone/water (75/25 v/v %) solution for temperatures up to 70 °C in contrast to the lipophilic pigment(s) extractable from dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt, which was(were) found to have an energy of activation of 99 kJ/mol for thermal degradation. In contrast, quantum yields for photodegradation of the lipophilic ham pigments exposed to 366 nm (420 nm) monochromatic light were larger for Parma ham than for nitrite-cured ham [1.6×10–5 (6.9×10–6) versus 1.6×10–6 (2×10–6) mol einstein–1] as determined for acetone/water (75/25 v/v %) solution. In agreement with these findings for the extracted lipophilic pigments, sliced Parma ham showed better colour stability than sliced dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt, when stored in the dark at low oxygen concentration, in contrast to a faster initial discolouration for Parma ham when exposed to light, as shown for chilled storage for 35 days under retail conditions for the two products each packed at two oxygen levels (0.4 and 21%).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Klostermeyer, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3260/1/artikel.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Adamsen, Christina E.; Møller, Jens K.S.; Hismani, Ramadan and Skibsted, Leif H.   (2004) Thermal and photochemical degradation of myoglobin pigments in relation to colour stability of sliced dry-cured Parma ham and sliced dry-cured ham produced with nitrite salt.   European Food Research and Technology. Zeitschrift für Lebensmittel-Untersuchung und -Forschung A, 218 (5), pp. 403-409.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3260/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>