<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of different paddock rotation strategies for organic sows on behaviour, welfare and the environment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelly, Hilary</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shiel, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edwards, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Day, Jon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Browning, Helen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Two alternative paddock rotations for dry sows were established on an organic farm: Rotational (40 x 40m moved three times per year) and Set Stocked (120 x 40m in place for one year). Sows showed distinct preferences in the location of dunging and urination within the paddocks (p&lt;0.001), but no differences between the paddocks. Vegetation cover under the sows was similar overall in the two paddock systems, but showed differences over the year. Work to model the potential for nutrient leaching in the two paddock systems is ongoing.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8420/1/kelly_Paddock_rotation_strategies_sows.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelly, Hilary; Shiel, Robert; Edwards, Sandra; Day, Jon and Browning, Helen    (2002) The effect of different paddock rotation strategies for organic sows on behaviour, welfare and the environment.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 273-276.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8420/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>