<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Yield, forage quality, residue nitrogen and nitrogen fixation of different forage legumes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaske, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ingwersen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fixed nitrogen accumulated by legumes is the main nitrogen source for organic farming systems. Knowledge about the amount of fixed nitrogen, its pathways into forage yield, crop residues, soil-N and yield formation of the following crop is needed for designing crop rotations.&#xD;
In a field experiment conducted in Northern Germany differently managed (cut, mulched) legumes (red clover, alfalfa, white clover) in pure stands and in mixture with a companion grass (Lolium perenne) have been grown to determine Yield, forage-quality, N2-fixation and residue nitrogen. &#xD;
Cropped grass/legume reached higher N2-fixation than mulched. While green manure grass/legume left up to 296 kg ha-1 of N in mulch, stubble and roots on the field, most cropped grass/legume mixtures left less than 120 kg N ha-1 in crop residues. Cropped swards showed higher N2-fixation than the mulched mixtures. Swards with red clover or alfalfa reached higher legume contents and harvestable biomass than swards with white clover. &#xD;
&#xD;
Conclusions&#xD;
The results show that biomass production, forage yields, residue nitrogen and N fixation of grass/legume mixtures can be influenced by various combinations of legume species and management. The factors listed have to be considered carefully when planning crop rotations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>vdf Hochschulverlag AG an der ETH Zürich</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2145/1/loges-2000-forage-legumes.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Loges, Ralf; Kaske, A.; Ingwersen, K. and Taube, F.    (2000) Yield, forage quality, residue nitrogen and nitrogen fixation of different forage legumes.  [Ertrag, Futterqualität, Stickstoff der Ernterückstände sowie N-Fixierung verschiedener Futterleguminosen.]  In: Alföldi, Thomas; Lockeretz, William and Niggli, Urs (Eds.)  IFOAM 2000 - The World Grows Organic - Proceedings of the 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference, vdf Hochschulverlag AG an der ETH Zürich, -83.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2145/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>