<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Feldversuche zur Wirkung von Spinosad-, Neem- und B.t.t.-&#xD;
Präparaten auf die Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers&#xD;
(Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kühne, Dr Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priegnitz, Uta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ellmer, Prof. Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moll, Dr. Eckard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kowalska, Dr. Jolanta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Colorado potato beetle (CPB) is one of the most important pests on potatoes&#xD;
(Solanum tuberosum). In many areas, preventive measures are not sufficient&#xD;
enoughto prevent the damage caused by the CPB. Therefore insecticides such as&#xD;
neem and Bacillus thuringiensis v. tenebrionis (B.t.t.) have an important role in organic&#xD;
potato production in Germany. The new insecticide Spinosad was added to Council&#xD;
Regulations (EEC) No. 2092/91 on organic production in 2008. It is now possible to&#xD;
use Spinosad in organic agriculture in the EU. The active ingredient of Spinosad is&#xD;
obtained from the bacterium Saccharopolyspora spinosa through fermentation. Field&#xD;
studies compared three treatments to control CPB in 2008. 1: single Spinosad&#xD;
treatment (24 g/ha active ingredient (a.i.)) 2: first treatment B.t.t. (60 g/ha (a.i.)),&#xD;
second treatment (+4d) B.t.t. (100 g/ha a.i.) 3: first treatment neem (25 g/ha a.i.),&#xD;
second treatment (+4d) B.t.t. (100 g/ha a.i.). There was an average of 27 larvae per&#xD;
plant before the treatments. All treatments displayed nearly the same significant&#xD;
degree of effectiveness (78 % - 82 %) with regards to the damaged leaf area 25 days&#xD;
after treatment in comparison to the untreated control. The increment of the Spinosad&#xD;
treatment to untreated control was significant with more than 103 dt/ha.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14330/1/K%C3%BChne_14330.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kühne, Dr Stefan; Priegnitz, Uta; Ellmer, Prof. Frank; Moll, Dr. Eckard and Kowalska, Dr. Jolanta    (2009) Feldversuche zur Wirkung von Spinosad-, Neem- und B.t.t.- Präparaten auf die Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say).       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14330/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>