<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The dialogue with farmers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, Gidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gratzer, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stöger, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whistance, Lindsay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejdell, Cecilie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Britt I. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nicholas, Phillipa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report covers the project outcome Deliverable 4.2 ‘Analysis completed after a joint effort to identify possibilities in each country as how to facilitate the best possible dialogue regarding animal health and welfare’ as part of the European CORE Organic project ‘Minimising medicine use in organic dairy herds through animal health and welfare planning.’ The work was intended to understand the processes and was analysed from the perspective of the key animal health and welfare (AHW) planning principles developed as part of the project. The analysis was completed on transcripts of interviews of facilitators and advisors who had participated in the ANIPLAN project, some of them as partners in the project group. &#xD;
&#xD;
If animal health and welfare planning is to gain widespread use among organic farmers, communication between farmers and between farmers and advisors and other actors in the organic farming environment is crucial. Whilst other forms of communication regarding the role and benefits of AHW assessment systems, such as benchmarking, may be the motivational catalyst needed to encourage engagement in the process, a creative dialogue with the individual farmer is necessary when identifying goals and planning means to reach the desired goals. In order to understand how this dialogue works in practice, and what issues arise, a series of interviews were conducted in all of the ANIPLAN participating countries, involving persons directly involved and those with other experiences. The analysis of the interviews was based on a theoretical framework concerning learning, knowledge and empowerment and a functional framework based on the animal health and welfare principles developed as an output from the ANIPLAN project.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18406/1/18406.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vaarst, Mette; Roderick, Stephen; Smolders, Gidi; Leeb, Christine; Walkenhorst, Michael; Winckler, Christoph; Gratzer, Elisabeth; Stöger, Elisabeth; Whistance, Lindsay; Brinkmann, Jan; March, Solveig; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Mejdell, Cecilie; Henriksen, Britt I. F. and Nicholas, Phillipa    (2011) The dialogue with farmers.    In:     The process of minimising medicine use through dialogue based animal health and welfare planning.  , pp. 64-79.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18406/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>