<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Thinking of going Organic?  Here is a step-by-step guide.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Anon,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As part of the Welsh Assembly Government’s commitment to organic farming, financial and technical support is available to all farmers converting to organic systems. Organic farming is good for the countryside, with benefits to biodiversity, animal welfare, water quality, public health and local economies. The market for organic produce in the UK is growing, and at the moment much of it has to be imported. This leaflet provides&#xD;
an introduction to the advice and information available to help you decide if organic production could be for you, and to support you through the conversion process.&#xD;
&#xD;
However, This edition of 'Thinking of going Organic' was published in April 2006.  The Welsh Assembly Government is currently reviewing the Organic Farming Scheme and advisory support, and so some of the information in this guide is out of date.  You should discuss it with a suitably qualified advisor before proceeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10856/1/A5_thinking_saes.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10856/2/A5_meddwl_cym.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Anon,     (2006) Thinking of going Organic? Here is a step-by-step guide.   Organic Centre Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10856/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>