<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The influence of phosphorus deficiency on growth and nitrogen fixation of white clover plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Dr Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjoerring, Dr Jan K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soussana, Dr Jean-Francois</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effects of P deficiency on growth, N2-fixation and photosynthesis in white clover (Trifolium repens L.) were investigated using three contrasting relative addition rates of P, or following abrupt withdrawal of the P supply. Responses to a constant below-optimum P supply rate consisted of a decline in N2-fixation per unit root weight and a small reduction in the efficiency with which electrons were allocated to the reduction of N2 in the nodules. Abrupt P removal arrested nodule growth and caused a substantial decline in nitrogenase activity per unit root weight, but not per unit nodule mass. &#xD;
Similarly, the rate of photosynthesis per unit leaf area was unaffected by abrupt P removal, while the CO2 acquisition for the plant as a whole decreased due to a decline in total leaf area, leaf area per unit leaf weight and utilisation of incoming radiation. These changes followed the decline in tissue P concentrations. The ratio between CO2-fixation and N2-fixation was maintained under short-term P deprivation but increased under long-term low P supply indicating a down-regulation of nodule activity following morphological and growth adjustments. It is concluded that N2-fixation does not limit the growth of clover plants experiencing P deficiency.  A low P status induces changes in the relative growth of  roots, nodules, and shoots rather than changes in N and/or C uptake rates per unit mass or area of these organs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/286/1/Pstress-final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Høgh-Jensen, Dr Henning; Schjoerring, Dr Jan K. and Soussana, Dr Jean-Francois   (2002) The influence of phosphorus deficiency on growth and nitrogen fixation of white clover plants.   Annals of Botany, 90, pp. 745-753.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/286/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>