<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Creation of BugBag. Redesign of Insect Trap for Biological Pest Control</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Svendsen, Mads Rømer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Jakob Wulff</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Introduction&#xD;
The project is based on research on pheromones and the project SoftPest Multitrap. Copenhagen Universitys Science and Life Sciences, more specifically Department of Plant and Environmental Sciences, has researched and developed the pheromonis for mass trapping of the Strawberry Blossom Weevil (Anthonomus Rubi) and the European Tarnished Plant Bug (Lygus Rugulipennis). Our foucus is on the user-experience Associated with the pheromonibased traps. Especially the distrubution, assembly, setup, Collection, cleaning, storage and&#xD;
&#xD;
The Problem&#xD;
The Strawberry Blossom Weevil and European Tarnished Plant Bug are a major problem to European strawberry producers and reduces the annual yield remarkably. The conventional strawberry producers can efficiently spray with pesticides to control the pest, however, this is harmful to the environment. The ecological strawberry producers lack effective pest control methods and has no options if they are attacked by the mentioned pest. A preromone-based pest control method is a promising alternative and it is useful for both conventional and ecological strawberry producers. However, a userdriven redesign of SoftPest Multitrap (figure 1) is nescessary. This is to ensure that the traps can be easily implemented in the various production methods and be a competitive alternative to pesticides.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26626/1/26626.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Svendsen, Mads Rømer and Andersen, Jakob Wulff   (2014) The Creation of BugBag. Redesign of Insect Trap for Biological Pest Control.    Bachelor thesis, Danmarks Tekniske Universitet, Design &amp; Innovation.  .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26626/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>