<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC REVISION – Research to support the revision of the EU Regulation on organic agriculture (www.organic-revision.org)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jespersen, Lizzie Melby</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The FP6 project, EEC 2092/91 (ORGANIC) REVISION www.organic-revision.org has delivered important inputs for the ongoing revision of the Council Regulation (EEC) 2092/91. The project has identified basic ethical values and value differences in organic agriculture and developed a procedure for balancing and integrating these basic values in the revision of the (EEC) 2092/91. It has also established an organic standards database www.organicrules.org on differences of 35 national standards from 14 European countries and the USA and 3 international organic standards compared with the (EEC) 2092/91. as a basis for identifying areas of the (EEC) 2092/91 where harmonisation, simplification or regionalisation could be recommended. The project has also analysed organic feed availability in relation to dietary requirements of pigs and poultry and provided specific recommendations on the criteria for approval of feed inputs. Further, the availability of organic seeds and propagation materials has been assessed, and recommendations on information exchange and decision criteria for the seed derogation regime have been developed. The EEC 2092/91 (Organic) Revision project has contributed to the ongoing revision of the (EEC) 2092/91 by delivering background information for the negotiation process on several issues, such as the integration of objectives and principles based on values in the new Council Regulation (EC) 834/2007 and criteria for the approval of conventional feed ingredients.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12962/1/12962.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jespersen, Lizzie Melby    (2007) ORGANIC REVISION – Research to support the revision of the EU Regulation on organic agriculture (www.organic-revision.org).       Paper at:   European Organic Congress, Brussels, December 4-5, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12962/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>