<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Parameters for apple quality: and an outline for a new quality concept - part 1 report</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bloksma, Joke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Northolt, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Machteld</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In real life it is hard to distinguish between the two life processes, growth and differentiation. We cannot expect one measured parameter to represent only one aspect of vital quality. But for most parameters we can recognise emphases on one or more aspects of the vital quality concept. We made this prelimary classification both by thinking about the concept and by looking at the experimental results. Also the conventional parameters are interpreted as a result of these processes in a more holistic way than usual.&#xD;
We realise that various parameters all concerning the same aspect of our quality concept can show different levels of the aspect. To belong to the same aspect of the quality concept does not automatically mean that their correlation (see annex 14.2) must be high. We still have to get a lot of more experience to validate the parameters’ character. Here we present our first research on this topic, including the unanswered questions and realise that more experimental series will bring more and more certainty.&#xD;
After this first project we cannot say which parameters are so similar that it makes the other redundant. Until now we learned something from every parameter to develop our quality concept. Most inspiring for the new quality concept were the crystallisations, the delayed luminescence and the Bovis-value.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4266/1/4266.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bloksma, Joke; Northolt, Martin and Huber, Machteld         (2001) Parameters for apple quality: and an outline for a new quality concept - part 1 report.  [Met Nederlandse samenvatting: Parameters voor appelkwaliteit en een aanzet tot een nieuw kwaliteitsconcept / mit Deutschen Zusammenfassung: Parametern für Apfelqualität und ein Entwurf eines neuen Qualitätsbegriffes.]  Louis Bolk Instituut publications, no. GVV01/FQH01. Louis Bolk Instituut.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4266/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>