<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of information about organic production on beef liking and consumer willingness to pay</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Napolitano, Fabio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Braghieri, Ada</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>piasentier, Edi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Favotto, Saida</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Naspetti, Simona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present study was aimed to assess the effect of information about organic production on beef liking and consumer willingness to pay. Mean scores of perceived liking were higher for organic beef (OB) as&#xD;
compared to conventional beef (CB). Expected liking scores were higher for OB than for CB. For OB the expected liking was significantly higher than the perceived liking expressed in blind conditions (negative disconfirmation), whereas for CB no difference was observed. Consumers completely assimilated their liking for OB in the direction of expectations. Consumers showed a willingness to pay for OB higher than the suggested price (P &lt; 0.001), the latter corresponding to the local commercial value for organic beef.&#xD;
We conclude that the information about organic farming can be a major determinant of beef liking, thus providing a potential tool for meat differentiation to traditional farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21974/1/7EffectInformation_FQP.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Napolitano, Fabio; Braghieri, Ada; piasentier, Edi; Favotto, Saida; Naspetti, Simona and Zanoli, Raffaele   (2010) Effect of information about organic production on beef liking and consumer willingness to pay.   Food Quality and Preference, 21, pp. 207-212.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21974/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>