<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Forage Crop Production in Atlantic Zones: an Ecophysiological Approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pedrol, Nuria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martínez, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within a schedule of long-term organic forage crop rotations, two mixed stands of ryegrass-clover were evaluated as following crops after winter cereal-legume mixtures under different sowing and tillage methods in Asturias (N. Spain). Significant differences were found in productivity, sward components, chemical composition and in growth dynamics. The crop sequence perennial ryegrass-white clover established under a triticale-field bean canopy produced an additional 6 t DM/ha, compared with oat-vetch followed by Italian ryegrass-red clover under regular post-harvest sowing, thus being a promising method for improving organic forage productions with minimum tillage. Changes in productivity and feeding values observed for both these ryegrass-clover swards along different growth periods were studied  together with soil nutrient evolution and seasonal climatic fluctuations. Correlation analysis showed ecophysiological links among crop, soil and climate variables.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>British Grassland Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hopkins, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7226/1/7226.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pedrol, Nuria and Martínez, Antonio    (2004) Organic Forage Crop Production in Atlantic Zones: an Ecophysiological Approach.   In: Hopkins, Alan (Ed.)  Organic Farming: Science and Practice for Profitable Livestock and Cropping. Occasional Symposium No. 37, British Grassland Society, 2004. Proceedings of the BGS/AAB/COR Conference., British Grassland Society, British Grassland Society Occasional Symposium Series, no. 37, pp. 105-109.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7226/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>