<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality Assessment of Summer and Autumn Carrots from a Biodynamic Breeding Project and Correlations of Physico-Chemical Parameters and Features Determined by Picture Forming Methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hagel, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bauer, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haneklaus, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schnug, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Introduction:&#xD;
Assessment of product quality is of special significance in organic farming and includes the supervision of crop quality in different growing systems (e.g., Fleck et al. 1998) and the characterisation of different cultivars. Several methods have been developed and applied for this purpose, e.g., the physico-chemical analysis of crops, picture forming methods (PFMs) and plant observation. So far only limited information is available on the comparability of these methods. This contribution aims to compare the results of the analysis of physico-chemical parameters of summer and autumn carrots with features determined by PFMs by means of correlation analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
Conclusions:&#xD;
High and significant correlation coefficients were found between quality parameters of summer and autumn carrots from a biodynamical breeding project determined by physico-chemical analysis and PFMs. This indicates close relationships between the two quality approaches which should be investigated further in future work.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IFOAM</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2191/1/2191-hagel-i-2000-carrot-ifoam.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hagel, I.; Bauer, D.; Haneklaus, S. and Schnug, E.    (2000) Quality Assessment of Summer and Autumn Carrots from a Biodynamic Breeding Project and Correlations of Physico-Chemical Parameters and Features Determined by Picture Forming Methods.   In: Alföldi, Thomas; Lockeretz, William and Niggli, Urs (Eds.)  Proceedings 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference, IFOAM, pp. 284-287.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2191/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>