<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies to support domestic organic markets in countries with emerging organic sectors</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Toralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kovacs, Annamaria</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents the current state and prospects of domestic organic market development in selected countries with emerging organic markets: The Czech Republic (CZ), Poland (PL), Hungary (HU), Ukraine (UA), Mexico (MX) and India (IN). While governmental support for organic farming varies across all countries studied, the organic sector is focused mainly on export markets in every country represented. The results of a two-step expert consultation indicate that development of the domestic market is mainly hampered by a lack of processing and distribution infrastructure, as well as the relatively low purchasing power of domestic consumers. Experts recommend that political support should prioritise national market development programmes for organic food (above all regional producer initiatives, vertical networks, establishment of a national organic logo). With regard to marketing measures, market development can be fostered by expanding the available range of domestic processed and convenience food, changing the price image and improving communication strategies that focus on health and quality aspects. In addition, distribution should not focus exclusively on conventional retail chains.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4455/4/Richter_Kovacs_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Richter, Toralf and Kovacs, Annamaria    (2005) Strategies to support domestic organic markets in countries with emerging organic sectors.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4455/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>