<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic data network: Harmonising organic market data collection in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Feldmann, Corinna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This contribution emerged as part of the collaborative project “Data network for better European organic market information” carried out in the 7th Framework Programme of the EU. Data from an online and a telephone survey among organic market data collectors form the basis for the analysis of the current situation of statistics on organic market data. The results reveal a heterogeneous picture, because organic market growth and data collection within the organic food sector have developed differently throughout Europe. Building on the survey results, the quality of data collection approaches is evaluated through the application of the data quality dimensions relevance, accuracy, comparability, coherence, accessibility/clarity, and timeliness/punctuality (Eurostat, 2009). Thereby best practice examples are identified and used for the elaboration of guidelines for the harmonisation of organic market data collection in Europe.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24247/1/PosterGewisola2013_Feldmann%26Hamm_OrganicDataNetwork.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Feldmann, Corinna and Hamm, Ulrich    (2013) Organic data network: Harmonising organic market data collection in Europe.       Poster at:   53. Jahrestagung der Gesellschaft für Wirtschafts- und Sozialwissenschaften des Landbau e.V., Berlin, Germany, September 25th to 27th, 2013.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24247/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>