<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Outdoor feeding management and needs of horses - an overview</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saastamoinen, Markku</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Feeding horses outdoors in winter and cold climate presents a challenge to horse owners and stable&#xD;
managers. Low temperatures, harsh winds and rain, snow and ice all contribute to the increasing&#xD;
nutrient requirements a horse has to keep themselves warm and maintain their body weight. The&#xD;
most challenging is to feed young growing horses – the largest group of horses kept in loose stables&#xD;
- the focus being on the energy demands of the horse. When the climatic energy demands are taken&#xD;
into account, also the weanling horses can maintain their body condition and proper growth (Autio,&#xD;
2008).&#xD;
Although horses are fed in groups, their individual needs have to be considered applying individual&#xD;
feeding. Some studies show both breed and individual differences in the digestibility of nutrients or&#xD;
energy demands among some horse breeds used in the Nordic countries (Saastamoinen, 1993;&#xD;
Ragnarsson, 2009; Jensen et al., 2010). There are also some studies found a tendency toward higher&#xD;
digestibility in ponies than in horses. Some individuals are so called “easy keepers” accumulating&#xD;
fat easily in their body. In addition, the amount of voluntary exercise of horses varies resulting&#xD;
different energy needs and feeding levels.&#xD;
To keep horses health and to guarantee their wellbeing, it is important to take care of the hygienic&#xD;
quality of the feeds and feeding facilities in the paddocks or loose stables. Poor hygienic quality of&#xD;
feeds and feeding may cause sever problems both in gastro-intestinal tract and airways of the horse.&#xD;
Feeds stored and fed outside alter poor climatic conditions, and may be source of many harmful&#xD;
micro-organisms.&#xD;
Eating and feeding is also part of the social life of the horses in paddocks and the loose housing&#xD;
systems. The horse can be characterised as a ‘herd’, ‘nomadic’ and ‘flight-animal’, which spends&#xD;
about 60% of its daily behaviour on voluntary food intake (Duncan, 1980; Vulink, 2001; Davidson,&#xD;
1999).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19453/1/Saastamoinen1.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Saastamoinen, Markku    (2011) Outdoor feeding management and needs of horses - an overview.   In:     Housing and management of horses in Nordic and Baltic climate, Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists, 7 (2), NJF Report, pp. 44-47.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19453/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>