<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings of XI SEAE CONGRESS SPANISH SOCIETY FOR ORGANIC FARMING</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Equipo Técnico , SEAE</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic production is based on agroecology, a science applying ecological farming systems and having three dimensions: transdisciplinary knowledge, interdisciplinary agricultural practices and social movements. Their integration provides a way of generating collective action alternatives to the dominant food system.&#xD;
Since a bit more than a decade the European civil society and the farmers and organic farmers movements have reflected and debated in discussion forums on the future of the agriculture, demanding favorable changes for agroecological systems, inspired by experiences linked to food sovereignty, socio-political principles (autonomy, “active” participation of operators) and the enhancement of local  knowledge. In the context of EU policies highlighted by innovation, Agroecology is emerging as an innovative practice to integrate and improve knowledge of farmers and strengthen the profitability and sustainability of agricultural systems to offer more jobs, attach greater importance to the role of women and, in turn, to facilitate the incorporation of young people to ensure generational change.&#xD;
The Spanish Society of Organic Agriculture (SEAE) organize since 1994, every two years its state scientific-technical Congress where knowledge and proposals are shared and discussed among stakeholders (researchers, advisers, farmers, processors, etc..), and the results of research and recent innovations that support the development of the organic sector are presented and discussed. This forms a singular space dialogue where organic production chain agents can get inspired to generate new ideas. Twelve years ago this forum was extended to Ibero-American countries. Since the previous edition (2012) SEAE combines this congress with its General Assembly and the Awards to the generation and management of agro-ecological knowledge (Eco-eLabora).&#xD;
As host of the XI Congress has chosen the city of Vitoria-Gasteiz, capital of the Basque Country which was nominated european CAPITAL GREEN in 2012. In Vitoria-Gasteiz there is a major citizens movement in favor of local and organic food via short marketing chains . In the territory of Alava province organic production is increasing, driven largely by urban demand for Vitoria-Gasteiz. The Alava and Basque agriculture is in particular organic farming and is practiced by families, keeping people and culture. The International Year of Family Farming,declared by UNO and implemented by FAO, reinforces this way of producing and keeping alive the rural world</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>SEAE</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27863/13/libro-actas-xicongresoseae14-v2-prot.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>(2014) Proceedings of XI SEAE CONGRESS SPANISH SOCIETY FOR ORGANIC FARMING.   SEAE.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27863/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>