<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pest management and biodiversity in organic fruit production: the case of apple orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>SAUPHANOR, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>SIMON, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BOISNEAU, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>CAPOWIEZ, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>RIEUX, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BOUVIER, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DEFRANCE, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>PICARD, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>TOUBON, J.-F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Numerous pesticide applications are required for orchard protection, regardless of the guidelines. Organic fruit production (OFP) mainly relies on the use of mineral fungicides and microbiological or naturally-occurring insecticides. The environmental impact of this type of production does not significantly differ from that of conventional production when assessed in terms of synthetic indicators. However, the abundance of earthworms, as well as the abundance and specific richness of arthropod pests and beneficials in the orchards and surrounding hedges, is greater in OFP than in conventional orchards. Generalist predators are usually less affected by OFP compounds than by the chemical pesticides applied in conventional orchards. OFP also benefits avian communities, and above all, insectivorous birds, for which organic orchards offer a suitable habitat similar to that of undisturbed natural areas. In addition to this general trend, discrepancies may be observed in the protection responses of different insect groups. The abundance of hymenopteran parasitoids is the lowest in organic orchards in which outbreaks of phytophagous mites are also recorded in relation to the intensive use of sulphur for scab protection. Biological insecticides often act in ways that are similar to those of chemical ones, and the restricted choice of available compounds is likely to induce resistance selection in insect pests. Although maintaining biodiversity is not a direct result of the implementation of OFP guidelines, it seems to be widely considered as an option by organic growers, both alone and as a complementary tool for pest regulation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15486/1/31-Sauphanor.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>SAUPHANOR, B. ; SIMON, S. ; BOISNEAU, C. ; CAPOWIEZ, Y. ; RIEUX, R. ; BOUVIER, J.C. ; DEFRANCE, H. ; PICARD, C.  and TOUBON, J.-F.    (2009) Pest management and biodiversity in organic fruit production: the case of apple orchards.  [Protection phytosanitaire et biodiversité en agriculture biologique. Le cas des vergers de pommiers.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 217-228.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15486/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>