<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of an active mating disruption concept against codling moth (Cydia pomonella) under the aspects of different application systems and varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schildberger, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wurm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kickenweiz, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Beside standard systems of mating disruption the activity of the product Exosex CM and&#xD;
Exosex 2 CM under the aspect of different application systems and several varieties were&#xD;
tested at the research station of the Federal College and Institute for Viticulture and&#xD;
Pomology Klosterneuburg. Male insects were attracted into the Exosex dispenser by using&#xD;
the appropriate pheromone, which acts on the pheromone receptive sensors on the male&#xD;
so that they cannot locate calling females. Standard mating disruption techniques usually&#xD;
rely on the introduction of amounts of pheromone emitted by natural populations of pest&#xD;
species into the atmosphere. Exosex CM significantly reduces deployment time and labour&#xD;
costs in the orchards, additionally the flexibility to fit in with IPM programmes was tested.&#xD;
The assessments were done visually on windfall fruits, fruits on the tree and on all fruits at&#xD;
harvest followed by statistical evaluation. Among the fruits sprayed with the IPM system&#xD;
there was an infestation rate of the first (Cydia pomonella) generation at the variety Idared&#xD;
of 0,8%, the second generation treated with Exosex showed an infestation of 13%. In the&#xD;
biological trial however the infestation by the first generation was about 4% and the&#xD;
infestation of the second generation about 31%.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13718/1/295-298.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schildberger, B.; Wurm, L. and Kickenweiz, M.    (2008) Evaluation of an active mating disruption concept against codling moth (Cydia pomonella) under the aspects of different application systems and varieties.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 295-298.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13718/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>