<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Growth performance of broilers fed with different strains of probiotics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tarun, Dr. Mercedes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Generally, this study aimed to determine the effects of different strains of probiotics on the growth performance of broilers. Specifically, to determine the effects of feeding different strains of probiotics on the growth performance of broiler and utilizing broiler chicks, An all mash ration with 21% CP was formulated. Completely Randomized Design (CRD) was used and Least Significant Differences (LSD) when comparing treatments; T1-Control (0 Probiotics), T2- 2 kg Lactobacillus sp./MT of feeds, T3- 2 kg Bacillus sp./MT of feeds, and T4-2 kg Pediococcus sp./MT of feeds. Statistical analysis revealed highly significant differences among treatments on the final body weight of broilers given diets with different strains of probiotics. Based from the result of the study, the inclusion of 2 kg Lactobacillus sp./MT of feeds in the diet of broilers had improved the growth of the experimental birds in terms of body weight, gain in weight, feed conversion and its economic  returns  due to the lactic acid content of Lactobacillus sp. The result obtained from this study suggest that inclusion of 2 kg of Lactobacillus sp. per metric tons of feeds can safely be used in the diet of broilers to produce an organically grown chicken for table meat as it produced the highest gain in weight, feed conversion and return above feed cost.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11625/1/Tarun_11625_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tarun, Dr. Mercedes    (2008) Growth performance of broilers fed with different strains of probiotics.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11625/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>