<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>BRIDGING THE GAP BETWEEN OLD AND NEW TECHNOLOGY: CONSIDERATION OF INDIGENOUS KNOWLEDGE IN MAIZE PESTS MANAGEMENT PRACTICES IN NIGERIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meludu, Nkiru T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adesina, Jimoh B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conventional pests management practices are carried out mainly through extensive exposure to chemicals (pesticides) used in agricultural production. The overall ailing effects of these chemical based products to the environment and human health are some of the challenges which appeal to look for alternative farming practices that would minimize the use of pesticides in agricultural production. It is against this background that this study was carried out to determine the perception of the effectiveness of indigenous and organic maize pest management practices among maize farmers in Oyo state in order to bridge the gap between the old and new technology and determine the relationship that will enhance the development of ecological organic agriculture (EAO). A well structured interview schedule was used to solicit for information from the 150 respondents using a systematic sampling technique. Frequency, percentage, Chi-square and Pearson Product Moment Correlation (PPMC) were used to describe and analyze the data generated. The farmers’ level of awareness on indigenous and organic maize pests management practices was high at (58%) level and the respondents level of utilization was also high at (61.3%) level, with a favourable perception about the effectiveness of indigenous and organic maize pests management practices and some of these practices are; cultural practices through the use of hoes and cutlasses, the use of traps, practice of bush fallow, early planting, crop rotation, mixed cropping system and biological pest control. Furthermore, Pearson Product Moment Correlation(PPMC) results showed that there is no significant relationship between some selected socio- economic characteristics age (r =0.091, p=0.270), year of formal education (r =0.010, p=0.903), farming experience ( r =0.128, p =0.120), family size (r =0.072, p=0.380), average income per month (r =0.056, p= 0.499) and the perception of the effectiveness of indigenous and organic maize pest management practices in the study area. The results of the study revealed that farmers’ level of awareness and utilization of indigenous and organic maize pest management practices was high and this is good for sustainable development EOA. The farmers perceive indigenous knowledge and organic system to mean the same and better option for against conventional farming system. Improvement of information on indigenous best practices to merge with EOA system for maize pest management through adequate extension services is eminent to enhance sustainable health of food and farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23136/1/23136_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meludu, Nkiru T. and Adesina, Jimoh B.    (2014) BRIDGING THE GAP BETWEEN OLD AND NEW TECHNOLOGY: CONSIDERATION OF INDIGENOUS KNOWLEDGE IN MAIZE PESTS MANAGEMENT PRACTICES IN NIGERIA.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 851-854.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23136/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>