<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prolonged suckling period in organic piglet production – Effects on some performance and health aspects</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bussemas, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weissmann, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic piglet suckling period typically takes about 6 weeks due to the minimum requirement of the EEC Regulation 2092/91 of 40 days. But piglets weaned in such a period are often characterized by inferior performance and health status. It is the aim of the present study to examine whether a prolonged suckling period of 63 days results in better performance and health status of the piglets. Therefore 36 sows were divided into 2 groups of 18 sows each as a control group with 42 days suckling period and a test group with 63 days suckling period. The rearing period for both the control group and the test group ended on day 77 p.n., which was also the end of the piglets´ data collection period. Three farrowing cycles with 108 litters were recorded. The extended suckling period resulted in an improved growth rate and in a reduced number of medically treated piglets and did not negatively affect the body condition and teats of the sows. Hence a prolongation of the suckling period compared to the minimum requirement of the EEC Regulation 2092/91 seems to be advisable.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12087/1/Bussemas_12087_rev.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bussemas, R. and Weissmann, F.    (2008) Prolonged suckling period in organic piglet production – Effects on some performance and health aspects.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12087/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>