<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In vitro efficacies of oils, silicas and plant preparations against the poultry red mite Dermanyssus gallinae</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perler, Erika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to test the effectiveness of physically acting substances (oils and silicas) and plant preparations for the control of the poultry red mite Dermanyssus gallinae (De Geer 1778). Reproduction and survival of fed D. gallinae females were evaluated in vitro for a total of 168 h using the ‘‘area under the survival curve’’ (AUC) to compare survival of the mites between treatments. Four oils (two plant oils, one petroleum spray oil and diesel), one soap, three silicas (one synthetic amorphous silica, one diatomaceous earth (DE) and one DE with 2% pyrethrum extract) and seven plant preparations (derived from Chrysanthemum cineariaefolium, Allium sativum, Tanacetum vulgare, Yucca schidigera, Quillaja saponaria, Dryopteris filix-mas, and Thuja occidentalis) were tested at various concentrations. All the oils, diesel and soap signifi-cantly reduced D. gallinae survival. All silicas tested inhibited reproduction. DE significantly reduced mite survival, but amorphous silica was less effective in vitro. Except for pure A. sativum juice and the highest concentration of C. cineariaefolium extract, the plant preparations tested resulted in statistically insignificant control of D. gallinae.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science+Business Media B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15721/1/Maurer_2009_Exp_Appl_Acarol.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Maurer, Veronika; Perler, Erika and Heckendorn, Felix   (2009) In vitro efficacies of oils, silicas and plant preparations against the poultry red mite Dermanyssus gallinae.   Exp Appl Acarol (Experimental and Applied Acarology), 48, pp. 31-41.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15721/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>