<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessment of selected soil parameters in a long-term Western Canadian organic field experiment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Entz, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Welsh, Cathy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tenuta, Mario</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chen, Yu Ying</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nelson, Alison</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Froese, Jane</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A long-term field study was used to compare soil nitrogen and phosphorous status, and soil aggregate stability in organic and conventional cropping systems.  Two rotations were tested: a grain only and a grain-alfalfa hay rotation.  The organic systems had a lower nitrate leaching potential than the same rotations under conventional management.  After 13 years, one organic system (the grain-alfalfa; no manure return) is suffering serious soil P depletion. However, the grain only and the grain-alfalfa with manure return to land systems had soil P levels similar to the prairie grass control treatment and showed no signs of P deficiency. Despite having lower levels of organic carbon, the organic soils had higher levels of wet aggregate stability than conventionally managed soils.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9887/1/Entz-etal-2007-soil_parameters.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Entz, Martin; Welsh, Cathy; Tenuta, Mario; Chen, Yu Ying; Nelson, Alison and Froese, Jane    (2007) Assessment of selected soil parameters in a long-term Western Canadian organic field experiment.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9887/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>