<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tolerance to weed harrowing in four spring barley varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Preben Klarskov</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holst, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andreasen, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to investigate possible interactions between a preventive and a curativ method  (combination of one pre and one post-emergence weed harrowing). We estimated the damages by weed harrowing in four pure varieties of spring barley, and analysed if there were differences in resistance and tolerance to weed harrowing between the varieties. As organic growing conditions are characterised by greater differences in nutrient levels, we further examined if there was any interactions between harrowing resistance and tolerance of the varieties and two nutrient level. Tolerance to weed harrowing was measured as an immediate effect (Resistance=how much of the plant is covered with soil after weed harrowing), a short-term effect (growth rate after the harrowing) and a long-term effect (tolerance=effect on yield). Resistance was measured by two non-destructive sensor-based methods reflectance measurements and analysis of digital images and the two methods were compared.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7872/1/7872.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Preben Klarskov; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Holst, Niels and Andreasen, Christian   (2006) Tolerance to weed harrowing in four spring barley varieties.       [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7872/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>