<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fate of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in manure and amended soil: effects of cattle feeding, manure type and dairy management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Franz, Eelco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Diepeningen, Anne D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Visser, Anna A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blok, Wim J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Bruggen, Ariena H.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the present study, we studied the effect of cattle diet on the survival of E. coli O157:H7 in manure from dairy cattle subjected to 6 different feeding regimes consisting of 3 different roughage types and 2 levels of crude protein concentrates. In addition, the rate of survival of E. coli O157:H7 in manure-amended soil as a function of manure type (manure vs. slurry) and dairy farm management (organic vs. conventional) was determined. The roughage type affected significantly the decline rate of E. coli O157:H7: decline was faster in manures with relative higher pH and fiber content. Decline was faster in slurry compared to manure and in organic slurry compared to conventional slurry.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4346/4/Franz_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Franz, Eelco; van Diepeningen, Anne D.; Visser, Anna A.; Blok, Wim J. and van Bruggen, Ariena H.C.    (2005) Fate of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in manure and amended soil: effects of cattle feeding, manure type and dairy management.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4346/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>