<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Further Development of Organic Farming Policy in Europe with Particular Emphasis on EU Enlargement</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Aim&#xD;
- Development of Institutions relevant to organic farming development analysed in 11 European countries.&#xD;
- Network analysis conducted in 11 European countries&#xD;
- 50 Farm surveys conducted on the impact of CAP reform measures on organic farming&#xD;
- 2 national workshops held for evaluating existing organic farming policy instruments and discuss new ones.&#xD;
&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
The EU-CEE-OFP project will identify how the complementary development of Organic Farming in both existing EU states, Switzerland, and in Central and Eastern European (CEE) Accession states can be fostered through policy design and innovation.&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims including target group:&#xD;
1. Analyse the capacity of relevant policy networks to establish and operate an OF Action Plan process and the acceptance by policy actors of successful or potentially successful OFP instruments: in 11 European countries and on EU level&#xD;
2. Involve Swiss policymakers/ stakeholders in identifying the parameters that could guide the further development of European OFP post EU expansion in Switzerland and the EU&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
- Literature review completed by qualitative expert interviews based on guiding questions for the analysis of institutional development&#xD;
- Network Analysis to analyse the structure of the actors’ network working on the development of organic farming policy&#xD;
- Quantitative interviews with farmers&#xD;
- Workshops based on common guidelines developed by a project partner.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4901/1/4901.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EU-CEEOFP: Further Development of Organic Farming Policy in Europe with Particular Emphasis on EU Enlargement.    Runs 2003 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Stolze, Mathias, Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick ; UWA, UK-Aberystwyth.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4901/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>