<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>IFOAM Training Manual: Training Manual for Organic Agriculture in the Humid Tropics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weidmann, Gilles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garibay, Salvador V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The first IFOAM Training Manual for Organic Agriculture in the Tropics (the Basic Manual) was published in 2004. The Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) together with partners of the organic movement in the Tropics were commissioned by IFOAM to complete two new training manuals that build on the Basic Manual. The new IFOAM training manuals address the two basic climatic zones of the Tropics, the Arid and Semi-Arid Tropics, and the Humid Tropics.&#xD;
For both new manuals, already existing material was collected, screened and condensed into comprehensive training manuals. Additionally, a large number of farmers, trainers and scientists were asked for their experience.&#xD;
Partner institutions from the Tropics actively collaborated in the development of the manuals. The partners of the manual for the Arid and Semi-Arid Tropics are from Asia (India), Africa (Senegal and Tunisia) and Latin&#xD;
America (Chile).&#xD;
The training manuals contain case studies of organic farming systems, describe successful organic marketing initiatives and offer guidelines for the main crops of the Tropics. With the informative text, transparencies and&#xD;
didactical recommendations the training manuals offer a resource basis for trainers with the idea of encouraging individual adaptation and further development of the material according to need. The training manuals are available on separate CDs in English, French and Spanish.&#xD;
The training manuals were commissioned by IFOAM and funded through its program IFOAM-GROWING ORGANIC II (I-GO II). The Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and the Swiss Import Promotion Programme (SIPPO) provided co-funding.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18685/1/Kilcher-etal-2007-training-manual.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kilcher, Lukas; Weidmann, Gilles and Garibay, Salvador V.    (2007) IFOAM Training Manual: Training Manual for Organic Agriculture in the Humid Tropics.   1 edition. IFOAM Training Manual . International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements , Bonn.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18685/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>