<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rotwein unter Hochspannung: Mehrjährige Qualitäts-&#xD;
Untersuchung mit Gas-Discharge-Visualisation (GDV)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bigler, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Levite, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Meer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaufmann, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Dr. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigated whether we can detect any differences in red wines produced either&#xD;
by bio-dynamic or by standard organic agriculture. We used standard methods to&#xD;
investigate the quality of the wines and Gas-Discharge-Visualisation (GDV) method to&#xD;
investigate a holistic quality of the wines. With the GDV-method, samples are exposed&#xD;
to high voltage. The halo-like gas discharge caused by a burst of electron emission of&#xD;
the sample is captured by a digital camera underneath a transparent, dielectric surface.&#xD;
The wine samples measured originate from an On-Farm experiment in South of&#xD;
France with two separately managed but neighbouring blocks (same soil and climate&#xD;
conditions): bio-organic and bio-dynamic. Apart from the use of bio-dynamic preparations,&#xD;
plant protection and fertilization was the same in both blocks. The vinification of&#xD;
the sampled grapes was made in two replicates which were analysed separately.&#xD;
During the three years of examination, the bio-dynamic samples did not reveal significant&#xD;
differences when assessed with standard methods (sensory triangle test, polyphenol&#xD;
analysis etc.). However, with GDV measurements the values for the imageparameter&#xD;
“mean intensity” were mostly higher for the wines from bio-dynamically&#xD;
produced grapes. In a „mixed effect model“ (GDV-parameter „mean intensity“ as&#xD;
dependent variable, replication und cultivation-system as fix and year as random&#xD;
effect) the difference was statistically significant. We conclude that the GDV-method&#xD;
has an interesting potential to detect very sensitively differences in food attributes.&#xD;
However, in order to interpret the results in terms of consumer-relevant quality further&#xD;
research is needed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14446/1/Bigler_14446.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bigler, C.; Levite, D.; van der Meer, M.; Kaufmann, A. and Weibel, Dr. F.    (2009) Rotwein unter Hochspannung: Mehrjährige Qualitäts- Untersuchung mit Gas-Discharge-Visualisation (GDV).       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14446/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>