<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC FARMING AND SOCIAL CAPITAL APPROACH IN THE  RESTORATION OF SUSTAINABLE AGRICULTURAL LIVELIHOOD IN A POST-CONFLICT SETTING: A CASE OF NORTHERN UGANDA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Odokonyero, Kennedy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report presents a discussion of how organic farming and social capital development can contribute towards the restoration of sustainable agricultural livelihood in a post-conflict setting; with a case study of Northern Uganda. Strictly speaking, the paper goes beyond a simple exposition of the value of organic farming, but it attempts to explain the complex ways in which social capital relates with organic farming to revitalize sustainable agricultural systems, and impact on the livelihood of communities in a post-conflict situation, with respect to household food security and income.&#xD;
The report hereby presented was produced based on a working method of ‘‘Colleague supervision’’, involving scheduled meetings with colleagues who co-participated in the ‘‘Organic Agriculture in a Development Perspective’’ course from 21st January, 2012 to the 16th May, 2012. By this method, interactive students’ group discussions were arranged between March and May, which involved formulation of the report scope, report structure, guiding direction of the report focus and selection of relevant literatures, based on the chosen situation and background knowledge of the problem identified in this report.&#xD;
It was from such mutual group interactions with colleagues that this report is finally presented, with immeasurable feedback from colleagues in pointing out inadequacies, omissions and suggesting areas of refinement.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Vaarst, Mette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-05-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21309/1/FINAL-ORGANIC_AGRIC_Report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Odokonyero, Kennedy     (editor): Vaarst, Mette (Ed.)    (2012) ORGANIC FARMING AND SOCIAL CAPITAL APPROACH IN THE RESTORATION OF SUSTAINABLE AGRICULTURAL LIVELIHOOD IN A POST-CONFLICT SETTING: A CASE OF NORTHERN UGANDA.    Aarhus University, Faculty of Science and Technology.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21309/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>