<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic agriculture: opportunities and challenges</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristiansen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taji, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reganold, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic movement may have gained a place in the spotlight of the mainstream media now, but it has not been like that for long. Since the 1950s, organic farmers operating at a grass roots level have devised, tested and shared production methods. They have codified a set of ideals into a pioneering best practice agricultural management system that addresses multiple community values. Niche markets have gradually been created, commonly based on trust and goodwill (formal certification did not begin until the 1960s and 1970s), and often using novel direct marketing strategies such as box schemes and community supported agriculture. After many years of consumers having to hunt around for their organic produce from several suppliers, perhaps directly from the farmer, the task is now a lot easier with specialist food shops and organic shelf space in supermarkets, in the industrialised world at least. Global links have been forged in all continents as organic agriculture has been seen to be an effective rural development option.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CSIRO Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Kristiansen, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Taji, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reganold, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14042/13/14042.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristiansen, P.; Taji, A. and Reganold, J.    (2006) Organic agriculture: opportunities and challenges.    In: Kristiansen, P.; Taji, A. and Reganold, J. (Eds.)   Organic Agriculture: a Global Perspective.  CSIRO Publishing, Collingwood, chapter 18, pp. 421-441.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14042/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>