<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Specialisation of organic farms through co-operation</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the present research is to analyse how organic farms could specialise and cultivate with appropriate efficiency without having to compromise the diversity necessary for organic farming. The obstacles for organic farm co-operation will be charted and the aim is to find viable solutions to the problems. The aim is also to influence political decision-making so that the threshold for co-operation could be lowered. &#xD;
&#xD;
In Finland, the share of organic production of the total agricultural land is currently 7%. The demand for organic products exceeds supply. Diversity decreases the profitability of the farm: In organic production, specialisation has been feasible only up to a certain point. Appropriate crop rotation means, in practice, that in addition to the main production line, the farm engages in supplementary production. However, diversified production inevitably leads to small-scale production. The amount of work increases the equipment and labour costs per parcel. Co-operation can bring even larger benefits in organic production than in conventional production. Genuine savings in workload are generated. On animal and cereal farms it would allow both farmers to specialise in their respective lines while safeguarding a sufficient nutrient rotation. This would be highly sensible also in terms of environmental impact. &#xD;
&#xD;
The research will comprise both a written section and two different farm-level studies. Literature and experts will be consulted in order to chart the technical and legislative obstacles, as well as those posed by subsidy policies for a comprehensive co-operation between farms. On the farm-level section, the project will be familiarised with two or three partnerships engaged in comprehensive co-operation. The research project will involve two to five farms for study purposes (project farms). These farms have recently launched co-operation or are planning to do so. The project will draw up a co-operation model jointly with the farms. The functioning of the model will be monitored throughout the research period. &#xD;
&#xD;
The progress of the project will be presented in media. The final report will be published in the form of a guide directed at advisory personnel and farms. The research will produce practical and immediately applicable data on the opportunities to expand co-operation between organic and conventional farms, as well as in the activities of the relevant authorities.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Specialisation of organic farms through co-operation.  [Luomutilojen erikoistuminen yhteistyön avulla.]   Runs 2003 - 2004.      Project Leader(s): Lätti, Markku, Work Efficiency Institute.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5686/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>