<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Living Soil Association: Pioneering Organic Farming and Innovating Social Inclusion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Living Soil Association of Tasmania (LSAT) (1946-1960) pioneered the concepts of organic food and farming in Australiaʼs smallest state, for the decade immediately after WWII. The LSAT was one of the worldʼs first organisations to promote organic farming. It was preceded by New Zealandʼs Humic Compost Society (founded in 1941), the Australian Organic Farming and Gardening Society (1944), Australiaʼs Victorian Compost Society (1945), and Englandʼs Soil Association (1946). The Tasmanian Association engaged, or was officially affiliated, with each of these four organisations. The LSAT actively courted and recruited a broad spectrum of organisations and government departments, particularly those with interests, or responsibilities, in agriculture, health, and education. The Association consistently sought a co-operative approach while avoiding a confrontational approach. An innovation of the LSAT was the provision for ʻJunior membersʼ; the LSAT constitution included separate and specific Objects for Junior Groups, one of which was for school children to eat organic food.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Journal of Organic Systems</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16429/1/16429.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2009) The Living Soil Association: Pioneering Organic Farming and Innovating Social Inclusion.   Journal of Organic Systems, 4 (1), pp. 15-33.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16429/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>