<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards a strategy for organic agriculture development in Lebanon</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BTEICH, Marie Reine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Lebanese agricultural sector faces problems, which limit its development and impoverish people involved in it. Organic agriculture aims at developing self-reliant and environmentally-sound farming systems, which can improve the economic and social situation of those who participate in the production, processing and marketing processes. Therefore organic agriculture can be considered as a solution to degraded agricultural systems and to unviable rural areas. In Lebanon, organic agriculture is in its very initial phase and to date, no field study has been undertaken to describe the status of the sector nor its potential for development. This study was based upon a survey conducted in Lebanon in March-April 2002. The survey covered the different interest groups involved, or likely to become involved, in the organic sector, namely: organic farmers, consumers, shop owners and institutions. The identification of requirements, strengths and weaknesses throughout the organic production, processing and marketing chain allowed proposing options for the development of the sector over the short, medium and long-term. Results essentially showed that while public institutions were neither interested nor equipped to promote organic agriculture, a number of pioneer and educated farmers and a few non-governmental organizations were quite active in the sector. The lack of agreed organic standards and a trusted guarantee system, coupled with national consumers’ enthusiasm with traditional foods and readiness to pay premiums for what is perceived as healthy food, suggest that capacity-building for organic agriculture should target local - rather than export - markets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6470/1/MariereineBteich02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>BTEICH, Marie Reine   (2002) Towards a strategy for organic agriculture development in Lebanon.  [Vers une stratégie pour le développement de l’agriculture biologique au Liban.]  Thesis, IAMB - Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 275. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6470/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>