<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswirkungen der muttergebundenen Kälberaufzucht auf das&#xD;
Melkverhalten der Kühe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Dr. Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Regula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roth, Béatrice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hillmann, Dr. Edna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The introduction of mother-bonded calf rearing into organic dairy farming faces some&#xD;
problems. Regarding the cow, the disturbed milk ejection seems to be the most important&#xD;
one. We compared two groups of cows, which had permanent (Kp, n=11) or temporarily&#xD;
(Kt,n=13) contact to their calves until the 90th day p.p. with cows separated&#xD;
from their offspring within 24 h after calving (Ko, n=24). Since suckling following the&#xD;
machine milking strongly influences milk ejection, the Kt-cows were allowed to meet&#xD;
their calves 15 minutes before the usual milking times (milking interval 10:14 hours) in&#xD;
a separated area. Milk flow curves were recorded at the 6th day after calving and&#xD;
afterwards every fortnight at least until the 90th day of lactation. At the same time&#xD;
bucket milk samples of each cow were collected. Results showed clear differences&#xD;
between the groups with and without calf contact. In these groups, the milk yield&#xD;
gained by machine milking was much lower (up to 10 kg per milking, p&lt;0.001) and&#xD;
contained less fat (- 1%, p&lt;0.001). The frequency of bimodal flow curves did not differ&#xD;
between the groups due to the loss of the cisternal milk in the Kt and Kp-group. Mean&#xD;
milk flow was reduced in the suckled cows and decreased significantly in the investigated&#xD;
period from 1.4 to 0.6 and from 1.1 to 0.8 kg min-1 (F2,463=27.36, p&lt;0.0001) for&#xD;
the Kp and Kt-group, respectively. Thus, suckling prior to machine milking does not&#xD;
avoid disturbed milk ejections in suckled cows. Further investigations should focus on&#xD;
splitting machine milking and suckling to solve this problem.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14021/1/Barth_14021.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barth, Dr. Kerstin; Schneider, Regula; Roth, Béatrice and Hillmann, Dr. Edna    (2009) Auswirkungen der muttergebundenen Kälberaufzucht auf das Melkverhalten der Kühe.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14021/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>