<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Can a peach production in organic farming be requalified with polyphenols ? &#xD;
A comparative case study in Rhone-Alpes Region (France)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fauriel, Joël</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, Stéphane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Plénet, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amiot, Marie-Jo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Peach production in the Rhône-Alps region is increasingly challenged by mediterranean European regions. A possible regional strategy would consist in the development of qualification signs. A significant part of the peach production is already labelled (CCP, Red Label, Organic). How such labels relate with quality attributes at field level ? Can polyphenols be considered as an asset in a re-qualification process of peach production? &#xD;
&#xD;
To contribute to these issues, we present preliminary results derived from field work in Rhône-Alps. The study was conducted on 12 orchards of yellow peach (cv Spring Lady) in farms. 10 orchards were managed according to the above mentioned specifications while 2 were cultivated without specifications. Farmers practices were characterised in 2004; their consequences on orchards conditions and performances were measured. Polyphenols analyses was conducted on 12 fruit samples. &#xD;
&#xD;
Organic peaches could be differentiated with usual qualitative attributes (firmness, refractometric index, calibre). Their polyphenol content appeared as 3 times higher than other fruits from our sample (147 mg/100g EAG versus 95,5 in Red Label; 55,5 in CCP and 62,5 for the others). Polyphenol contents from standard production were consistent with reference levels, whereas Red Labelled peaches were intermediate. Tree vigour and environmental conditions apparently play a key-role in the synthesis of total polyphenols. These results open perspectives for integrating production processes in quality construction, since polyphenol content could be an additional asset in organic fruit production and not simply a stress indicator, and for relating production with marketing initiatives.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6850/1/6850.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fauriel, Joël; Bellon, Stéphane; Plénet, Daniel and Amiot, Marie-Jo    (2005) Can a peach production in organic farming be requalified with polyphenols ? A comparative case study in Rhone-Alpes Region (France).       Poster at:   International symposium on human health effects of fruits and vegetables, Quebec, Canada, August 17-20, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6850/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>