<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FATTY ACID COMPOSITION OF ORGANIC GOAT KID MEAT FROM DAIRY GOAT AND CROSSBRED MEAT GOAT KIDS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bender, Sophia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ude, Gracia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Georg, Heiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In contrast to the increasing demand for dairy goat products in Germany, a market for goat kid meat as a related product does not exist. Thus, the objective of this study was to develop a concept for organic goat kid meat production for dairy goat farms. In collaboration with a wholesaler, organic dairy goat farmers and marketing research the experimental part of this study was to find out if cross-breeding of meat-goats could improve meat quality and performance of fattening goat kids together with other factors like concentrate ratio of the diet, genotype, sex, housing vs. pasture as well as raising strategy during milk feeding period. Our results indicate that even a low input level of concentrates (10 % of total dry matter intake per goat kid and year) is sufficient to achieve the requested carcass weight of 12 kg at slaughter when goat kids are kept on pasture. Dressing percentage in both experimental years was affected by concentrate level, the more concentrates (40 %) the higher dressing percentage. Comparing years 2011 and 2012, dressing percentage was 4 % higher in 2012 for both concentrate levels. Daily weight gain per kid ranged from 122 to 133 g/d significantly influenced by concentrate level and sex, in 2011 as well by genotype. A low concentrate level (KF10) resulted in higher contents of Omega 3 fatty acids, male KF10-goat kids had highest omega 3 content of 1.19 g/100 fatty acid. The raising of “Capretto” type kids for slaughter indicated, that artificial rearing of kids using cow milk is beneficial compared to mother bonded rearing.&#xD;
Results indicated, that rearing and fattening of goat kids even under low input production levels on pasture can be realized und will produce higher meat qualities regarding fatty acid composition.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24073/1/24073_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bender, Sophia; Ude, Gracia; Rahmann, Gerold; Aulrich, Karen and Georg, Heiko    (2014) FATTY ACID COMPOSITION OF ORGANIC GOAT KID MEAT FROM DAIRY GOAT AND CROSSBRED MEAT GOAT KIDS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 523-526.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24073/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>