<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigating the selectivity of weed harrowing with new methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bibby, Bo Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schou, Anders P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In six field experiments it was investigated whether row spacing, timing, direction and orientation of post-emergence weed harrowing in spring barley influenced the selectivity and whether it is important that increasing intensities of harrowing are generated either by increasing number of passes or increasing driving speed. Selectivity was defined as the relationship between crop burial in soil immediately after treatment and weed control. To estimate crop burial, digital image analysis was used in order to make the estimations objective. The study showed that narrow row spacing decreased selectivity in a late growth stage (21) whereas row spacing in the range of 5.3 cm to 24 cm had no effects in an early growth stage (12). Harrowing across rows decreased selectivity in one out of two experiments. Whether repeated passes with the harrowing were carried out in the same orientation along the rows or in alternative orientations forth and back was unimportant. There were indications that high driving speed decreases selectivity and that repeated passes with low driving speed are better than single treatments with high driving speed. Impacts on selectivity, however, were small and only significant at high degrees of weed control. Timing had no significant impact on selectivity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14987/1/14987.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Jesper; Bibby, Bo Martin and Schou, Anders P.   (2008) Investigating the selectivity of weed harrowing with new methods.   Weed Research, 48 (6), pp. 523-532.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14987/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>