<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Advanced Non-Chemical and Close to Plant Weed Control system for Organic Agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nørremark, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Swain, Kishore</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Melander, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Use of chemical has been reduced in agriculture for controlling weeds emergence. The use of alternative systems, such as cultural practices (mulching, flame, intercropping etc.) and mechanical system (hoe, tine etc.) has been introduced by various researchers. Automation technique based on sensors controlled system has enhanced the efficiency of the mechanical system for weed control. Mostly, low cost image acquisition sensors and optical sensor to detect the plant ensuring swift operation of vehicles close the crop plants to remove competitive weeds. The available system need to be evaluated to get best possible system for close to plant (CTP) weed removal. In the study various non-chemical weed control measures has been explored and 30 mechanical tools for CTP were evaluated. High precision tillage solutions and thermal weed control by pulsed lasers for eradication of stem or main shoot were found to be the most promising weed control concepts for CTP operation.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Salokhe, V.M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Soni, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20656/4/20656.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nørremark, Michael; Swain, Kishore and Melander, Bo    (2009) Advanced Non-Chemical and Close to Plant Weed Control system for Organic Agriculture.   In: Salokhe, V.M.  and Soni, P. (Eds.)  Proceedings of the conference 'Role of agricultural engineering in advent of changing global landscape' , p. 8.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20656/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>