<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswinterung im Jahr 2011/12: Auswirkungen auf &#xD;
Winterweizen-Liniensorten und Winterweizenpopulationen in der F10</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brumlop, Sarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>TThree winter wheat composite cross (CC) populations were created in 2001 in the UK consisting either of 20 modern wheat parents (called A population), a subset of 12 high quality parents (Q), or a subset of 9 high yielding parents (Y). Seed of the F4 was transferred to the University of Kassel in 2005 and the populations were grown since then under organic and conventional conditions in well separated large (&gt;100 m2) plots in two parallel sets (12 populations total) without conscious selection applied. In the conventional system fungicides and insecticides were not applied to expose the populations to natural pest and disease pressure. In addition, since the F8 two A populations have been maintained as broadcast sown populations without mechanical weed control. In the F10 all 14 populations were compared in a replicated field trial to the mixture of the 20 parents and the three wheat cultivars Achat, Akteur, and Capo. The parents were also grown in unreplicated plots for seed increase. A serious frost period of 3 weeks in February after an unusually mild winter resulted in winterkill in 16 out of the 20 parent varieties to the point that the plots had to be given up. In contrast, the populations, the mixture of the 20 parents, and the three reference varieties recovered, resulting in low but acceptable yields.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21495/1/21495_Brumlop.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brumlop, Sarah and Finckh, Maria R.    (2013) Auswinterung im Jahr 2011/12: Auswirkungen auf Winterweizen-Liniensorten und Winterweizenpopulationen in der F10.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21495/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>