<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Establishment of potato variety performance trials under growing regimes</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to select potato varieties suitable for organic production, information is required on yield, marketability, post-harvest storage performance and disease and pest resistance of different potato varieities grown under organic conditions.  This project will aim to study selected potato varieitiess growing under organic conditions in order to provide information on the following: general field performance, with emphasis on characteristics important for organic conditions (e.g. speed of emergence, ground cover, foliage blight), and comparison with results from non-organic sites; yield and marketability prior to and after storage; the incidence of a range of common skin disorders (e.g. common scab, black scurf, silver scurf, black dot netted scab); the incidence of rotting in stored produce; blight control strategies used by organic growers; the efficacy of planting physiologically old seed and harvest date to escape blight in combination with permitted fungicides and varities of varying resistance; and variety choice and PCN control.  Results of the study will provide information on the relevance of data collected from non-organic trials to the organic situation (comparison of data from organic and non-organic sites may indicate if there is improved health under organic conditions).  The study will also provide better understanding of control measures useful in minimising potato blight, as well as data regarding the level of skin blemish diseases from organically grown produce and its impact on crop value.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Establishment of potato variety performance trials under growing regimes.    Runs 1991 - 1995.      Project Leader(s): Unspecified, , National Institute of Agricultural Botany.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9970/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>