<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ist eine temporäre Reduzierung der Bodenbearbeitungsintensität zu Körnerleguminosen im ökologischen Landbau ohne Ertragseinbußen erreichbar?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stieber, Jette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtke, Knut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic agriculture intensive soil tillage is often used to suppress weeds, pests and pathogens and encourage the mineralization of nitrogen. Nevertheless intensive soil tillage promotes erosion by wind and water, soil compaction and nutrient losses. The present field trial determined the effects of reduced tillage and no-till on yield development of pea to counteract these negative impacts of conventional tillage. At Pinkowitz (near Dresden) pea was seeded after a cover crop of oat and sunflower in three different tillage systems: after plow, cultivator or without any soil tillage (direct seeding). In half of the plots subterranean clover was undersown into emerging pea crop stands. The plant growth of pea and weeds as well the Nmin stock in soil was ascertained at two appointments, and on ripeness of pea. No-till caused a significant lower plant density which could not fully compensated by higher seed numbers per plant or seed weight. So grain yield was significant higher after plowing and reduced tillage in comparison to no-till. The low capability for compensation was caused by high weed yield, low Nitrogen Nutrition Index and soil physical parameters. To achieve higher grain yield with no-till it is important to identify the causes of low emergence.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21227/1/21227_Stieber.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stieber, Jette and Schmidtke, Knut    (2013) Ist eine temporäre Reduzierung der Bodenbearbeitungsintensität zu Körnerleguminosen im ökologischen Landbau ohne Ertragseinbußen erreichbar?       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21227/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>