<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökonomische Rentabilität legumer Zwischenfrüchte &#xD;
im Fruchtfolgeglied Getreide - Getreide</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cais, Kathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rehm, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salzeder, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schätzl, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The cropping of leguminous cover crops usually leads to higher yields in subsequent cereals. The economic efficiency of leguminous cover crops was calculated in several field trials. Criterion was the yield (with adjusted costs) from the succeeding crops winter triticale and spring oats, respectively, after different leguminous cover crops undersown or as stubble seed in comparison to a control plot without cover crop. Thereby, the costs for seeds and the variable machine costs were taken into account. &#xD;
The highest yield was reached for both types of grain following undersown white clover, the second highest following undersown black medic. In contrast, the yield was lower following red clover and grass-clover undersowings as well as different stubble seeds. In parts of these variants, the yield was even lower than in the control without cover crop.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21329/1/21329_Urbatzka.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, Peer; Cais, Kathrin; Rehm, Anna; Salzeder, Georg and Schätzl, Robert    (2013) Ökonomische Rentabilität legumer Zwischenfrüchte im Fruchtfolgeglied Getreide - Getreide.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21329/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>