<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alternative à la chimiothérapie dans la maîtrise du parasitisme digestif des petits ruminants:  Rôle des tanins condensés</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Recent results have shown that tanniferous plants might represent an alternative option to chemical drugs to control parasitic nematodes of the gastrointestinal tract in small ruminants since some anthelmintic activity has been associated with the consumption of the plants.&#xD;
The 2 main objectives of the project are :&#xD;
&#xD;
1 to understand the mechanisms explaining the activity of tannin rich  plants against nematode parasites of sheep and goats&#xD;
&#xD;
2 to identify  novel natural resources to exploit for non chemical control of parasite &#xD;
in various farming systems, including organic farming. In particular, the project focus on potential  industrial agroressources &#xD;
&#xD;
In vitro and in vivo  assays   on parasites  and on infected  animals to measure the anthelmintic effects, methods of histology and electron microscopy to examine the lesions induced by tannin to the worms, and biochemical analysis of plant extracts or industrial agroressources have been used.&#xD;
&#xD;
The project is still  in progress. &#xD;
&#xD;
However,  the current results indicate that : &#xD;
&#xD;
- condensed tannins interfere both with the main function  and structure  of third stage larvae &#xD;
&#xD;
- some industrial resources for tannins have been identified</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Alternative à la chimiothérapie dans la maîtrise du parasitisme digestif des petits ruminants: Rôle des tanins condensés.  [Alternatives to chemical drugs in the control of gastrointestinal parasitisim in small ruminants : role of condensed tannins.]   Runs 2005 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Hoste, Dr Hervé, INRA.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6525/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>