<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Composition of volatile compounds in bovine milk heat  treated by instant infusion pasteurization and correlation to sensory analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hougaard, A.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vestergaard, J.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varming, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bredie, Wender L. P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ipsen, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Volatile compounds in skim milk and nonstandardised milk  subjected to instant infusion pasteurisation at 80째C, 100째C and 120째C were compared with raw milk, high temperature short time pasteurised milk and milk pasteurised at 85째C/30 s. The composition of volatile compounds differed between infusion pasteurisation treated samples and the reference pasteurisations. The sensory properties of skim milk subjected to instant infusion pasteurisation were described by negative attributes, such as cardboard sour and plastic flavours, which are not associated normally with fresh milk. Partial least squares modelling showed good correlation between the volatile compounds and the sensory properties, indicating the predictive and possible causal importance of the volatile compounds for the sensory characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-02-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18767/1/18767.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hougaard, A.B.; Vestergaard, J.S.; Varming, C.; Bredie, Wender L. P. and Ipsen, R.   (2011) Composition of volatile compounds in bovine milk heat treated by instant infusion pasteurization and correlation to sensory analysis.   International Journal of Dairy Technology, 64 (1), pp. 34-44.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18767/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>