<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Muligheder og barrierer for brug af økologiske ingredienser i skolemadsordninger</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Stine Rosenlund</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Hannah Wirenfeldt</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The report considers the following aspects:&#xD;
1. The arguments that two Danish municipalities mention in relation to using, or choosing not to use, organic ingredients in school meal systems.&#xD;
2. The reasons for school meal companies to use, or not to use, organic ingredients in their production as well as the challenges they meet in relation to organic food.&#xD;
In relation to analyzing how the municipalities organize the school meal systems, we include issues such as the most common arguments used to legitimize their choice of meal system, objectives, involvement of users, most relevant decision makers etc. In the case of school meal companies, the project includes an analysis of barriers such as economy, supply of organic ingredients, structural conditions, cooperation with municipalities etc.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14871/1/14871a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14871/2/14871b.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Stine Rosenlund and Schmidt, Hannah Wirenfeldt   (2008) Muligheder og barrierer for brug af økologiske ingredienser i skolemadsordninger.  [Barriers and possibilities for using organic ingredients in school meal systems.]  Thesis, Technical University of Denmark, Roskilde Universitetscenter.  .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14871/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>