<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sensory milk properties at the farm level – the terroir dimension</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vestergaard, Jannie S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Troels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bredie, Wender L.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In recent years, the Danish milk market has shown an increase in the consumption of organic milk as well as a growing variety of milk with specific features including farm milk. The production of milk from a single farm and pasture-based (PB) feeding regimes is of special interest as it implies a “sense of place” or terroir. The PB feeding regimes vary with season and might also vary on a day-to-day basis. It is therefore important to understand the impact of the feed on the sensory properties of the milk [1].  &#xD;
This study aims at demonstrating how analytical sensory analysis can provide important information about the influence of breed, season and variation in farm management from PB feeding regimes on the sensory properties of organic farm milk. The study was performed in 2007 and 2008 during two seasons (spring/autumn) representing 28 milk samples from 7 organic farms with either Holstein or Jersey cows. PB feeding regimes were based on pastures with varying amounts of white clover together with perennial ryegrass and supplement feeding with silage and concentrates. Significant results were found for season and breed with a larger variation in sensory flavour properties of spring milk and milk from Holstein cows. In general, there was a tendency of the milk being characterized as having a ‘greener’ odour, ‘sweet’ and ‘maize-like’ flavour in spring and a more ‘bitter’ taste in the autumn. The results show a distinct relation between sensory milk properties and the amount of pasture in the ration and white clover in the pasture. Relations to other production conditions such as composition of the supplement feed also tended to have an impact on the sensory characteristics of the milk. &#xD;
It is thus concluded, that a sensory analytical tool can provide important information about the sensory properties of organic farm milk, reflecting time and place. Seasonal variations appear to be an important factor in the terroir dimension of milk and may be more actively used in relation to communication of the sensory properties to the consumer.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-07-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16354/2/16354a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vestergaard, Jannie S.; Kristensen, Troels; Søegaard, Karen and Bredie, Wender L.P.    (2009) Sensory milk properties at the farm level – the terroir dimension.   In:     Delegate Manual, Elsevier, Oxford, UK.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16354/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>