<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>2004 update of overview supply and demand of organic concentrated feed in the EU</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lowman, Steve</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Summary of key trends and changes in 2004&#xD;
The total organic flock in the EU 25 appears to have increased by between 6 and 9 per cent, depending on stock category. Greatest increases occurred for sheep in France, Italy, Spain and the UK. In the other livestock categories, increases in some countries were balanced by decline in others, leading to overall small increases (see Table 3 update1).&#xD;
&#xD;
The production area of organic cereals increased between 2003 and 2004 by approximately 6 %. Significant reduction (9%) in the cereals area seems to have occurred in Italy, Spain and Hungary, whereas the area increased in Austria, Greece and Portugal (see Table 4 update).&#xD;
&#xD;
The area for pulses appears to have declined by a further 14% in the EU 25. Reductions occurred in particular in France and Italy as two important producers of organic pulses, but increased in some other countries. There is greater uncertainty in the data for pulses, as not as many countries report data for pulses separately.&#xD;
&#xD;
On 100% organic rations the demand for concentrate feeds for all organic livestock currently kept in the EU would have risen from approximately 1.1 million to 1.2 million tonnes. The proportions remain unchanged (65% of this demand is for cereals, 26% for pulses that could be grown in most regions of the EU, and 9% for high quality protein sources) (see Table 5 update).&#xD;
&#xD;
In all three years, the EU would have grown more than sufficient organic cereals to feed all organic livestock on a 100% organic diet. For organic cereals, there seems to be a surplus of supply over demand that would allow for further increases in stock numbers at current feed production levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
A potential deficit for home grown pulses that was projected for 2003 is likely to have increased further in 2004, because of reductions in the area for organic pulses. It appears that the intended shift to 100% organic diets has not stimulated increases in the production of organic pulses in the EU.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10980/1/wp42_2004_supply__and_demand_update.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10980/2/eu_feed_2004_update.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne and Lowman, Steve         (2004) 2004 update of overview supply and demand of organic concentrated feed in the EU.   EEC 2092/91 (Organic Revision Internal Project Report), no.  D 41(2) 2004 update. University of Wales Aberystwyth, Institute of Rural Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10980/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>