<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modellansatz und -konzeption zur quantitativen Politikfolgenabschätzung für den biologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matthias, Stolze</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peter, Midmore</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Although organic farming has expanded significantly in Germany and Switzerland in the last decade, there is still a lack of a sectoral policy model that is able to analyse the impact of policy measures on organic farming. Equilibrium models and econometric models are considered for various reasons as rather inappropriate, whereas optimisation models in form of a sector-consistent farm group model seem to be a promising model approach. The bottom-up approach of this type of model  makes it possible to analyse the impacts of policy measures on farm incomes and volume of production of organic and conventional farms at farm type, regional and sectoral level.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3677/1/3677.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sanders, Jürn; Lampkin, Nicolas; Matthias, Stolze and Peter, Midmore    (2005) Modellansatz und -konzeption zur quantitativen Politikfolgenabschätzung für den biologischen Landbau.   In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3677/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>