<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ertrag und Zuckergehalte bei Möhren nach Applikation der biologisch-dynamischen Präparate Hornmist und Hornkiesel in verschiedenen Umwelten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fleck, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Fragstein, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2002 and 2003 field experiments with organically grown carrots (cv. 'Rodelika') were performed to investigate effects of ridge vs. flat cultivation, nitrogen supply, EM application and biodynamic spray preparations on yield and sugar fractions. Particularly in the dry summer of 2003 ridge cultivated carrots produced lower yields than those from the flat system. In both years EMs resulted in higher yields; nitrogen fertilization (horn pellets) affected yields only in the first year. Biodynamic horn manure preparation decreased yields and increased glucose content of the carrots in 2003. In 2002 horn silica increased quantities of monosaccharides.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3840/1/3840.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fleck, Michael; von Fragstein, Peter and Heß, Jürgen    (2005) Ertrag und Zuckergehalte bei Möhren nach Applikation der biologisch-dynamischen Präparate Hornmist und Hornkiesel in verschiedenen Umwelten.  [Effects of biodynamic spray preparations horn manure and horn silica on yield and sugar content of different cultivated carrots.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3840/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>