<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von biologischer und konventioneller Bewirtschaftung&#xD;
auf biologische Bodenqualitätsparameter: Entwicklungen im&#xD;
DOK Langzeitversuch nach pH-Regulierung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oberholzer, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the long-term DOK field trial at Therwil, Switzerland, agricultural farming systems&#xD;
are compared since 1978: CONFYM (mineral and organic fertilisers, synthetic&#xD;
pesticides), BIOORG (organic fertilisers, mechanical weeding and biological disease&#xD;
and pest control) and BIODYN (with composted manure and bio-dynamic&#xD;
preparations), all of them at two fertiliser intensities of 0.7 and 1.4 livestock units per&#xD;
ha, respectively. They are compared with CONMIN (conventionally managed,&#xD;
exclusively minerally fertilised) and NOFERT (unfertilised control). CONFYM and&#xD;
CONMIN were limed with 2.7 t CaCO3 ha-1 in 1999, CONMIN with additional 2 t&#xD;
CaCO3 ha-1 in 2005, since pH values had dropped below officially recommended&#xD;
values. In spring of 1998 and 2006 soil samples from 0 to 20 cm depth were analysed&#xD;
for soil microbial biomass (substrate induced respiration SIR and chloroform&#xD;
fumigation extraction CFE), soil respiration and dehydrogenase activity.&#xD;
NOFERT and CONMIN exhibited the lowest microbial soil properties Manure&#xD;
application influenced most soil microbial parameters positively. Differences between&#xD;
treatments in soil microbial parameters were smaller in 2006 than in 1998 due to pH&#xD;
regulation. Only CFE and dehydrogenase activity were higher in BIODYN than in&#xD;
BIOORG and CONFYM in 2006. For physiological methods SIR and soil respiration,&#xD;
no differences between these three systems were measured. Because of liming,&#xD;
manure use, a wide ley rotation and equal plant residue management no more&#xD;
differences between BIOORG and CONFYM, representing the predominant farming&#xD;
systems in Switzerland were observed for all soil microbial properties.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14512/1/Oberholzer_14512.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oberholzer, Hans-Rudolf; Fließbach, Andreas; Mäder, Paul and Mayer, Jochen    (2009) Einfluss von biologischer und konventioneller Bewirtschaftung auf biologische Bodenqualitätsparameter: Entwicklungen im DOK Langzeitversuch nach pH-Regulierung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14512/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>