<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The challenge of ecological justice in a globalising world</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ecological justice is a challenging concept in relation to the current development of agriculture, including organic agriculture, because it positions social and ecological interests against market liberalism and economic growth. Ecological justice concerns fairness with respect to common environments, and it is therefore closely connected to the idea of commons. The concepts of commons and ecological justice are particularly relevant to organic agriculture, which builds on close cooperation with ecological systems and cycles, and they may suggest ways to resist the pressures of globalisation and structural and technological developments.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ISOFAR, Bonn, Germany</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Köpke, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cornish, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4307/4/4307-Alroe_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alrøe, Hugo F.    (2005) The challenge of ecological justice in a globalising world.   In: Köpke, U.; Niggli, U.; Neuhoff, D.; Cornish, P.; Lockeretz, W. and Willer, H. (Eds.)  Researching Sustainable Systems 2005. Proceedings of the First Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agricultural Research., ISOFAR, Bonn, Germany, pp. 406-409.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>