<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Role of forage legumes mixed cropping on biomass yield and bacterial community composition</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zarea, Mohammad Javad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ghalavand, Amir</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jamshidi, Ehsan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Intercropping berseem clover (Trifolium alexandrinum L.) may increase forage yield and free-living N2-fixing bacterial species community. Berseem clover was mixed with Persian clover (Trifolium resupinatum L.) at ratios of 1:0, 3:1, 1:1 and 1:3 and with Persian clover/ annual medic (Medicago regidula cv. Regidula) at ratio of 1:1:1 at Field Crops Department, Faculty of Agriculture, Tarbiat modares university, Tehran, Iran in 2007. Mixed ratio had significant effect on total forage yield. Total forage yield was greatest with a 1:1:1 ratio of clovers to annual medic. Total intercrop yields with clovers/ annual medic at 1:1:1 plants m–2 was 214.37g m–2 DM yields. Mixed cropping increased rhizosphere microorganisms viz. bacteria, free-living N2-fixing bacteria and Azotobacter counts. Free-living N2-fixing bacterial species and Azotobacter populations of 96 g-1 soil*103 cells and 24 g-1 soil*102 cells, respectively, obtained from mixed cropping with 1:1:1 clovers to annual medic ratios.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11208/1/Zarea_11208_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zarea, Mohammad Javad; Ghalavand, Amir and Jamshidi, Ehsan    (2008) Role of forage legumes mixed cropping on biomass yield and bacterial community composition.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11208/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>