<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Regulierung von Steinbrand (Tilletia caries) unter besonderer Berücksichtigung von Befallstoleranzgrenzen und direkten Maßnahmen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Waldow, Franziska</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahn, Marga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to the Council Regulation (EEC) No 1452/2003 since 1st January 2004 all plant material used for organic farming should have been produced under organic farming conditions. Seed-borne diseases tend to accumulate and develop into a problem after several multiplication cycles without adequate disease control. In recent years, contamination of wheat seeds with spores of Tilletia caries has become a serious problem for seed quality and yield.&#xD;
The objectives of this research were the determination of threshold values depending on cultivar resistance and the optimisation of seed treatment methods. For the determination of threshold values and the evaluation of effectiveness of seed treatments field trials were performed during two years at five sites with three cultivars ('Ökostar', 'Aron', 'Batis'), three infection levels (20, 100, 1000 spores / grain), and two treatments (hot water, Tillecur).&#xD;
Infestation was different in the two years at the sites. It depended on the sowing date and weather. Differences between inoculations and cultivars were clearly visible. Highly susceptible cultivars had bunted ears after inoculation with 20 spores / grain, the medium susceptible cultivar with 1000 spores / grain in the first year and with 20 spores / grain in the second year. After Tillecur treatment a small number of infested ears were counted, after hot water treatment a lower effect was recorded.&#xD;
Field trials and calculations of the theoretical spore load revealed the risk potential of a low infestation. To avoid disease accumulation in seed production, susceptible cultivars even at very low contamination of 5-10 spores / grain should be treated. For less susceptible cultivars treatment must be done from 20 spores / grain on.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, D-Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3680/1/3680.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Waldow, Franziska and Jahn, Marga    (2005) Untersuchungen zur Regulierung von Steinbrand (Tilletia caries) unter besonderer Berücksichtigung von Befallstoleranzgrenzen und direkten Maßnahmen.  [Investigations in control of common bunt (Tilletia caries) of wheat with special reference to threshold levels and direct control methods.]  In: Heß, J. and Rahmann, G. (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, D-Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3680/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>