<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Element composition and quality of lettuce (Lactuca sativa var. Biweri), grown with sheep-manure composts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Radics, László</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pusztai, Péter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bíró, Borbála</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bíró, Zsolt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Németh, Tamás</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monori, István</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two representative Hungarian soil-types (slightly humus sandy and loamy saline) were used to study the effect of various compost-products, made from sheep-yard manure and phosphorous amendments on the biomass-production of lettuce (Lactuca sativa var. Biweri) in a pot-experiment. Two types of phosphorous amendments, such as raw-phosphate with high- or a phosphorous rock with low solubility were used as amendments during the twelve-week composting process. Pots of five-hundred g weight were used and considering the ecophysiological demand of the lettuce, low (30 t/ha) optimum (60 t/ha) and provocative (120 t/ha) levels of manure compost were applied to the soils. Yield of lettuce and mineral content analysis were done by ICP and soil-analysis by TVG. Statistical differences were shown (LSD5%) following ANOVA. An increasing yield of lettuce was recorded simultaneously by the compost doses up to the provocative level at both soil-types. Effect of composts was found to be the best at the low-fertility sandy soil with slight humus content. Among the compost-types, the low-releasing-phosphorous-rock was the most appropriate also on the sandy soil. Summarizing the results, sheep-manure-composts could be the prospective amendments for the low-fertility soils.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12264/1/Radics_12264_ed.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Radics, László; Pusztai, Péter; Bíró, Borbála; Bíró, Zsolt; Németh, Tamás and Monori, István    (2008) Element composition and quality of lettuce (Lactuca sativa var. Biweri), grown with sheep-manure composts.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12264/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>