<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Haltungsindikatoren Integumentschäden und Sauberkeit&#xD;
auf die Eutergesundheit von Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werne, Steffen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heil, Fritz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maeschli, Ariane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Notz, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Staehli, Pamela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Mastitis in dairy cows is a multi-causal disease. Animal husbandry is one of the important&#xD;
factors influencing herd udder health. In our study, skin lesion scores and cleanness&#xD;
scores are used as animal-based indicators for husbandry problems. We investigated&#xD;
the impact of husbandry on the prevalence of skin lesions and the correlation&#xD;
between skin lesions, cleanness and udder health in 67 herds joining the Swiss udder&#xD;
health project “pro-Q”. 62.8% of all examined cows had at least one skin lesion. 13%&#xD;
of all cows were seriously dirty. Housing factors, such as dimension and design of the&#xD;
lying area influenced the prevalence of skin lesions significantly. Hard surface, rubber&#xD;
mats, narrow dimensions of lying place, horns, as well as stanchion barns were risk&#xD;
factors for skin injuries. Cleanness and udder health were well correlated, which was&#xD;
not true for skin lesions and udder health. Thus, the cleanness score may be used as&#xD;
an indicator for increased mastitis risk. The skin lesion score can be used as an indicator&#xD;
for husbandry quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14470/1/Ivemeyer_14470.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivemeyer, Silvia; Werne, Steffen; Heil, Fritz; Maeschli, Ariane; Notz, Christophe; Schneider, Claudia; Staehli, Pamela; Walkenhorst, Michael and Klocke, Peter    (2009) Einfluss der Haltungsindikatoren Integumentschäden und Sauberkeit auf die Eutergesundheit von Milchkühen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14470/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>