<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Treatment of Clinically Diagnosed Equine Sarcoid with a Mistletoe Extract (Viscum album austriacus)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Christen-Clottu, Ophélie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burger, Dominik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Straub, Reto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gerber, Vinzenz</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background: Equine sarcoids (ES) are common, difficult to treat, and have high recurrence rates. Viscum album extracts (VAE) are used in human cancer treatment. Hypothesis: That therapy with VAE (Iscador P) is effective in the treatment of ES. Animals: Fifty-three horses (444 ES); 42 were treated with VAE or placebo as monotherapy; 11 were treated with VAE or placebo after selective excision of ES. Methods: Prospective, randomised, blinded, clinical trial. Horses were randomly assigned to treatment (VAE; n = 32) or control group (Placebo; n = 21). One milliliter of VAE (Iscador P) in increasing concentrations from 0.1 to 20 mg/mL or physiological NaCl solution was given SC 3 times a week over 105 days. Number, localization, and type of the ES were documented over 12 months. A subset of 163 clinically diagnosed equine sarcoid (CDES) lesions (95 VAE, 68 Placebo) was evaluated in detail, considering clinical findings and tumor volume. Results: No undesired adverse effects were observed except for mild edema at the injection site in 5 of 32 horses (16%). Complete or partial regression was observed in 13 horses of the VAE group (41%) and in 3 of the control horses (14%; P &lt; .05). After VAE treatment, 48 of 95 CDES (67%) showed an improvement compared with 17 of 68 CDES in the control group (40%; P &lt; .01). Twenty-seven CDES had disappeared completely in the VAE group (38%) compared with 9 CDES in the control group (13% NS). Conclusions and Clinical Importance: VAE (Iscador P) represents a safe and effective treatment for CDES.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>American College of Veterinary Internal Medicin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17314/1/Christen-Clottu_et_al_2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Christen-Clottu, Ophélie; Klocke, Peter; Burger, Dominik; Straub, Reto and Gerber, Vinzenz   (2010) Treatment of Clinically Diagnosed Equine Sarcoid with a Mistletoe Extract (Viscum album austriacus).   Journal of veterinary international medicine, 24 (6), pp. 1483-1489.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17314/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>