<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Neue Materialien als Einstreu in Liegeboxen von Milchviehställen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zähner, Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schrade, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaeren, Dr. Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtko, Dr. Janet</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sand, compost and recycled manure solids are used on some commercial farms as&#xD;
bedding material in cubicles as an alternative to conventional straw mattresses or soft&#xD;
rubber mats. The aim of the present studies was to evaluate these bedding materials&#xD;
in dairy-cow cubicles in terms of process engineering, animal welfare, hygiene, work&#xD;
economics and farm management. From an animal welfare and hygienic point of view,&#xD;
these mentioned materials are recognized as safe. Where sand is used as bedding,&#xD;
the working-time requirement for cubicle maintenance is comparable to that for soft&#xD;
rubber mats; where compost and recycled manure solids are used, it is comparable to&#xD;
that for straw mattresses. The material costs for sand are high, whilst those for compost&#xD;
are low. Investment in a liquid manure separator is only worthwhile for relatively&#xD;
large farms or for use in farming collectives.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14089/1/Z%C3%A4hner_14089.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zähner, Dr. Michael; Schrade, Sabine; Schaeren, Dr. Walter and Schmidtko, Dr. Janet    (2009) Neue Materialien als Einstreu in Liegeboxen von Milchviehställen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14089/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>