<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategien zur Bekämpfung von Streifen- und Netzfleckenkrankheit der Gerste im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wilbois, K-P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Waldow, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, K-J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogt-Kaute, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spieß, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahn, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wächter, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koch, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Barley leaf stripe (Drechslera graminea) and net blotch (Drechslera teres) are important seed transmitted diseases in organic barley cultivation in Europe. In the poster different measures and agents to control both diseases are investigated and discussed. Our research reveals that barley leaf stripe as well as net blotch can be sufficiently controlled in organic farming by physical methods (warm water and hot air treatment) or by the alcoholic plant strengtheners Lebermooser and - less effectively - by Milsana®. The plant protection product Cedomon® was not always sufficiently effective to control barley leaf stripe and net blotch. Depending on the imposed measure and on the barley type (hulless, hulled), variety and seed origin more or less adverse side effects on germination were observed and should thus be considered.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9501/1/9501_Wilbois_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wilbois, K-P.; Waldow, F.; Müller, K-J.; Vogt-Kaute, W.; Spieß, H.; Jahn, M.; Wächter, R. and Koch, E.    (2007) Strategien zur Bekämpfung von Streifen- und Netzfleckenkrankheit der Gerste im Ökologischen Landbau.  [Strategies to combat barley leaf stripe and net blotch of barley in organic farming.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9501/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>