<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Can agricultural cultivation methods influence the healthfulness of crops for foods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Maja M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Henry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halekoh, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lauridsen, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the current study was to investigate if there are any health eﬀects of long-term consumption of organically grown crops using a rat model. Crops were retrieved over two years from along-term ﬁeld trial at three diﬀerent locations in Denmark, using three diﬀerent cultivation systems(OA, organic based on livestock manure; OB, organic based on green manure; and C, conventional with mineral fertilizers and pesticides)with two ﬁeld replicates. The cultivation system had an impact on the nutritional quality, aﬀecting γ-tocopherol, some amino acids, and fatty acid composition. Additionally, the nutritional quality was aﬀected by harvest year and location. However, harvest year and location rather than cultivation system aﬀected the measured health biomarkers. In conclusion, the diﬀerences in dietary treatments composed of ingredients from diﬀerent cultivation systems did not lead to signiﬁcant diﬀerences in the measured health biomarkers, except for a signiﬁcant diﬀerence in plasma IgGl evels.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21074/1/21074.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Maja M.; Jørgensen, Henry; Halekoh, Ulrich; Olesen, Jørgen E. and Lauridsen, Charlotte   (2012) Can agricultural cultivation methods influence the healthfulness of crops for foods.   J. Agric. Food Chem., 60 (25), pp. 6383-6390.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21074/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>