<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The School Food Revolution: Public Food and the Challenge of Sustainable Development - Book Review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Italy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The School Food Revolution is a timely book for a world of obesogenic food, a world of the fat poor in rich countries, and the hungry poor in poor countries. Worldwide, malnourishment is a marker of poverty. Readers impatient for the revolution are advised to go directly to Chapter 4 - School Food as Social Justice: The Quality Revolution in Rome.&#xD;
Morgan and Sonnino report that “in Italy the public sector has been actively fighting against the generalized deterioration in the population’s nutritional habits”. They identify in Italy “the first organic school meals system”, “the first organic university canteen” and “an organic hospital menu”. They report Italian legislation that “establishes a direct and explicit link between organic and local food and public sector catering … This national law created a regulatory context that encouraged many municipalities to turn organic”.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Journal of Organic Systems</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hill, Stuart</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15076/1/SchoolFoodRevolution.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2008) The School Food Revolution: Public Food and the Challenge of Sustainable Development - Book Review.   Journal of Organic Systems, 3 (2), pp. 59-60.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15076/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>