<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of the dynamics of discourses on the development of organic farming in Flanders</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>De Cock, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dessein, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Krom, M.P.M.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Discursive dynamics have played an important role in determining the development of the organic farming sector in Flanders (the northern part of Belgium). These dynamics co-shaped political and institutional changes including the implementation of EU regulations and the deployment of supply-and market-driven measures. Moreover, discursive dynamics mediated the effects of these political-institutional changes on the willingness of agricultural stakeholders –including individual farmers– to contribute to a growth of the organic agricultural sector. Our results suggest that a focus on institutional changes or individual farmers’ willingness to convert may be useful but only partially explains organic agricultural developments.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24577/1/24577p.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>De Cock, L.; Dessein, J. and de Krom, M.P.M.M.    (2013) Impact of the dynamics of discourses on the development of organic farming in Flanders.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 149-150.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24577/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>