<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Standortanpassung durch Nachbau und Auslese im landwirtschaftlichen Betrieb – eine Studie mit Landsorten der Linse</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Horneburg, Dr Bernd</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agrobiodiversity and the on-farm production of seeds have been decreasing on a glo-bal scale during the past century. The concept of an organic farm as a self contained organism requires an entirely different development: Decentralized organic breeding can achieve an adaptation to local pedoclimatic conditions and preferences. Until now very little research has been carried out into the mechanisms and prospects of local adaptation fostered by breeding and maintaining varieties on farm.&#xD;
To gain additional knowledge field trials were carried out in three farms during three years. Three lentil (Lens culinaris Medik.) landraces were subjected to natural selec-tion, positive mass selection, and progeny testing. Agronomic, morphological, and phenological traits have been investigated. The results indicated changes in the population structure influenced by the location and the method of selection. Bottlenecks in population size in a varieties’ biography can severely reduce the adaptation ability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3384/1/3384.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Horneburg, Dr Bernd    (2005) Standortanpassung durch Nachbau und Auslese im landwirtschaftlichen Betrieb – eine Studie mit Landsorten der Linse.  [Local adaptation by conservation and selection on-farm. A study with lentil landraces.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3384/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>