<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Successful control of apple scab with hydrated lime</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grimm-Wetzel, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schönherr, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In an attempt to control scab, a 12-year-old apple orchard was treated with suspensions of 5 g/l hydrated&#xD;
lime (Ca(OH)2) using overhead irrigation for 15 min. No other fungicides were used. In treatment A, irrigation&#xD;
was started when infection according to Mills had taken place. In treatments B and C, treatment was delayed&#xD;
by 6 h and 20 h, respectively. Irrigation was initiated when the scab warning system signaled even very low&#xD;
infection risk, and a total of 62 treatments were applied. At harvest, the fruits of ‘Golden Delicious’ and&#xD;
‘Jonagold’ varieties of untreated controls were scabbed, while those of ‘Elstar’, ‘Fiesta’, and ‘Kent’ had no&#xD;
visible scab symptoms. During both conventional and ULO storage for 7.5 months, all control fruits&#xD;
developed scab symptoms. All fruits from A, B, and C treatments were free of scab at harvest and after&#xD;
storage. All control trees had scabbed leaves at harvest time; treated trees were free of scab on their upper&#xD;
leaf surfaces, while up to 15% of the leaves had at least one scab lesion on their lower surfaces. This was&#xD;
attributed to poor wetting of these surfaces by sprinkler irrigation, while the fruits and upper leaf surfaces&#xD;
were fully covered with hydrated lime suspensions. At harvest, leaves and fruits were covered with whitish&#xD;
calcium carbonate residues which could be removed by a brief dip in 20 g/l aqueous citric acid. There were&#xD;
no signs of phytotoxicity on either leaves or fruits.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13798/1/ecofruit_12th_15.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Grimm-Wetzel, Peter and Schönherr, Jörg    (2006) Successful control of apple scab with hydrated lime.  [Erfolgreiche Bekämpfung des Apfelschorfs mit Kalziumhydroxid.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 83-86.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13798/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>