<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kulturschutz – Arbeitszeitbedarf beim Einsatz von Netzen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Riegel, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schick, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Belau, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The product quality requirements of modern outdoor vegetable cultivation are becoming&#xD;
more stringent and increasing importance is also attached to a defined guarantee&#xD;
of yield. These demands may be satisfied by using protective netting.&#xD;
The working methods employed in practice and the process technology hardly differ.&#xD;
The differences between individual variants - 1 to 7% per net – are therefore relatively&#xD;
low, as is the size degression. An average of 1.3 manpower-minutes per m are required&#xD;
for the complete process. The time requirement per net is about 26.7 min., 13 min.&#xD;
of which are needed for placement and 11.1 min. for removal. The difference is made&#xD;
up by transportation to and from the field and loading the nets.&#xD;
Covering the crop takes up 48 % or almost half the total working time requirement.&#xD;
Removing the nets accounts for 42 %. 10 % is used in driving to and from the field for&#xD;
placement and in loading the rolls or bales of netting before placement and after&#xD;
removal. There is no additional transportation time, as the nets are carried as part of&#xD;
the relevant transport to and from the field. Removal involves no extra journey times if&#xD;
the netting is removed from the crop immediately prior to harvesting, the journey to&#xD;
and from the field then being calculated as part of the working time requirement for&#xD;
harvesting.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13730/1/Riegel_13730.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Riegel, M.; Schick, M. and Belau, T.    (2009) Kulturschutz – Arbeitszeitbedarf beim Einsatz von Netzen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13730/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>