<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anbau der Blauen Lupine (Lupinus angustifolius) mit&#xD;
unterschiedlichen Reihenabständen und Bewertung der&#xD;
Futterqualität mittels NIRS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Blue lupins have become more important in animal feeding due to increasing organic&#xD;
animal husbandry. They have a low starch content, a high protein content and the best&#xD;
protein quality of the home-grown grain legumes. The feed quality of blue lupins can&#xD;
be analysed by NIRS very quickly and cost-efficiently. Weed infestation in pure stands&#xD;
of blue lupin is often a problem. Mixed cropping systems are a good alternative for&#xD;
weed suppression, but the yield percentage of blue lupins in mixed cultivation is low.&#xD;
Weed infestation can be reduced by hoeing. Therefore the cultivation of blue lupins&#xD;
with the possibility of hoeing in the wider row distances (25.0 cm, 37.5 cm), were&#xD;
compared to 12.5 cm row distance (only currying). Field experiments were conducted&#xD;
in combinations with two different cultivars (Boruta, determinate type), Bora (branched&#xD;
type) and two seeding rates (normal: 100% and reduced: 75% of the seeding rate).&#xD;
The results show a significant effect of the factors year, cultivar and row distance for&#xD;
the grain yield. Yields of the row distance 12.5 cm and 25.0 cm were, with 2.21 and&#xD;
2.23 t ha-1 DM, on the same level; but yield of the row distance 37.5 cm was&#xD;
significantly lower (1.98 t ha-1). The reduction of seeding density had no significant&#xD;
effect on yield and the tested parameters of feed quality. The 37.5 row distance had a&#xD;
lower protein content, and a higher starch content, but no difference in metabolised&#xD;
energy for pigs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14293/1/Boehm_14293.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Böhm, Herwart and Aulrich, Karen    (2009) Anbau der Blauen Lupine (Lupinus angustifolius) mit unterschiedlichen Reihenabständen und Bewertung der Futterqualität mittels NIRS.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14293/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>