<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The productivity of organic dairy herds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hovi, Malla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taylor, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Organically managed ruminant systems place particular emphasis on maximising production from forage. Therefore, it is important that efficiency measures take full account of forage inputs. The Livestock Production Efficiency Calculator (LPEC) calculates the total metabolisable energy (ME) required by livestock and estimates forage inputs as the difference between total requirement and that supplied by other measured feeds. Productivity is expressed in terms of output (£) minus other valued inputs (£) per unit of forage ME. Estimates of production parameters were used to produce productivity indices for thirteen organic dairy herds. The productivity of herds was compared, and sensitivity analyses were conducted to examine the potential impact of a number of economic and production scenario. The relationships between yield, fertility, culling and herd productivity were examined. The advantages of this productivity analysis of organic production systems is that full account is taken of the most important input i.e. grazed and conserved forage and that all of the determinants of productivity and their interactions are considered.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8284/1/roderick_productivity_dairy.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Roderick, Stephen; Hovi, Malla and Taylor, Nick    (2002) The productivity of organic dairy herds.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 185-188.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8284/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>