<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Low temperature/short duration steaming as a sustainable method of soil disinfection</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Loenen, Mariska C A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turbett, Yzanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mullins, Chris E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilson, Michael J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fielden, Nigel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seel, Wendy E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Soil samples containing resting structures of fungal crop pathogens (Verticillium dahliae, Sclerotinia sclerotiorum, Sclerotium cepivorum, Pythium ultimum), potato cyst nematodes (Globodera rostochiensis and Globodera pallida) and weeds (Chenopodium album and Agropyron repens) were treated with aerated steam in the laboratory at temperatures ranging from 50–80oC in a specially constructed apparatus. Steaming at 50 or 60oC for three minutes, followed by an eight-minute resting period in the steamed soil and immediate removal from the soil thereafter, resulted in 100% kill of all weeds, fungi and nematodes. Low temperature/ short duration soil steaming could become a sustainable alternative to chemical or high-temperature steam soil disinfestation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8261/1/Loenen_steaming_soil_disenfection.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Loenen, Mariska C A; Turbett, Yzanne; Mullins, Chris E; Wilson, Michael J; Fielden, Nigel; Seel, Wendy E and Leifert, Carlos    (2002) Low temperature/short duration steaming as a sustainable method of soil disinfection.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 211-214.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8261/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>