<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Susceptibility to Apple Scab, Nectria Cancer and Powdery Mildew of Different Unsprayed Apple Varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kühn, Birka Falk</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Twentyfive apple varieties were evaluated for Apple scab (Venturia inaqualis), Nectria&#xD;
canker (Nectria galligena) and Powdery mildew (Podosphaera leucotricha) for 4 to 7 years.&#xD;
The trees were grown unsprayed. The weather conditions at the experimental orchard&#xD;
normally results in high infections of apple scab and low infections of powdery mildew.&#xD;
Infections of Apple scab is often seen also in scab resistant varieties. Williams Pride,&#xD;
Katinka and Katrina (scabresistant varieties) were the only varieties not showing scab in&#xD;
the experimental period. The two scabresistant varieties Angold and Produkta (varieties&#xD;
having a poor fruit quality) was unsusceptible to Nectria canker. The reference variety&#xD;
Elstar/Elshof was in all plantings among the most resistant varieties. Powdery mildew is&#xD;
not a problem at the experimental orchard. Most varieties had low susceptibility to&#xD;
Powdery mildew. Varieties with low susceptibility to diseases in general were Angold,&#xD;
Produkta, Rajka, Rubinola, Ahrista, Gerlinde, Gul Richard, Sukkertop, Katinka, Katrina,&#xD;
Marian and Primicia.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14545/1/41_Falk_221_226.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kühn, Birka Falk    (2004) Susceptibility to Apple Scab, Nectria Cancer and Powdery Mildew of Different Unsprayed Apple Varieties.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 221-226.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14545/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>