<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agromere: how to integrate urban agriculture in the development of the Dutch city of Almere?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jansma, Ir. Jan Eelco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Visser, Dr. Andries</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Wolf, Ir. Pieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stobbelaar, Dr.Ir. Derk-Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Urban agriculture produces green city areas with as an extra dimension providing food, energy, care, education or recreation for the civilians. And thus it can contribute to a more sustainable and liveable cities. The objective of the project Agromere is to create a process which will lead to a new residential quarter where agriculture is fully integrated in city live. Agromere is situated in the fast growing city of Almere, the Netherlands. In a combined stakeholder and design process a township is designed which integrates living (5,000 inhabitants) with urban agriculture on 250 ha. During this process an enthusiastic network of stakeholders has been established which developed innovating and unique ideas on urban farming. The potential for organic farming in the city is high because of its emphasis on animal welfare and consumer relations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12812/1/12812.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jansma, Ir. Jan Eelco; Visser, Dr. Andries; De Wolf, Ir. Pieter and Stobbelaar, Dr.Ir. Derk-Jan    (2008) Agromere: how to integrate urban agriculture in the development of the Dutch city of Almere?       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12812/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>