<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of a European Information System for Organic Markets - Improving the Scope and Quality of Statistical Data. Proceedings of the 1st EISfOM European Seminar, held in Berlin, Germany, 26-27 April, 2004</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Contents&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Plenary Session	&#xD;
	&#xD;
Welcome address	&#xD;
Massimo Burioni	&#xD;
&#xD;
Introduction to the European Information System for Organic Markets and the aims of the 1st EISfOM European Seminar, Berlin, April 2004	&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin	&#xD;
&#xD;
The current situation of data collection and processing of organic farming and marketing across Europe&#xD;
Toralf Richter	&#xD;
&#xD;
Problems and solutions for the collection of data on organic markets: experiences from previous research projects&#xD;
Ulrich Hamm	&#xD;
&#xD;
Current Eurostat initiatives on organic farming statistics	&#xD;
Ana Martinez	&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic agricultural statistics and information at the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organisation: initiatives, opportunities and challenges	&#xD;
Robert Mayo	&#xD;
&#xD;
Stakeholder perspectives on the need for data and the role of private and public institutions	&#xD;
Victor Gonzálvez	&#xD;
&#xD;
Quality assurance issues in DCPS for agricultural commodities: an analysis of the theoretical and analytical tools and methods used in the assessment of data quality&#xD;
Guido Recke	&#xD;
&#xD;
Data received from Member States  in accordance with Regulation 2092/91	&#xD;
Per Ahle	&#xD;
&#xD;
Group 1: Farm Production -  Farm Structure Survey (FSS) and administrative (2092/91) data&#xD;
Results from the Community farm structure survey and Council Regulation (EEC) No. 2092/91 reporting:  organic farming data and derived agri-environmental indicators	&#xD;
Koen Duchateau	&#xD;
&#xD;
Compilation of basic statistical data on organic farming in Europe and worldwide - challenges and opportunities	&#xD;
Minou Yussefi, Santiago Olmos, Helga Willer	&#xD;
&#xD;
Problems regarding the official statistical survey on organic agriculture in Italy	6&#xD;
M. Adua and A. Pallotti&#xD;
	&#xD;
Opportunities for the development of organic data collection and processing based on Finnish experiences	&#xD;
Sampsa Heinonen	&#xD;
&#xD;
The “Observatoire”of French organic production: data collection since 1995 and &#xD;
future developments	&#xD;
Katell Guernic	&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic production in official agricultural statistics  of Germany	&#xD;
Torsten Blumöhr	&#xD;
&#xD;
Developing the data collection system for organic farming in Poland	&#xD;
Marta Wroblewska, Ewa Szymborska	&#xD;
&#xD;
International data harmonisation  - learning from UK experiences	&#xD;
Rob Haward	&#xD;
&#xD;
Data collecting and evaluation of the organic agriculture system in Turkey	&#xD;
Erdal Süngü	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 1: Farm Structure Survey (FSS) and administrative (2092/91) data	&#xD;
Lizzie Melby Jespersen and Helga Willer	&#xD;
 &#xD;
Group 2: Farm Incomes and Prices	&#xD;
&#xD;
Information systems on organic farming: FADN and market statistics	&#xD;
Krijn J. Poppe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Summarizing results from earlier EISfOM activities on farm incomes and farm level prices&#xD;
Sjaak Wolfert	&#xD;
&#xD;
Current and future perspectives for economic analyses on organic farming with the EU-FADN&#xD;
Alberto D’Avino	&#xD;
&#xD;
Comparing organic and conventional farm incomes in FADN - Issues in international &#xD;
harmonisation and quality assurance	&#xD;
Frank Offermann	&#xD;
&#xD;
Acquisition of participants for the FADN in Germany and practical issues of &#xD;
quality management	&#xD;
Rainer Meyer	&#xD;
&#xD;
The integration and analysis of data on organic farming in the Swiss Farm Accountancy Data Network	&#xD;
Beat Meier	&#xD;
&#xD;
ZMP-Comparison of producer prices for milk	&#xD;
Reinhard Schoch	&#xD;
&#xD;
Determination of organic product prices at farm level	&#xD;
Markus Rippin	&#xD;
&#xD;
Producer price premiums – an indicator for the viability of organic farming &#xD;
at the European level?&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin	&#xD;
&#xD;
HDRA’s contribution to organic horticultural data collection in Europe	&#xD;
Ulrich Schmutz and Chris Firth	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 2: Farm Incomes and Prices	&#xD;
Jürn Sanders and Johan Bakker	&#xD;
&#xD;
 &#xD;
Group 3: Supply chain/Trade (Import/Export)  volumes and prices	147&#xD;
&#xD;
Understanding organic markets and the production of relevant statistics with special focus on the trade/wholesaler/processor level	&#xD;
Jens Vestergaard	&#xD;
&#xD;
The price of organic fruit and vegetables: analysis of one year of monitoring from production to consumer in Italy	&#xD;
Francesco Giardina and Luigi Guarrera	&#xD;
&#xD;
BioStockManager®: A software solution for data collection along the whole supply chain&#xD;
Harald Falkner	&#xD;
&#xD;
Statistics on organic farming and organic products in Denmark&#xD;
Poul Henning Larsen	&#xD;
&#xD;
e-Cert, inspection and certification software	&#xD;
Frank Rumpe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Stakeholder perspectives and data management	&#xD;
Conrad Thimm 	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 3: Statistics on organic farming:  Supply Chain Level	&#xD;
Norbert Gleirscher and Raffaele Zanoli	&#xD;
&#xD;
Group 4: Retailers and consumers&#xD;
&#xD;
Information from household panels about the market for organic farming	&#xD;
Micaela Schantl	&#xD;
&#xD;
Retailer and consumer panel data: strengths and weaknesses in surveying organic food demand	&#xD;
Paul Michels	&#xD;
&#xD;
bioVista – retail panel for the organic food market&#xD;
Christoph Spahn	&#xD;
&#xD;
Consumer Price Monitoring in Germany - ZMP-Panel of retail trade	&#xD;
Hans-Theo Erkes	&#xD;
&#xD;
A European information system for organic markets based on current panels: A critical assessment of possibilities and constraints	&#xD;
Paul Michels	&#xD;
&#xD;
The Household Budget Surveys as a source of information for the study of the consumption of organic products	&#xD;
Antonio Puente Rodero	&#xD;
&#xD;
Surveys carried out in Hungary in connection with organic products and arising problems&#xD;
Annamária Kovács	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 4: Consumer and Retailer Level	&#xD;
Sylwia Zakowska-Biemans, Toralf Richter,  Susanne Lux, Gabriele Hempfling	&#xD;
&#xD;
Group 5: Supply Balance Sheets	&#xD;
Chair: Ulrich Hamm and Guido Recke; Rapporteur: Jessica Aschemann	&#xD;
&#xD;
Supply Balance Sheets	&#xD;
Francis Weiler	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 5: Supply Balance Sheets	&#xD;
Ulrich Hamm, Jessica Aschemann, Guido Recke	&#xD;
&#xD;
Group 6: Policy Evaluation	&#xD;
	&#xD;
Evaluation of European organic farming policies - development of indicators &#xD;
employing the MEANS framework	&#xD;
Jon Tuson and Nicolas Lampkin	&#xD;
&#xD;
OECD Work on Agri-environmental indicators: Lessons for data harmonisation and policy evaluation	&#xD;
Darryl Jones	&#xD;
&#xD;
Results of Group 6: Policy Evaluation	&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin and Jon Tuson	&#xD;
&#xD;
Summary and conclusions of the 1st EISfOM European Seminar, Berlin, April 2004	&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Recke, Guido</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lampkin, Nic</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vaughan, Alison</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2935/1/recke-et-al-2004-eisfom-oe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Recke, Guido; Willer, Helga; Lampkin, Nic and Vaughan, Alison (Eds.)      (2004) Development of a European Information System for Organic Markets - Improving the Scope and Quality of Statistical Data. Proceedings of the 1st EISfOM European Seminar, held in Berlin, Germany, 26-27 April, 2004.    FiBL-Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2935/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>