<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>POTENTIALS OF ORGANIC SESAME PRODUCTION IN HUMID TROPICAL AFRICA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>VICTOR, IDOWU</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>ADE, ENIKUOMEHIN</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>TOPE, AINA</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>OLUWATOBI, BELLO</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The development and release of improved and high yielding sesame varieties can fast track the drive to meet the increasing global demand for certified organic sesame. Variety E-8 (Check), three recently released (NCRIBEN-01M, NCRIBEN-02M and NCRIBEN-03L), four already available with farmers (PBTil, Domu, ABBS and 530-6-1) varieties, and eight recently acquired accessions (Cameroon white, CIANO-16, CIANO-27, Pachequeno, Kwandere, Eva, Adakuawari and CROSS-95) were evaluated for their yield performance under organic system in 2010 – 2012. Fourteen test varieties were laid out in a randomized complete block design and replicated twice in 2010 and 2011. In 2012, a split plot design was used in which fertilizer application (F0 – no fertilizer and F1 – organic fertilizer applied) was assigned to the main plot and 15 test varieties to the sub plot. The grain yield of all the test varieties were greater than the world average (490 kg ha-1), except Cameroon white and Domu when growing conditions were favourable in 2010 and 2011. However, under less favourable growing conditions of 2012, only Kwandere, Adakuawari, CIANO-27, ABBS, 530-6-1, PBTil, NCRIBEN-02M and E-8 recorded grain yield above world average. It is therefore, recommended that Kwandere, Adakuawari, CIANO-27 and NCRIBEN-02M be advanced to the farmers for large scale production alongside the varieties already with them.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22873/1/22873_%20OWC14_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>VICTOR, IDOWU; ADE, ENIKUOMEHIN; TOPE, AINA and OLUWATOBI, BELLO    (2014) POTENTIALS OF ORGANIC SESAME PRODUCTION IN HUMID TROPICAL AFRICA.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 831-834.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22873/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>