<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The World of Organic Agriculture – Density-equalizing&#xD;
Map</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hennig, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Latin America</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United States</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>World</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The World Map of Organic Agriculture presents countries as proportional in size to their share of the total of world organic hectares. Such a map can be referred to as an equal-area cartogram or a density-equalising map. Equal-density cartograms are a tool for presenting a fresh view of tabulated geographic data sets.&#xD;
&#xD;
The World Map of Organic Agriculture accounts for all of the hectares of organically managed agricultural land (certified organic and in-conversion organic) reported by FiBL and IFOAM in 'The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics &amp; Emerging Trends 2013'. The map visually reveals relationships between the territories of the world and highlights the regional strengths and weaknesses of the global diffusion of organic agriculture. The World Map of Organic Agriculture is generated by the Worldmapper GIS algorithm developed at the University of Sheffield as a cartographic visualisation tool.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) &amp; International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lernoud, Julia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22490/7/22490.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John and Hennig, Benjamin    (2013) The World of Organic Agriculture – Density-equalizing Map.    In: Willer, Helga; Lernoud, Julia and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture: Statistics and Emerging Trends 2013.  Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) &amp; International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), Frick &amp; Bonn, p. 129.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22490/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>