<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Facing the organic reality : the diversity of development models and their consequences on research policies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sylvander, Dr Bertil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, Dr Stephane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benoit, Dr Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>While OF&amp;F specificity or diversity are acknowledged in many studies, the process of selecting development models is still a pending issue. Based on literature review and our experience, we propose a comprehensive description of such models. Two main axes determine four models. The first axis refers to governance patterns, whether individual or collective. The second one opposes means-based OF to system redesign. Four models are then described, and potential transitions among them are discussed. The role and nature of public policies likely to support candidate models is finally examined. On this basis, this paper intends to openly lay down the stakes of a public research policy for OF&amp;F. As the current poli-cies generally consider implicitly OF&amp;F as an homoge-nous entity, the authors emphasize it’s the diversity and show how the research agendas are strongly connected to the development models for OF&amp;F.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8247/1/Facing_the_organic_reality-consequences_on_research-19april06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sylvander, Dr Bertil; Bellon, Dr Stephane and Benoit, Dr Marc    (2006) Facing the organic reality : the diversity of development models and their consequences on research policies.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8247/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>