<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic and healthy eating strategies in schools- Separate strategies or two sides of the same coin?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A former study in the Danish primary schools has shown that there is an association between organic school food policies and indicators (proxies) for healthy eating among children when (school food coordinators) statements on indicators (proxies) for healthy eating are used as variable. This project continue to search for the above signs  of associations but involving also a “bottom” level (pupils) perspective in addition to the “top” level (school food coordinators) in the previous study. &#xD;
The project is to study the following hypothesis: organic food service praxis/policy (POP) is associated with praxis/policies for healthier eating in Danish school food service. In other words if organic procurement policies and the resulting praxis in schools can help build a healthier eating habits among pupils in such school as compared to schools without organic policies/praxis. &#xD;
The last perspective is going to be studied in a comparative study design where the Danish case (existing data from WBQ) will be compared with new data from school food service in Germany, Italy and Finland. These data is going to be collected through a web survey.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16549/1/16549.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>He, Chen    (2009) Organic and healthy eating strategies in schools- Separate strategies or two sides of the same coin?       Poster at:       [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16549/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>