<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rapid treatment monitoring by field spectroscopy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>András, Jung</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boglárka, Hegedűs</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dóra, Drexler</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Michael, Vohland</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agricultural crops are in different physiological conditions caused by fertilizer, pest and disease incidence, drought or frost. Vegetation response to treatments varies with both the type and the degree of treatment. On the other hand, treatment may cause biochemical changes in the cellular or leaf structure, which have an effect on pigment system or the canopy moisture content.&#xD;
A variety of factors, including climate, soil, nutrients, phytomass, water content, disease, weeds, insects and more can be measured using ﬁeld spectral radiometers, airborne multispectral, hyperspectral and thermal cameras. High resolution remote sensing provides primary source of information for identifying, classifying, mapping, monitoring of agricultural phenomenon. It can provide data for site speciﬁc management and precision organic farming.&#xD;
In case of our experiments using foliar fertilization treatments on organic spelt fields, field spectroscopy showed a good potential to predict crop quality, while point measurements (SPAD) could not be correlated with spelt quality data. Investigations will be broadened in 2014 in order to gain more detailed results.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24193/1/24193_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>András, Jung; Boglárka, Hegedűs; Dóra, Drexler and Michael, Vohland    (2014) Rapid treatment monitoring by field spectroscopy.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 595-598.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24193/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>