<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Acrylamid-Bildungspotenzial ökologisch erzeugter Getreidearten&#xD;
und Sorten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stockmann, Falko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mast, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graeff, Dr. Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Prof. Dr. Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>By heating up carbohydrate-rich food, like cereals and potatoes, Acrylamide (AA), a&#xD;
probably carcinogen food ingredient, will be created due to a reaction of free Asparagine&#xD;
(Asn) and reducing sugar within the Maillard-Reaction. Up to now two opportunities&#xD;
to decrease AA are discussed. Firstly by changing technological food processing&#xD;
steps e.g. receipt modifications and secondly by plant production e.g. finding species&#xD;
and cultivars low in the content of precursors of AA. For cereals, free Asn is the limiting&#xD;
factor for formation of AA. By investigations of conventionally produced wheat-,&#xD;
spelt- and rye samples differences were found in the amount of Asn both in species&#xD;
and cultivars. It was assumed that these differences could also be found in organically&#xD;
produced cereals. However, up to now no study has investigated the AA content of&#xD;
organically produced cereals. Therefore, the objectives of this study were to investigate&#xD;
i) are there species and cultivars low in free Asn And, ii) is there a correlation&#xD;
between the content of free Asn and the formed AA? To clarify these aspects, organically&#xD;
produced grain samples (mainly wheat, spelt and rye) of a 2-yr field trial were&#xD;
analysed of free Asn and the AA-Formation Potential (AA-FP). The results showed&#xD;
differences in the content of free Asn within species and cultivars, indicated by a&#xD;
strong correlation between Asn and the AA-FP. In conclusion, an option for reducing&#xD;
AA in organic products could be the selection of species and cultivars low in free Asn.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14336/1/Stockmann_14336.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stockmann, Falko; Mast, Benjamin; Graeff, Dr. Simone and Claupein, Prof. Dr. Wilhelm    (2009) Acrylamid-Bildungspotenzial ökologisch erzeugter Getreidearten und Sorten.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14336/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>