<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of the woolly apple aphid (Erisoma lanigerum Hausm.) by releasing earwigs (Forficula auricularia L.) and support oil applications - an interim report of first year results</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Toups, Ina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trautmann, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fieger-Metag, Nicole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buchleither, Sascha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bathon, Horst</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract&#xD;
The woolly apple aphid (Erisoma lanigerum Hausm.) has been recognised for some years as a serious pest in organic fruit growing where they may cause severe economic damage due to a lack of control strategies. Based on preliminary results a new project has been started in 2007 testing combinations of releasing earwigs and oil applications in order to develop an on-farm control strategy. In this paper we present preliminary results of the first year of the project´s field trials. They showed good efficacies for applying oil preparations by brush. The efficacy of releasing earwigs depended on the infestation intensity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V., D-Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15176/1/Control_WAA_eco_fruit.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Toups, Ina; Zimmer, Jürgen; Trautmann, Martin; Fieger-Metag, Nicole; Buchleither, Sascha and Bathon, Horst    (2008) Control of the woolly apple aphid (Erisoma lanigerum Hausm.) by releasing earwigs (Forficula auricularia L.) and support oil applications - an interim report of first year results.   In:     Proceedings to the Conference, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V., D-Weinsberg, pp. 203-207.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15176/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>