<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bio-PhytoPRE - ein Warn- und Prognosesystem zur Bekämpfung der Kraut und Knollenfäule im ökologischen Kartoffelanbau in der Schweiz</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Musa-Steenblock, Tomke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Switzerland</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic potato production, copper fungicides are the only mean for an effective direct control of late blight. To avoid negative impacts of copper accumulation in the environment, intensive research is done to develop efficient copper free agents (CFA) and new strategies for disease prevention. However, the search for such CFA and strategies proves to be more difficult than expected. Therefore an abdication of copper products is not yet possible. To approach a copper free organic potato production, the Agroscope FAL Reckenholz is developing the Bio-PhytoPRE decision support system to assist Swiss organic potato producers to control late blight with reduced amounts of copper or CFA.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3211/1/3211.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Musa-Steenblock, Tomke and Forrer, Hans-Rudolf    (2005) Bio-PhytoPRE - ein Warn- und Prognosesystem zur Bekämpfung der Kraut und Knollenfäule im ökologischen Kartoffelanbau in der Schweiz.  [Bio-PhytoPRE – a decision support system for late blight control in organic potato production in Switzerland.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3211/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>