<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erzeugung von Verarbeitungskartoffeln im Ökologischen Landbau: Effekt von Standort und Sorte auf Ertragsstruktur und die Qualität von Pommes frites</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Thorsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Norbert U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>First experiments in the years 2000 and 2001 have shown a high effect of the factor “site” on the suitability for processing of different potato varieties in organic farming. Constitutive on these preview tests an assortment of 8 different potato varieties for processing to Potato chips were set up on three locations with different soil qualities in the years 2003 and 2004. First results of the year 2003 confirm the influence of the site on the quality of potatoes for processing. Interesting for organic farmers are the varieties Agria and Marena with high yield on all three sites and good quality of the product after harvesting and storage.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3610/1/3610.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krause, Tanja; Haase, Thorsten; Böhm, Herwart; Heß, Jürgen; Loges, Ralf and Haase, Norbert U.    (2005) Erzeugung von Verarbeitungskartoffeln im Ökologischen Landbau: Effekt von Standort und Sorte auf Ertragsstruktur und die Qualität von Pommes frites.  [Production of potatoes for processing in organic farming: effect of site and variety on yield structure and quality of Potato chips.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3610/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>