<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biofumigation zur Bekämpfung von Verticillium dahliae</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Michel, Dr Vincent</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cruciferous plants with high contents of glucosinolates can be used to control soilborne&#xD;
diseases. During the degradation of such plants, the glucosinolates are&#xD;
transformed into isothio- and thiocyanates. These molecules are volatile and toxic,&#xD;
therefore, this method is called biofumigation. In this context, the efficacy of two brown&#xD;
mustard (Brassica juncea) and one canola (Brassica napus) cultivars to reduce the&#xD;
number of Verticillium dahliae microsclerotia was tested in pot trials. Verticillium&#xD;
dahliae is the causal agent of verticillium wilt of a large number of important crops.&#xD;
Microsclerotia are the surviving structures of V. dahliae in the soil. A strong decrease&#xD;
of the number of microsclerotia was observed using the high glucosinolate-containing&#xD;
brown mustard cultivar ISCI-99 and an intermediate effect was observed with a low&#xD;
glucosinolate-containing canola cultivar in a silty soil. However, when ISCI-99 was&#xD;
incorporated in a sandy soil, no such effect on the microsclerotia was measured. The&#xD;
efficacy of biofumigation with glucosinolates depends not only on the plant species but&#xD;
also on the soil type.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14147/1/Michel_14147.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Michel, Dr Vincent    (2009) Biofumigation zur Bekämpfung von Verticillium dahliae.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14147/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>