<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regionale Bio-Vermarktungsinitativen und ländliche Entwicklung – Perspektiven, Potentiale und Fördermöglichkeiten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the 3 year EU-project “Organic Marketing Initiatives and Rural Development (OMIaRD)” the analysis of 67 OMI’s showed that internal business-related factors are generally much more decisive for success than external, context-related factors. Detailed analysis of the impact of OMIs on rural development in four case-study regions (AT, FR, IT, UK) showed that not only economic factors (e.g. employment effects and capital flow in the region), but also or even often more “soft” factors are relevant. However, policy-makers, especially at regional level, need to become more aware of these valuable benefits of OMIs for sustainable rural development and take this sufficiently into account when enhancing support measures.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3738/1/3738.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, Otto and Sanders, Jürn    (2005) Regionale Bio-Vermarktungsinitativen und ländliche Entwicklung – Perspektiven, Potentiale und Fördermöglichkeiten.  [Organic market initiatives and rural development – perspectives, potentials and policy support measures.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3738/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>