<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The development of an integrated modelling system to support decisions on organic farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Julian, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oglethorpe, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wright, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
An Integrated Decision Support System (IDSS) is developed which synthesises current understanding of organic farming by means of a multiple objective framework incorporating GIS, biophysical models and socio-economic models of the farming goals. The IDSS uses a multitiered concept of a farming system as a collection of micro-enterprises at the field level, with individual resource endowments, objectives and activities. Farm-level decision drivers trickle down to affect the micro-level field enterprise selection. Biophysical models describe typical forage, cereal, root and legume output and a user-friendly interfaces permits easy access and output display via a GIS. A prototype of the IDSS framework, being developed as a part of the SAC organic research programme is presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8242/1/Julian_Integrated_modelling_decision_support.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Julian, C.; Smith, N; Oglethorpe, David and Wright, J    (2002) The development of an integrated modelling system to support decisions on organic farms.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 161-164.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8242/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>