<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of protein and lipid source in organic feed for organic trout on sensory quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hyldig, Grethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Green-Pedersen, Ditte Pedersen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacobsen, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baron, Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jokumsen, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Henrik Hauch</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work was to study whether the type of  protein and lipid source in feed for organic Rainbow trout (Onchorhynchus mykiss) influenced the sensory quality. The protein sources were fishmeal and a matrix of organic vegetable plant mealsproteins, while the lipid sources were fish oil and organic oils of linseed, sunflower, rapeseed and grape seed, respectively. Sensory profiling was performed after 3, 5, 7 and 14 days of storage in ice. Besides sensory analysis also lipid profiles weare measured. The resultsed showed that the lipid type in the feed aeffected the sensory characteristics after 3 days of storage. Especially the trout that had grape seed oil in the feed had a different sensory profile than the trout that had fish oil in the feed. These differences could be explained by the lipid profiles in the fillets. Also after 7 days of ice storage differences in the sensory profile wereas observed again as a result of the used lipid types used. After 7 days of ice storage ThusHere the trout that had grape seed oil orand rapeseed oil for instance had a more neutral flavor and odor profile compared to the other trout fed on linseed or sunflower oil´s. After 14 days of storage no effect of lipid type in the feed was observed, but the trout which had fish meal as protein source had higher intensity of several negative sensory descriptors compared to trout that had the vegetable protein matrix. Overall the results showed that the dietaryfeeds content of protein and lipid aeffecteds the sensory characteristics of the trout in different ways during the ice storage period.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19721/2/19721.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hyldig, Grethe; Green-Pedersen, Ditte Pedersen; Jacobsen, Charlotte; Baron, Caroline; Jokumsen, Alfred  and Nielsen, Henrik Hauch    (2011) The effect of protein and lipid source in organic feed for organic trout on sensory quality.  [Effekten af protein og lipid kilde på den sensoriske kvalitet af økologisk regnbueørred.]      Speech at:   WEFTA, April 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19721/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>