<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Orale Eisengabe bei Saugferkel unter den Bedingungen der&#xD;
ökologischen Ferkelerzeugung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hagmüller, Dr. Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gallnböck, Ing. Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Iron prophylaxis in suckling piglets is usually administered as intramuscular or subcutaneous&#xD;
injection. These formulations are medicinal products and therefore prescribable&#xD;
in organic producing farms. Although iron dextran is not allowed through the EU&#xD;
Regulation 834/07 there are no restrictions about medicinal products. Used as feed&#xD;
additive iron dextran is prohibited. Oral administration of iron pastes is common in&#xD;
some organic farms. This paper deals with oral administration of iron pastes containing&#xD;
only approved feed additives like iron oxid or iron sulfate.&#xD;
22 litters were included. Piglets were randomised and assigned to either control or&#xD;
experimental group. With the exception of a commercial paste given two times (day 1&#xD;
and 7) none of the experimental pastes could achieve satisfactory results. Either the&#xD;
serum iron level decreased considerably or the piglets became pale and weight gain&#xD;
decreased.&#xD;
In summary under the restriction of the EU regulation 834/07 sufficient oral supplementation&#xD;
with iron is not possible. The only acceptable possibility is an intramuscular&#xD;
or subcutaneous administration of 200 mg of iron dextran at the second or third day of&#xD;
life.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14011/1/Hagm%C3%BCller_14011.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hagmüller, Dr. Werner and Gallnböck, Ing. Markus    (2009) Orale Eisengabe bei Saugferkel unter den Bedingungen der ökologischen Ferkelerzeugung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14011/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>