<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Processing strategies. QLIF subproject 5: Development of a framework for the design of minimum and low input processing strategies, that guarantee food quality and safety</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic processing standards already prohibit the use of many chemicals, additives and preservatives, which are used in the processing of conventional foods. Yet, there are frequent discussions of the underlying principles on organic food processing regarding such aspects as environmentally friendly processing, minimal use of additives, sensory quality, and transportation. It is therefore essential to develop a framework or code of practice, which can be used to determine whether novel processing strategies are compatible with organic processing standards and principles as well as consumer demands and expectations in relation to quality characteristics of processed food. In the present subproject part of the research comprised an assessment of alternative sanitising protocols under controlled laboratory conditions in the processing of fresh cut lettuce and mixtures of fresh-cut-vegetables. During these studies it was found that, with regard to ecological aspects, ozone is a good alternative to the existing disinfectants, such as chlorine, in the organic field. Further research concerned an assessment of processing technologies that may improve the nutritional composition of dairy products, such as increased content of conjugated linolenic acids (CLA).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Elsgaard, L</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16592/1/16592.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kretzschmar, U.    (2009) Processing strategies. QLIF subproject 5: Development of a framework for the design of minimum and low input processing strategies, that guarantee food quality and safety.   .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16592/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>