<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil properties, crop yield and quality with farmyard manure with and without biodynamic preparations and with inorganic fertilizers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oltmanns, Meike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 1980 a 2 factor fertilization experiment compares 3 fertilization types (farmyard manure with and without biodynamic preparations vs. inorganic fertilizers) applied at 3 different rates in a 4 field crop rotation. Except for fertilization all other elements of cultivation were the same in all treatments and followed normal organic farming practices. The key results of the experiment obtained in more than 2 decades are reported with respect to soil parameters (e.g. organic carbon content, microbial biomass and activity, particulate organic matter, amino acid content, carbon source utilization, micronutrients), crop parameters (yield formation depending upon fertilization and site conditions, mycorrhiza development) and weed abundance.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Raupp, Joachim</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pekrun, Carola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Oltmanns, Meike</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8568/1/ltefly.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Raupp, Joachim and Oltmanns, Meike    (2006) Soil properties, crop yield and quality with farmyard manure with and without biodynamic preparations and with inorganic fertilizers.    In: Raupp, Joachim; Pekrun, Carola; Oltmanns, Meike and Köpke, Ulrich (Eds.)   Long-term Field Experiments in Organic Farming..  ISOFAR Scientific Series, no. 1. Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin, pp. 135-155.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8568/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>