<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>BerryMeat - New market perspectives using herbs and berries in organic meat products. What has been achieved?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Flemming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grevsen, Kai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fenger, Morten</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The overall objective of the project was to increase the portfolio of organic meat products for the consumer, by supplying new products preserved by organic grown herbs and berries. The consumers will benefit from a growing range of new, attractive, organic meat products, the Danish producers of organic meat products will benefit form a growing market and the producers of organic herbs and berries will experience an increasing demand for organic grown herbs and berries.&#xD;
The project has been consumer driven, as the project initially investigated the attitude of the organic consumer to this new way to produce organic meat-products. Also at the end of the project, the consumer acceptance of the resulting two new meat products (dices of ham, with garlic &amp; sage covered in a basil pesto and poultry sausages with rose hip, sea buck thorn and ramsons) was investigated, as the test panel were presented for the products (taste, visual appearance) and their willingness to buy the product were tested.&#xD;
The project has demonstrated that the consumers are ready for such new meat products and ready to pay a reasonable extra price, provided they have a positive experience when buying the product. The project has investigated 5 relevant plants, which is found acceptable for the consumers to use in meat products. Further, they have the potential for a commercial, organic production in Denmark. In combination with the increasing demand for organic product in DK, an excellent perspective for development of more organic meat products added herbs and berries should exist. This will, in longer terms, increase the demand for organic grown herbs and berries in Denmark.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-04-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25753/7/25753.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Flemming; Jensen, Martin; Grevsen, Kai and Fenger, Morten    (2014) BerryMeat - New market perspectives using herbs and berries in organic meat products. What has been achieved?   ICROFS news, 25 April 2014,  .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25753/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>