<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Institutionalisation of Social Movements: A Comparative Perspective on Organic Agriculture Organisations in Denmark and Japan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fomsgaard, Saki Ichihara</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Asia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study deals with competing strategic orientations of the organic agriculture movement toward institutionalisation: a division in whether organic agriculture should develop within the prevailing system (pro-institutional strategy) or preserve its alternativeness compared to conventional agriculture (anti-institutional strategy). It aims to investigate development and reasons of the specific strategies and evaluate their impact on the organic agriculture movement as a social movement. This aim is pursued by a comparative study of the leading organic agriculture organisations in Denmark and Japan: The former as a typical pro-institutional case and the latter as an anti-institutional case.  The inquiry overall takes an integrative framework based on strategic-relational approach (SRA) that envisages transcending the traditional division among nature, structure, culture and actor. This framework is further operationalised by the major social movement theories and a perspective of discursive democracy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-04-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26799/7/26799.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fomsgaard, Saki Ichihara   (2014) Institutionalisation of Social Movements: A Comparative Perspective on Organic Agriculture Organisations in Denmark and Japan.    PhD thesis, Aalborg University, Department of Culture and Global Studies.  .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26799/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>