<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>To what extent does organic farming rely on nutrient inflows from conventional farming?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nowak, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nesme, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>David, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pellerin, Sylvain</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is increasingly recognized as a prototype for sustainable agriculture. Its&#xD;
guidelines ban the use of artiﬁcial fertilizers. However, organic farms may import nutrients&#xD;
from conventional farming through material exchanges. In this study, we aimed at estimating&#xD;
the magnitude of these ﬂows through the quantiﬁcation of nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium&#xD;
inﬂows from conventional farming to organic farming. Material inﬂows and outﬂows were&#xD;
collected for two cropping years on 63 farms. The farms were located in three French&#xD;
agricultural districts distributed over a gradient of farming activity deﬁned by both the&#xD;
stocking rate and the ratio of the farm area under arable crops. Our results showed that on&#xD;
average, inﬂows from conventional farming were 23%, 73% and 53% for nitrogen,&#xD;
phosphorus and potassium, respectively. These inﬂows were strongly determined by the farm&#xD;
production systems. However, for farms similar in terms of production systems, the inﬂows&#xD;
also depended on the local context, such as the proximity of organic livestock farms: the&#xD;
reliance of organic farming on conventional farming was lower in mixed than in specialized&#xD;
districts. These results highlight the necessity to quantify the contribution of nutrient inﬂows&#xD;
from conventional farming when assessing organic farming and development scenarios.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25455/3/Nowak_Nesme_2013_EnvironResLett_8.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nowak, Benjamin; Nesme, Thomas; David, Christophe and Pellerin, Sylvain   (2013) To what extent does organic farming rely on nutrient inflows from conventional farming?   Environmental Research Letter, 8, 044045.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25455/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>