<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Blattmasse von Rotklee als Proteinquelle für Schweine</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sommer, hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study focuses on the utilization of local clover-like legumes as a protein source for pigs. It is examined how high crude protein can be concentrated in red clover (Trifolium pratense) by separating the leaf mass of the stems. In this part of the study, the two breeds Titus and Milvus have been compared. The digestibility of the material was determined by an in-vitro method. Preliminary results show that the concentration of crude protein increased up to 27.5 % compared to the whole-plant content of 21.9 %.The concentration of digestible crude protein in the leaf rose averagely by 21 % compared to the whole plant. With Titus, a total of 15.7 dt ha-1 leaf mass protein was harvested. With Milvus, 14.0 dt protein leaf mass per ha were yielded.&#xD;
Separation of the leaf mass from the stems seems to offer a potential source of protein for organic pig farming. The preliminary results of the ongoing studies show that this alternative can be really powerful.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21559/1/21559_sommer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sommer, hendrik and Sundrum, Albert    (2013) Blattmasse von Rotklee als Proteinquelle für Schweine.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21559/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>