<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Phosphorus load from equine critical source areas and its reduction using ferric sulphate</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Närvänen, Aaro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jansson, Håkan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Uusi-Kämppä, Jaana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jansson, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perälä, Paula</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The increasing number of horses, especially in urban areas has made the phosphorus (P) load of exercise areas (paddocks) more and more obvious but there has been a lack of information regarding how to assess this load and what can be done to lower it. In the surface soil (1-2 cm) of areas that are affected by horse manure, like paddocks, we measured very high extractable P contents. When testing soils from these areas using a rainfall simulator we found a close correlation between the extractable soil P in the surface soil and the dissolved reactive P in runoff water. In a runoff treatment test trial we used ferric sulphate to treat paddock runoff water. The chemical dosage was carried out using a tube doser placed in a well. After ferric sulphate treatment the runoff was discharged into a sedimentation pond and then filtered in a sandbed. The chemical treatment was performed during one year and the reduction of the dissolved P and total P in the runoff was 95 % and 81 %, respectively. Our Agri-Environmental Programme has not been successful in reducing the total P status in our agriculturally loaded lakes. We suggest that the cost-effective chemical treatment of waters from the high P equine areas should be included in the programme. Also in other countries in the Baltic Sea catchment area reductions of P contents in waters from equine areas should be carried out.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-06-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16436/1/ber.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Närvänen, Aaro; Jansson, Håkan; Uusi-Kämppä, Jaana; Jansson, Helena and Perälä, Paula   (2008) Phosphorus load from equine critical source areas and its reduction using ferric sulphate.   Boreal Environment Research, 13, pp. 265-274.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16436/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>