<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of compost tea and organic fertilizers on organic potato</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kochbati, Hela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work is to compare the effects of compost tea and organic fertilizers allowed in organic agriculture on potato growth, development, tuberisation and nutrition (cv. Spunta).Many observations related to agronomic aspects were released as height of plants, diameter of stems, foliar surface, vegetative vigor and evaluation of late blight. The results obtained during the potato development cycle showed us good vegetative growth and tolerance to late blight.Comparison between compost tea produced on farm and commercial organic fertilizers imported costly, in order to characterize the effects of these treatments on potato crop gave us in general similar results regarding the plant growth, yield and plant nutrition. Soil fertility was improved, mineral analysis before and after experiment illustrate that there are a large amounts of organic matter, nitrogen, phosphorus, and potassium are available in the soil after harvest and decrease of magnesium and sodium owing to exportation of these two last nutrients for physiological development and metabolism reactions during the cycle of plant growth.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6862/1/6862.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kochbati, Hela   (2003) Effects of compost tea and organic fertilizers on organic potato.  [Effets de compost et des engrais organique sur la pomme de terre.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 328. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6862/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>