<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic production and consumption in Norway - new knowledge through research and dissemination</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Serikstad, G.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, A.-K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brunberg, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grøva, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørheim, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Norwegian government has since 2006 had a goal of 15 % organic food production and consumption, initially by 2015 and later adjusted to 2020. The goal has primarily been justified by consumer demands, and to some extent by environmental benefits. Organic farming is said to be a “spear point” in the development of a more environmental friendly and sustainable agriculture in Norway, but the government’s policy lacks thorough political support and the goal is far from achieved.&#xD;
In 2012, certified land and land area under conversion to organic farming comprised 5.6 % of the agricultural area (Debio 2013). The turnover of organic products was more than 1.1 billion NOK in 2012; an increase of 11 % from 2011 (NAA 2012). In 2009, organic food represented 1.3 % of total food turnover in Norway (Willer and Kilcher 2011). The share of grassland in organic managed land comprised 77 % in 2012 (Debio 2013). Strong efforts are needed to reach the official goal in 2020 and to diversify the organic production. The Action Plan for Organic Farming (MAF 2009) points out actions to reach the governmental goal, including research and dissemination of knowledge.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24563/1/24563.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24563/2/24563p.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Serikstad, G.L.; Løes, A.-K.; Brunberg, E.; Grøva, L.; Steinshamn, H. and Sørheim, K.    (2013) Organic production and consumption in Norway - new knowledge through research and dissemination.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 93-94.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24563/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>