<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Punch planting, flame weeding and stale seedbed for weed control in row crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Punch planting is introduced as a new method to reduce weeds within rows in organically grown crops. In this method a hole is punched in the soil, and a seed is dropped into it, without seedbed preparation and soil disturbance outside the hole. In two years, punch planting with flame weeding, normal planting with flame weeding and normal planting without flame weeding were compared in fodder beet for five planting dates. Each planting date represented a lag-period since establishment of the stale seedbed. Over all planting times and years, punch planting with flame weeding reduced intra-row weed densities by 30% at the 2-4 leaves stage of fodderbeet compared to normal drilling with flame weeding. Punch planting with flame weeding also reduced intra-row weed densities by 50% compared to normal drilling without flame weeding. There was no generally improved performance of punch planting with flame weeding over years by later planting, but delayed planting reduced intra-row weed densities significantly. Over two years, 240 day degrees Celsius (four weeks) planting delay reduced intra-row weed densities in the range of 68% to 86% depending on plant establishment procedure. Punch planting with flame weeding offers a promising method of weed control in organic farming. &#xD;
&#xD;
"This is a preprint of an Article accepted for publication in Weed Research © 2003 European Weed Research Society. For further information on Weed Research please refer to www.blackwellpublishing.com/wre"</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1785/2/Punch_planting.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Jesper   (2003) Punch planting, flame weeding and stale seedbed for weed control in row crops.   Weed Research, 43, pp. 393-403.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1785/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>