<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agronomic and economic performance of organic, conventional and GM-cotton in Central India - First results of a long-term farming systems comparison</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baruah, Rajeev</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zundel, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jain, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Over the past five years the organic cotton production in India has grown many folds. In the conventional cotton arena, the genetically modified cotton is growing at an unprecedented rate. In view of these developments, it was considered necessary to carry out a systematic comparison between the various cotton production systems common in the area. Further, this research attempts to address the larger issues:&#xD;
•	Put the discussion regarding the benefits and drawbacks of organic agriculture on a rational footing;&#xD;
•	Help to identify challenges for organic agriculture that can then be addressed systematically;&#xD;
•	Provide physical reference and meeting points for stakeholders in agricultural research and development and thus support decision-making and agricultural policy dialogue at different levels.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18377/4/baruah-etal-2008-organic-textile-conference.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baruah, Rajeev; Zundel, Christine and Jain, S    (2008) Agronomic and economic performance of organic, conventional and GM-cotton in Central India - First results of a long-term farming systems comparison.       Poster at:   Organic Fibre and Textile Conference, Carpi, Italy, 16-17 June.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18377/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>