<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Principles and practicality of organic dairy cattle breeding: different options and implications</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nauta, MSc W.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roep, Dr. D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As yet there is no set of generally acknowledged rules for organic animal breeding. Most organic farmers depend on conventional breeding programmes, which conflict with organic principles. Do we need a separate, distinct organic breeding system? And how can we support the development of organic breeding? These questions were explored in a PhD study. In general organic farmers and other interest groups express the need for a separate, fully organic breeding system, particularly in view of the modern reproduction technologies used in conventional breeding. Also the difference in the magnitude of GxE between organic and conventional milk production indicates that a separate breeding program might be needed. In practice, however, organic farmers respond to different, and sometimes opposing, strategic and practical considerations. In this situation three options are identified in the development of organic breeding: adaptation of conventional breeding, an organic breeding program and improved natural breeding. Each path has its own implications and demands. Organic breeding is the subject of experimentation and learning on the one hand and of social debate on organic principles on the other. This process needs to be enhanced and interconnected, before well-founded decisions can be taken on further development of organic breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12445/1/Nauta_12445_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nauta, MSc W.J. and Roep, Dr. D.    (2008) Principles and practicality of organic dairy cattle breeding: different options and implications.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12445/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>