<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production and persistency of red clover (Trifolium pratense) varieties when grown in mixtures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iepema, Goitste</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Eekeren, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Dongen, Marian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the Netherlands organic and conventional dairy farmers are taking an increasing interest in grass and red clover mixtures for ley pastures (cutting only). A constraint to the adoption of such mixtures is the persistency of the red clover (Trifolium pratense L.) varieties presently used in the Netherlands; Rotra, Barfiola, Violetta and Merviot. The latter being the most persistent under practical circumstances. Testing of red clover varieties in Switzerland showed a high degree of persistency of the so-called ‘mattenklee’ varieties such as Astur and Pica (Suter et al., 2004). We compared eight red clover varieties including 2 ‘mattenklee’ varieties in mixtures with perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.) and white clover (Trifolium repens L.), and a mixture containing white clover and perennial ryegrass only.&#xD;
Red clover mixtures out yielded the white clover mixtures by 5.4 t dry matter (DM) ha -1 . ULC 1715186 and Astur were the most productive red clover varieties. The development of the clover content of Astur showed that this variety scored highest on persistency.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Lloveras, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gonazalez-Rodriguez, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vasquez-Yanez, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pinero, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Santamaria, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Oleaamd, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Poblaciones, M.J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8683/1/1782.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Iepema, Goitste; van Eekeren, Nick and van Dongen, Marian    (2006) Production and persistency of red clover (Trifolium pratense) varieties when grown in mixtures.   In: Lloveras, J.; Gonazalez-Rodriguez, A.; Vasquez-Yanez, O.; Pinero, J.; Santamaria, O.; Oleaamd, L. and Poblaciones, M.J. (Eds.)  Grassland Science Europe, 11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8683/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>