<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A comparative study of nitrate leaching from intensively managed monoculture grass and grass-clover pastures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>P.S., Hooda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>M., Moynagh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>I.F., Svoboda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H.A., Anderson</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nitrate leaching losses from intensively managed monoculture grass and grass-clover pastures were measured during 1994-96 at a long-term experimental farm in south-west Scotland. Field-size lysimeter plots were established in 1993 on the existing pastures on a silty clay loam non-calcareous gley. No fertilizer-N was applied to the grass-clover, while the monoculture grass was fertilized with c.240 kg N ha-1 year-1, but both swards received 2-3 cattle slurry applications annually (120-390 kg total N ha-1 year-1). The pastures supported 2-3 cuts for silage conservation, and were grazed by dairy cattle and stocked with sheep during the winter months. &#xD;
Initially, leachate nitrate concentrations from the fertilized grass were considerably larger than those from the clover-based pasture, but became similar with time. The annual nitrate leaching losses from the grass-clover (24-38 kg NO3-N ha-1) were less than that from the monoculture grass (30-45 kg NO3-N ha-1), but the differences were not large considering the additional fertilizer-N applied to the latter treatment. Results also suggested that greater leaching losses occur during a warmer, drier year, compared to a cooler, wetter year, regardless of the source of N-input.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1998</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6175/1/Younie2002Effect.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>P.S., Hooda; M., Moynagh; I.F., Svoboda and H.A., Anderson   (1998) A comparative study of nitrate leaching from intensively managed monoculture grass and grass-clover pastures.   Journal of Agricultural Science, 131 (3), pp. 267-275.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6175/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>