<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of probiotic inocula on the population density of lactic acid bacteria and enteric pathogens in the intestine of weaning piglets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Modesto, Monica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stefanini, Ilaria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>D'Aimmo, Maria Rosaria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mazzoni, Maurizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trevisi, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tittarelli, Carla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bosi, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biavati, Bruno</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Because antibiotic resistance occurs in bacteria at an alarming rate, significant research has been focused on finding alternative treatments which do not involve the use of antibiotics.&#xD;
The promotion of beneficial gut bacteria can increase the resistance of animals to possible intestinal infections. &#xD;
Probiotics can be administered to humans or animals, offering preventive benefits of protecting the host from various types of intestinal diseases, providing positive effects on digestive processes and stimulating influence on the growth of organism, strengthening the barrier function of the gut microbiota and/or non-specific enhancement of the immune system.&#xD;
A study was designed to screen potential probiotic Bifidobacterium spp. strains with the ability to multiply in the intestine of weaned piglets and then to assess their health promoting effects when challenged with two enteric pathogens.&#xD;
Three series of trials were conducted with 60 weaning pigs fed one of 12 different Bifidobacterium spp. strains either once or twice a day.&#xD;
The most effective probiotic treatment (Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis, strain Ra 18, at a dose of 1011cfu twice a day) was then challenged in two series of experiments with the enteric pathogens, Salmonella enterica serovar typhimurium and E. coli K88.&#xD;
Bifidobacterium animalis subsp. lactis strain Ra 18 significantly increased (p&lt;0.01) the number of viable bifidobacteria in the cecum contents. When it was challenged with Salmonella, Ra 18 reduced excretion of this pathogen with the faeces. On the whole, supplementation with Ra 18 had a positive effect on the growth performance of pigs except after challenge with E. coli K88 where pigs susceptible to ETEC adhesion were lighter than pigs not susceptible.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9793/1/Modesto-etal-2007-probiotic_weaning_piglets.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Modesto, Monica; Stefanini, Ilaria; D'Aimmo, Maria Rosaria; Mazzoni, Maurizio; Trevisi, Paolo; Tittarelli, Carla; Bosi, Paolo and Biavati, Bruno    (2007) Effect of probiotic inocula on the population density of lactic acid bacteria and enteric pathogens in the intestine of weaning piglets.       Poster at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9793/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>