<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of organic matter stability during the composting process of agroindustrial wastes.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tittarelli, Fabio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trinchera, Alessandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Intrigliolo, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benedetti, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Composting of wastes from citrus industrial processing (pastazzo and sludge) was studied in order to evaluate the evolution of organic matter during the process and to individuate chemical and/or biochemical techniques able to set the stability of the final product. Composts from two open-air piles of different composition were sampled every month during the whole period of composting (5 months) and the organic matter of each sample was characterised by chemical and biochemical techniques. Humification rate (HR%) and humification index (HI) were determined. Extracted organic matter of six samples collected for each compost was investigated by isoelectric-focusing technique (IEF). The biochemical analysis was based on the study of C-mineralisation after the addition of each collected sample to soil. Results obtained clearly demonstrated organic matter evolution during composting processes. Humification rates increased and humification indexes decreased over time, while extracted organic matter showed electrophoretic behaviour typical of stabilised organic compounds. Moreover, mineralisation patterns confirmed the increased level of organic matter stability during the composting process.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Insam, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riddech, N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Klammer, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8184/1/Tittarelli_final_version.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tittarelli, Fabio; Trinchera, Alessandra; Intrigliolo, Francesco and Benedetti, Anna    (2002) Evaluation of organic matter stability during the composting process of agroindustrial wastes.    In: Insam, H.; Riddech, N. and Klammer, S. (Eds.)   Microbiology of composting.  Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg, pp. 397-406.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8184/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>