<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fruit quality of Elstar en Santana in the Netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jansonius, Pieter Jans</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The growth of the market for Dutch organic apples is disappointing. Especially the large-scale introduction&#xD;
in the supermarket channel is not happening as fast as many hoped. One of the explanations&#xD;
given is that there is a gap between the quality as produced and the quality as expected by the&#xD;
retailers. In a three year project the Louis Bolk Institute together with many other partners in the&#xD;
sector have tried to facilitate talks on apple quality between actual partners in the different chains&#xD;
from producer till retailer. During this period we monitored the quality of Elstar and Santana on&#xD;
many farms and on the shelf in the different outlets. This has given us detailed information about&#xD;
the current quality of Dutch organic apples. Presented here are some preliminary results of the&#xD;
monitoring at the farms. The project will end mid 2004, final results will be published by the end of&#xD;
the year. Progress of the project can be followed through the website www. louisbolk.&#xD;
nl/projects/fruit/’classy apples’.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14534/1/32_Jansonius_174_178.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jansonius, Pieter Jans    (2004) Fruit quality of Elstar en Santana in the Netherlands.  [Fruchtqualität von Elstar und Santana in den Niederlanden.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, p. 173.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14534/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>