<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECTS OF ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL N-FERTILIZATION&#xD;
ON QUALITY TRAITS IN CORIANDER (CORIANDRUM SATIVUM L.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carrubba, Alessandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Catalano, Caterina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Militello, Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic cropping management of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants, the best quality expression is crucial to gain satisfactory incomes. Coriander (Coriandrum sativum L.) is an annual herbaceous plant with a commercial value due to the typical scent of its fruits (commonly termed “seeds”), rich in a pale yellow oil (1-2% in small-sized types, 0.2-0.5% in large-sized ones). Several studies have been done for determining the composition of volatile fraction of Coriander, which was found to vary also as a consequence of cropping techniques, including nitrogen fertilization. In order to gain useful information about the effects, if present at all, of organic N fertilization on Coriander quality in terms of volatiles composition pattern, a three-year trial (2004-2006) was carried out using different types and rates of organic and conventional N fertilizers. Volatile composition of fruits was obtained by means of GC-MS and data were evaluated by multivariate statistical analysis. The most representative compound are linalool, followed by camphor, geranyl acetate and geraniol. The group partition was mainly due to different quantitative ratio of compounds; the differences in volatile composition, however, followed a scheme more resembling the cropping year than the fertilization management.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fertilitas Agrorum</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sequi, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ferri, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rea, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Montemurro, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vonella, Alessandro Vittorio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>FORNARO, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20546/1/Roma_Nfert_quality.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Carrubba, Alessandra; Catalano, Caterina and Militello, Marcello    (2009) EFFECTS OF ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL N-FERTILIZATION ON QUALITY TRAITS IN CORIANDER (CORIANDRUM SATIVUM L.).   In: Sequi, P.; Ferri, D.; Rea, E.; Montemurro, F.; Vonella, Alessandro Vittorio and FORNARO, F. (Eds.)  MORE SUSTAINABILITY IN AGRICULTURE: NEW FERTILIZERS AND FERTILIZATION MANAGEMENT, Fertilitas Agrorum, pp. 174-179.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20546/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>