<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Weed Management Website</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Davies, Dr Gareth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turner, Dr Becky</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bond, Dr Bill</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This website (organicweeds.org.uk) aims to be a primary resource on weed management for organic farms, reporting on the latest weed information, weeding techniques and weed research. It aims to act as a focal point for farmers, growers, advisors and researchers to share their experiences with weeds. It contains a large amount of collated information and knowledge on individual weeds and weed management techniques including many up to date scientific literature reviews in pdf format. In addition the site contains farm case histories and the results on on-going work on various themes such as perennial weeds (docks, thistles, couch) and systems approaches to weed management. All interested people (farmers, advisors and researchers) are invited to contribute to the site.&#xD;
This website contains a lot of archived literature reviews on weeds and organic weed management arising from a Defra funded project (OF0315). The website will be maintained indefinitely and all interested parties are encouraged to contribute to it in the spirit of open access.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Web product</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7891/1/HDRA_Organic_Weed_Management.htm</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Davies, Dr Gareth; Turner, Dr Becky and Bond, Dr Bill    (2006) Organic Weed Management Website.   .  Online at &lt;http://www.organicweeds.org.uk &lt;http://www.organicweeds.org.uk&gt;&gt;.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7891/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>