<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How Perennial Grass has Modified Distribution of Organic Carbon in a Peach Orchard in Emilia-Romagna Region (Italy)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Montecchio, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Francioso, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gioacchini, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ciavatta, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, the distribution of the total and humified organic carbon in a peach orchard tilled-irrigated on the row and perennial grassed on the inter-row space after 16 years of cultivation were evaluated. The TOC has shown differences not statistically significant in the 0-20 cm horizon, whereas the difference in the row vs. inter-row 20-40 cm horizon was significant. The highest content of humic substances was found in the 0-20 cm of the inter-row with perennial grass vs. row tilled soil: the absence of tillage increases the accumulation of humified compounds. DRIFT and  TG-DTA analysis pointed out  only some small structural variation in the humic fraction of  the samples taken from the layer at depth 20-40 cm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12174/1/Montecchio_12174_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Montecchio, D.; Francioso, O.; Gioacchini, P. and Ciavatta, C.    (2008) How Perennial Grass has Modified Distribution of Organic Carbon in a Peach Orchard in Emilia-Romagna Region (Italy).       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12174/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>