<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Composting poultry manure by fly larvae (Musca domestica) eliminates Campylobacter jejuni from the manure</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nordentoft, Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hald, Birthe</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Introduction The common house fly, Musca domestica (Md) is an important carrier of zoonotic agents, and Campylobacter jejuni is one that may be transmitted between animals and humans by flies. Colonized animals shed the bacteria in feces where larval stages of Md flies develops. Aim of the present study To monitor fly larvae composting of poultry manure artificially contaminated with C. jejuni, and to investigate a possible transmission route of C. jejuni from the manure through the fly larvae to the adult fly.&#xD;
Conclusions&#xD;
The addition of fly larvae both accelerated the degradation of manure and C. jejuni. Pupae or newly hatched flies were not carriers of C. jejuni although larvae were grown in contaminated manure.&#xD;
Impact&#xD;
When composting poultry manure with Md fly larvae, it is possible both to reduce the amount of waste and to sanitize it from C. jejuni, thereby reducing the risk of contaminating the environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24730/7/24730.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nordentoft, Steen and Hald, Birthe    (2013) Composting poultry manure by fly larvae (Musca domestica) eliminates Campylobacter jejuni from the manure.       Poster at:   CHRO 2013, Aberdeen, 15-19 september 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24730/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>