<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects  of the repeated distribution of sainfoin hay on the resistance and the resilience of goats naturally infected with gastrointestinal nematodes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>V., Paolini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., De La Farge</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., Prevot</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ph., Dorchies</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H., Hoste</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Due to the high prevalence of anthelmintic resistance in goats, the need to explore novel approaches to control nematodes and&#xD;
to reduce the exclusive reliance on chemotherapy is strongly demanded in this host species. In sheep, several studies have shown&#xD;
that the consumption of tannin-rich legume forages was associated with positive effects on host resilience and resistance to&#xD;
parasite infection. In goats, studies on such interactions between tanniferous plants and nematode infections remain few. The&#xD;
objectives of the current study were to examine under natural conditions the effects of consumption of sainfoin hay by goats on&#xD;
the parasite populations and on host resilience.&#xD;
Eighteen adult cull goats naturally infected with Haemonchus contortus, Teladorsagia circumcincta and Trichostrongylus&#xD;
colubriformis were used in the study. At the start of the assay, the goats were allocated into two groups, balanced according to&#xD;
weight and the levels of egg excretion. The two groups grazed separate pastures for 3 months with similar stocking rates. Goats&#xD;
from group S received each month indoors, for 7 days, sainfoin hay and control goats (group C) received hay of ryegrass. The&#xD;
diets in both groups were made isoenergetic and isoproteic and the refusals measured. Individual parasitological and&#xD;
pathophysiological measurements were performed fortnightly in order to compare host resistance and resilience. At the&#xD;
end of the study, five goats per group were necropsied. The distribution of sainfoin was associated with: (1) a higher consumption&#xD;
of hay; (2) significant, lower levels of nematode egg excretion which was associated with a decrease in worm fertility but no&#xD;
change in worm population; however, the number of intestinal worms was reduced by 50% in group S; (3) a better host&#xD;
resilience. In particular, after 2 months of grazing, two control goats died and half of the remaining animals needed to be treated&#xD;
whereas this was not the case in group S. These differences were related to significant changes in pepsinogen and phosphate&#xD;
values (PCV) but not in pepsinogen and phosphate concentrations. These results demonstrate that a repeated distribution of&#xD;
sainfoin hay to grazing goats might be beneficial in regard of pasture contamination and host resilience. They suggest that&#xD;
administration of sainfoin hay might represent a valuable alternative and adjunct to reduce nematode infections in dairy goat flock.&#xD;
# 2004 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6994/1/vetparasitol2005sainfoin.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>V., Paolini; F., De La Farge; F., Prevot; Ph., Dorchies and H., Hoste   (2005) Effects of the repeated distribution of sainfoin hay on the resistance and the resilience of goats naturally infected with gastrointestinal nematodes.   veterinary Parasitology (127), pp. 277-283.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6994/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>