<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A diversified organic pork production – presentation of a concept based on seasonal outdoor rearing of very small entire males</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kongsted, A.G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claudi-Magnussen, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, B.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The risk of boar taint in entire males is supposed to increase with increased age and weight. Thus, a method to reduce this risk may be to slaughter the pigs at a low age and weight. This strategy is investigated as part of a new concept for organic pig production. It is hypothesised that organic pork has to differ markedly from conventional in order to overcome the heavy price competition. A seasonal outdoor rearing system based on production of small entire males, large female pigs and sows slaughtered after their first litter is believed to be a feasible strategy for producing organic pork with high credibility and superior eating quality. The study included a traditional breed, the Danish Black-Spotted. 17 gilts farrowed in April. Within the first week after birth all male pigs, except 2 male pigs per litter, were castrated. The piglets were weaned at 10 weeks of age in June/July but stayed in the paddocks with access to the farrowing hut. The entire male pigs were slaughtered in July at approximately 40 kg live weight. The female pigs were slaughtered in the beginning of November. hvad med Preliminary results showed e.g. a higher daily gain for entire males compared to castrated (390 vs. 332 g per day) and indicated higher content of skatole in the traditional breed compared to a more modern breed.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Kongsted, A.G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Claudi-Magnussen, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Andersen, B.H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14807/1/14807.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kongsted, A.G.; Claudi-Magnussen, C. and Andersen, B.H. (Eds.)    (2008) A diversified organic pork production – presentation of a concept based on seasonal outdoor rearing of very small entire males.     p. 100. Proceedings of EAAP annual meeting, Vilnius, Lithuania, 24-27th August 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14807/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>