<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of timing of sulfur application and nitrogen fertilization on yield and quality of barley</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of S and N application on the redistribution of S and the effect of N application and time of S application (from sowing to the middle of heading) on yield and quality of spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was investigated in pot experiments. Nitrogen and sulphur had a clear interactive effect on the yield of all plant parts with little or no effect of S at low N application rates and similar low effect of N without S application. About 70% of leaf N was redistributed to the ears in plants growing at adequate S supply compared with about 35% of leaf N in S-deficient plants.  The proportion of ear N and S originating from the redistribution of leaf N and S was 49% and 23%, respectively. &#xD;
Deficiency symptoms were observed already at the beginning of tillering at the highest levels of N application and the number of ears per plant clearly decreased by delayed S application. Sulphur applied when the flag leaf was first visible compensated for this and prevented yield reductions. The higher the N levels, the earlier S had to be applied for yield reductions to be avoided. The contents of the S-containing amino acids cysteine and methionine increased when S was applied later than at sowing. Sulphur application had a relatively higher impact on grain quality than on dry matter yield and this was more so the later the application occurred.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/234/1/J_Eriksen_abstract.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J    (2001) Effects of timing of sulfur application and nitrogen fertilization on yield and quality of barley.   In:     Book of abstracts from COST Action 829 meeting Sulfur-Nitrogen Interactions in Plants.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/234/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>