<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Resistance to the attack of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin) of some Sicilian olive cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rizzo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caleca, Virgilio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetic resistance of olive germplasm could be an important tool in the control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin), the key pest in the Mediterranean olive growing. Up to now, no study was carried out on olive cultivars stressed a complete resistance to the attack of B. oleae, and few scientific data are available on susceptibility to olive fruit fly of Sicilian cultivars, although differences among susceptibility of cultivars could be usefully considered to obtain quality productions and to reduce insecticides use both in organic and conventional olive growing.&#xD;
The present study was carried out at Castelvetrano (Trapani province, Sicily), in the olive germplasm collection of Ente di Sviluppo Agricolo of the Sicilian Region and Dipartimento di Colture Arboree of the University of Palermo. From 2002 to 2005, infestation levels in drupes of 18 cv, representing the most widely cultivated in Sicily was recorded. Samplings were carried out every 11-20 days, starting from the second half of August to the end of October. Moreover, from 2003 to 2005  infestation levels were correlated with size and hardness of olives, while in 2004-2005 data on olive coloration were collected at different ripening stages.&#xD;
Among the cultivars producing larger olives, Nocellara del Belice resulted the most susceptible to the olive fruit fly attacks, while Nocellara messinese was the less infested one. Among cultivars with medium, small-sized fruits Moresca, Vaddarica, Nasitana frutto grosso, Minuta and Bottone di gallo were the less susceptible ones. Among the tested cultivars Nocellara del Belice was the most attacked one in every year of the research.  &#xD;
A positive correlation between infestation and olive size was found, resulting in higher infestation levels on the cultivars producing larger olives. B. oleae showed a clear preference for green drupes, instead of reddish or blackish ones. In two out of three years a negative correlation between hardness and infestation was found in September.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Caruso, Tiziano</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Motisi, Antonio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10995/1/Rizzo%26Caleca_olivebioteq_167.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rizzo, Roberto  and Caleca, Virgilio     (2006) Resistance to the attack of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin) of some Sicilian olive cultivars.   In: Caruso, Tiziano  and Motisi, Antonio  (Eds.)  Proceedings of Olivebioteq 2006, Second International Seminar “Biotechnology and quality of olive tree products around the Mediterranean Basin” November 5th –10th, Mazara del Vallo, Marsala, Italy;, 2, pp. 291-298.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10995/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>