<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gibt es bei Körnererbsen Sortenunterschiede in der Anfälligkeit gegenüber bodenbürtigen Krankheiten?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vogt-Kaute, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jorek, Bettina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tilcher, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil borne diseases cause damage in production of peas on many organic farms. Several varieties and breeding lines from Czech Republic and the United States were compared with German varieties in naturally infected soils. Because of very dry weather conditions a field trial with spring peas did not show diseases. In pot trials some varieties with colored flowers (containing tannine) and some winter peas were included in the trials. Some genotypes showed a tendency to a lower level of infection and to higher plant weights compared to plants grown in soil being treated with heat. But in most cases there were no statistic significances. Nevertheless there is a potential for plant breeding to develop peas varieties with a better tolerance against soil borne diseases. Differential diagnosis can be used for testing varieties.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21487/1/21487_vogt-Kaute.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vogt-Kaute, Werner; Jorek, Bettina and Tilcher, Ralf    (2013) Gibt es bei Körnererbsen Sortenunterschiede in der Anfälligkeit gegenüber bodenbürtigen Krankheiten?       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21487/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>