<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vision Research Agenda to 2025</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slabe, Anamarija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlüter, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The TP Organics Vision Research Agenda was prepared between June 2007 and July 2008 on the basis of wide-ranging discussions with farmers’ organizations, scientists, organic traders and retailers, and EU-wide umbrella organizations representing a variety of commercial, non-commercial and civil interests.&#xD;
Up to now, research projects and national framework programmes on organic agriculture have addressed immediate technology gaps in organic agriculture and food production.&#xD;
This Vision has been politically expedient and has given rise to a greater number of producers and professional skills for the task of serving unexpectedly fast growing consumer driven markets. Thus, many organic research projects had a short term perspective only. In contrast to this, our vision takes a long-term perspective on the research needs of organic agriculture and food systems. The three strategic research priorities presented in the vision focus in particular on the inconsistencies between economy, ecology and social cohesion in agriculture and food production and propose research activities and insightful learning concepts for organic and other farming systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>TP Organics</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>TP Organics, TPO</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17214/1/17214.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niggli, Urs; Slabe, Anamarija; Schmid, Otto; Halberg, Niels and Schlüter, Marco    (2008) Vision Research Agenda to 2025.     TP Organics, Brussels.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17214/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>