<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Annual report 2001 LBI organic fruit growing research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bloksma, Joke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jansonius, PieterJans</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanen, Marleen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Overview of projects, funding bodies and partners in 2001 and plans for 2002&#xD;
1. ‘Improving production in apples and pears’, a project allied to research into nitrogen supply in organic fruit growing by the PPO (=Institute for Applied Plant Research Fruit). The object is to design and evaluate practical measures to regulate mineral uptake, growth and fruit-cropping, and to anticipate sudden changes in conditions such as frost, drought, extreme precipitation or an off year.&#xD;
2. ‘Pear scab and fruit tree canker’, a number of small projects in which LBI collaborates with the PPO&#xD;
3. ‘Classy Apples’ project to improve the internal and external quality of organic apples in the growing phase, in collaboration with growers, trade, extension services and the PPO. Funded by growers, trade, Rabobank and government. &#xD;
4. ‘Parameters for apple quality’: Fundamental methodological project to identify meaningful criteria for internal quality for the organic market.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/579/1/lf67.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bloksma, Joke; Jansonius, PieterJans and Zanen, Marleen         (2002) Annual report 2001 LBI organic fruit growing research.   Louis Bolk Instituut Publications, no. LF67. Louis Bolk Instituut, Fruit growing.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/579/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>