<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erfahrungen bei der Haltung horntragender Milchkühe im Laufstall&#xD;
– Probleme und Lösungsansätze in der Praxis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knierim, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Loose housing systems are commonly designed for cows without horns. Farmers&#xD;
keeping horned herds are facing increased risks of injuries among the cows. Interviews&#xD;
were carried out on farms with 62 horned dairy herds in order to collect practical&#xD;
evidence on problems and suitable measures related to the keeping of loose housed&#xD;
horned cows. Most farmers see the feeding area, the cubicles and the waiting area&#xD;
before milking as problem areas. A possibility to securely lock all cows in the feeding&#xD;
rack and an easy retreat from the rack is regarded important. The cubicles should&#xD;
offer an exit to the front, which can be used by cows when attacked from behind.&#xD;
Generous space allowances in the waiting area as well as in the whole stable were&#xD;
recommended. Regarding management measures which help to improve conditions in&#xD;
an existing stable, especially a number of adequate measures to integrate new cows&#xD;
into the herd were described by the farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14182/1/Schneider_14182.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schneider, Claudia; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Klocke, Peter and Knierim, Ute    (2009) Erfahrungen bei der Haltung horntragender Milchkühe im Laufstall – Probleme und Lösungsansätze in der Praxis.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14182/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>