<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Relocalising the food chain: the role of creative public procurement</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Morgan, Kevin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morely, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Networks and ownership</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The conventional food chain presents a challenge to sustainable development, containing hidden costs such as health bills, environmental damage and economic costs to the rural economy. This report argues for the development of local food chains, which would bring the 'multiple dividend' of healthier diets, local markets for local producers, lower food miles and better understanding between producers and consumers.&#xD;
&#xD;
Barriers to the growth of local food chains include EU procurement regulations and UK local government legislation that prohibit explicit 'buy local' policies, health auditing conventions which neglect the health gains of nutritious food; catering cultures that are biased to a few large firms; tendering procedures that are too complex for small suppliers; and lack of logistical and marketing capacity on the part of local producers.&#xD;
&#xD;
Schools and hospitals should be the focus for a concerted local food campaign in the UK. A local food action plan is required to reform the regulatory regime, balance demand and supply, and make it easier for consumers, especially parents and children, to buy nutritious local food, including organic food.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10852/1/RelocalisingProcurement.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Morgan, Kevin and Morely, Adrian         (2002) Relocalising the food chain: the role of creative public procurement.    Cardiff University, The Regeneration Institute.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10852/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>