<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of bioactive compounds from Sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia Scop.) on the in vitro larval migration of Haemonchus contortus: role of tannins and flavonol glycosides</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>E., BARRAU</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>N., FABRE</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>I., FOURASTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H., HOSTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Anthelmintic bioactivity against gastrointestinal nematodes has been associated with leguminous forages supporting the hypothesis of a role of condensed tannins. However, the possibility that other compounds might also been involved has received less consideration. Using bio-guided fractionation, the current study aimed at characterising the biochemical nature of the active compounds present in sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia), previously identified as an  anthelmintic leguminous forage. The effects of sainfoin extracts were evaluated on 3rd stage larvae (L3) of Haemonchus contortus by using a larval migration inhibition (LMI) assay. Comparison of extracts obtained with several solvent systems showed that the bioactivity was associated with the 70:30 acetone/water extract. Further fractionation of the later allowed the separation of phenolic compounds. By use of a dialysis method, compounds were separated with a molecular weight cut-off of 2000 Da. The in vitro  anthelmintic effects of the fraction with condensed tannins was confirmed. In the fraction containing molecules of MW &lt; 2000 Da, 3 flavonol glycosides were identified as rutin, nicotiflorin and narcissin. At 1200 μg/ml, each inhibited significantly migration of larvae. Addition of polyvinyl pyrrolidone (PVPP) to both fractions before incubation restore larval migration. These results confirmed the role of both tannins and flavonol glycosides in the anthelmintic properties of sainfoin.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6982/1/SainfoinPR2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>E., BARRAU; N., FABRE; I., FOURASTE and H., HOSTE   (2005) Effect of bioactive compounds from Sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia Scop.) on the in vitro larval migration of Haemonchus contortus: role of tannins and flavonol glycosides.   Parasitology (131), pp. 531-538.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6982/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>