<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Der Einfluss symbiotischer Bodenpilze auf den Stickstoffzyklus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bender, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Conen, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neftel, Albrecht</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberholzer, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olbrecht, Luise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jocher, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rollog, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Heijden, Marcel G.A</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To increase nutrient use efficiency and reduce nutrient losses are key aspects for sustainable agriculture. Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) are an import and widespread group of plant-symbiotic soil fungi. Here we investigate the role of those soil microorganisms, for effective nutrient recycling. We conducted greenhouse and lysimeter experiments to compare the cycling of important plant nutrients in systems with high and low abundance of AMF. AMF increased plant N nutrition, reduced leaching losses of mineral N, and prevented emissions of N2O, an important greenhouse gas. The results show the importance of AMF for an effective nutrient management. Farmers should implement strategies to promote AMF in the soil, as they are an indispensable compound of sustainable agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21514/1/21514_Bender.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bender, Franz; Conen, Franz; Neftel, Albrecht; Oberholzer, Hans-Rudolf;  Olbrecht, Luise;  Jocher, Markus;  Rollog, Mark and van der Heijden, Marcel G.A    (2013) Der Einfluss symbiotischer Bodenpilze auf den Stickstoffzyklus.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21514/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>