<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Fütterung auf die Milchfettzusammensetzung: Naturwiesenfutter&#xD;
im Vergleich zu Kunstwiesenfutter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Ueli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Collomb, Marius</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A trial was carried out to investigate the influence of forage from temporary or from&#xD;
permanent grassland as well as permanent grassland supplemented with maize silage&#xD;
on the milk fat composition. The trial lasted seven weeks: two weeks of adaptation&#xD;
period and five weeks of experimental period. The forage was offered ad libitum in the&#xD;
stable. None of the cows received concentrates, only a mineral supplement was added.&#xD;
Both feed intake as well as milk production were recorded daily. Before the trial&#xD;
and three times during the trial milk samples were taken and in addition to the fat,&#xD;
protein and lactose content different fatty acids in the milk fat were analysed.&#xD;
The variant with the forage from the permanent grassland had, in comparison with the&#xD;
forage from the temporary grassland, higher proportions of unsaturated fatty acids and&#xD;
higher contents of omega-3 and of conjugated linoleic acid (CLA). With increasing age&#xD;
of the forage, the contents of omega-3 and CLA decreased. The addition of maize&#xD;
silage had a stronger influence on these fatty acids, as the lowest amounts of omega-&#xD;
3 and CLA were found.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14054/1/Wyss_14054.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wyss, Ueli and Collomb, Marius    (2009) Einfluss der Fütterung auf die Milchfettzusammensetzung: Naturwiesenfutter im Vergleich zu Kunstwiesenfutter.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14054/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>