<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gentechnikfreie Bioproduktion.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art: &#xD;
System and produce flow analyses in organic production are being conducted. &#xD;
We look at the possible interfaces where GMO’s could contaminate organic production. &#xD;
For all of the critical contamination points  solutions are developed like excluding critical substances, strict control of  separation of flow of goods and quality assurance systems. &#xD;
We analyse and propose measures, including some for legislators, for the coexistence of GM-free agriculture and agriculture using genetically modified organisms. &#xD;
Definition of the problem: &#xD;
Organic agriculture is recognized as a system of production which must be protected from genetic engineering. Legal regulations have been passed in Switzerland and the EU concerning GM contamination for the food and feedstuffs sector. Many measures already have been taken. The discussion on how to keep organic production and processing GMO free is still going on, in particular when genetically modified plants are being planted in the EU (questions of coexistence).&#xD;
Project aims: &#xD;
Keep organic farming GMO free &#xD;
Methodology: &#xD;
Literature studies, interview of experts, own tests</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5417/1/fibl-projekt-GVO.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Gentechnikfreie Bioproduktion.  [GMO-free organic production.]   Runs 2002 - 2003.      Project Leader(s): Oehen, Bernadette and Nowack, Karin, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5417/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>