<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A comparative study of clinical manifestations, haematological and serological responses after experimental infection with Anaplasma phagocytophilum in two Norwegian sheep breeds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stuen, Snorre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grøva, Lise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Granquist, Erik G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sandstedt, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Ingrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, Håvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background: It has been questioned if the old native Norwegian sheep breed, Old Norse Sheep (also called&#xD;
Norwegian Feral Sheep), normally distributed on coastal areas where ticks are abundant, is more protected against&#xD;
tick-borne infections than other Norwegian breeds due to a continuously high selection pressure on pasture. The&#xD;
aim of the present study was to test this hypothesis in an experimental infection study.&#xD;
Methods: Five-months-old lambs of two Norwegian sheep breeds, Norwegian White (NW) sheep and Old Norse&#xD;
(ON) sheep, were experimentally infected with a 16S rRNA genetic variant of Anaplasma phagocytophilum (similar&#xD;
to GenBank accession number M73220). The experiment was repeated for two subsequent years, 2008 and 2009,&#xD;
with the use of 16 lambs of each breed annually. Ten lambs of each breed were inoculated intravenously each&#xD;
year with 0.4 ml A. phagocytophilum-infected blood containing approximately 0.5 × 106 infected neutrophils/ml. Six lambs of each breed were used as uninfected controls. Half of the primary inoculated lambs in each breed were&#xD;
re-challenged with the same infectious dose at nine (2008) and twelve (2009) weeks after the first challenge. The&#xD;
clinical, haematological and serological responses to A. phagocytophilum infection were compared in the two&#xD;
sheep breeds.&#xD;
Results: The present study indicates a difference in fever response and infection rate between breeds of&#xD;
Norwegian sheep after experimental infection with A. phagocytophilum.&#xD;
Conclusion: Although clinical response seems to be less in ON-lambs compared to NW-lambs, further studies&#xD;
including more animals are needed to evaluate if the ON-breed is more protected against tick-borne infections&#xD;
than other Norwegian breeds.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19867/1/PAPER_III.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stuen, Snorre; Grøva, Lise; Granquist, Erik G; Sandstedt, Karin; Olesen, Ingrid and Steinshamn, Håvard   (2011) A comparative study of clinical manifestations, haematological and serological responses after experimental infection with Anaplasma phagocytophilum in two Norwegian sheep breeds.   Acta Veterinaria Scandinavica, 53 (8), pp. 1-8.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19867/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>