<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Policy change and learning: Implementing EU environmental policies affecting agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kröger, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This thesis aims to show whether and how the implementation of the EU environmental policy could be improved through policy learning. The results are based on two case studies: the development of agri-environmental policy in Finland and the implementation of the Water Framework Directive(WFD)in Ireland.&#xD;
&#xD;
The institutional analysis shows that the institutional structures changed due to the membership: the formal structures changed almost overnight and, as a result of increased cross-sectoral cooperation and policy learning, the informal structures also changed.&#xD;
&#xD;
The implementation of agri-environmental policy was studied in one administrative region, namely Uusimaa, located in southern Finland.&#xD;
&#xD;
The adaptation of EU environmental policies is an interesting research topic, not only because of the policy process itself but also because of the actors and context involved.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16108/1/mtttiede2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kröger, Laura   (2009) Policy change and learning: Implementing EU environmental policies affecting agriculture.    PhD thesis, MTT Agrifood Research Finland. MTT Science, no. 2. MTT Agrifood Research Finland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16108/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>