<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CORE ORGANIC – Coordination of European Transnational Research in Organic Food and Farming (www.coreorganic.org)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jespersen, Lizzie Melby</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>CORE Organic is a 3-year FP6 ERA-NET cooperation project between the public bodies responsible for the national funding of research in organic food and farming in 11 EU countries, AT, CH, DE, DK, FI, FR, IT, NL, NO, SE and UK. The overall objective of the project, which started in 2004, was to enhance the quality, relevance and utilisation of resources in European research in organic food and farming by gathering a critical mass and establishing a joint research programme. Project activities have focused at: &#xD;
·	Increased exchange of information and establishment of a common, open web-based archive (Organic Eprints: www.orgprints.org)&#xD;
·	Coordination of existing research and integration of knowledge &#xD;
·	Sharing and developing best practice for evaluating organic research &#xD;
·	Identification and coordination of future research &#xD;
In 2007 the CORE Organic partners launched a pilot call for joint transnational research projects in organic food and farming, and 8 research projects were selected for transnational funding by means of a virtual common pot approach. The overall funding budget for the 8 projects, which will be running for 3 years, is about 8.2 million EUR.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12963/1/12963.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jespersen, Lizzie Melby    (2007) CORE ORGANIC – Coordination of European Transnational Research in Organic Food and Farming (www.coreorganic.org).       Paper at:   European Organic Congress, Brussels, December 4-5, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12963/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>