<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkungen von ‚Effektiven Mikroorganismen EM’ auf pflanzliche und &#xD;
bodenmikrobiologische Parameter im Feldversuch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scheid, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Widmer, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberholzer, Hansruedi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effectiveness of the bio-fertilizer ‚Effective Microorganisms’ (EM) was investigated in a four years field experiment (2003-2006) at Zürich, Switzerland. The experiment was arranged to separate the effect of the microorganisms in the EM treatments (Bokashi and EMA) from its substrate (sterilized treatments). Crop yields and soil microbiological parameters as soil respiration and microbial biomass were determined. The EM treatments showed no effect on yield and soil microbiology which were caused by the EM microorganisms. Observed effects could be related to the effect of the carrier substrate of the EM preparation. The sampling time showed stronger ef-fects on soil microbial biomass (SIR) and soil respiration compared to the effect of the treatments. Hence ‘Effective Microorganisms’ will not be able to improve yields and soil quality in mid term (3 years) in organic arable farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9691/1/9691_Mayer_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mayer, Jochen; Scheid, Susanne; Widmer, Franco; Fließbach, Andreas and Oberholzer, Hansruedi    (2007) Wirkungen von ‚Effektiven Mikroorganismen EM’ auf pflanzliche und bodenmikrobiologische Parameter im Feldversuch.  [Effects of ‚Effective Microorganisms EM’ on plant and microbiological parameters in a field experiment.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9691/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>