<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modernitet, tid, rum og økologiske fødevarenetværk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The title of the project is ”Modernity, time, space and organic food networks”. The empirical basis for the project is case-studies of four different alternative organic food networks. A fundamental assumption behind the project is that modernity causes disembedding, meaning functional differentiation and distanciation of food networks in time and space, which has potentially negative consequences socially as well as ecologically. The theme of the project can thus be summed up as four questions, which will be adressed in the thesis: &#xD;
&#xD;
1.Does disembedding take place in alternative organic food networks?&#xD;
2.If it does, how does disembedding take place?&#xD;
3.Given that disembedding takes place, what are the driving forces?&#xD;
4.Regardless if disembedding takes place or not, can the selected alternative organic food networks be said to integrate both social and ecological objectives in the production and consumption of organic food?</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4005/1/Edition02_A4a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kjeldsen, Chris   (2004) Modernitet, tid, rum og økologiske fødevarenetværk.  [Modernity, time, space and organic food networks.]   PhD thesis, Aalborg Universitet, Institut for Økonomi, Politik og Forvaltning.  .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4005/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>