<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>On farm Haferflugbrand Resistenzzüchtung &#xD;
auf dem Dottenfelderhof von 2005 bis 2012</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmehe, Ben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Becher, Thorben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spieß, Hartmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2005 an organic oat (Avena sativa L.) breeding programme was initiated by the on farm breeding and research institute at Dottenfelderhof, Hessen, Germany, with the purpose of releasing oat varieties suitable for organic agriculture. From the very beginning it was one goal to develop varieties resistant to loose smut of oat (Ustilago avenae), which can be a severe problem for the certification of seeds. Therefore registered varieties as well as gene bank accessions were used for crosses and evaluated for resistance to loose smut over the years. In this paper the selection process is being described and the resistant level of the present filial generations in 2012 is shown. Additionally the results of the evaluation of registered varieties from 2010-12 are presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21141/3/21141_schmehe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmehe, Ben; Becher, Thorben and Spieß, Hartmut    (2013) On farm Haferflugbrand Resistenzzüchtung auf dem Dottenfelderhof von 2005 bis 2012.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21141/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>