<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Concentrate Mixture, Grass Pellets, Fodder Beets, or Barley as Supplements to Silage ad libitum for High-yielding Dairy Cows on Organic Farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mogensen, Lisbeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Troels, Kristensen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A total of 246 Danish Holstein cows were included in three experiments. In each experiment, Barley (B) was compared with another type of supplementary feeds: a Concentrate mixture (C), Grass pellets (G), or Fodder beets (F). The concentrate mixture resulted in a higher (P = 0.002) milk yield (25.9 vs 23.7 kg), a tendency of a lower (P = 0.07) fat content (4.08 vs 4.25%), and a higher (P = 0.006) ECM yield (25.7 vs 24.1 kg) compared to feeding barley as supplement at the same energy level. Grass pellets resulted in a lower (P = 0.01) milk fat content (3.74 vs 4.07%), a tendency of a lower (P = 0.12) protein content (3.14 vs 3.23%), but no different milk or ECM yield compared to feeding barley as supplement at the same dry matter level. The total mixed ration with fodder beet tended to decrease (P = 0.12) milk yield (20.7 vs 22.0 kg) and the ECM yield (P = 0.05) was lower (21.5 vs 22.9 kg) whereas the composition of the milk was unaffected compared to the total mixed ration with barley.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4680/1/4680.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mogensen, Lisbeth and Troels, Kristensen   (2003) Concentrate Mixture, Grass Pellets, Fodder Beets, or Barley as Supplements to Silage ad libitum for High-yielding Dairy Cows on Organic Farms.   Acta Agriculturae Scandinavica, Section A - Animal Science, 53 (4), pp. 186-196.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4680/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>