<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECT OF Melia azedarach ON APHID (Brevcorinae brassicae) OF ORGANIC CABBAGE FARMING</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rana Bhat, Basanta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yubak, Dhoj GC</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to assess the effectiveness of botanical plant material use in reducing cabbage aphid population (Brevicoryne brassicae), an experiment was conducted in the research command area of Ecological Service Centre at Devghat-9, Gaight, Tanahun during the winter of 2001/2002. Two levels of concentration, 1:5 and 1:10, from the fresh green leaves of Bakaino (Melia azedarach L.), were applied to the aphid population in cabbage at five and ten days intervals. The result indicated that the 1:5 concentrated solution of Bakaino (Melia azedarach L.) extract at five day intervals was most effective in lowering the aphid population and scale of leaf damage as compared to other treatments. Even the 1:10 concentration sprayed at the shorter period of interval was found to be effective. Similarly, the research indicated that both concentration of plant extract and spraying interval are equally important for effective pest management, indicating the possibility of using botanical plant materials in the development of organic insect pest management methods in vegetables.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4316/3/Rana_Bhat_Dhoj_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rana Bhat, Basanta and Yubak, Dhoj GC    (2005) EFFECT OF Melia azedarach ON APHID (Brevcorinae brassicae) OF ORGANIC CABBAGE FARMING.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4316/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>