<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Through Internal Control System, Jatirogo Organic Coconut Sugar Farmers Gained Access to the Export Market</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Setyowati, Theresia Eko</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>By founding Jatirogo organic coconut sugar ICS, 1,554 farmer members now have stronger bargaining power in marketing organic coconut sugar. Jatirogo organic coconut sugar ICS has succeeded to export its organic gula semut. By obtaining international certifications (EU Regulation, NOP-USDA, and JAS), KSU Jatirogo sends organic gula semut to various countries, such as the United States, Australia, and European and Asian countries, by collaborating with KSU Jatirogo and exporting companies.&#xD;
&#xD;
Many people question the ability of farmers to export their produce. By organizing themselves in producing organically, the organic coconut sugar farmers in the region of Menoreh Mountain have since 2008 proven their ability in exporting gula semut. Since 2011, they have also been able to fund international certification independently, without supporting donors.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24320/2/24320.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Setyowati, Theresia Eko    (2014) Through Internal Control System, Jatirogo Organic Coconut Sugar Farmers Gained Access to the Export Market.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24320/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>