<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>HOW TO IMPROVE RESEARCH COMMUNICATION IN TRANSNATIONAL PROJECTS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alföldi, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krebs, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bertelsen, Ulla Sonne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Good research dissemination has to define the exploitable results, to produce suitable dissemination tools and select the best dissemination channels in order to bring the key messages to the target groups. &#xD;
Publications in peer-reviewed journals and other forms of written documents such as articles in popular journals or technical leaflets are traditionally the most selected tools and channels for research dissemination (Poulsen 2010). Because consolidated research results are available usually at the end of a research project only, continuous dissemination activities during the lifetime of a project is not always ensured. We argue that new media including blogs, YouTube videos, Facebook, and Twitter, can help to create an arena for a potential target audience, creating awareness of the research project and assuring a continuous information flow. &#xD;
The aim of this paper is to provide recommendations to researchers on how to improve the dissemination of their research. Furthermore we propose additional criteria to funding bodies to be considered in call announcements, and when selecting and evaluating research proposals.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23609/1/23609_OWC14_Alfoeldi_etal_ResearchCommunication_9Jan2013-revCH_final_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alföldi, Thomas; Krebs, Adrian; Willer, Helga and Bertelsen, Ulla Sonne    (2014) HOW TO IMPROVE RESEARCH COMMUNICATION IN TRANSNATIONAL PROJECTS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1019-1022.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23609/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>