<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Herleitung und Prüfung statischer Humusbilanzkoeffizienten für den ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brock, Christopher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Humus balances are tools for the assessment of humus management in farming practice. We evaluate the coefficients for organic farming systems that are comprised in the actual draft revision of the German standard method for humus balancing by VDLUFA. Specific coefficients for organic farming are supported by the N balance in the soil-plant system under organic management, and the coefficients under survey relate to plausible yield levels. The evaluation of the balances without and with application of farming-system specific coefficients in four organic long-term field experiments in Germany showed overall weak correlations of all balances with the test criteria soil C change, winter wheat yield level, and N balance, but balancing with specific coefficients yielded slightly better results than unspecific balancing.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21587/1/21587_brock.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brock, Christopher and Leithold, Günter    (2013) Herleitung und Prüfung statischer Humusbilanzkoeffizienten für den ökologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21587/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>