<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Animal Husbandry across the world: Towards an Action Plan for development and strengthening of Organic Animal Husbandry.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The goal of the workshop is to provide a diagnosis of the Organic Animal Husbandry situation across the world, and together with the participants, discuss and identify development needs and demands concerning research, education, extension, outreach, market and public policies.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements - Animal Husbandry Alliance (IFOAM-IAHA), Bonn and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Schmid, Otto</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Chander, Mahesh</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Escosteguy, Angela</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Früh, Barbara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27707/1/IAHA-OWC2014-proceedings_end_10Oct2014update.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, Otto; Chander, Mahesh; Escosteguy, Angela and Früh, Barbara (Eds.)    (2014) Organic Animal Husbandry across the world: Towards an Action Plan for development and strengthening of Organic Animal Husbandry.   International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements - Animal Husbandry Alliance (IFOAM-IAHA), Bonn and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.  Proceedings of IAHA Preconference and Workshop at the 18th Organic World Congress, Istanbul, Turkey, 12. and 15. October 2014.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27707/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>