<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswirkungen der Entkopplung der Direktzahlungen auf den&#xD;
ökologischen Landbau in Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Offermann, Dr. Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Dr. Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nieberg, Dr. Hiltrud</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The 2003 CAP reform has a strong influence on the financial performance of organic&#xD;
and conventional farming by decoupling direct payments and reducing price support.&#xD;
This paper aims to identify and assess the impact of the CAP reform on the relative&#xD;
profitability and production structure of organic farms in Germany. The statistical&#xD;
analysis of FADN data from the years 2003/04 and 2006/07 suggests that differences&#xD;
in payments from the first pillar decreased as a result of the reform, affecting positively&#xD;
the relative profitability of organic farms. A survey among German organic farmers&#xD;
revealed however that only a minority attributes changes in profits to the CAP reform&#xD;
and decoupling, respectively. This suggests that organic farmers still require more&#xD;
specific information and advice in order to use the new possibilities given through&#xD;
decoupling.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14312/1/Offermann_14312.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Offermann, Dr. Frank; Sanders, Dr. Jürn and Nieberg, Dr. Hiltrud    (2009) Auswirkungen der Entkopplung der Direktzahlungen auf den ökologischen Landbau in Deutschland.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14312/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>