<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Activities of organic farmers succeeding in reducing lameness in dairy cows</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leach, Katharine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barker, Zoe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maggs, Clare</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sedgwick, Anouska</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whay, Helen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bell, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Main, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sixty-seven organic producers were among 189 dairy farmers completing the “Healthy Feet Project” in the UK. This aimed to reduce lameness in dairy herds by implementing existing knowledge. Participants received input at two levels: monitoring alone, or monitoring with extra support through a single veterinary advisory visit, annual visits from a trained non-veterinary facilitator and materials and contacts to encourage change. On average lameness on organic farms reduced by 12 percentage points over the three year period. On the farms achieving the greatest reduction,the most common changes were improvements to tracks and cubicle comfort, and more frequent footbathing or foot trimming. Practices to improve foot cleanliness, such as more frequent removal of slurry, were less often adopted. Further progress might be achieved by improvements of foot hygiene. Several farms with low lameness that reduced prevalence further improved their handling facilities and treated cows more promptly.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, D</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-09-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21760/1/Leach_lameness_2OAHC_2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leach, Katharine; Barker, Zoe; Maggs, Clare; Sedgwick, Anouska; Whay, Helen; Bell, Nick and Main, David    (2012) Activities of organic farmers succeeding in reducing lameness in dairy cows.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, D (Eds.)  Agriculture and Forestry Research (362), pp. 143-146.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21760/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>