<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>From image to technology: a multidisciplinary approach for improving the quality of organic bread.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>ALESSANDRIN, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DESMONTS, M.-H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>CHIRON, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DUCASSE, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study is part of a research programme devoted to improving the quality of organic bread. It aims to identify and test prototypes of breads approved by consumers. This is achieved by analysing consumer representations and preferences and placing them within the framework of technological, sensory and nutritional dimensions of the products. The multidisciplinary approach implements an original qualitative approach that combines three consumer focus groups made up of both loyal and occasional consumers, and confrontation sessions with the programme scientific partners. Four prototypes of organic breads have thus been formalised and subsequently tested on a sample of 120 consumers from two sites (Angers and Strasbourg). From an operational point of view, proposals for organic breads approved by consumers are formulated. In terms of methodology, the contributions of a multidisciplinary study are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15485/1/29-Alessandrin.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ALESSANDRIN, A. ; DESMONTS, M.-H. ; CHIRON, H.  and DUCASSE, M.    (2009) From image to technology: a multidisciplinary approach for improving the quality of organic bread.  [De l'Image à la Technologie : une approche pluridisciplinaire pour l'amélioration de la qualité du pain biologique.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 203-208.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15485/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>