<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Experiences with entomopathogenic nematodes for the control of overwintering codling moth larvae in Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volk, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Entomopathogenic nematodes were tested for their potential as tool in resistance&#xD;
management of codling moth Cydia pomonella L. in organic fruit growing. In two field tests,&#xD;
the adults emerging from stems treated with nematodes were monitored. In one trial, 90 %&#xD;
of efficacy could be shown. On-farm trials with favourable weather conditions showed an&#xD;
efficacy about 50-60 % on fruit infestation by codling moth in the year following the&#xD;
application. On-farm trials with unfavourable weather conditions showed no results. The&#xD;
favourable weather conditions for the application are discussed with reference to German&#xD;
conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13712/1/277-283.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.; Zimmer, J.; Volk, F. and Zebitz, C.P.W.    (2008) Experiences with entomopathogenic nematodes for the control of overwintering codling moth larvae in Germany.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 277-283.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13712/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>