<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fairness and satisfaction in business relationships: results of a survey among Swiss organic farmers and buyers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mühlrath, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Detlev</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schumacher, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents results of a standardized online survey among Suisse organic farmers and their buyers on fairness and satisfaction in business relations. A majority of participating Suisse organic farmers and buyers are satisfied with their business relationships. Farmers not only expect their buyers to pay fair prices but also to act consistently, be transparent and invest in good personal relations. Buyers expect their agricultural suppliers to provide high quality products, be reliable and transparent while fair prices are mentioned less frequently. Especially regarding perceived fair payments by business partners, this slightly differing perspective between farmers and buyers can also be observed. Presented measurement items of an adapted organizational justice scale in agricultural buyer supplier relationships can be used for further analysis.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23946/1/23946_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mühlrath, Daniel; Möller, Detlev and Schumacher, Jörg    (2014) Fairness and satisfaction in business relationships: results of a survey among Swiss organic farmers and buyers.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1027-1030.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23946/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>