<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Current evaluation procedures for plant protection products used in organic agriculture. Proceedings of a workshop held September 25–26, 2003 in Frick, Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The report describes the evaluation procedures for plant protection products used in organic agriculture. The articles, written by experts on the subject, summarize the situation in various (mainly European) countries and the evaluation procedures and criteria for international institutions (Codex Alimentarius, IFOAM Basic Standards). &#xD;
&#xD;
This volume of proceedings was produced as part of a workshop of the European funded Project ‘Organic Inputs Evaluation’.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Table of Contents&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Foreword&#xD;
Summary	Bernhard Speiser and Otto Schmid&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Austria	&#xD;
Alexandra Hozzank	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Denmark	&#xD;
Rasmus Ørnberg Eriksen	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in France&#xD;
Marie-Christine Monnier	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Germany &#xD;
Christian Schüler	&#xD;
 &#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Italy	30&#xD;
Cristina Micheloni	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming  in the Netherlands	 &#xD;
Rob Boeringa and Marc Trapman&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Poland	&#xD;
Anamarija Slabe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Portugal &#xD;
Alexandra Maurer da Costa &#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Slovenia &#xD;
Anamarija Slabe &#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Spain &#xD;
Victor Gonzálvez&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in Switzerland&#xD;
Bernhard Speiser, Otto Schmid and Lucius Tamm	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in the United Kingdom&#xD;
Christopher Stopes, Rob Haward and Richard Plowright	&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant protection products in organic farming in the USA&#xD;
Brian Baker	&#xD;
&#xD;
Development of evaluation criteria for inputs for organic farming, in view of their compatibility  with organic farming principles	&#xD;
Klaus-Peter Wilbois	&#xD;
&#xD;
IFOAM policies concerning inputs evaluation	&#xD;
Francis Blake&#xD;
&#xD;
Input Criteria of Codex Alimentarius for Organic Agriculture&#xD;
Otto Schmid&#xD;
&#xD;
Overview of EU Regulations for  Plant Protection Products in Organic Farming&#xD;
Bernhard Speiser and Otto Schmid	&#xD;
&#xD;
Comparison of the IFOAM Basic Standards,  the Codex Guidelines, and the EU Regulation	&#xD;
Otto Schmid	&#xD;
&#xD;
About the ‘ORGANIC INPUTS EVALUATION’ project</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Speiser, Bernhard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schmid, Otto</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2942/1/speiser-schmid-2004-inputs-oe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Speiser, Bernhard and Schmid, Otto (Eds.)      (2004) Current evaluation procedures for plant protection products used in organic agriculture. Proceedings of a workshop held September 25–26, 2003 in Frick, Switzerland.    FiBL-Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2942/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>