<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spatial variability of microbial indicators and assessment of tillage systems on the soil microbiological functioning on organic farming.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>VIAN, Ph D Jean François</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>PEIGNE, Dr Joséphine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>CHAUSSOD, Dr Rémi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DAVID, Dr Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>ROGER-ESTRADE, Pr Jean</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Reduction tillage, in modifying the soil microorganisms’ environment, modifies their potential to supply plants nutrients. This is of primary importance in organic farming as the nutrients availability is mainly dependent on the organic matter degradation by microorganisms. To study the effect of tillage on soil physical and microbiological properties, we compare 4 tillage practises (deep and shallow ploughing, chisel and no tillage) in an experimental field near Lyon. Our objective is to link a structural statement with a microbiological functioning in order to study the microorganisms’ abilities to supply nitrogen and phosphorus. For such studies, it is of primary importance to use a convenient sampling design as the microbiological properties are highly variable in space and time. So, we first studied, before the treatments differentiation, the spatial variability of some microbiological properties. We first present this study briefly and its utilities for the future assessment of the tillage practises on the soil microbiological functioning.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7635/1/Tillage_and_nutrition.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>VIAN, Ph D Jean François; PEIGNE, Dr Joséphine; CHAUSSOD, Dr Rémi; DAVID, Dr Christophe and ROGER-ESTRADE, Pr Jean    (2006) Spatial variability of microbial indicators and assessment of tillage systems on the soil microbiological functioning on organic farming.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7635/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>