<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Localized organic agri-food supply chains in Rhône-Alpes (France): diversity of organisations and highlights of the notion of proximity</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chazoule, Carole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fleury, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitrolles, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For ten years, innovative forms of distribution of organic products have emerged between long and short supply chains. They are often defined as "localized agrifood systems". We based this work on the analysis of 18 localized agrifood systems in the Rhône-Alpes region (France). First, it presents the dynamics of construction and organization of these agrifood systems: diversity of actors involved, relationships between actors and rules that have been gradually established. We used the concept of geographical and relational proximity to analyse these supply chains and to highlight the mechanisms implemented to address the limits of short supply chains, particularly an increasing number of intermediaries. Then we assessed their performances with regard to the advantages commonly given to short supply chains. Finally we demonstrated that localized supply chains are in some cases a way towards conventionalisation of organic agriculture and in others a form of mitigation of the agribusiness model.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26209/1/Chazoule_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chazoule, Carole; Fleury, Philippe and Vitrolles, D.   (2013) Localized organic agri-food supply chains in Rhône-Alpes (France): diversity of organisations and highlights of the notion of proximity.  [Filières agroalimentaires biologiques de proximité en Rhône-Alpes : diversité des modes d’organisation et éclairages sur la notion de proximité.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 163-173.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26209/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>