<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Eigenschaften von Mischungen mit perennierenden&#xD;
Leguminosen und Gräsern aus dem Anbau in alternierenden&#xD;
Reihen unter Einbeziehung einer Hochzuckergras-Sorte</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Laser, PD Dr. Harald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köhnke, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Three different perennial legume species (Lotus corniculatus, Medicago sativa,&#xD;
Trifolium pratense) were cultivated in alternate drills with one of three different grasses&#xD;
each. L. corniculatus is known to be rich in tannins, which are supposed to have&#xD;
positive effects on protein digestion of ruminants and methane emissions. One of the&#xD;
grass components was a Lolium perenne cultivar (cv. Aberavon) with increased&#xD;
concentrations of water-soluble carbohydrates (wsc). The influence of this grass&#xD;
variety on forage characteristics in mixtures was tested compared to other grasses&#xD;
(Lolium perenne cv. Gladio and Lolium multiflorum cv. Ligrande). Dry matter yield of&#xD;
different mixtures was determined and concentration of wsc in herbage before ensiling&#xD;
was analysed. Digestibility of organic matter (DOM) in silages was determined&#xD;
encymatically. Aberavon had higher contents of wsc compared to other grasses but&#xD;
there were no differences in DOM of silages caused by the grass cultivar. Mixtures&#xD;
containing Aberavon yielded less dry matter than other grasses. Dry matter yields of&#xD;
mixtures with L. corniculatus were similar or slightly inferior to the yield of the mixtures&#xD;
with M. sativa or T. pratense. Digestibility of silages including L. corniculatus was&#xD;
similar to M. sativa variants and even superior to T. pratense mixtures in single cases.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14133/1/Laser_14133.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Laser, PD Dr. Harald; Köhnke, Sandra and Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter    (2009) Eigenschaften von Mischungen mit perennierenden Leguminosen und Gräsern aus dem Anbau in alternierenden Reihen unter Einbeziehung einer Hochzuckergras-Sorte.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14133/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>