<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>REDUCTION OF FAECAL MICROBIOLOGICAL INDICATORS IN DIFFERENT COMPOST TOILETS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Møller, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forslund, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalsgaard, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Large variations in numbers of faecal indicator bacteria were found irrespective of the storage time of collected human faeces. Little heat seemed generated from composting processes when bin units were stored locally in households. The low reduction in microbiological parameters and very limited temperature increase were generally corroborated by the results obtained in experiment 2 when pathogen indicators were added to thoroughly mixed faecal matter. Even though Salmonella died of rapidly the other faecal bacterial indicators survived in large numbers. We conclude, that the collection and storage of human faeces in the closed plastic bins studied here is associated with only little temperature increase and subsequent reduction in faecal bacterial indicators and pathogens. Thus, the bin units do not seem especially suitable for composting and hygienisation of human faeces</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2088/1/MFDposter2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Møller, J.; Forslund, A. and Dalsgaard, A.    (2003) REDUCTION OF FAECAL MICROBIOLOGICAL INDICATORS IN DIFFERENT COMPOST TOILETS.       Poster at:   ECOSAN 2end International Symposium on Ecological Sanitation, Lübeck, Germany, 7-11 April, 2003.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2088/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>