<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Study and assessment of compost of different organic mixtures and effect of organic compost tea on plant diseases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Znaïdi, Akram</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daami, Megda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ben Kheder, Mohamed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mahjoub, Mohamed</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four compost treatments representing different organic mixtures were studied: &#xD;
- Treatment T1: 100% cattle manure &#xD;
- Treatment T2: 80% cattle manure and 20% sheep manure &#xD;
- Treatment T3: 70% cattle manure, 20% sheep manure and 10% poultry &#xD;
manure. &#xD;
- Treatment T4: 50% cattle manure, 20% sheep manure, 20% poultry manure &#xD;
and 10% crushed wheat straw. &#xD;
The results showed that the temperature was higher for the 4th treatment which &#xD;
was richer in carbon than the other treatments. &#xD;
The initial alkaline pH decreases for all treatments and approaches neutrality &#xD;
at the end of composting process, essentially for the first treatment. There is also a &#xD;
decrease in the carbon / nitrogen ratio. &#xD;
At the maturity stage, a compost tea was prepared from different composts &#xD;
after five days extraction period. The four compost teas were tested on different plant &#xD;
pathogens: Fusarium roseum var sambucinum, Fusarium oxysporum, Fusarium &#xD;
oxysporum, Fusarium solani var coeruleum, Phytophtora erythroseptica and &#xD;
Rhizoctonia solani. All the treatments were efficient against these pathogens and &#xD;
especially the 4th treatment which considerably reduces also the dry rot of Fusarium &#xD;
solani in potato tubers during storage. This is considered an important result since &#xD;
Fusarium solani seems to be the most important pathogen in Tunisian soils. &#xD;
Our studies should be carried out in order to determine the better combination &#xD;
of organic mixtures, the better method of compost tea extraction (aerobic or &#xD;
anaerobic), the optimal period of extraction and doses to be used.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3079/1/Study_and_assessment_of_compost_of_different_organic_mixtures_and_effects_of_organic_compost_tea_on_plant_diseases.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Znaïdi, Akram; Daami, Megda; Ben Kheder, Mohamed and Mahjoub, Mohamed    (2002) Study and assessment of compost of different organic mixtures and effect of organic compost tea on plant diseases.    Working paper, Technical Center of Organic Agriculture.   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3079/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>