<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New findings in organic farming research and their possible use for Central and Eastern Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>3rd Scientific conference brought an opportunity to share information on recent research finding in organic agriculture in central and Eastern Europe. &#xD;
Themes of the Proceedings:&#xD;
- Why do Czech consumers purchase organic food?&#xD;
- Cost competitiveness of selected agricultural products in conventional and organic farms in Poland&#xD;
- Raspberry processing by using new separation processes&#xD;
- Effect of different grassland communities in organic farming on chosen soil properties with focus to carbon&#xD;
- Influence of flesh colour on the content of major antioxidants in potatoes from ecological growing&#xD;
- Current situations in organic cereal seed offer in the Czech Republic&#xD;
Poster section:&#xD;
- Phenotypic Yield Stability of Five Sweet Corn Hybrids Grown in Organic, Low Input and Conventional Agricultural Systems&#xD;
- Effects of organic wheat cultivation in wider rows on the grain yield and quality&#xD;
- Effect of mulching materials on the soil temperature, soil water potential, number and weight tubers of organic potatoes&#xD;
- Influence of Year and Variety to Production of Ecologically Grown Spring Barley&#xD;
- Possibilities of legume-cereal intercropping to increase self-suffi ciency with animal fodder in organic farming&#xD;
- Evaluation of selected traits of proso millet grown under organic and conventional farming systems&#xD;
- Innovative experience of ecological technologies improvement is on a way to an organic production&#xD;
- Influence of year and cultivation practice on common buckwheat&#xD;
- The possibility of use of Trichoderma asperellum in organic field production&#xD;
- Quality of potatoes from different farming systems&#xD;
- The comparison of conventional beef production and bio-production using the method of life cycle assessment&#xD;
- Evaluation of microbiological contamination of sage (Salvia offi cinalis L.) and lemon balm (Melissa offi cinalis L.) herbs&#xD;
- Requirements on properties and characters of wheat species grown in organic system&#xD;
- Total Phenolic Content (TPC) of the Grain of Wheat x Spelt Hybrids and Their Parental Forms&#xD;
- Technological quality of minor spring wheat species from organic farming and possibilities of their utilization.&#xD;
- Organic Methods of Flax Protection Against Fusarium Wilt.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioinstitut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sarapatka, Borivoj</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20485/1/sbornikabstrakt2011_web.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sarapatka, Borivoj (Ed.)    (2011) New findings in organic farming research and their possible use for Central and Eastern Europe.   Bioinstitut.  Proceedings of 3rd Scientific Conference 2011, Prague, Czech Republic, 14th – 15th November 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20485/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>