<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sozialverhalten von Milchziegen in kleinen Gruppen und Folgerungen&#xD;
für die Strukturierung eines Laufstalls</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aschwanden, Janine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gygax, Lorenz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wechsler, Beat</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keil, Nina M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Due to their rank-based relationships goats must observe a certain distance to each&#xD;
other (individual distance). However, this is not always possible in the limited space of&#xD;
a loose-housing pen and can therefore be the reason for frequent aggressive social&#xD;
interactions. In this study, the size of the individual distances between goats, influencing&#xD;
factors, modifications of the feeding place and the loose-housing pens were tested&#xD;
with respect to reducing aggressive behaviour.&#xD;
For most of the goats possible individual distances at feeding were &gt; 0.4m. This is&#xD;
more than the recommended space of a feeding place per goat. Modifications of the&#xD;
feeding place and the loose-housing pen included solid partitions and lying niches&#xD;
allowing for visual cover. Another feature consisted of elevated levels by platforms at&#xD;
different heights. All the measures were effective in reducing aggressive behaviour.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14251/1/Aschwanden_14251.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aschwanden, Janine; Gygax, Lorenz; Wechsler, Beat and Keil, Nina M.    (2009) Sozialverhalten von Milchziegen in kleinen Gruppen und Folgerungen für die Strukturierung eines Laufstalls.  [Social behaviour of goats in small groups and conclusions for the structuring of loose-housing systems.]      Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11. bis 13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14251/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>