<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Symbiotische Stickstofffixierung in biologisch und&#xD;
konventionell bewirtschafteten Wiesen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flura, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Because of lower nitrogen (N) input it is assumed that organically cultivated legumes&#xD;
fix more N2 than legumes grown under conventional cropping. Using the natural 15N&#xD;
abundance method, we assessed symbiotic N2 fixation by white and red clover. The&#xD;
clover was growing in a grass-clover meadow installed as part of the crop rotation of a&#xD;
long term (30 years) field experiment. Dry matter yields were similar for organic and&#xD;
conventional meadows on plots fertilized at levels typical for the respective system,&#xD;
but organic meadows tended to higher clover yields. The proportion of N derived from&#xD;
atmosphere (Ndfa) in both clover species was on average 84%. It was not significantly&#xD;
affected by the cropping system. Because of more legumes, amounts of fixed N2 (Nfix)&#xD;
were higher in organic than conventional meadows. Under low fertilization intensity,&#xD;
low available potassium and phosphorus contents limited Nfix through lower legume&#xD;
dry matter production while Ndfa remained high.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14215/1/Oberson_14215.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oberson, Astrid; Frossard, Emmanuel; Mayer, Jochen; Flura, Thomas; Mäder, Paul and Lüscher, Andreas    (2009) Symbiotische Stickstofffixierung in biologisch und konventionell bewirtschafteten Wiesen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14215/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>