<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of cropping systems on the potential formation of acrylamide in different cultivars of wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stockmann, M. Sc. Falko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graeff, Dr. Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weber, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Prof. Dr. Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Acrylamide (AA) – probably carcinogen – is thermally created in carbohydrate-rich food (e. g. cereals) within the Maillard-Reaction by the reaction of asparagine and reducing sugars. First steps to decrease AA focused on changes in the technological food production process. However, these possibilities are limited due to occurring taste anomalies and consumer tolerance. Therefore, it might be an alternative to influence the precursors of AA. Up to now, multiple studies considering the influence of fertilisation, species, and cultivars on the content of asparagine (Asn) and reducing sugars have been carried out. But there is still a lack of information about the influence of the production system on the AA level. It can be expected that the amount of AA is different and might be lower in organic production systems, because of the difference in nitrogen management (amount and type). The aim of this study was to check organically and conventionally grown wheat samples of different cultivars for the level of the precursor Asn and the AA-formation-potential. The samples were obtained from locations in Switzerland and Germany. Partial significant differences in the amount of Asn and in the AA-formation-potential suggested an influence of the production system and thus a further chance to intervene.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11975/1/Stockmann_11975_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stockmann, M. Sc. Falko; Graeff, Dr. Simone; Weber, A. and Claupein, Prof. Dr. Wilhelm    (2008) Influence of cropping systems on the potential formation of acrylamide in different cultivars of wheat.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11975/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>