<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einsatz von Kräutern, Tonmineralien und Effektiven Mikroorganismen&#xD;
zur Prophylaxe des Absetzdurchfalles</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hagmüller, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vielhaber, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gallnböck, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hahn, Isabella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franz, Chlodwig</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of an herbal blend (Flos Chamomillae, Fruct. Myrtilli, Rad. Taraxaci, Herba&#xD;
Rhapontici Carthamoides, Rad. Dauci Carotae, Bulbus Allii Sativi) in combination with&#xD;
zeolite and Effective Microorganisms on diarrhea incidence of weaning pigs was&#xD;
studied. 82 healthy piglets were divided into four groups by compensating randomization:&#xD;
treatment and control and for both light and heavy. The animals of the experimental&#xD;
group were administered the herbal blend orally. The piglets were weighed&#xD;
regularly. Faeces were appraised with a faecal score on a scale from 0 (formed faeces)&#xD;
to 2 (fluid faeces). Diarrhea occurred in all groups. Blood sample collections were&#xD;
performed for analysis of haptoglobin and nonesterified fatty acids. The results showed&#xD;
no significant difference between experimental and control group. Considering&#xD;
the piglets of the light group a significant higher daily weight gain in the experimental&#xD;
group was found (327 g vs. 241 g, p = 0.0126). There was also a clear trend (p =&#xD;
0.0603) toward faecal scores being lower in the light treatment group. Heavy piglets&#xD;
were not affected by eating the herbs. Our results showed that, while this particular&#xD;
herbal blend did not prevent diarrhea in piglets after weaning, it lessened the severity&#xD;
of diarrhea and significantly improved weight gains in the light treated piglets compared&#xD;
with the light untreated piglets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14574/1/Hagm%C3%BCller_14574.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hagmüller, Werner; Vielhaber, Barbara; Gallnböck, Markus; Hahn, Isabella and Franz, Chlodwig    (2009) Einsatz von Kräutern, Tonmineralien und Effektiven Mikroorganismen zur Prophylaxe des Absetzdurchfalles.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14574/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>