<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Data on estimated area harvested, production, production sold as organic for organic bananas, cocoa, coffee, palm oil, soybeans, sugarcane, tea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garibay, Salvador V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>World</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Voluntary sustainability standards have grown rapidly in number and importance in global commodity markets over the past decade. &#xD;
&#xD;
The growth of voluntary sustainability standards has occurred in parallel with growing recognition of the importance of economic drivers in implementing sustainable development, as evidenced by the global call for a green economy.&#xD;
&#xD;
The State of Sustainability Initiatives Review 2014 reports &#xD;
on systems and market trends across 16 of the most important &#xD;
standards initiatives operating across 10 key commodity sectors.&#xD;
&#xD;
The Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) contribtued data on organic agriculture, based on the data collected in the framework of its annual report on organic agriculture worldwide (www.organic-world.net/yearbook.html).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Institute for Sustainable Development (IISD) and International Institute for Environment and Development (IIED)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Potts, Jason</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lynch, Matthew</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wilkings, Ann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Huppe, Gabriel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cunningham, Maxine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Voora, Vivek</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27695/8/ssi_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga and Garibay, Salvador V.    (2014) Data on estimated area harvested, production, production sold as organic for organic bananas, cocoa, coffee, palm oil, soybeans, sugarcane, tea.    In: Potts, Jason; Lynch, Matthew; Wilkings, Ann; Huppe, Gabriel; Cunningham, Maxine and Voora, Vivek (Eds.)   The State of Sustainability Initiatives Review 2014. Standards and the Green Economy. 1 edition. International Institute for Sustainable Development (IISD) and International Institute for Environment and Development (IIED), Winnipeg and London .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27695/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>