<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Basic substances: a new opportunity for approval copper at EC phytopharmaceutical regulation 1107/2009</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>MARCHAND, Patrice A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Bio control agents:&#xD;
BCA, promising for plant protection are the combination of macro organisms, microorganisms, chemical mediators (pheromones, semiochemicals), and natural substances (from mineral, animal, or vegetal origin). &#xD;
EC regulation:&#xD;
Following, the enter in vigour of the new phytochemical EC Regulation 1107/2009 on May 14th 2011, the opportunity of approval at EU level, for new categories, are now available. Together with regular active substances, as previously managed by Dir 91/414, two new categories were introduced “Basic Substances” described via Article 23 and “Low Risk Substances” defined in Art. 22. Further specific EU-Guidance documents, regarding data requirement, are available or in progress for BCAs sub-category: microorganisms (baculovirus), pheromones (sclp) or botanicals.&#xD;
a. Opportunity of testing the first category (basic substances) for plant extract and light compounds as agriculture aid was engaged by ITAB in 2011 and ended up with an EU-Guidance document, available as working document (SANCO/10363/2012 rev.7) managed by DGSanco in one hand, and Equisetum (Horsetail) BSA pilot project in the other hand. &#xD;
b. Implementation of the second category (Low Risk substances) is in progress in order to produce equivalent Guidance document for early 2014.&#xD;
Basic substances:&#xD;
As matter of fact, these approvals as basic substance are by derogation to general pesticide regulation. Opportunity of the use of plant water extract (Nettle) and food compounds (sugars) in agriculture was not previously attach to any regulation, except in organic farming although some were approved at EC Directive 91/414 (Garlic extract, acetic acid) but as phytopharmaceuticals. Among these alternative products used for crops protection, notably from plants, natural extracts used traditionally by gardeners or farmers, are deemed potentially interesting. The use of these natural extracts preparations can be done now in compliance with regulatory requirements as plant protection substitution product, or plant defense enhancer for agriculture, and especially organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-12-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24914/1/Marchand_2014_%2324914_abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>MARCHAND, Patrice A.    (2013) Basic substances: a new opportunity for approval copper at EC phytopharmaceutical regulation 1107/2009.  [Grundstoffe: eine neue Chance für die Genehmigung Kupfer bei Pflanzenschutzmitteln EG Verordnung 1107/2009.]      Keynote presentation at:   Kupfer als Pflanzenschutzmittel, BERLIN, Dec. 5 2013.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24914/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>