<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss unterschiedlicher Kleegrasnutzungssysteme auf Ertrag, Sortierung und Qualität ökologisch erzeugter Verarbeitungskartoffeln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Norbert U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The most organic produced potatoes are used for direct marketing or home requirements. But due to the growing demand for “Convenience-products” like potato crisps and chips the production of processing potatoes offers farmers an alternative. In contrast to conventional agriculture the nutrient supply in organic potato production must be secured by preceding crops or organic fertilization. Clover grass as  preceding crop is common in praxis. But as the case may be how the clover grass is utilized  (mulching, cut mowing) a different nitrogen fixation and mineralization is possible. In a period of two years (2003/2004) the effect of different clover grass management systems on yield, grading and quality of processing potatoes was under examination on the experimental farm of the University of Kiel in Northern Germany. The tested management systems showed only a low effect on yield and quality on the following crop potato. In 2003 a small yield increase was  achieved by the mulch system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3607/1/3607.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krause, Tanja; Böhm, Herwart; Loges, Ralf; Taube, Friedhelm and Haase, Norbert U.    (2005) Einfluss unterschiedlicher Kleegrasnutzungssysteme auf Ertrag, Sortierung und Qualität ökologisch erzeugter Verarbeitungskartoffeln.  [Effect of different management systems of clover grass on yield, grading and quality of organic potatoes for processing.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3607/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>