<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic products – the choice of bulgarian mothers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivanova, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vassileva, Elka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stefanov, Stiliyan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tipova, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The goal of the presented survey is to analyse the perceptions and attitudes of the group of mothers with small children as consumers of organic products. &#xD;
The self–administered questionnaire survey method in the form of anonymous interviews following a standardised questionnaire was used for the purposes of the survey. Within the course of this research their knowledge and understanding of organic foods and foods’ attributes as a motive for purchase were examined. Complete analysis of data is done on the basis of purchase of organic foods: frequency of purchase of organic foods specially marked as such; buying as result of special demand for organic products; willingness of consumers to pay a higher price for organic foods.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Korean Academy of Commodity Science and Technology</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lee, Yong-Hak</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shin, Hojung</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17056/6/16_IGWT_Korea_Organic_Mathers_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivanova, Daniela ; Vassileva, Elka ; Stefanov, Stiliyan and Tipova, Nina    (2008) Organic products – the choice of bulgarian mothers.   In: Lee, Yong-Hak and Shin, Hojung (Eds.)  The 16th Symposium of IGWT - Achieving Commodity &amp; Service Excellence in the Age of Digital Convergence - Proceedings, Korean Academy of Commodity Science and Technology, Suwon, Korea, Vol. I, pp. 356-360.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17056/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>