<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Case study: Duchy College Organic Studies Centre</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Burke, Jean</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Le Grice, Phil</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Coswinsawsin Organic Demonstration Farm supports a stockless vegetable and cereal rotation and achieved organic status in January 2001. Over 18 months 430 people attended 18 organic farming events. Work included trials and demonstration plots, monitoring of small mammal and bird populations and a green waste composting project which are ongoing. £972,199 Objective 1 funding was awarded to expand activity across all sectors of production and establish the Organic Studies Centre at Duchy College. The project will link organic research to demonstration, technology transfer and training. The emphasis will be on farmer participation and research will be taken onto commercial farms. 82% of respondents to a farmer survey were interested in participation in organic trials and demonstration. It is anticipated that dissemination of up to date information at farm level will improve competitiveness and financial viability of farm businesses.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8378/1/burke_LeGrice_Duchy_College_Studies_Centre.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Burke, Jean and Le Grice, Phil    (2002) Case study: Duchy College Organic Studies Centre.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 119-120.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8378/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>