<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rhizodeposition of nitrogen by red clover, white clover and ryegrass leys</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Dr Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjoerring, Dr Jan K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Correct assessment of the rhizodeposition of N in grassland is essential for evaluation of the biological N2-fixation of legumes, for the total N balance of agro-ecosystems, and for the pre-cropping value of  grasslands. Using a leaf-feeding technique by which plants were 15N labelled while growing in mezotrons in the field, the rhizodeposition of N by unfertilised red clover, white clover and perennial ryegrass growing in pure stands was shown to amount to 64, 71 and 9 g N m-2, respectively, over two complete growing seasons. The corresponding values for red clover and white clover growing in mixtures with ryegrass were 89 and 32 g N m-2, respectively. The rhizodeposited N compounds, including fine roots, constituted more than 80% of the total plant-derived N in the soil, and in all cases exceeded the amount of N present in stubble. In the mixtures of red clover-ryegrass and white clover-ryegrass and the pure stands of red clover, white clover and ryegrass, respectively, the rhizodeposition constituted a 1.05, 1.52, 1.26, 2.21 and 2.77 fold increase over the total shoot N harvested during the two production years. In pure stands and mixtures of clover, 84 and 92%, respectively, of this N derived from biological N2 fixation. It is concluded that rhizodeposition provides a very substantial input of N to legume-based grassland systems with great consequences for ecosystem N balance and turnover. Furthermore, the amount of atmospheric-derived N in the rhizodeposits may exceed that in the harvested shoots.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/288/1/rhizo_deposition_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Høgh-Jensen, Dr Henning and Schjoerring, Dr Jan K.   (2001) Rhizodeposition of nitrogen by red clover, white clover and ryegrass leys.   Soil Biology &amp; Biochemistry, 33, pp. 439-448.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/288/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>