<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of gastrointestinal nematodes in organic beef cattle through grazing management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hertzberg, Hubertus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Figi, Rolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noto, Fabio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Gastrointestinal nematodes (GIN) are a major health and economic risk factor in ruminant production in organic and conventional farms (Thamsborg et al., 1999). Fattening of organic beef cattle (OBC) on pasture is an emerging area for organic farmers in Switzerland, which partly compensates the declining development in dairy production. So far, there are no data available about the parasitic status of beef cattle kept in organic farms between weaning (4-6 month) and slaughter (24-26 month).&#xD;
&#xD;
The aim of the present study was to assess the parasitological status of organic beef cattle in the pre-alpine and alpine region of Switzerland and to analyse the benefits of different grazing strategies for GIN control.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sundrum, Albert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Padel, Susanne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3158/1/hertzberg-et-al-2004-control-of-gastrointstinal-nematodes.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hertzberg, Hubertus; Figi, Rolf; Noto, Fabio and Heckendorn, Felix    (2004) Control of gastrointestinal nematodes in organic beef cattle through grazing management.    In: Hovi, Malla; Sundrum, Albert and Padel, Susanne (Eds.)   Organic livestock farming: potential and limitations of husbandry practice to secure animal health and welfare and food quality. Proceedings of the 2nd SAFO Workshop 25-27 March 2004, Witzenhausen, Germany.  SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project, pp. 129-135.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3158/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>