<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A method for soil health assessment in the conversion to organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mata, Macarena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garrido, Marisol</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Longhurst, Phil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seaton, Roger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
The regulation for the assessment of the conversion to organic farming establishes the use of soil/produce pollution and the type of agricultural practices as indicators of performance. However, these indicators don’t reflect the complexity of the soil ecosystem and soil health. Therefore, complementary indicators were sought (soil biostructure and field capacity), and a specific three-steps method for the assessment and monitoring of soil health during the conversion process was developed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8236/1/mata_soil_health_assessment_conversion.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mata, Macarena; Garrido, Marisol; Longhurst, Phil and Seaton, Roger    (2002) A method for soil health assessment in the conversion to organic farming.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 149-151.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8236/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>