<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The organic food supply chain in relation to information management and the interaction between actors</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kottila, Marja-Riitta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maijala, Adeline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roenni, Paeivi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conventional retailers play a significant role in selling organic food, and therefore, it is important to understand how the demand - supply chain of organic food works as an element of the conventional food system. The proportion of organic food in the conventional food chains is small, and this poses a great challenge to the performance of the chain. Surveys and case specific studies on consumers and supply chain actors indicate that the changes in the conventional food system have an impact on the organic chain. The main obstacles to the optimisation of the organic food chain include poor information management, insufficient communication with consumers, and the diverging objectives and needs of the actors of the chain.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4402/4/4402-Kottila_etal_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kottila, Marja-Riitta; Maijala, Adeline and Roenni, Paeivi    (2005) The organic food supply chain in relation to information management and the interaction between actors.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4402/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>