<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Immunological effects of feeding different sources of vitamin E and seaweed in a sheep herd during the winter season</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Novoa-Garrido, Margarita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aanesen, Lise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lind, Vibeke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Hans J.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Govasmark, Espen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, Håvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In winter fed organic raised sheep inadequate plasma vitamin E levels is common and therefore&#xD;
supplementation is recommended. The objective of the present work was to test the supplementation&#xD;
of natural vitamin E and seaweed meal on the immune status of ewes and their offspring.&#xD;
Forty Norwegian White Sheep ewes were randomly allocated to three supplementation treatments:&#xD;
natural vitamin E, synthetic vitamin E, seaweed meal, and control. The feeding experiment lasted&#xD;
the entire indoor feeding period. Ewes and newborn lambs were vaccinated against different environmental&#xD;
microorganisms and pathogens. Different immunological parameters were measured.&#xD;
Supplementing the ewes with natural vitamin E had positive effect on immunity against Mycobacterium&#xD;
bovis in lambs. Seaweed, on the other hand, had negative effect on the passive transfer of maternal&#xD;
antibodies in lambs the first week after birth. The adaptive immunity was not affected by&#xD;
seaweed supplementation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut - Bundesforschungsinstitut für Ländliche Räume, Wald und Fischerei</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21668/1/Novoa-Garrido_et_al_2012_Immunology_sheep.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Novoa-Garrido, Margarita; Aanesen, Lise; Lind, Vibeke; Larsen, Hans J.S.; Govasmark, Espen and Steinshamn, Håvard    (2012) Immunological effects of feeding different sources of vitamin E and seaweed in a sheep herd during the winter season.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Ressortforschung für den Ökologischen Landbau 2008, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut - Bundesforschungsinstitut für Ländliche Räume, Wald und Fischerei, Braunschweig, Germany, Agriculture and Forestry Research, Special Issue No. 362, no. 362, pp. 207-210.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21668/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>