<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Indigenous sheep breeds in organic livestock production in karst areas of Croatia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Radin, Ms Lada</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Šimpraga, prof. Miljenko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vojta, dr. Aleksandar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marinculić, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic sheep breeding in Croatia is based on indigenous breeds, which are well adapted to their environment. This practice eliminates most of the problems usually encountered when imported foreign breeds have to be adjusted to the new conditions. Karst areas, encompassing about 50% of Croatian territory, are the natural habitat to eight of nine indigenous sheep breeds. These areas are nearly free from pollution, which makes them ideal for organic production. These facts were the foundations for the onset of the projects “Organic lamb production in Croatia” and “Standardisation of some health parameters of Croatian indigenous sheep breeds”. Their goal is to promote and support the development of organic sheep production in Croatian karst areas. In the course of two years, we monitored housing conditions, feeding regime and general health status of animals from five organic flocks. We took blood and faeces samples to determine normal ranges of key physiological and biochemical parameters, since no such previous data existed. They will provide the basis for health monitoring as an aid to veterinarians and sheep breeders in organic production. The development of organic livestock production in the karst areas of Croatia is aimed at accelerating the economic growth of this underdeveloped region by providing a framework for creating a competitive product, while preserving the traditional way of life and protecting the environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11569/1/Radin_11569_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Radin, Ms Lada; Šimpraga, prof. Miljenko; Vojta, dr. Aleksandar and Marinculić, A.    (2008) Indigenous sheep breeds in organic livestock production in karst areas of Croatia.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11569/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>