<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wheat Growing and Quality in Organic Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This chapter will present criteria of the selection of suitable varieties for the organic farming system, depending on land and climatic conditions of a farm, current legislation, availability of seeds, options of the final use, etc. Data in this chapter are based on results of the trials carried out by authors on their working places and a discussion on o given topic. Exact small-plot trials with particular selected varieties (bread and hard wheat) and genetic resources of hulled wheat species (einkorn, emmer wheat, spelt wheat) were established on the authors' working places between 2005 and 2010. Significant and important characteristics for the organic farming (morphological, biological characteristics, yield formation and structure of yield, qualitative parametres of the production).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Intech</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Nokkoul, Raumjit</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20757/1/InTech-Wheat_growing_and_quality_in_organic_farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Konvalina, Petr; Stehno, Zdenek; Capouchova, Ivana and Moudry, Jan    (2012) Wheat Growing and Quality in Organic Farming.    In: Nokkoul, Raumjit (Ed.)   RESEARCH IN ORGANIC FARMING. 1 edition. Intech, Rijeka, Croatia, chapter 7, pp. 105-122.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20757/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>