<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC AGRICULTURE: A WAY FORWARD TO ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY IN INDIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bodapati, Subrahmanyeswari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chander, Mahesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Among several benefits of organic agriculture, emphasis on gender equality is one important aspect which makes it unique as it is believed that it empowers women. This can be contrasted with conventional agriculture, which is said to marginalise women. To understand gender dynamics in organic farming, 111 men and 69 women registered organic farmers were studied using a semi-structured interview schedule and on-farm observations in the context of livestock production activities during 2006-07 in the North Indian state of Uttarakhand, which has embraced organic agriculture by declaring itself as first organic state in India. Land and livestock ownership was mostly with men, whereas income was jointly managed by both men and women followed by women members alone in most of the households. Animal husbandry activities were performed by both men and women, followed by women members of the family, whereas, decision making in animal husbandry activities though reflected plurality, the final decisions in most of the cases rested with men only. This study was not designed to compare the gender dimensions in conventional/traditional farms against organic farms, yet it was observed that women's formal involvement was being encouraged through appropriate policy interventions in the state of Uttarakhand. In particular, the gender sensitisation training imparted by the Uttarakhand Organic Commodity Board (UOCB) appeared to have played key role in making women's participation more proactive and visible. The authors recommend that studies should made to compare the conventional and organic agricultural systems along gender dimensions so as to know to what extent organic agriculture is helping in achieving the millennium goal of gender equality and women's empowerment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24252/7/24252.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bodapati, Subrahmanyeswari and Chander, Mahesh   (2011) ORGANIC AGRICULTURE: A WAY FORWARD TO ACHIEVE GENDER EQUALITY IN INDIA.   Journal of Organic systems, 6 (3), pp. 13-19.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24252/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>