<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>“Comparing economic and environmental sustainability of  intensive and  organic agricultural systems to support  land use policy formulation aimed at reducing agrarian distress in Karnataka, India”</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shah, Pratik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Karnataka state is a state of  India with diverse agro-climatic zones.In 2001 it had a population  of  53  million  and 66% of population habitants living  in villages. Agriculture is  still major  occupation  in  the  rural  areas of Karnataka and more than 90% of rural people  are  dependent on agriculture and agro-industries.  However irregular rainfall patterns,pest attacks and poor nutrient management are  resulting more frequently in  crop failures. This has resulted in agrarian distress as with crop failures, farmers are unable to repay the loans. The government of Karnataka introduced Karnataka state policy of organic farming to decrease agrarian distress. In order to  asses the impacts of  this policy on  agriculture,  economic and ecological sustainability were compared among organic agriculture and conventional agriculture in two districts, Mysore and Chitradurga. Input and output relationships of agriculture were  quantified  by  a  technical  coefficient  generator  (TechnoGIN). Four  scenarios were selected  for comparing  the organic and conventional agriculture: 1) Difference between  organic  agriculture and  conventional  agriculture  in  current  situation; 2)Projecting changes in future for the year 2015; 3)Different impacts of crop failure on debts  of  farmers; 4)Optimal nutrient  management  in conventional and organic agriculture. The  data  used  were based on own field surveys and farm surveys  by ATREE NGO), agricultural scientist expertise and literature  review.  Economic indicators included gross income, fertilizer costs and net profit and the ecological indicators included nitrogen losses, nitrogen surpluses, water requirements and the biocide index. Results  shows  that different crop rotations vary  in profitability while comparing organic and conventional agriculture, but the risk of getting in debt are more in conventional than organic even while projecting the changes for the year 2015. The nitrogen losses and surpluses are more in conventional than organic agriculture but there is problem of nitrogen mining in organic farming. In the end we can conclude that due to low costs of inputs in organic compared to conventional agriculture,Karnataka state policy of organic farming can reduce distress in the selected villages in Mysore and Chitradurga due to low risk of getting debts. However,considering  the  major crops,organic farming is less of an option in Mysore,as productivity and hence profitability is lower compared to conventional farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-02-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19207/1/Final_thesis_Pratik_Shah.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Shah, Pratik   (2010) “Comparing economic and environmental sustainability of intensive and organic agricultural systems to support land use policy formulation aimed at reducing agrarian distress in Karnataka, India”.    Masters thesis, Wageningen University and Research centre, Plant Production System.  .   [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19207/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>