<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Risks and Recommendations Regarding Human Pathogens in Organic Vegetable Production Chains</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>PathOrganic assesses risks associated with the consumption of fresh and minimally processed vegetables due to the prevalence of bacterial human pathogens (e.g. Salmonella enterica, pathogenic E.coli, Campylobacter spp., Listeria monocytogenes) in plant produce. The project aims at evaluating whether organic production poses a risk on food safety and at identifying potential sources of pathogen transmission (e.g. animal manure). The project also evaluates whether organic production may reduce the risk of pathogen manifestation.&#xD;
From a European perspective, vegetable-linked outbreaks are not well investigated. In this project we assess the spread and persistence of bacterial pathogens in organic vegetable production taking into consideration regionally different environmental and management factors. A conceptual model describing food chains and pathogen transfer pathways together with novel sampling strategies and specifically adjusted methods provides the basis for large-scale surveys of organic production lines in six European countries. Critical control points will be determined and evaluated and factors suggesting a problem will be analyzed in greenhouse and field experiments. Finally, a quantitative risk assessment model will be elaborated. Recommendations based on the project results will be communicated to end-users, policy makers and the scientific community for improving food safety in organic production.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    PATHORGANIC: Risks and Recommendations Regarding Human Pathogens in Organic Vegetable Production Chains.    Runs 2007 - 2010.      Project Leader(s): Sessitsch, Doz.Dr. Angela, Austrian Research Centers GmbH - ARC.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11524/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>