<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Observing Environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noe, Egon</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>&gt; Context • Society is faced with “wicked” problems of environmental sustainability, which are inherently multiperspectival, and there is a need for explicitly constructivist and perspectivist theories to address them.&#xD;
&#xD;
&gt; Problem • However, different constructivist theories construe the environment in different ways. The aim of this paper is to clarify the conceptions of environment in constructivist approaches, and thereby to assist the sciences of complex systems and complex environmental problems. &#xD;
&#xD;
&gt; Method • We describe the terms used for “the environment” in von Uexküll, Maturana &amp; Varela, and Luhmann, and analyse how their conceptions of environment are connected to differences of perspective and observation. &#xD;
&#xD;
&gt; Results • We show the need to distinguish between inside and outside perspectives on the environment, and identify two very different and complementary logics of observation, the logic of distinction and the logic of representation, in the three constructivist theories.&#xD;
&#xD;
&gt; Implications • Luhmann’s theory of social systems can be a helpful perspective on the wicked environmental problems of society if we consider carefully the theory’s own blind spots: that it confines itself to systems of communication, and that it is based fully on the conception of observation as indication by means of distinction.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21848/7/21848.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted and Noe, Egon   (2012) Observing Environments.   Constructivist Foundations, 8 (1), pp. 39-62.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21848/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>