<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Animating Domain-Specific Complex Knowledge: An Analysis of Organic Food Communication</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kastberg, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The pivotal point of this paper is an analysis of an animated film, “MultiTrust”. The film is a result a research project dealing with the “Multicriteria assessment and communication of effects of organic food systems”. A primary intention of this project was to help consumers make informed choices when it comes to purchasing organic foods. The animation presents a novel way of communicating domain-specific knowledge of organic food products to consumers. In order to analyze “MultiTrust”, a model of analysis is presented, which is framed by the research field communication and language for special purposes and – due to the filmic format – informed by social semiotics and multimodal analysis. The findings of the analysis are documented at the level of presentation, orientation and organization. The paper ends with a discussion of the potential of the animated film as a means to communicate domain-specific knowledge of organic foods to a lay audience.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-12-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24915/3/24915.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kastberg, Peter   (2013) Animating Domain-Specific Complex Knowledge: An Analysis of Organic Food Communication.   Zeitschrift für Translationswissenschaft und Fachkommunikation, 7 (1), pp. 30-49.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24915/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>