<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of annual self-reseeding legumes on subsequent crops in organic rotation programme</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Al-Bitar, Lina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil fertility management is a critical issue in organic agriculture, and nitrogen supply is the most important aspect, especially in the Mediterranean region. Biological nitrogen fixation by legumes seems to be a successful strategy in that nitrogen-fixing legumes can provide most of the nitrogen used in Mediterranean agriculture in a form not readily leached. According to Pimentel et al., 1992, in the U.S., an estimated $50 billion worth of nitrogen is provided by biological N fixation. Thus, the inputs of nitrogen into Mediterranean agricultural systems by biological fixation in nodulated legumes are fundamental to obtain sustainable and economic production.&#xD;
This study aimed at evaluating the impact of annual self-reseeding legumes on subsequent crops performances in a rotation programme in organic farming.&#xD;
15 cultivars of annual self-reseeding legumes belonging to the genera Trifolium, Medicago, Ornithopus and Biserrula were grown over two cropping cycles as green manures followed by lettuce and corn. &#xD;
All legume treatments had significant positive effects on both subsequent crops.. In fact, marketable yield of lettuce increased an average of 55% over the control and yield of maize grain was an average of 15% over the control. Medicago sphaerocarpa cv Orion, Trifolium subterraneum cv York, T. glanduliferum cv Prima, and T. spumosum cv WCT36 gave the best results with both crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4213/4/Albitar_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Al-Bitar, Lina    (2005) Effect of annual self-reseeding legumes on subsequent crops in organic rotation programme.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4213/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>