<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heterogeneity of protected crop colonization by beneficial insects: role of crop management and landscape context</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aviron, Stéphanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perraudin, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Redondo, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varennes, Y-D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lefèvre, Amélie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Enhancing insect pest control by their natural enemies is considered as a promising crop protection strategy in organic vegetable production systems. In Mediterranean areas, native natural enemies such as mirid bugs (Heteroptera: Miridae) settle spontaneously in protected vegetable crops and can play an important rolefor pest regulation, which remains however very heterogeneous from field to field and hardly predictable. The present study is part of the project REGABRI, which aims at identifying key factors of colonization of organic and conventional protected tomato crops by mirid bugs in Roussillon area. A first survey in 2010-2011 on 34 crops showed that mirids abundances in crops vary according to management practices and landscape features in the crops surroundings (100m to 200m). A second survey in 2012 made it possible to identify uncultivated or cultivated elements in the crops surroundings, that might enhance (source habitats) or on the contrary reduce (dilution and sink effects) tomato crops colonization by mirids. These results showed that a systemic approach, considering the field, the cropping systems as well as the landscape scale, is needed to optimize conservation biological control on protected vegetable systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26017/1/Aviron_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aviron, Stéphanie; Perraudin, M.; Redondo, S.; Varennes, Y-D. and Lefèvre, Amélie   (2013) Heterogeneity of protected crop colonization by beneficial insects: role of crop management and landscape context.  [Hétérogénéité de la colonisation des cultures maraîchères sous abri par les auxiliaires indigènes : rôle de la conduite des cultures et de leur environnement paysager.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 351-363.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26017/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>