<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of permanent ground cover on agronomic properties and soil fertility in an organic peach orchard</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Parveaud, Claude-Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomez, Christelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bussi, Claude</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capowiez, Yvan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In conventional orchards, weeds on the raw are mainly controlled with chemical herbicides because of&#xD;
their efficiency, their low cost and ease of use. The most common method in organic orchard to&#xD;
eliminate weeds on the raw consists of tillage operations. However, some drawbacks of these&#xD;
mechanical methods have been demonstrated: (1) the energetic cost (non-renewable energy) is high,&#xD;
(2) this method is time-consuming, (3) tillage interferes with the development of superficial roots and&#xD;
can hurt the trunk, (4) the physical, chemical and biological properties of the soil can be disturb and (5)&#xD;
erosion and runoff potentially increase. Cover crops are interesting alternatives to manage ground&#xD;
cover but the effect on the agronomic properties and the soil fertility of these methods should be&#xD;
assessed. This study is included in the national program “Casdar SolAB” supported by the French Ministry of&#xD;
Agriculture. The effect of a White Clover crop versus tillage practice on the tree raw was assessed in&#xD;
an irrigated organic Peach orchard. White Clover was sowed in 2004. Soil parameters (water and&#xD;
nutrients availability, soil porosity, root density, earthworms density, soil profile) and agronomic&#xD;
parameters (yield, fruit quality, pests and diseases damages) were recorded since 2004. A 50%&#xD;
decrease of the organic fertilizer supply in the White Clover treatment has not affected yield and fruit&#xD;
quality from 2005 to 2009. It suggests this cover crop is well adapted to our pedoclimatic conditions&#xD;
without exerting a significant competitive effect. Root density is higher in the superficial layers of the&#xD;
soil in the White Clover treatment. Simplified Beerkan test used to assess soil porosity has also shown&#xD;
that soil porosity is higher in this treatment. No vole damage was observed in the plot.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-08-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17223/1/Poster_Soil_Fertility_IHC_V4.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Parveaud, Claude-Eric; Gomez, Christelle; Bussi, Claude and Capowiez, Yvan    (2010) Effect of permanent ground cover on agronomic properties and soil fertility in an organic peach orchard.       Poster at:   28th International Horticultural Congress, Lisbonne, Portugal, 22-27 August 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17223/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>