<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Wirkung von Düngerart und Düngermenge auf die&#xD;
Partitionierung von Kohlenstoff und Stickstoff in Pools mit&#xD;
unterschiedlichem Umsatz</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ludwig, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heitkamp, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Type and rate of fertilizer influence the level of organic carbon and total nitrogen in the&#xD;
soil markedly, but the effect on different pools is open to question. Soil samples were&#xD;
taken from a sandy Cambisol at Darmstadt, Germany, after 27 years of different&#xD;
fertilization treatments. The six treatments were: straw incorporation plus application&#xD;
of mineral fertilizer (MSI) and application of farmyard manure (FYM) each at high (140&#xD;
– 150 kg N ha-1 year-1), medium (100 kg N ha-1 year-1) and low (50 – 60 kg N ha-1&#xD;
year-1) rates. After 266 days of incubation (10°C, 50% water-filled pore space)&#xD;
mineralization of C (1130 – 1820 kg ha-1) and N (90 – 125 kg ha-1) depended on the&#xD;
rate and not on the type of fertilizer. Very labile and labile pools were obtained by&#xD;
fitting a two-pool model on the mineralization data. The very labile pool (turnover: 17&#xD;
days, C/N ratio: 23) was unaffected by treatments. Storage of C (1.8 – 3.2 t ha-1) in the&#xD;
labile pool (turnover 462 days, C/N ratio: 22) increased significantly with the rate of&#xD;
fertilizer. The size of the intermediate pool was significantly higher in FYM (15 -18 t&#xD;
ha-1) than in MSI treatments (12- 14 t ha-1). A passive pool, obtained by oxidation with&#xD;
Na2S2O8, was independent of treatments. Our study shows that labile and&#xD;
intermediate pools were affected differently by fertilization.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14438/1/Ludwig_14438.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ludwig, B.; Raupp, J. and Heitkamp, F.    (2009) Die Wirkung von Düngerart und Düngermenge auf die Partitionierung von Kohlenstoff und Stickstoff in Pools mit unterschiedlichem Umsatz.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14438/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>