<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Overview on different sterilization techniques for baby food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Väisänen, Hanna-Maija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Beck, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seidel, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The nutritional quality of the product as well as other quality attributes like microbiological and sensory quality are essential factors in baby food industry, and therefore different alternative sterilizing methods for conventional heating processes are of great interest in this food sector. This report gives an overview on different sterilization techniques for baby food. The report is a part of the work done in work package 3 ”QACCP Analysis Processing: Quality – driven distribution and processing chain analysis“ in the Core Organic ERANET project called Quality analysis of critical control points within the whole food chain and their impact on food quality, safety and health (QACCP).&#xD;
The overall objective of the project is to optimise organic production and processing in order to improve food safety as well as nutritional quality and increase health promoting aspects in consumer products. The approach will be a chain analysis approach which addresses the link between farm and fork and backwards from fork to farm. The objective is to improve product related quality management in farming (towards testing food authenticity) and processing (towards food authenticity and sustainable processes.&#xD;
The articles in this volume do not necessarily reflect the Core Organic ERANET’s views and in no way anticipate the Core Organic ERANET’s future policy in this area. The contents of the articles in this volume are the sole responsibility of the authors. The information contained here in, including any expression of opinion and any projection or forecast, has been obtained from sources believed by the authors to be reliable but is not guaranteed as to accuracy or completeness. The information is supplied without obligation and on the understanding that any person who acts upon it or otherwise changes his/her position in reliance thereon does so entirely at his/her own risk.&#xD;
The writers gratefully acknowledge the financial support from the Core Organic Funding Body: Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry, Finland, Swiss Federal Office for Agriculture, Switzerland and Federal Ministry of Consumer Protection, Food and Agriculture, Germany.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Helsinki (Eigenverlag)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17236/1/Reports60.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo; Väisänen, Hanna-Maija; Beck, Alexander; Kretzschmar, Ursula and Seidel, Katrin         (2010) Overview on different sterilization techniques for baby food.    University of Helsinki (Eigenverlag), Mikkeli, Finnland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17236/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>