<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Use and efficiency of EU public policy measures for organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper summarises the result of a study carried out on behalf of the EU Commission that had two main aims of firstly, providing a comprehensive overview of public support measures for organic farming in all 27 Member States and, secondly, exploring the relationship between policy measures, policy strategies and the development of the organic farming sector (both in terms of production and market development) in six case study countries (Austria, Czech Republic, Denmark, Germany, Italy and the United Kingdom. &#xD;
The results show  a wide variation in support rates and policies  between EU member states that these have the potential to influence significantly the competitive position of producers within the European organic market. The development of the organic sector is influenced by external factors and by the effective combination of various support policies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21017/1/Padel_etal_2012_ORCBulletin109.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne; Sanders, Jürn and Stolze, Matthias    (2012) Use and efficiency of EU public policy measures for organic farming.   Organic Research Centre Bulletin, June 2012, 109, pp. 10-11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21017/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>