<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswirkungen unterschiedlicher Haupt- und Zwischenfrucht-Kombinationen auf Ertrag und den Schaderregerbefall der Folgefrucht Kartoffel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Surböck, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schiessendoppler, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ledermüller, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Infections with diseases like black scurf (Rhizoctonia solani) and common scab (Strep-tomyces scabies) cause tuber blemishes. In addition, black scurf has an adverse impact on tuber yield, size and shape. The aim of the study was to assess the effect of combinations of main and catch crops on tuber yield, quality and sanitary status. The tested variants were: var. 1: pea without a catch crop apart from volunteer peas, var. 2: pea with a catch crop consisting of white mustard, California bluebell and volunteer peas, var. 3: oat without a catch crop, var. 4: oat with an underseed of white clover. Although in the variants tested no significant difference was achieved for tuber yield, disease occurrence and degree of infection with black scurf and common scab, ten-dentiously similar results were obtained for single variants and over the whole testing period. Highest tuber yields and lowest infection rates with the diseases under investi-gation were obtained for variant two.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9593/1/9593_Surb%C3%B6ck_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Surböck, Andreas; Schiessendoppler, Elisabeth; Ledermüller, Johann; Friedel, Jürgen and Freyer, Bernhard    (2007) Auswirkungen unterschiedlicher Haupt- und Zwischenfrucht-Kombinationen auf Ertrag und den Schaderregerbefall der Folgefrucht Kartoffel.  [Effects of different combinations of main and catch crops on yield and disease occurrence of a following potato crop.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9593/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>