<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Areas of natural occurrence of melipona scutellaris Latreille, 1811(Hymenoptera: Apidae) in the state of Bahia, Brazil.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alves, Rogério M.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carvalho, Carlos A.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Souza, Bruno A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santos, Wyratan S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The bee Melipona scutellaris is considered the reared meliponine species with the largest distribution in the North and Northeast regions of Brazil, with records from the state of Rio Grande do Norte down to the state of Bahia. Considering the importance of this species in the generation of income for family agriculture and in the preservation of areas with natural vegetation, this study aimed at providing knowledge on the distribution of natural colonies of M. scutellaris in the state of Bahia. Literature information, interviews with stinglessbee beekeepers, and expeditions were conducted to confirm the natural occurrence of the species. A total of 102 municipalities showed records for M. scutellaris, whose occurrence was observed in areas ranging from sea level up to 1,200-meter height. The occurrence of this species in the state of Bahia is considered to be restricted to municipalities on the coastal area and the Chapada Diamantina with its rainforests. Geographic coordinates, elevation, climate and vegetation data were obtained, which allowed a map to be prepared for the area of occurrence in order to support conservation and management policies for the species.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22372/1/Alves_Areas.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alves, Rogério M.O.; Carvalho, Carlos A.L.; Souza, Bruno A. and Santos, Wyratan S.   (2012) Areas of natural occurrence of melipona scutellaris Latreille, 1811(Hymenoptera: Apidae) in the state of Bahia, Brazil.  [Áreas de ocorrência natural de melipona scutellaris Latreille, 1811 (Hymenoptera: Apidae) no estado da Bahia, Brasil.]  Anais da Academia Brasileira de Ciências, 84 (3), pp. 679-688.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22372/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>