<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies for regulation of seed borne diseases in organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borgen, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of seed borne diseases on organic cereal production in North-Western Europe is discussed as well as the potential of the possible control measures. It is concluded that it is essential for the organic seed production to put more focus on the control the seed borne diseases. Possible control measures exist, but only a few are used at present. Small seeds are statistically more infected by a number of seed borne diseases than larger seeds. Removal of these seeds by size and gravity separation could be used more frequently. Varieties resistant to the most significant seed borne diseases are available, and improved heat treatment techniques are being developed and are likely to be available for practice in the coming years. Some organic certifying bodies allow application of cupper-salts and bio-agents, but the use of these does to some extent conflict with the fundamental principles of organic diseases management.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ISTA, Internatinal Seed Testing Association</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Muschick, Michael</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Meier, Sarah Anne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Raubo, Patricia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3191/1/NB127.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borgen, Anders   (2004) Strategies for regulation of seed borne diseases in organic farming.   Seed Testing International - ISTA News Bulletin, 127, pp. 19-21.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3191/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>