<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A participatory methodology for large scale field trials in the UK</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Dr H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hinchsliffe, Miss K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clarke, Dr S M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pearce, Dr B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gibbon, Dr D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lyon, Dr F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Harris, Dr F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Dr J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Prof M S</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Farmer participation was essential in developing a uniquely useful set of wheat variety trials data on a wide range of organic farms over two years. Although the trials were successful, it became clear that some of the participating farmers felt there were some limitations in the process. These included a lack of ownership in the project and a concern for more researcher help. It was clear that a greater time in-vestment was needed at the start of the project to help with farmer understanding and ownership. De-spite the negative comments, farmers appreciated their involvement, particularly in contrasting their own views and information with that from the wider scene.  Farmer participation is essential for systems-level research and this project helped to develop a small core of trained farmers and researchers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7447/1/denmark_congress_06_PC_social_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7447/2/7447.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jones, Dr H.; Hinchsliffe, Miss K.; Clarke, Dr S M; Pearce, Dr B; Gibbon, Dr D; Lyon, Dr F; Harris, Dr F; Thomas, Dr J and Wolfe, Prof M S    (2006) A participatory methodology for large scale field trials in the UK.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7447/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>