<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Arbeitszeitbedarf in der Mutterkuhhaltung&#xD;
unter kleinstrukturierten Produktionsbedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schrade, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keck, Margret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schick, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There was a lack of up-to-date statistics on the working time requirements in suckler&#xD;
cattle farming under Swiss production conditions. A combination of final and causal&#xD;
methods for recording working time was used to determine working-time input and&#xD;
working-time requirements, to survey influence variables and draw up working-time&#xD;
models using a model calculation system. The total working time spent on suckler&#xD;
cattle farming varied between 28 and 120 hours per cow per year, with an average of&#xD;
66 hours per cow per year. Over half of this time was spent on routine work, 20 % on&#xD;
management work, 19 % on other non-daily work and 3 % on direct marketing, animal&#xD;
care and animal handling, respectively. The larger the herd size, the lower the time&#xD;
spent on winter routine work. Feeding systems such as ad-libitum feeding in racks or&#xD;
self-feeding at the bunker silo have a positive effect on working time requirements.&#xD;
Besides herd size, factors such as the housing system, process engineering, type of&#xD;
production, available working time, intensity of production and farm management also&#xD;
have a significant effect on working time.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14248/1/Schrade_14248.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schrade, Sabine; Keck, Margret and Schick, Matthias    (2009) Arbeitszeitbedarf in der Mutterkuhhaltung unter kleinstrukturierten Produktionsbedingungen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14248/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>