<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A pilot socio-economic analysis of QLIF dairy projects</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nicholas, Dr. Phillipa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Dr. Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Prof. Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Butler, Dr. Gillian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wagenaar, J.P.T.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A pilot socio-economic impact assessment was carried out on three dairy projects within QLIF to identify the business, consumer and policy issues likely to influence the adoption of the innovations resulting from QLIF.  A socio-economic analysis is pre-sented related to the key outcomes from the three projects which include: manage-ment systems to reduce mastitis and antibiotic use in organic dairy farms and how milk quality can be enhanced through high forage organic feeding systems.  Due to a lack financial data costs had to be assumed based on other studies. The socio-economic analysis identified a significant number of potential economic and social implications of implementing strategies developed in the QLIF project that aim at increasing animal health welfare and milk quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12664/1/Nicholas_qlif_dairy_socio-economic_evaluation_2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nicholas, Dr. Phillipa; Lampkin, Dr. Nicolas; Leifert, Prof. Carlo; Butler, Dr. Gillian; Klocke, Peter and Wagenaar, J.P.T.M.    (2008) A pilot socio-economic analysis of QLIF dairy projects.       Paper at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12664/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>