<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characteristics of the dairy goat primary sector at the Rio de Janeiro State, Brazil.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Junior, Edizio Santos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vieira, Ricardo Augusto Mendonça</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henrique, Douglas Sampaio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fernandes, Alberto Magno</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A survey was done based on 19 goat shepherds at counties of Centre-highlands, Northern and North-western regions of the Rio de Janeiro State and at the county of Pedra Dourada, Zona da Mata region, State of Minas Gerais. We aimed to characterise the primary sector of the goat milk production chain settled at those regions. Therefore, questionnaires were applied in order to depict profiles of the shepherds, their families, the role of the wife in the activity, the resources available, dependence on income generated by the activity, and how producers administrate their business. Farms were distributed in five strata according to the following daily milk production averages and standard deviations: 8.8 ± 0.9, 15.7 ± 3.9, 22.6 ± 2.7, 34.4 ± 3.4, and 183.8 ± 54.2 L/d. Approximately 42% of the interviewed producers conducted their activities according to a household production model and the income earned was exclusively from the dairy goat husbandry. Sons and daughters performed an important role in the business (27.80%), but most of them (62.73%) worked out at non farm activities. The percentage of wives that worked directly in the activity (@47%) indicated that it could contribute to gender equity in the rural environment. Most of the production systems (63.16%) presented positive gross margins. We have noticed, however, that shepherds perceived only the business gross margin and that the most accurate registries taken were those related to revenues. In general, producers of the higher strata were favoured by their larger production scale, but asymptotic behaviours for costs and amounts invested in animals, equipments and buildings were observed. These characteristics should be considered when policies related to the dairy goat primary sector have to be planned.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22681/1/Santos%20Junior_Characteristics.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Junior, Edizio Santos ; Vieira, Ricardo Augusto Mendonça ; Henrique, Douglas Sampaio  and Fernandes, Alberto Magno    (2008) Characteristics of the dairy goat primary sector at the Rio de Janeiro State, Brazil.  [Características do setor primário da caprinocultura leiteira no estado do Rio de Janeiro, Brasil.]  Revista Brasileira de Zootecnia, 37 (4), pp. 773-781.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22681/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>