<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 6. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LowInputBreeds Consortium,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This 6th newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project is quite a lengthy document reporting on the second Symposium of the LowInputBreeds project, which was held in Hammamet, Tunisia, in May 2012. This issue serves as proceedings of the papers presented as well as progress reports on the four speciesspecific subprojects of LowInputBreeds, which were also presented in Hammamet.&#xD;
The second LowInputBreeds Symposium was held together with the 14th International Seminar of the FAO-CIHEAM Network on Sheep and Goats, Sub-Network on Nutrition. The seminar was entitled "Feeding and management strategies to improve livestock productivity, welfare and product quality under climate change".&#xD;
The LowInputBreeds partners are very grateful to the National Institute of Agricultural Research of Tunisia (INRAT), and in particular to Dr. Hichem Ben Salem for hosting this very well organised seminar and for having made it possible to accommodate the LowInputBreeds Symposium.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24646/1/LowInputBreeds-Newsletter-no-6-2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LowInputBreeds Consortium,     (2012) Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 6. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24646/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>