<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biogaserzeugung im viehlosen Betrieb: Effekte auf Stickstoffmanagement, Erträge und Qualität</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stinner, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Dr. Kurt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming systems without livestock some problems arise concerning the nitrogen management: On the one hand, there is a lack of transportable nitrogen fertilisers, on the other hand there is a potential for high losses with the usual management. The biological N2 fixation is decreased, when clover grass is mulched. If the biomass of intercrops and clover grass gets mineralised in autumn, it can be leached in winter. &#xD;
In the trial referred to here, the impact of fermentation of biomass on some agricultural parameters like yield etc. are investigated within a crop-rotation of clover grass, potatoes, winter wheat, peas, winter wheat and summer wheat with undersown clover grass. Intercrops are sown after winter wheat and peas. &#xD;
In the control variant the coupled products (clover grass, straw and intercrops) are left on the field as mulch. In the biogas system this material is harvested for digesting. The remaining products are used as fertilisers. There are liquid products which were used to fertilise the winter wheat and solid ones, which were used for fertilizing potatoes and summer wheat. This system allows a higher efficiency of the nitrogen management: The yield and the content of raw protein in winter wheat increased. The solid material did not mineralise as fast as necessary. It would be better to add this material to the intercrops.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3717/1/3717.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stinner, Walter; Möller, Dr. Kurt and Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter    (2005) Biogaserzeugung im viehlosen Betrieb: Effekte auf Stickstoffmanagement, Erträge und Qualität.  [Biogas production in a stockless farming system: Effects on nitrogen management, yield and quality.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3717/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>