<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bovine colostral antibodies and selected lactobacilli as means to control gastrointestinal infections</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rokka, Susanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aims of this study were to investigate the effects of bovine colostrum and specific colostral antibodies, and some lactic acid bacteria on gastrointestinal infections, especially Helicobacter pylori induced gastritis and dental caries caused by Streptococcus mutans. The effect of colostrum on the activity of the complement system in neonatal calves was also studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
It was possible to increase substantially complement and opsonization activities of serum by feeding colostral whey concentrate to neonatal calves. A colostral immune preparation (IP) containing specific antibodies against Helicobacter felis prevented but did not eradicate an experimental Helicobacter felis infection in mice. However, the IP combined with amoxicillin lowered the level of inflammation and colonization more than amoxicillin alone. The specific anti-cariogenic antibodies of IP remained active and functional when added to UHT milk or fermented with LGG and stored for an extended time. Further, the combination of IP and LGG prevented the adherence of Streptococcus mutans effectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
Lactobacillus plantarum MLBPL1 isolated from sauerkraut showed anti-Helicobacter activity mainly associated with cell wall, from where it can be extracted into the culture supernatant. Colostral preparations, and acidifying microbes (L. plantarum MLBPL1 and LGG) reduced the adhesion of Helicobacter pylori on human gastric adenocarcinoma cells. They also reduced the IL-8 production of the infected cells. IL-8 secretion is a primary response to Helicobacter pylori infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
Supplementation of an antibiotic treatment with a food product containing probiotic lactobacilli and/or IP could offer a potential complementary means to suppress gastrointestinal infections.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14862/1/met131.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rokka, Susanna   (2008) Bovine colostral antibodies and selected lactobacilli as means to control gastrointestinal infections.   Thesis, MTT Agrifood Research Finland. Agrifood Research Reports, no. 131. .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14862/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>