<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Contents of α-tocopherol and β-carotene in grasses and legumes harvested at different maturities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Danielsson, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nadeau, Elisabet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gustavsson, Anne-Maj</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Søren K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soegaard, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nilsdotter-Linde, Nilla</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Concentrations of α-tocopherol and β-carotene in forage species at various maturities were studied in Scandinavia. Red clover (RC)/timothy (TI), RC/meadow fescue (MF), and&#xD;
birdsfoot trefoil (BT)/TI mixtures were grown in Skara and Umeå, Sweden. RC/TI,RC/perennial ryegrass (PR), white clover/PR and BT/TI were grown in Foulum, Denmark. Forages in Sweden were cut one week before heading (BH), at heading and one week after heading of TI. The regrowth was cut six and eight weeks after each harvest in the spring growth cycle. In Denmark, one first harvest and three regrowths were taken. Results from Skara and Foulum are presented. Highest concentrations of α-tocopherol and β-carotene (mg&#xD;
kg-1 DM) in legumes were found in BT grown in Skara (49.8 and 69.6 in spring growth cycle,48.1 and 79.8 in regrowth) and in Foulum (81.3 and 89.2). MF had more α-tocopherol and β-carotene than TI in the spring growth cycle (73.5 and 54.2 vs. 46.9 and 43.0 mg kg-1 DM). Highest concentrations of vitamins in the regrowth were found six weeks after BH with 71.8 and 104.8 mg α-tocopherol and 99.6 and 73.1 mg β-carotene kg-1 DM in legumes and grasses,respectively.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19768/1/EGF2008vitaminslutlig.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Danielsson, Hanna; Nadeau, Elisabet; Gustavsson, Anne-Maj; Jensen, Søren K.; Soegaard, Karen and Nilsdotter-Linde, Nilla    (2008) Contents of α-tocopherol and β-carotene in grasses and legumes harvested at different maturities.   In:     Grassland Science in Europe, 13, pp. 432-434.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19768/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>