<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Buchweizen: ein Futtermittel für Legehennen?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leiber, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messikommer, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meier, J.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wenk, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Buckwheat (Fagopyrum esculentum) has a high ecological value due to the long and&#xD;
intensive flowering as well as its favorable impact on soil fertility. In addition, as a&#xD;
typical catch crop, it provides the possibility of a second harvest on arable land in&#xD;
moderate European regions. However, in Europe demand for buckwheat kernels as&#xD;
food is low. Therefore, the question arises whether cultivation of this plant could be&#xD;
promoted by using it as animal feed. In the current experiment, the extent to which&#xD;
buckwheat is consumed by laying hens was tested in conjunction with potential effects&#xD;
on egg yield and quality. Three groups of laying hens (n=13 per group) were fed a&#xD;
layer diet containing either 40% wheat, 40% hulled buckwheat or 40% crude buckwheat.&#xD;
Feeds were offered ad libitum in form of groats. Feed intake was measured and&#xD;
eggs were sampled before and during the experiment. Feed intake was significantly&#xD;
increased with crude buckwheat, as also were egg weights. Egg number was not&#xD;
affected. The weight and stability of the eggshell were significantly higher with crude&#xD;
buckwheat. The color of the yolk was slightly altered with hulled buckwheat. The&#xD;
results demonstrate that buckwheat is an interesting option as an ecologically and&#xD;
economically valuable feed source for layers, which at least does not cause negative&#xD;
impacts on feed intake and egg yield, compared to wheat.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14795/1/Leiber_14795.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leiber, F.; Messikommer, R.; Meier, J.S. and Wenk, C.    (2009) Buchweizen: ein Futtermittel für Legehennen?       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14795/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>