<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimising farmyard manure utilization by varying the application time and tillage strategy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Elly M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, Ingrid K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Martin N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract. Two field experiments were carried from 1999 to 2001 to assess the effectiveness of autumn, winter and spring application of straw-based farmyard manure (FYM). The soil was a sandy loam containing 106 g clay kg-1 situated in the temperate coastal climate of Denmark. The FYM was applied manually to experimental plots at a target rate of 300 kgN ha-1. The manure was incorporated by three initial tillage strategies (harrowing, rotavating or no-tillage) prior to ploughing. All combinations of tillage strategies were also carried out without manure application. Spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was grown, followed by ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.). The results suggest that, as far as circumstances permit, FYM should be applied in spring to achieve the optimum use of nitrogen in the manure. Further, yield and nitrogen uptake did not benefit from harrowing or rotavating the manure before ploughing. When manure was not applied, soil tillage prior to ploughing did not significantly affect grain yield or nitrogen uptake.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3187/1/hug04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Elly M.; Thomsen, Ingrid K. and Hansen, Martin N.   (2004) Optimising farmyard manure utilization by varying the application time and tillage strategy.   Soil Use and Management, 20, pp. 173-177.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3187/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>