<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results from the arable crop rotation study at Oak Park 2000 - 2007</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kennedy, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Merfield, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mahon, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An organic rotation trial was established at Oak Park in 2000. The crop sequence in the seven year rotation was: two years grass-clover, winter wheat, potatoes, winter oats, lupins and spring barley. The grass-clover, which supplies nitrogen to the system, also provides vegetation which of late is cut and mixed with cereal straw to produce compost. The compost replaced sheep manure which was available up to 2007. Manure was applied to potato plots prior to cultivation for the period 2002 to 2007 and to barley plots from 2005 to 2007. The average yield of crops over the period of the rotation was: winter wheat 5.9 t/ha, potatoes 32.7 t/ha, winter oats 5.8 t/ha, lupins 2.4 t/ha and spring barley 4.5 t/ha. Triticale, which was grown in one of the plots designated for winter wheat, had an average yield of 7.5 t/ha. Lupins have been unsatisfactory due to uncompetitiveness with weeds and lateness of maturity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Teagasc, Ireland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008-12-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19851/1/T.KennedyOrgConf08.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kennedy, T.; Merfield, C. and Mahon, T.    (2008) Results from the arable crop rotation study at Oak Park 2000 - 2007.   In:     Teagasc Organic Production Research Conference Proceedings, Teagasc, Ireland, pp. 59-70.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19851/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>