<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainability, overall and process efficiency of energy crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schäfer, Winfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A method to calculate efficiency of energy crop production including sun energy,&#xD;
direct and indirect energy for cultivation, processing, and conversion into fuel is&#xD;
demonstrated using rape and derived fuels as an example. Every production and&#xD;
conversion step is a process and calculated separately. The overall efficiency&#xD;
includes energy input and output of all processes. The process efficiency of rape&#xD;
cultivation reaches in Finland up to 1100 %. However, the overall energy efficiency of&#xD;
rape methyl ester (RME) is 1 to 2 ‰ only. The production of biogas from manure of&#xD;
dairy fed by rape meal results in a process energy efficiency of 33 to 41 %, but the&#xD;
overall energy efficiency of RME and biogas together is only 1.2 to 2.5 ‰. In&#xD;
contrast, thermal or photovoltaic solar collectors improve overall efficiency 1 to 3&#xD;
orders of magnitude compared to fuel production from rape. Competition for&#xD;
cultivation area and the low photosynthetic efficiency limit the feasibility of fuel&#xD;
production from energy crops. As a measure for sustainability of renewable fuel&#xD;
production, the energy surplus of energy conversion from insolation to fuel per&#xD;
resident and square meter is proposed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CD-ROM: Slovak Association for Sustainable Agriculture, c/o Slovak Agricultural Research Centre – Research Institute of Plant Production, Piešťany</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lehocka, Zuzana</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Klimekova, Marta</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sukkel, Wijnand</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15164/1/ECOMIT_Sch%C3%A4fer_2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schäfer, Winfried    (2008) Sustainability, overall and process efficiency of energy crops.   In: Lehocka, Zuzana; Klimekova, Marta and Sukkel, Wijnand (Eds.)  ECOMIT: proceedings of the 5th International Scientific Conference on Sustainable Farming systems, CD-ROM: Slovak Association for Sustainable Agriculture, c/o Slovak Agricultural Research Centre – Research Institute of Plant Production, Piešťany, pp. 82-87.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15164/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>