<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Suitability of peach and nectarine cultivars for organic production under pannonic climate conditions in Austria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Öhlinger, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spornberger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keppel, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The suitability of nectarine and peach cultivars for organic production was examined&#xD;
in a field experiment in the experimental orchard of the institute in Vienna. Therefore,&#xD;
fifteen cultivars including Redhaven as standard cultivar were planted in 2003 and&#xD;
cultivated organically.&#xD;
Characteristics of the cultivars, such as blossom, growth, yield and susceptibility to&#xD;
frost damage and diseases (Taphrina deformans and Monilinia ssp.) were examined.&#xD;
Furthermore, fruit quality characteristics were checked in the laboratory.&#xD;
The results of growth, yield, susceptibility to damages and diseases and fruit quality&#xD;
showed significant differences among the cultivars. ‘Redhaven’, ‘Sweethaven’,&#xD;
‘Redcal’, ‘Benedikte’ and ‘Mireille’ can be recommended for organic production&#xD;
regarding the results of susceptibility of peach diseases. ‘Red Robin’, ‘Royal Glory’&#xD;
and “Nectared 6’ can partly be recommended. ‘Weingartenpfirsich Eibesthal’,&#xD;
‘Sunglo’, ‘Diamond Princess’, Early Devil’ and ‘Royal Gem’ seem to be unsuitable for&#xD;
commercial organic production.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13656/1/123-126.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Öhlinger, B.; Spornberger, A. and Keppel, H.    (2008) Suitability of peach and nectarine cultivars for organic production under pannonic climate conditions in Austria.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Boos, Markus, (Hrsg.) Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 123-126.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13656/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>