<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mineralization of 15N-labelled sheep manure in soils of different texture and water contents</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, I. K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjønning, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, B. T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to investigate the effect of soil moisture and texture on C and N mineralization of applied organic matter, sheep faeces was sandwiched between two halves of intact soil cores and incubated at 20°C. The soils contained 10.8 (L1), 22.4 (L3) and 33.7% (L5) clay, respectively, and were drained to seven different matric potentials in the range –15 to –1500 hPa. Evolution of CO2-C was determined during four weeks of incubation. Contents of NO3-N, 15N and microbial biomass N were determined at the end of the incubation.&#xD;
The net release of CO2-C from the faeces (estimated as the difference between soils with and without faeces) and the total CO2-C evolution from soils with faeces was not related to soil moisture contents. Most CO2-C evolved from faeces amended soils in the least clayey L1 soil. The faeces caused immobilization of soil NO3-N but the soil matric potential had no major effects on the net NO3-N production. Less than one per cent of the faeces 15N was found as NO3-N at the end of the incubation.&#xD;
The unamended sandy L1 soil held least N in microbial biomass but showed the largest increases in biomass N when faeces was added to this soil. The content of microbial biomass N in soils with faeces application peaked in the most clayey soil (L5). The recovery of faeces 15N at the end of the incubation ranged from 89 to 102%. The variation in 15N recovery was not related to soil clay content nor to soil matric potential. &#xD;
	The experimental set-up was designed to mimic field conditions where manure is left as a discrete layer surrounded by structurally intact soil. In this situation the soil clay content and the soil moisture level appeared to have little influence on the C and N turnover in the manure layer.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/271/1/HarmTaskBf%C3%A6ces_rev1.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thomsen, I. K.; Schjønning, P. and Christensen, B. T.   (2003) Mineralization of 15N-labelled sheep manure in soils of different texture and water contents.   Biology and Fertility of Soils (37), pp. 295-301.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/271/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>