<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aligning Insect IPM Programs With a Cropping Systems Perspective: Cover Crops and Cultural Pest Control in Wisconsin Organic Corn and Soybean</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cullen, E.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holm, K.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This article presents a conversation among researcher, agroecology student, and farmers about the association between cover crops and seedcorn maggot in organic grain crops. Survey data showed that Wisconsin organic farmers would use cover crop management, insect degree day forecasting, and planting date cultural controls, given appropriate knowledge context and extension information provision. We developed electronic and print resources and engaged with farmers and educators nationally through the eOrganic Community of Practice. Project outcomes exemplify student and farmer ability to effect change in land grant university extension recommendations through integrated pest management content and delivery aligned with a cropping systems perspective.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-03-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24311/7/24311.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Cullen, E.M. and Holm, K.M.   (2013) Aligning Insect IPM Programs With a Cropping Systems Perspective: Cover Crops and Cultural Pest Control in Wisconsin Organic Corn and Soybean.   Journal of Sustainable Agriculture, 37 (5), pp. 550-577.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24311/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>