<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In vitro compatibility of microbial agents for simultaneous application to control strawberry powdery mildew (Podosphaera aphanis)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sylla, Justine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alsanius, Beatrix W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krüger, Erika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Becker, Dorit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wohanka, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biological control of plant pathogens on strawberries may be improved by the simultaneous application of different biological control agents (BCAs). Therefore, the compatibility of various BCAs which had previously shown to be effective against powdery mildew (Podosphaera aphanis (Wallr.) U. Braun &amp; S. Takam) under laboratory conditions was examined in vitro. Inhibitory effects between fungal and bacterial BCAs were demonstrated in dual culture tests on two solid nutrient media. Leaf disc assays with single and multiple strain treatments demonstrated either unaffected or significantly improved control of P. aphanis for many multiple strain treatments, even if antagonistic interactions previously occurred in dual culture tests. Highest inhibition of powdery mildew conidiation (80.7% reduction) was achieved with multiple strain treatments with Bacillus subtilis FZB24 and Metarhizium anisopliae (p&lt;0.001). In this combination, conidiation was 3.7 times lower than in single treatments with B. subtilis indicating synergistic interactions between these BCAs. Combinations of Trichoderma harzianum T58 and B. subtilis FZB24 showed antagonistic interactions in dual culture tests as well as in leaf disc assays. In this combination, powdery mildew conidiation on leaf discs was four times higher compared to single treatments with T. harzianum T58.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22910/1/sylla-etal_crop-protection_2013-9_vol51_s40-47.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sylla, Justine; Alsanius, Beatrix W.; Krüger, Erika; Becker, Dorit and Wohanka, Walter   (2013) In vitro compatibility of microbial agents for simultaneous application to control strawberry powdery mildew (Podosphaera aphanis).   Crop Protection, 51 (9), pp. 40-47.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22910/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>