<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Etablierung von Wiesenrispengras in einer 3-schnittigen Dauerwiese mittels Kurzrasenweide</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohrer, Hannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Poa pratensis is one of the most important grass species in Alpine region with a high protection against weed infestation. The most difficulties for an establishment in permanent grassland are a steady juvenile growth and a low competitive strength during this time. In a four-year (2008-2011) field trial the establishment of P. pratensis using continuous grazing in permanent grassland was investigated at the organic grassland and dairy farm of the AREC Raumberg-Gumpenstein. Variant 1 was used under a three times cutting management. During two years of continuous grazing (2008-2009), variant 2 was treated without reseeding and variant 3 was reseeded with P. pratensis variety BALIN three times (each time with 10 kg ha-1) in 2008. In 2010 and 2011 all three variants were used as a three times cutting management. The reseeded variant 3 reached the significantly highest projective cover of P. pratensis with 27 %, while variant 2 achieved 18 % and the cutting variant 1 11 %. Continuous grazed swards (variant 2 and 3) indicated typical changes in botanical composition with a significantly lower cover of Dactylis glomerata and Poa trivialis in comparison to the cutting variant 1. The highest leaf area index of 5.5 was measured in the reseeded variant 3 and illustrates the density of the sward. While the dry matter yield showed no differences between the three variants and amounted approximately 10,000 kg ha-1, the reseeded variant 3 reached significantly higher amounts of crude protein (1,475 kg ha-1) and content (144 g kg-1 DM) in comparison to variant 1 (1,335 kg ha-1 CP, 132 g kg-1 DM CP).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21321/1/21321_Starz.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Starz, Walter; Steinwidder, Andreas; Pfister, Rupert and Rohrer, Hannes    (2013) Etablierung von Wiesenrispengras in einer 3-schnittigen Dauerwiese mittels Kurzrasenweide.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21321/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>