<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>LIVING ON FARM – A NEW APPROACH OF COMMUNITY SUPPORTED AGRICULTURE (CSA)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schäfer, Winfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The development of living on farm is described from an agricultural engineer's point of view focussing on opportunities for elderly in Finland. There are three main groups: Anthroposophical social farms, farms governed by a strict ecological philosophy of life, and farms looking for diversifi­cation concerning ecology, business and on-farm living communities. However, the boundaries between these groups are fluid. The farms may create additional income by offering accommodation, janitorial and transport services, basic and other services to people, who want to live on the farm. Thus, the traditional target of community supported farms -  processing and selling the farm products to a community of customers - is considerably extended.&#xD;
In the long run, the increasing number and the aging of the dwellers may create new working places for nursing services personnel, which in turn may recreate doing com­pensating work on the farm. Creating facilities for living on farm requires some convincing in respect of authorities as well as new technical solutions in renewable energy supply, water supply, waste processing and nutrient recycling. Living on farm for elderly requires new skills in both disciplines: agriculture and geriatric care. Industrial farming and food processing do not coincide with salutogenetic aims. Therefore living on farm is a domain of organic farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23601/1/63601%20Sch%C3%A4fer%20Living%20on%20farm.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schäfer, Winfried    (2014) LIVING ON FARM – A NEW APPROACH OF COMMUNITY SUPPORTED AGRICULTURE (CSA).   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 247-250.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23601/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>