<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biofumigation auch gegen pflanzenparasitische Nematoden?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eder, Reinhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roth, Irma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zinsstag, Christof</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koch, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biofumigation refers to a biological method to reduce diseases, pests and weeds in&#xD;
the soil which is suitable for organic production systems. Cruciferous plants with a&#xD;
high level of Glucosinolates are grown for about two months in the field. To achieve&#xD;
the biofumigation effect, the intercrop is mulched during full bloom and rapidly&#xD;
incorporated into the soil. The Gluconisolates are converted during biological&#xD;
degradation into volatile substances toxic for certain diseases or pests. Nematodes&#xD;
are also sensitive to these substances and are reduced thereby. Besides using the&#xD;
incorporation of fresh plant material, pellets made of dried cruciferous plants and sold&#xD;
as fertilizer might be an alternative approach for nematode control. The pellets are&#xD;
incorporated into the soil before planting, avoiding the cultivation of plants for several&#xD;
months as in conventional biofumigation. First results from pot and greenhouse&#xD;
experiments show effects on plant growth, galling index and reproduction rate of root&#xD;
knot nematodes (Meloidogyne spp.). Further studies conducted at the Agroscope&#xD;
Changins-Wädenswil Research Station ACW are underway to evaluate the potential&#xD;
of this method for the control of different Meloidogyne-species and host plants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14212/1/Eder_14212.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eder, Reinhard; Roth, Irma; Zinsstag, Christof and Koch, Walter    (2009) Biofumigation auch gegen pflanzenparasitische Nematoden?       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14212/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>