<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The use of outdoor runs with rooting areas and drinkers by organic pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vermeer, Herman M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borgsteede, Fred H.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Altena, Henk</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Hygiene is often a problem on the outdoor runs of growing organic pigs. Manure and urine are mainly excreted outside, but spread all over the run. Reducing the dirty surface may improve well being, reduce ammonia emission, improve hygiene and re-duce labour. The presence of a rooting area and of a drinker on the outdoor run were tested in a 2x2 facto-rial design. The pens with the rooting areas had a higher number of pigs on the outdoor run than the pens without a rooting area (1.6 vs 1.2 pigs). This was caused by more pigs in area 2 and 3. At higher temperatures there were more pigs outside, except in the rooting area: this was popular at all temperatures.&#xD;
A rooting area resulted in a cleaner outdoor area, however in some cases the rooting area became a dunging area. An extra outdoor drinker leads to a cleaner area around the drinker, but to a dirtier in-door area.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7467/1/Paper_Outdoor_run_congres_Odense.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vermeer, Herman M.; Borgsteede, Fred H.M. and Altena, Henk    (2006) The use of outdoor runs with rooting areas and drinkers by organic pigs.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7467/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>