<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Kräuterfutterkomponente eines kommerziellen Ergänzungsfuttermittels auf Serumparameter, Fruchtbarkeit und Langlebigkeit von Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spranger, Dr. Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arndt, Dr. Gabriele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaette, Dr. Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A randomized placebo controlled trial investigates an herbal mixture containing mainly Urtica dioica L. (herba), Trigonella foenum-greacum L. (semen), Silybum marianum (L.) Gaert. (fructus) and Achillea millefolium L. (herba). The herbal mixture was fed daily (50g per cow) about 60d from dry off to calving date. 63 dairy cows (32 in the herb-(h)- and 31 in the placebo-(p)-group) of one organic farm were included in the study. Cows were differentiated depending on their lactation number: 19 first lactating cows (L1; h: n=10, p: n=9), 23 cows of second to fourth lactation (L2-4; h: n=11, p: n=12) and 21 cows with more than four lactations (L&gt;4; h: n=11, p: n=10). The herbal group showed the following significant differences (p&lt;0.05) compared to placebo: serum phosphate contents in lactating group L&gt;4 were higher; abnormalities in at least one of 7 tested serum parameters in lactating group L1  were less; in L&gt;4 less ovarian follicles and larger uteri could be found in early lactation; a longer intercalving period (h: 387 days; p: 344 days) but a lower overall culling rate (h: 17%; p: 50%) and culling rate for fertility reasons (h: 3%; p: 23%). The herbal mixture seemed 1. to improve the postpartal metabolic status of dairy cows, 2. to prolong the postnatal anoestrus but 3. to decrease the culling rate particularly for fertility reasons. Overall the prolonged intercalving period will have a lower economic effect than the decreased culling rate.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17531/3/Walkenhorst_17531.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Walkenhorst, Dr. Michael; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Spranger, Dr. Jörg; Arndt, Dr. Gabriele and Schaette, Dr. Roland    (2011) Einfluss der Kräuterfutterkomponente eines kommerziellen Ergänzungsfuttermittels auf Serumparameter, Fruchtbarkeit und Langlebigkeit von Milchkühen.       Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17531/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>