<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agronomic performance and yield stability of pea-barley intercropping in European organic farming system.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Monti, Michele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crozat, Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dahlmann, Christoff</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dibet, Audrey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Fragstein, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gooding, Mike J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauggaard Nielsen, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Erik S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kasyanova, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellostas Muguerza, Natalia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pristeri, Aurelio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Intercropping of cereal and grain legumes in European cropping system (INTERCROP) is an European Project  in which a multidisciplinary team of scientist conducts research on intercropping under different regional organic cropping systems. The project’s core experiments was a field trial in which pea and barley were intercropped in spring sowing and compared with respective sole crops during 2003-2005. One of the main deliverables of the Project (Workpackage 2) was the evaluation of agronomic performance of intercrop in term of yield advantage and yield stability. Results of this activity carried out, in five European Countries  (Denmark, France, Germany, Italy and United Kingdom) in the basic field experiments, are presented in this contribution.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7519/1/Monti1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Monti, Michele; Crozat, Yves; Dahlmann, Christoff; Dibet, Audrey; von Fragstein, Peter; Gooding, Mike J.; Hauggaard Nielsen, Henrik; Jensen, Erik S.; Kasyanova, Elena; Bellostas Muguerza, Natalia and Pristeri, Aurelio    (2006) Agronomic performance and yield stability of pea-barley intercropping in European organic farming system.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7519/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>