<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetic characterization of Apulian wild population of the parasitoid Psyttalia (Opius) concolor (Szepligeti) for biological control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>KARAM, Nisrine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Given the morphological similarity between the released Psyttalia (Opius) concolor and the wild Apulian ones, the biological control program against the olive fruit fly Bactrocera oleae is faced with problem of evaluating the efficacy of the release using the released reared endoparasitoid. A DNA molecular technique, the Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA (RAPD) was used to define eventual molecular markers and to assess the genetic variability between seven wild Apulian populations and one reared strain of P. concolor. A RAPD approach highlights a high genetic similarity among the populations from Puglia, suggesting a common evolutionary history. It also revealed a high genetic homogeneity between the reared and the Apulian samples, ruling out the possibility of detecting diagnostic markers which may differentiate between the populations. Principal coordinate analysis (PCO) and cluster analysis provided an estimate of the degree of differentiation between the populations. They indicate a low genetic differentiation among them.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7008/1/Nisrine05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>KARAM, Nisrine   (2005) Genetic characterization of Apulian wild population of the parasitoid Psyttalia (Opius) concolor (Szepligeti) for biological control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin).  [Caractérisation génétique de la population sauvage des Pouilles du parasitoïde Psyttalia (Opius) concolor (Szepligeti)pour la lutte biologique contre Bactrocera oleae. (Gmelin).]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 404. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7008/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>