<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strengthening the positive links between organic farming and a sustainable development of rural areas</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knickel, Karlheinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Münchhausen, von, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peter, Sarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming can play a major role in the sustainable development of rural areas. Our assumption is that it supports the finding of a new balance between societal demands for high environmental quality, the pressures resulting from competition in a world market economy and a wide array of rural development goals and initiatives. The German 'Regional Action - Rural Areas Shaping the Future' pilot programme has been implemented in order to gain best-practice models for securing the economic, ecological and social viability of rural areas and for trial-testing a new integrated, bottom-up approach. In this contribution we present the results of an analysis of the project databank of the Regional Action pilot programme. It is concluded that the projects that are being implemented aim at a reconstitution of nature-society relations, indicating that agriculture and the potential of rural areas are no longer being evaluated in mono-functional terms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8178/1/Knickel_2p.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Knickel, Karlheinz; Münchhausen, von, Susanne and Peter, Sarah    (2006) Strengthening the positive links between organic farming and a sustainable development of rural areas.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8178/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>