<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quantifizierung der N-Rhizodeposition von Leguminosen in einem Gefäßversuch unter Gewächshaus- und Freilandbedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Landgraf, Anke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtke, Knut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The N rhizodeposition of legumes is defined as the N release into the soil via roots during the growth of the plant. The aim of the experiment presented here was to estimate the N rhizodeposition of red clover and pea using 15N labelling split-root technique in pot experiments under greenhouse and field conditions. The proportion of total N rhizodeposition of the total plant-N was not significantly affected by the tested factors. It amounted between 7 % to 19 % and 9 % to 10 % for plants grown under greenhouse and between 4 % to 11 % and 10 % to 15 % under field conditions for red clover and pea, respectively. In the experiment the absolute amount of N derived from rhizodeposition [mg pot-1] was in the first year tendential and in the following year significant higher by red clover than by the pea. Furthermore, the amount of N derived from rhizodeposition was in the second year significant higher by the legumes are grown under greenhouse compared to legumes are grown under field conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21524/1/21524_Landgraf.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Landgraf, Anke and Schmidtke, Knut    (2013) Quantifizierung der N-Rhizodeposition von Leguminosen in einem Gefäßversuch unter Gewächshaus- und Freilandbedingungen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21524/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>