<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pollenflug, BUWAL</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
This project intends to evaluate and test a monitoring system for the general surveillance of GMPs in Switzerland based on pollen-sampling (Bees, technical pollen sampler) in order to assess the current situation and its evolution. &#xD;
Comparable studies were conducted in Germany by the Federal Agency for Nature Conservation (Hofmann et al. 2005: www.bfn.de/08/0802.htm)&#xD;
and in Austria by the Federal Ministry for Health and Women &#xD;
(Dolezel et al. 2003:  www.bmgf.gv.at/cms/site/bestelliste.htm?channel=CH0295)&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Until now Switzerland is considered to be “GMP-free” to date. Nevertheless, GMP may already exist in the environment, since several sources for entry exist: Pollen entering from neighbouring countries, GMP contaminated seeds and animal feed, transport of GMP seeds through Switzerland, release from contained systems. &#xD;
Project aims including target group:&#xD;
The project intends to develop and test a monitoring system for the appearance and dissemination of GMPs within Switzerland. &#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
DNA array technology and TaqMan PCR assays with known limits of detection will be developed for a fast and reliable detection of transgenic DNA in pollen mixtures by the KLBS. &#xD;
In addition, the method for collecting pollen samples using honeybees or technical pollen samplers will be evaluated by FiBL</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Pollen-screening: Pollenflug, BUWAL.  [Establishment of a monitoring system to survey the appearance and dissemination of genetically modified plants into Switzerland.]   Runs 2004 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Oehen, Bernadette, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5691/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>