<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluß der Futterversorgungsbasis auf den Preis von 100% Bio-&#xD;
Legehennen-Alleinfutter in Abhängigkeit von der Preisentwicklung&#xD;
von Einzelfuttermitteln in den Jahren 2005, 2007 und 2008</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Deerberg, Dr. Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keppler, Christiane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knierim, Prof. Dr. Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keil, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four layer-mash rations based on 100% agricultural feedstuffs of organic origin and&#xD;
with different levels of energy content were tested at the University of Kassel some&#xD;
years ago. The rations had different parts of inland feedstuffs (grain, grain legumes,&#xD;
grass meal) and components from foreign countries (soybean, sesame cake). High&#xD;
energy compositions had a larger part (ca.28%) of foreign feedstuffs. The part of&#xD;
foreign components could be reduced about 10% by decreasing energy content.&#xD;
Ascending costs for the feedstuffs resulted in greater increase of costs for those mixtures&#xD;
with greater amounts of foreign feedstuffs. It would be necessary to search for&#xD;
more solutions in order to strengthen inland feedstuff production and regional organic&#xD;
energy consume.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14164/1/Deerberg_14164.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Deerberg, Dr. Friedhelm; Keppler, Christiane; Knierim, Prof. Dr. Ute and Keil, Joachim    (2009) Einfluß der Futterversorgungsbasis auf den Preis von 100% Bio- Legehennen-Alleinfutter in Abhängigkeit von der Preisentwicklung von Einzelfuttermitteln in den Jahren 2005, 2007 und 2008.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14164/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>