<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Umstellung von Stall- auf Weidefütterung auf den Vormagen pH-Wert von Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Horn, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohrer, Hannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gasteiner, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To investigate the effect of feed transition from barn feeding to pasture on the course of ruminal pH a study with 8 lactating dairy cows was undertaken. Therefore, an indwelling pH-measurement and data transmitting system was used. The experiment started at 27th March 2012 and a gradual transition from barn feeding to pasture feeding was done (periods P1-P6). After 7 days of barn feeding (P1) animals were given pasture progressively with increasing grazing time from 2 to 7 h/d (P2, day 8-14). In P3 (day 15-21) the cows spent 7 hours/d on pasture. Beginning on day 22, animals had 20 h/d access to pasture (continuous grazing), only semi-daily interrupted for 2 hours for milking and additional feeding (P4-P6). During the barn feeding period (P1), average ruminal pH was highest (6.44) and deviation of H+-ion concentration was lowest. In P2 and P3 ruminal pH depressed significantly (6.24 and 6.21 resp.) and increased again from P4 to P6 (6.30, 6.33, 6.36 resp.). The short-term deviation of H+-ion concentration was highest in the first week of day and night grazing (P4).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21143/1/21143_steinwidder.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinwidder, Andreas; Horn, Marco; Pfister, Rupert; Rohrer, Hannes and Gasteiner, Johann    (2013) Einfluss der Umstellung von Stall- auf Weidefütterung auf den Vormagen pH-Wert von Milchkühen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21143/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>