<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Postcard from Oxford: Rudolf Steiner at Manchester College</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At the height of his powers, Rudolf Steiner presented a two-week conference at Oxford. The ‘Oxford Holiday Conference’ was titled ‘Spiritual Values in Education &amp; Social Life’ (Mackenzie, 1922b), and it was this 1922 conference that laid the foundations for establishing Waldorf education in Britain and from there the rest of the Anglo world. The original Waldorf School had been established in 1919 by Rudolf Steiner at the invitation of a German industrialist, Emil Molt, in Stuttgart, Germany. Steiner states that in the Waldorf School he sought "to apply the educational principles arising out of Anthroposophy”. The Stuttgart school began with 150 students and this had grown to 700 by the time of the Oxford Conference. The Oxford Conference ran from 15-29 August, there were 14 presenters, 230 delegates, morning lectures were presented by Steiner in Arlosh Hall at Manchester College, and afternoon lectures were held at Keble College. The Conference was organised by Professor Millicent Mackenzie. Steiner spoke in German, with George Adams Kaufmann translating. The Conference was widely and favourably reported in the British press. At the close of the Conference a committee was formed of at least 11 individuals, including Mackenzie and Professor L. P. Jacks, the Principal of Manchester College, to progress the ideas presented. Photos of the Conference venues within Manchester College include the Manchester College Library, Arlosh Hall and the Manchester College Chapel.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18810/1/Paull2010ManchesterJBDT.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2010) A Postcard from Oxford: Rudolf Steiner at Manchester College.   Journal of Bio-Dynamics Tasmania, 100, pp. 6-14.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18810/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>