<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biodiversitätsbewertung von Bio-Ackerbaubetrieben&#xD;
in Österreich</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Drapela, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petrasek, Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meier, Matthias Samuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfiffner, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindenthal, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents results of an on-farm biodiversity assessment of 45 organic arable farms in eastern Austria (region Weinviertel). The core of the assessment method consists of 99 parameters concerning agricultural practices and semi-natural habitats and their impacts on genetic diversity, habitat diversity and species diversity of eleven indicator species groups. For each farm, a biodiversity performance score was calculated ranging from 0 to 100 %, where 100 % would be reached with the highest possible scores for all parameters. The biodiversity assessment of the 45 organic arable farms revealed big between-farm differences in the biodiversity performance (16.8 to 50.6 %; Ø 32.8 ± 6.1 %). While 32 farms for example achieved biodiversity scores &gt; 40 % in their crop area, only nine farms got more than 10 % concerning semi-natural habitats. These results show that although the assessed farms achieved good biodiversity performances regarding their agricultural practices due to their organic management, semi-natural habitats – which play an essential role in conserving biodiversity in agricultural landscapes – are underrepresented on all farms and reveal the need for improvement concerning conserving and promoting biodiversity on these farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21460/1/21460_drapel.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Drapela, Thomas; Petrasek, Richard; Meier, Matthias Samuel; Pfiffner, Lukas; Lindenthal, Thomas and Schader, Christian    (2013) Biodiversitätsbewertung von Bio-Ackerbaubetrieben in Österreich.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21460/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>