<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How can sustainable agricultural systems promote food security in a changing climate?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sumelius, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bäckman, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rötter, Reimund</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nyairo, Newton</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valkila, Joni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Parviainen, Tuulikki</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zahidul Islam, K.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Motaher Hossain, Md.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tenaw, Shimelles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ingutia, Rose</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A theoretical framework of the link between climate change, rural development, sustainable agriculture, poverty, and food security is presented. Some options to respond to climate change are described. Current knowledge and potential effects on agricultural productivity is discussed. Necessary conditions for successful adaptation includes secured property rights to land, institutions that make  market access possible and credit possibilities. The options of mitigation and enhanced capacity and the requirements for their implementation are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>BOKU university</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17308/1/Sumelius.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sumelius, John; Bäckman, Stefan; Kahiluoto, Helena; Rötter, Reimund; Nyairo, Newton; Valkila, Joni; Parviainen, Tuulikki; Zahidul Islam, K.M.; Motaher Hossain, Md.; Tenaw, Shimelles and Ingutia, Rose    (2010) How can sustainable agricultural systems promote food security in a changing climate?   In:     Building sustainable rural futures. The added value of systems approaches in times of change and uncertainty, BOKU university, pp. 1411-1416.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17308/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>