<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Beurteilung der Fruchtqualität beim Apfel im Rahmen des EU-Projekts Hidras</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kellerhals, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eigenmann, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The EU project Hidras (High Quality Disease Resistant Apples for a sustainable agriculture, QLK5-CT-2002-01-01492) aims to identify genetic factors controlling apple fruit quality with the objective of increasing the acceptability of disease resistant apples. At Agroscope Changins-Wädenswil (ACW) we are performing ex-pert panel tests and  consumer tests. The consumer inquiry during the public fair BEA 2005, end of April 2005 in Bern, Switzerland, resulted in comprehensive information on  consumption trends in apple for dif-ferent age groups. This work is coordinated with partners in Poland and Belgium. All the age groups consid-ered flavour, juiciness and firmness as very important quality criteria for apples. The preference of apples to other fruit such as pears, bananas or citrus is more significant with adults and especially elder people. How-ever, apple was the most favourite fruit species for all age classes. Almost one third of the adults prefer an apple to other snacks. On the other hand, children prefer chips and popcorn and only 12% prefer an apple to other snacks.&#xD;
The overall appearance and eating quality of scab resistant varieties (Ariane, Topaz and Goldrush) and non-resistant varieties (Gala, FAW 5878 and La Flamboyante) evaluated by the same consumers con-firmed, that the resistant varieties were competitive in respect to fruit quality with the non-resistant varieties.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8932/1/ecofruit_12th_30.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kellerhals, Markus and Eigenmann, Christian    (2006) Beurteilung der Fruchtqualität beim Apfel im Rahmen des EU-Projekts Hidras.  [Evaluation of apple fruit quality within the EU project Hidras.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Weinsberg, Germany, pp. 165-171.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8932/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>