<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Corporate Responsibility: The Stakeholder Paradox Reconsidered</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Karsten Klint</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Is it legitimate for a business to concentrate on profits under respect for the law and ethical custom? On the one hand, there seems to be good reasons for claiming that a corporation has a duty act for the benefit of all its stakeholders. On the other hand, this seems to dissolve the notion of a private business; but then again, a private business would appear to be exempted from ethical responsibility. This is what Kenneth Goodpaster has called the stakeholder paradox: either we have ethics without business or we have business without ethics.&#xD;
&#xD;
Through a different route, I reach the same solution to this paradox as Goodpaster, namely that a corporation is the instrument of the shareholders only, but that shareholders still have an obligation to act ethically responsible. To this, I add discussion of Friedman’s claim that this responsibility consist in increasing profits. I show that most of his arguments fail. Only pragmatic considerations allow to a certain extent that some of the ethical responsibility is left over to democratic regulation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11344/1/11344.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Karsten Klint   (2007) Corporate Responsibility: The Stakeholder Paradox Reconsidered.   Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Ethics, 20 (6), pp. 515-532.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11344/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>