<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Schnelle Bestimmung der Futterqualität und der Aminosäuren von Erbsen mittels Nah-Infrarotspektroskopie</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jürgens, Hans-Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The EU-VO 889/2008 sets the year 2012 as the deadline for the exclusive use of organically produced feedstuffs. Protein and amino acid requirements must then be satisfied with local protein-rich feeds. Analytical data of organic feeds, as compared with conventional table values, shows clear deviation of protein and amino acids between conventional and organic feeds. The standard tabular values are not sufficient for the calculation of the feed rations in organic monogaster nutrition. Exact knowledge of the main ingredients and amino acids contents are needed for an acceptable calculation of the feed rations, and for this reason a fast and easy analytical method is necessary. The ability of NIRS to evaluate the quality and content of amino acids in peas was studied. Pea samples from different areas in Germany (n=207) were analysed and used to develop NIRS equations. The performance data obtained shows that the main ingredients and the amino acids could be well predicted with the NIRS. The prediction accuracy for the sulfur-containing amino acids was satisfactory. Pea samples from a future season should be used to improve the stability of the data and to check the quality of the calibrations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17560/3/Aulrich_17560.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aulrich, Karen; Böhm, Herwart and Jürgens, Hans-Ulrich    (2011) Schnelle Bestimmung der Futterqualität und der Aminosäuren von Erbsen mittels Nah-Infrarotspektroskopie.       Poster at:</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17560/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>