<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluß der Stoppelbearbeitung auf Ertagsbildung und Unkrautaufkommen unter den Produktionsbedingungen des Ökologischen Landbaus unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Wirkung des Stoppelhobels</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pekrun, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a field experiment started in August 1998 at the Experimental Station for Organic Farming Kleinhohenheim of the University of Hohenheim the effect of stubble tillage on yield formation and weed control was tested. Three types of stubble tillage were compared to a control which consisted of not cultivating the stubble after harvest. The treatments were: chiselling (15 cm), shallow ploughing (7 cm) and rototillering (5 cm). In autumn all treatments were ploughed at 25 cm depth. So far, stubble tillage has not had any significant effects on weeds or yields. However, there was a tendency of stubble tillage having an impact on perennial weeds.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Reents, Hans Jürgen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8985/1/Pekrun1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pekrun, Carola and Claupein, Wilhelm    (2001) Einfluß der Stoppelbearbeitung auf Ertagsbildung und Unkrautaufkommen unter den Produktionsbedingungen des Ökologischen Landbaus unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Wirkung des Stoppelhobels.  [The influence of stubble tillage on yields and weeds under the conditions of organic farming with special reference to shallow ploughing post harvest.]  In: Reents, Hans Jürgen (Ed.)  Von Leit-Bildern zu Leit-Linien: 6. Wissenschaftstagung zum Ökologischen Landbau, Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin, pp. 203-206.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8985/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>