<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Higher productivity in Danish arable crop production</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The projected expansion of organic farming in Denmark is conditioned on increased arable crop production, which requires higher and more stable crop yields. This must be achieved while also phasing out the use of imported conventional manure and reducing environmental impacts, such as greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions. HighCrop has two main hypotheses: 1) Higher yields and reduced environmental impact can be achieved by introduction of energy crops and improved management of nitrogen (N) in catch crops, green manure and crop residues; and 2) Low yields in practical arable organic farming are caused by a knowledge gap that requires new strategic management tools to overcome. HighCrop applies a comprehensive approach linking research, development and demonstration. Research will improve our understanding of effects of N dynamics and weed pressure on crop productivity, N leaching, GHG emissions and soil biodiversity to derive essential models for N and weed management in organic arable cropping systems. The key to development and dissemination will be new knowledge transfer tools which will be targeted by identification of real and perceived barriers on the farm, as well as in supply and knowledge chains. These concepts and tools will be tested on organic farms and disseminated to Danish organic advisers and farmers. HighCrop will also make use of participatory approaches to synthesize and disseminate knowledge by organising workshops focusing on different supply chains.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19608/1/HighCrop.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    HighCrop: Higher productivity in Danish arable crop production.  [Højere produktivet i dansk økologisk planteproduktion.]   Runs 2011 - 2013.      Project Leader(s): Olesen, Jørgen E..</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19608/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>