<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of White clover (Trifolium repens cv. Huia) cover crop on agronomic properties and soil biology in an organic peach orchard</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Parveaud, Claude-Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomez, Christelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bussi, Claude</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capowiez, Yvan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In orchards, cover crops are interesting alternative strategies to tillage or chemical herbicides for managing weeds in the tree row. However, little is known about the effect of cover crops on agronomic properties and soil biology in organic orchards. To fill this gap, the effects of two weed managements, a White clover cover crop (CC) versus classical tillage practice (T) on the tree row, were assessed in an irrigated organic Peach orchard. White clover was sown in 2004, 2006 and 2009 in the tree row and ploughed in 2006 and 2008. Root density, earthworm density, water infiltration rate, nitrogen content and water availability were measured in the soil, in the tree row. In 2009, peach root density observed in the superficial layers was higher in CC treatment. Sampling dates and treatment have a significant effect on total earthworm density with higher abundance observed in CC. However, no difference was observed between CC and T anecic earthworm groups known to make large and vertical burrows. Infiltration rate measured with the simplified Beerkan method was higher in CC treatment. This could be explained by the thick superficial root mat which was associated to a significant higher epigeic earthworm density in CC. Whereas nitrogen supplies were twice lower in CC treatment since 2005, soil nitrogen availability was equivalent in both treatments. These results demonstrate the agronomic interest of nitrogen-fixing plants used as a cover crop in organic peach orchards.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21132/1/64-Parveaud-Peach-CoverCrop-revised-version.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Parveaud, Claude-Eric; Gomez, Christelle; Bussi, Claude and Capowiez, Yvan   (2012) Effect of White clover (Trifolium repens cv. Huia) cover crop on agronomic properties and soil biology in an organic peach orchard.   ACTA HORTICULTURAE, 933 (1), pp. 373-380.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21132/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>