<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breeding and feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems (4th NAHWOA Workshop)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>content:&#xD;
Part A: Breeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems&#xD;
Part B: Feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems&#xD;
Part C: Posters and additional papers&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
The theme of the 4 th NAHWOA Workshop was  Breeding and feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems . According to most organic certification body standards and the current EU legislation, breeding and feeding are the two cornerstones of health and welfare in organic livestock systems. It is apparent form these proceedings that the concept of  organic breeds  or  organic breeding  is far from clear and that a lot of work needs to be carried out before 2005, when the current EU derogation allowing sourcing of livestock from conventional breeding systems to organic systems runs out. Similarly, the requirement to feed 100% organic feedstuffs from 2004 onwards makes heavy demands on the development of organic rations for monogastric livestock in particular. These proceedings show that a substantial amount of work is already being carried out to satisfy these requirements, and that some encouraging results are already there. &#xD;
In addition to the thematic papers, these Proceedings also include a paper by Kat Bazeley et al., presented at the third NAHWOA workshop in France in October 2000. Due to an editorial error this paper was left out form the appropriate proceedings. We would like to apologise for this and hope that those who have searched for this reference in the past will now be able to locate it. Also, abstracts of three posters presented both in Wageningen are presented.&#xD;
&#xD;
precise content:&#xD;
&#xD;
Part A: Breeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems&#xD;
&#xD;
W. Nauta: Breeding strategies for organic animal production, an international discussion&#xD;
R. Baumung, J. Sölkner, E. Gierzinger, A.William: Ecological total merit index for an Austrian dual purpose cattle breed&#xD;
D. Endendijk, T. Baars, H. Endendijk: Family breeding at Rivelinohoeve &#xD;
B. Bapst: Swiss experiences on practical cattle breeding strategies for organic dairy herds&#xD;
P. Sørensen :Breeding strategies in poultry for genetic adaptation to the organic environment&#xD;
P. Koene: Animal welfare and genetics in organic farming of layers: the example of cannibalism&#xD;
H.R.C. Kelly, H.M. Browning, A.P. Martins, G.P. Pearce, C. Stopes, S.A. Edwards: Breeding and feeding pigs for organic production &#xD;
G. Rahmann: Breeding goats for organic production in Germany &#xD;
T. BAARS, W. NAUTA: Breeding for race diversity, herd adaptation and harmony of animal build: a breeding concept in organic farming&#xD;
H. Hirt, M. Bestmann, W. Nauta, L. Philipps, H. Spoolder: Discussion report: Breeding for health and welfare &#xD;
&#xD;
Part B: Feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems&#xD;
&#xD;
B.S.E. Jonsson: Results from the Öjebyn-project. Eleven years of organic production &#xD;
T. Kristensen, S. Struck: Organic dairy cow feeding with emphasis on Danish conditions &#xD;
W.F. Knaus, A. Steinwidder, W. Zollitsch: Energy and protein balance in organic dairy cow nutrition model calculations based on EU regulations&#xD;
B. NIELSEN, S.M. THAMSBORG: Organic beef production with emphasis on feeding and health of dairy bred bull calves&#xD;
Knud Erik Bach Knudsen: Influence of feed and feed structure on disease and welfare of pigs &#xD;
A. SUNDRUM: Managing amino acids in organic pig diets &#xD;
A. Walker, S. Gordon:  Nutrition issues in organic poultry systems &#xD;
M. Hovi, A. Sundrum: Discussion report: Feeding for health and welfare &#xD;
&#xD;
Part C: Posters and additional papers&#xD;
&#xD;
K. Bazeley, A. Hibbert, G. Anderson: The measurement of quality of stockmans hip for dairy farm assurance schemes&#xD;
A. Martini, A., Giorgetti, D. Rondina, C. Sargentini, R. Bozzi, M. Moretti, C. Pérez Torrecillas, R. Funghi, M. Lucifero: The Maremmana, a rustic breed ideal for organic production. Experimental experiences&#xD;
G. Smolder:s Growth and development of young stock on organic dairy farms &#xD;
M. Plomp: Feeding of dairy cattle on organic farms in the Netherlands &#xD;
&#xD;
List of Delegates</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Baars, Ton</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/876/1/hovi-2001-4thNAHWOA-proceedings.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hovi, Malla and Baars, Ton (Eds.)    (2001) Breeding and feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems (4th NAHWOA Workshop).    . Proceedings of NAHWOA: Network for Animal Health and Welfare in Organic Agriculture, Wageningen, Netherlands, 24-27 March 2001.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/876/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>