<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving control of storage diseases on apple by combining biological and physical post-harvest methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vorstermans, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Laer, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Creemers, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jijakli, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pujos, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Post-harvest non-chemical treatments consists of a large range of different approaches,&#xD;
including strengthening of the commodity’s natural defence mechanisms, thermotherapy,&#xD;
application of antagonistic microorganisms and natural antimicrobial substances.&#xD;
NEX0101 is a promising antagonistic biocontrol agent containing the yeast Candida&#xD;
oleophila as the active ingredient. NEX0101 was developed by Bionext, a spin-off from the&#xD;
laboratory of Dr. H. Jijakli, and is currently evaluated for commercial use. The product&#xD;
contains a yeast strain isolated from apple fruit and was originally developed for the control&#xD;
of post-harvest diseases on apple. The antifungal effectiveness of this antagonist can be&#xD;
increased by addition of calcium salts. As the mode of action of this yeast is based on the&#xD;
colonisation of wounds, the mean targets of NEX0101 are blue mould, caused by&#xD;
Penicillium expansum, and grey mould, caused by Botrytis cinerea. Facing possible latent&#xD;
infections, thermotherapy by using hot water treatments could provide an advanced control&#xD;
towards lenticelrot (Gloeosporium spp.). A combination of both physical and biological&#xD;
treatment techniques could broaden the spectrum to all key pathogens on apple and pear.&#xD;
The use of NEX0101 for the control of P. expansum was examined in combination with&#xD;
calcium gluconate. According to the results the combination NEX0101 with calcium&#xD;
gluconate provides an advanced mould control towards P. expansum The best results&#xD;
were achieved using NEX0101 in combination with post-harvest dipping by thermotherapy.&#xD;
The hot water treatment alone was clearly inefficient towards wound parasite P.&#xD;
expansum, on the contrary thermotherapy stimulates the decay caused by this postharvest&#xD;
pathogen. For the future a combination of biological and physical treatments could offer a&#xD;
worthy non-chemical alternative for organic and integrated fruit growers towards fruit rot&#xD;
decay, although more research is necessary to implement these methods in practice.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13667/1/172-176.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vorstermans, B.; Van Laer, S.; Creemers, P.; Jijakli, H. and Pujos, P.    (2008) Improving control of storage diseases on apple by combining biological and physical post-harvest methods.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 172-176.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13667/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>