<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of soil structure using participatory methods in the semiarid region of Brazil.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Araújo, Ana Leônia de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oliveira, Renato Teixeira de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferreira, Tiago Osório</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romero, Ricardo Espíndola</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conservation practices are important in improving the environmental protection of agroecosystems in semiarid regions, as these are considered to be fragile environments. Soil-quality indicators are useful elements in evaluating the impact of some agricultural management practices, and the use of recognized indicators which are able to be measured by farmers is an innovative approach that seeks to integrate both scientific and local knowledge. This study aimed to evaluate the impact of various management practices through indicators of soil quality related to soil structure, in areas of family farming where agroecological consortiums are employed. These indicators were identified as important by the farmers themselves, and methodologies were suggested for field application by the farmers, which were later compared to applications made in the laboratory. The indicators used were penetration resistance of the soil and stability and dispersion of aggregates for areas of agroecological consortium and natural vegetation. It can be concluded that agroecological consortia contribute to the conservation of soil structure and that the involvement of farmers plays an important role in developing research.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-01-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28501/1/Ara%C3%BAjo_evaluation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Araújo, Ana Leônia de; Oliveira, Renato Teixeira de; Ferreira, Tiago Osório and Romero, Ricardo Espíndola   (2013) Evaluation of soil structure using participatory methods in the semiarid region of Brazil.  [Avaliação da estrutura do solo utilizando métodos participatórios na região semiárida brasileira.]  Revista Ciência Agronômica, 44 (3), pp. 411-418.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28501/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>