<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performance of wheat composite crosses on station and on-farm</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heinrich, Sven</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brumlop, Sarah</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The F11 of 14 winter wheat composite cross populations (CCPs) were compared in replicated field trials to the mixture of the 20 parents and three commercial wheat cultivars in replicated field trials. In addition, one population was given to farmers for on-farm testing. In 2012 severe frost killed 16 out of the 20 parental varieties of the CCPs. In contrast, the mixture of these varieties and the CCP populations survived well. The CCPs with high yielding parents yielded still highest in the F12 and quality in the CCPs with high quality parents was highest. CCPs on-farm were comparable in performance with farmers reference varieties.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Chable, Véronique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goldringer, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Howlett, Sally</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Barberi, Paolo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miko, P</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mendes-Moreira, P</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rakszegi, M</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ostergaard, H</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Borgen, Anders</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pedersen, T</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bocci, Riccardo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28192/1/finckh-etal-2014-SolibamFinalCongress-book-of-abstract-p107-108.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Finckh, Maria R.; Heinrich, Sven and Brumlop, Sarah    (2014) Performance of wheat composite crosses on station and on-farm.   In: Chable, Véronique; Goldringer, I.; Howlett, Sally; Barberi, Paolo; Miko, P; Mendes-Moreira, P; Rakszegi, M; Ostergaard, H; Borgen, Anders; Finckh, Maria R.; Pedersen, T and Bocci, Riccardo (Eds.)  Diversity strategies for organic and low systems. Book of abstracts of SOLIBAM final congress, Nantes, 7-9 July 2014, pp. 107-108.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28192/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>