<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CH-FARMIS 2.0: A Sector-Model to Assess the Economic and Environmental Impacts of Swiss Direct Payment Schemes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nic</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Quantitative sector models are an essential tool to forecast the sector-wide economic effects of agricultural policies. However, to cover ecological effects with economic sector models is still a methodological challenge. This poster describes a promising approach, which is currently implemented at the Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) to meet this challenge.&#xD;
CH-FARMIS is a sector consistent farm group model, which is able to forecast economic impacts of policies on farm, regional and sector-level. In a flexible way, CH-FARMIS is able to split up the farm sector in farm groups according to various characteristics (region, farming system, farm type, etc.). CH-FARMIS is based on positive mathematical programming (PMP) to allow for a realistic reproduction of the Swiss agricultural sector. Currently, CH-FARMIS is augmented in two ways in order to illustrate the environmental impacts of farmers’ decisions and land use: Firstly, intensity levels of farm production are introduced. Secondly, all farm activities and their intensity levels are equipped with ecological indicators, which are derived from LCA data. In an iterative Delphi-procedure, polling a set of competence teams, the LCA data is adapted to the model needs and transposed from farm level to sector level. The following indicators will be implemented in CH-FARMIS 2.0: Biodiversity, water contamination (N, P) and energy use.&#xD;
The enlarged version of CH-FARMIS will be a flexible tool which can be used for both exante assessments of policy reforms and the quantitative evaluation of single direct payments. CH-FARMIS 2.0 is planned to be operable in mid 2008.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL), CH-Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13401/1/schader-etal-2006-Poster_CH-Farmis.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schader, Christian; Sanders, Jürn; Lampkin, Nic and Stolze, Matthias    (2006) CH-FARMIS 2.0: A Sector-Model to Assess the Economic and Environmental Impacts of Swiss Direct Payment Schemes.       Poster at:   Symposium on Farmers' Decisions, Land Use and Environmental Impact, Zürich, University Zürich, Department of Geography, SIE, 18 October 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13401/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>