<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Werte ökologischer Lebensmittel: Anforderungen an eine erfolgreiche Kommunikation mit Verbrauchern</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a world where more and more organic products are mass produced, and where most consumers have little – if any – contact with the organic farmers who have produced their food, many people feel that the underlying principles of the organic movement are coming under increasing threat. According to our research consumers are mostly interested in additional ethical attributes like “higher animal welfare standards”, “regional/local production” and “fair producer prices” and they are willing to pay more for products which are produced following these higher standards. This gives producers the opportunity to differentiate their products in the organic market. When communicating these additional ethical attributes of organic food producers must take care to use a wording in accordance with their customers’ comprehension in order to build up and sustain a trustful producer-consumer-relationship.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17424/3/Zander_17424.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hamm, Ulrich and Zander, Katrin    (2011) Werte ökologischer Lebensmittel: Anforderungen an eine erfolgreiche Kommunikation mit Verbrauchern.  [Values of organic food: how to communicate successfully!]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17424/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>