<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Possibilities and limitations of protein supply in organic poultry and pig production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Dr. Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Diplo. Biologe Uwe</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic poultry and pig production has to face severe restrictions in the availability of feedstuffs of high quality protein. The objective of the project was to assess by meta-analysis of the literature whether the restrictions can be compensated by others measures without jeopardizing the goal of a high level of product- and process-related quality. &#xD;
Calculations showed that, in general, it is possible to formulate diets for poultry and pigs without the use of non-organic feedstuffs. However, there is a huge variation between farms on the local, regional or national level in their ability to provide organic diets. Several measures are outlined that are at the organic farmer's disposal to adapt to the restricted availability of high protein feedstuffs. &#xD;
The risk of the occurrence of diseases and welfare problems in organic livestock production due to suboptimal nutrient provision by the farmer is compa-rably low, and can be handled by a proper manage-ment. Intensification of meat production, however, encloses a system-related increase in the risks of animal health disorders. From the animal health and welfare point of view, organic farming should be protected towards the negative side effects of an intensified meat production by setting limits with respect to the intensification process.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7346/1/7346_EC_Revision.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert; Schneider, Dr. Kerstin and Richter, Diplo. Biologe Uwe    (2006) Possibilities and limitations of protein supply in organic poultry and pig production.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7346/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>