<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ursachen einer geringen Akzeptanz für den Einsatz von Bioprodukten im Schweizer Außer-Haus-Verzehr</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hofmann, Ruth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Dr. Toralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Even Switzerland is the country with the highest per capita consumption rate of organic products in Europe, the penetration rate of organic products in the hospitality sector is still low in comparison with countries like Germany, France or Italy. The objective of the study is to analyse the reasons behind. The analysis bases on an empirical study in the Swiss hospitality sector in 2004. The results indicate a lack of benefits caused by the content and implementation of various competing label programs. Therefore the authors suggest to merge the different label approaches for organic products in the hospitality sector to a common strong Swiss label program for organic and regional produced food.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3720/1/3720.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hofmann, Ruth and Richter, Dr. Toralf    (2005) Ursachen einer geringen Akzeptanz für den Einsatz von Bioprodukten im Schweizer Außer-Haus-Verzehr.  [Reasons for the low acceptance of organic products in the Swiss hospitality sector.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3720/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>