<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Codling moth populations less susceptible to CpGV: What about higher concentrations?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Triloff, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In an organic orchard with a codling moth (CM) population less susceptible to CpGV it was tested,&#xD;
whether an increased dosage of CpGV by factor 10 would result in any increased efficacy.&#xD;
The applications were set in shorter than weekly intervals with 10 ml/ha Madex (low dosage plot)&#xD;
and 100 ml/ha Madex (high dosage plot). The higher dosage showed also a better efficacy, especially&#xD;
on the “active damage” (live larvae).&#xD;
The orchard where the experiments were conducted was known to have a less susceptible CM&#xD;
population (2004) although there were no serious CM problems reported by the farmer despite the&#xD;
CM control was done only with CpGV. It was investigated, whether natural antagonists might have&#xD;
been a reason for the absence of serious problems in this orchard. No signs of a strong presence of&#xD;
other antagonists were found but CM the population was increasing very much in the year the experiment&#xD;
was conducted (2005). Thus, probably the reason for the absence of CM problems seems&#xD;
to be just a delayed increase of the CM population after the development of a lower susceptibility of&#xD;
CM against CpGV.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13758/1/ecofruit_12th_3.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.; Triloff, P. and Zebitz, C.P.W.    (2006) Codling moth populations less susceptible to CpGV: What about higher concentrations?  [Minderempfindlichkeit des Apfelwicklers gegenüber CpGV: Kann durch eine Erhöhung der Aufwandmenge die Wirksamkeit verbessert werden?]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 25-29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13758/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>