<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New market perspectives using herbs and berries in organic&#xD;
meat products</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the project is to extend the range of organic meat products by introducing new interesting flavour variants. The novelty is to utilize herbs and berries for biological preservation and to provide the products with a new and interesting flavour profile and appearance. The project is consumerdriven as MAPP will study how ecological consumers relate to a new preservation technology in the form of berries and herbs. They will also study how the consumers relate to the new products by evaluations and when buying the products. Among Danish berries and herbs, AU-IHP will select and produce the cultivars which are to be screened at DMRI for anti-microbial activity and favourable flavour characteristics in meat products. Furthermore, AU-IHP will optimize cultivation and storage conditions, preserving the desired characteristics after harvest in the best possible way. DMRI will combine the selected berries and herbs to obtain the best result. The work includes an investigation of how berries and herbs should be added to the meat products and it must be clarified how different raw materials and meat processing affect the anti-microbial activity. The results from DMRI will be validated at test productions at the two participating plants. Finally, we will document that the selected berries and herbs can guarantee food safety and favourable eating quality throughout the entire shelf-life. Economic estimates for total production costs will be made.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19603/1/BerryMeat_application.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    BERRYMEAT: New market perspectives using herbs and berries in organic meat products.  [Nye markedsmuligheder med krydderier og bær i økologiske kødprodukter.]   Runs 2011 - 2013.      Project Leader(s): Hansen, Flemming, The Danish Technological Institute - DMRI.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19603/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>