<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>STANDARDS AND COMPLIANCE SYSTEMS FOR ORGANIC AND BIO-DYNAMIC AGRICULTURE&#xD;
IN AUSTRALIA:PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wynen, Els</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Australia does not yet have standards for organic and bio-dynamic produce for the domestic market, although there are standards for exports. Recently, there has been a move towards the establishment and adoption of standards for the domestic market. Debate has centred on which organisation would be most suitable to host such standards. An important issue was the acceptability of the final standards to the Government, so that it would be willing to legalise the word ‘organic’ according to those standards. Other issues of concern were ownership of and control over the standards, copyright, compliance with the standards, and costs of developing and maintaining standards. Given the requirements identified by the industry as being of importance, the process of Standards Australia, an independent, not-for-profit body recognised by the Australian Government as the national standard-setting body overseeing the establishment of an Australian Standard appears to be the best option. The important requirement of industry ownership seems secure, while government regulation – facilitating compliance enforcement - is likely to follow with government acceptance of the process by which the Australian Standards are being established. In addition, the cost of this process will be significantly lower than that of the existing process with the National Standard.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Macgregor, Neil</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hill, Stuart</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13238/1/13238.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wynen, Els   (2007) STANDARDS AND COMPLIANCE SYSTEMS FOR ORGANIC AND BIO-DYNAMIC AGRICULTURE IN AUSTRALIA:PAST, PRESENT AND FUTURE.   Journal of Organic Systems, 2 (2), pp. 38-55.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13238/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>