<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Approaches and achievements of biodynamic vegetable breeding by Kultursaat e.V. (Germany) using the example of RODELIKA one of the first certified biodynamic varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fleck, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 1998 RODELIKA is officially registered as a newly bred carrot variety. It had been developed by positive mass-selection over a 13 year period, based on an old-established variety within a farm based biodynamic system. The goal was a fine root with good health and a focus on taste and ability of maturation. Thus a selection-scheme in organoleptic characteristics sweetness and aroma was created. Numerous investigations demonstrate the very high inner quality of RODELIKA. Property rights of this open-pollinated variety are held by the charitable association Kultursaat eV as a common heritage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16513/1/santafe09.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fleck, M.    (2009) Approaches and achievements of biodynamic vegetable breeding by Kultursaat e.V. (Germany) using the example of RODELIKA one of the first certified biodynamic varieties.  [Wege, Ziele und Errungenschaften der biologisch-dynamischen Gemüsezüchtung von Kultursaat e.V. am Beispiel von RODELIKA, einer der ersten Möhrensorte aus zertifiziert biologisch-dynamischer Züchtung.]      Paper at:   1st International IFOAM-Conference on Animal and Plant Breeding, Santa Fe, New Mexico, USA, 25. - 28.08.2009.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16513/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>