<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A continuous labelling approach to recover photosynthetically fixed carbon in plant tissue and rhizosphere organisms of young beech trees (Fagus sylvatica L.) using 13C depleted CO2</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Esperschütz, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buegger, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lang, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Munch, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schloter, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winkler, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A continuous labelling experiment using 13C-CO2 was set up in open-top chambers in order to follow fluxes of assimilates from the plant into the rhizosphere. Labelling was performed for one growing season by adding low amounts of CO2 depleted in 13C to the atmosphere of the open-top chambers, resulting in a difference of ∆ 13C 5‰ V-PDB compared to ambient conditions. The label was recovered in both plant parts and soil microbial communities, analysed via phospholipid fatty acid (PLFA) side chains. PLFA 18:2ω6,9 showed a significant incorporation of the 13C label in October, indicating that fungi utilized plant derived carbon. In bacterial PLFA no label incorporation was detected, probably due to a lower use of rhizodeposits or a preference to older carbon compounds as energy sources. This experimental setup represents a low-cost continuous labelling method for field experiments with only minor increase of CO2 concentrations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26374/1/Esperschuetz_etal_2009_PS323.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Esperschütz, J.; Gattinger, A.; Buegger, F.; Lang, H.; Munch, J.; Schloter, M. and Winkler, J.   (2009) A continuous labelling approach to recover photosynthetically fixed carbon in plant tissue and rhizosphere organisms of young beech trees (Fagus sylvatica L.) using 13C depleted CO2.   Plant and Soil, 323 (1-2), pp. 21-29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26374/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>