<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Arbeitszeitbedarf für die Bewirtschaftung von Milchviehausläufen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schick, Dr. Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Riegel, Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartmann, Dr. Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klöble, Dr. Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As existing figures on working-time requirements for outdoor runs in cattle husbandry are often out of date or insufficiently detailed for individual use and in particular as few reliable work-economics data are available for ecological forms of farming, figures on working-time requirements and influencing variables for dung removal and spreading of litter in outdoor runs in cattle and pig farming were recorded as a subproject within the framework of the KTBL-KU 2005 project. This report presents the results for dairy cattle husbandry. The calculations are based on an outdoor run area of 6 m2 per cow. Each outdoor run cleaning operation takes between 0.1 and 1.3 MPmin per cow, depending on the method used and the herd size. If the run is spread with litter, these tasks take between 0.1 and 0.7 MPmin per operation per cow. The working time requirement for outdoor run maintenance breaks down into the sub-tasks of cleaning, spreading of litter (if carried out) and, depending on the method, inspection (scraper). Major savings can be expected from process and organisational optimisation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9713/1/9713_Schick_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schick, Dr. Matthias; Riegel, Marion; Hartmann, Dr. Wilfried and Klöble, Dr. Ulrike    (2007) Arbeitszeitbedarf für die Bewirtschaftung von Milchviehausläufen.  [Working-time requirement for outdoor runs in dairy cattle husbandry.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9713/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>