<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Field applications of entomopathogenic fungi against Rhagoletis cerasi</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two myco-insecticides, Naturalis-L (Beauveria bassiana) and PreFeRal®WG&#xD;
(Paecilomyces fumosoroseus), were applied against adult R. cerasi (Diptera: Tephritidae)&#xD;
in two orchards in north-western Switzerland in summer 2006. Both products were applied&#xD;
at a concentration of 5.75x104 CFU / ml. With four applications at seven day intervals the&#xD;
whole flight period of R. cerasi was fully covered. During this period (5th June – 6th July)&#xD;
the temperature averaged 19.2°C, total precipitation was 60 mm. Under these conditions&#xD;
Naturalis-L significantly reduced the number of damaged fruit (efficacy: 69-74%), whereas&#xD;
damage was not significantly reduced with PreFeRal®WG (efficacy: 27%). Fungus&#xD;
infested flies were found on the yellow sticky traps proving that the myco-insecticides&#xD;
worked as predicted.&#xD;
Climatic conditions were different in 2007: temperature averaged 15.9°C (16th May – 4th&#xD;
July), total precipitation was 281 mm. In 2007 only Naturalis-L was tested: with five&#xD;
applications an efficacy of 73% and 78% was obtained on the cherry varieties Langstieler&#xD;
and Dolleseppler, respectively. However, for the latest ripening and most infested variety&#xD;
Schauenburger only an efficacy of 18% was observed. In these cherries a high number of&#xD;
young larvae were found indicating that the efficacy was low at the end of the treatment&#xD;
period. In conclusion a control of R. cerasi with myco-insecticides seems possible.&#xD;
However, application regime still has to be improved and should not only be adapted to the&#xD;
flight period of R. cerasi, but also to the cherry varieties.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13650/1/087-092.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, C. and Wyss, E.    (2008) Field applications of entomopathogenic fungi against Rhagoletis cerasi.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 87-92.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13650/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>