<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Developing an Agro-forestry System for Production of a Commercial Organic Chicken Flock Focusing on Profits on a ‘Triple Bottom Line’</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aspray, Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O'Brien, Josie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Philipps, Lois</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In most modern free-range poultry systems birds do not fully utilise the range provided. Knowledge of the ancestral history of the domestic chicken, combined with research observations suggests benefits of agro-forestry systems for chickens. A commercial organic poultry agro-forestry system was developed for Sheepdrove Organic Farm, Berkshire, UK, affording the benefits of an agro-forestry system, whilst retaining commercial viability.  Five avenues of highly diverse parallel hedges incorporating tree, shrub and herb species were planted. On-going monitoring of the system was put in place to evaluate its development.  The programme consists of monitoring: 1) biodiversity 2) soil nutrient status and respiration 3) behaviour and welfare of the poultry.  Conventionally profits tend to be viewed purely in terms of economic gain.  However in an organic farm-ing system more emphasis is placed on the intrinsic and sustainable qualities it has.  Organic farming adopts a holistic approach to profit, viewing it in environmental, social and economic terms. The profits afforded by the agro-forestry system are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7436/1/Denmark_Conf_Agroforestry.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7436/2/7436_OBrien.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aspray, Claire; O'Brien, Josie and Philipps, Lois    (2006) Developing an Agro-forestry System for Production of a Commercial Organic Chicken Flock Focusing on Profits on a ‘Triple Bottom Line’.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7436/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>