<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Agriculture Programming for Sustainability in Primary sector of India: Action and Adoption</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, Arun K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Programming generally used in computer science that interrelate all the  components   such a way so that not only it proved  to be use friendly but also  fast in execution. &#xD;
Same concept is taken in this paper about organic farming (OF)  by including all the components i.e. basic ideology of  OF, including all the components i.e. primary industry , relation of OF with social ( food security),economical(self sustainable)and  environmental issues ( climate resilience), infrastructure of  knowledge, research market and policy support and acceptance. These all factors used in programming for promotion of OF in India with projection of  converting 50% country into OF within 5 years. A separate planning also suggested for  rainfed and irrigated area.&#xD;
It can be a status paper for all who are interested in policy making, production, research, marketing , social development ,environmental conservation with organic farming not only in India but also several parts of the world.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-07-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26657/12/26657.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sharma, Arun K.   (2014) Organic Agriculture Programming for Sustainability in Primary sector of India: Action and Adoption.   Productivity, 55 (1), pp. 1-17.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26657/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>