<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farmers for Nature - Wildlife-friendly Organic Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Malikova, Alena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dytrtova, Karolina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capounova, Katerina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meindl, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfiffner, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This project was one of 79 projects supported under the first open call under the Czech NGO Fund, financed by Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway. During the celebration meeting in June 24th, 2008 with Norwegian Embassy, this project was selected for public presentation as one of the best ones in the category of Environment Protection.&#xD;
The year 2008 was successful regarding the growing interest among organic farmers (11 new farms have joined the project), increasing number of participants in regular spring seminar (52 participants), PR activities (30 media references) and capacity building for Bioinstitut´s team (2 new co-workers were employed) were performed. The project was very well accepted not only among farmers, for whom it is primarily intended, but also by state authorities and the wider public. The Ministries of Agriculture and the Environment value our work to develop model farms, which should in the future be able to serve as practical examples of landscape conservation management in the Czech Republic. Our activities have significantly contributed that the valuable area of Letní stráň is set under protection until the year 2016 in the Přemyslovské Sedlo area of the Jeseník Mts. (northward in Moravia region near Šumperk).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FiBL Switzerland, FiBL Austria, Bioinstitut Czech Republic</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20196/1/ProgressReport_2008_CZ_A.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Malikova, Alena; Dytrtova, Karolina; Capounova, Katerina; Meindl, Peter and Pfiffner, Lukas         (2008) Organic Farmers for Nature - Wildlife-friendly Organic Production.    FiBL Switzerland, FiBL Austria, Bioinstitut Czech Republic.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20196/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>