<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen von Weizen (Triticum aestivum L.) mit den drei Bildschaffenden Methoden Kupferchloridkristallisation, Steigbildmethode und Rundfilterchromatographie</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fritz, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Athmann, Miriam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ten encoded wheat samples from 2008 were taken from a field trial on the comparison of different organic and conventional production systems at Hennef, Germany. The samples were examined with the image forming methods biocrystallization, capillary dynamolysis and circular chromatography. The images of the encoded samples were a) characterised and b) assigned to experimental factors. The factors investigated were i) nitrogen supply, ii) fertilizer type, and iii) horn silica application. The ten samples were assigned 100% correctly to low and high N supply. Within the production methods, samples were assigned correctly to mineral fertilization and manure fertilization.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21637/1/21637_fritz.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fritz, Jürgen; Athmann, Miriam and Köpke, Ulrich    (2013) Untersuchungen von Weizen (Triticum aestivum L.) mit den drei Bildschaffenden Methoden Kupferchloridkristallisation, Steigbildmethode und Rundfilterchromatographie.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>