<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Blattlaus- und Erbsenwicklerbefall in Wintererbsen-Reinsaaten: Ein Vergleich zu Sommererbsen-Reinsaaten und Wintererbsen-Mischsaaten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gronle, Annkathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The infestation of peas by aphids and moths was assessed in winter pea sole crops and compared to spring pea sole and winter pea-triticale intercrops. The field experiments were conducted in Northern Germany in the growing seasons 2009-2011. The maximum number of pea aphids per plant and the percentage of attacked plants were lower in semi-leafless and normal-leafed winter pea sole crops than in semi-leafless spring peas. Pea moth larvae damaged 6-32 % of seeds in winter peas and 40-55 % of seeds in spring peas. Winter pea-triticale intercropping reduced the attack of pea aphids, whereas no beneficial effect of intercropping was observed concerning moth-damaged peas. Owing to the earlier maturity, winter peas were less susceptible to pea pest attacks than spring peas. Winter-pea intercropping is a partially effective method for pest control in peas.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21332/1/21332_Gronle.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gronle, Annkathrin and Böhm, Herwart    (2013) Blattlaus- und Erbsenwicklerbefall in Wintererbsen-Reinsaaten: Ein Vergleich zu Sommererbsen-Reinsaaten und Wintererbsen-Mischsaaten.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21332/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>