<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative Study of Consumers’ Perceptions and Attitudes to Organic Agricultural Products in Bulgaria and Romania</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vassileva, Elka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivanova, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Botezat, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tomescu, Ada-Mirela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the paper is to describe the perceptions and attitudes to organic products of a particular set of potential consumers in Bulgaria and Romania. Quality analysis according to the method of “focus groups” was used. The results obtained from the four focus groups conducted in Bulgaria and the two focus groups in Romania during the period April – May 2007 were analysed.&#xD;
Within this comparative study the different associations which potential consumers in Bulgaria and Romania have for organic foods come to the fore. The willingness of participants in the focus groups to pay a higher price for organic foods, related to the greater added value due to their ecological method of production and healthy effect is discusses. It was established that the groups of organic foods preferred by the Bulgarian and Romanian participants in the focus groups are one and the same. The insignificant differences are due to the eating habits in the two countries.&#xD;
All respondents, irrespective of their nationality confirm the necessity for a special label for organic products. The reasons for this are: facilitating customer’s choice; differentiation from other products (easy recognition and identification); information to consumers; guarantee for the organic origin and quality of the foods; information and promotion of organic foods.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Korean Academy of Commodity Science &amp; Technology (KACST)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lee, Yong-Hak</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Shin, Hojung</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-08-18</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17038/8/16_IGWT_Korea_Organic_BG_RO_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vassileva, Elka; Ivanova, Daniela; Botezat, Elena and Tomescu, Ada-Mirela    (2008) Comparative Study of Consumers’ Perceptions and Attitudes to Organic Agricultural Products in Bulgaria and Romania.  [Сравнително изследване на потребителските възприятия и отношения към биологичните селскостопански продукти в България и Румъния.]  In: Lee, Yong-Hak and Shin, Hojung (Eds.)  The 16th Symposium of IGWT - Achieving Commodity &amp; Service Excellence in the Age of Digital Convergence - Proceedings, Korean Academy of Commodity Science &amp; Technology (KACST), Suwon, Korea, Vol. 1, pp. 376-380.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17038/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>