<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Shaping professional identity for sustainability. Evidence in Finnish public catering</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Catering for sustainability is often presented as a legitimate perspective for caterers to promote more&#xD;
equitable economic development locally and across distances through food procurement, integrated&#xD;
with environmental protection and concern for thewelfare of customers and staff. Caterers are thus seen&#xD;
as agents responsible for sustainable food systems within their reach. This paper explores how public&#xD;
caterers use their position and productive intelligence in promoting a sustainable food system within the&#xD;
power field of their contextual networks. This article crystallises this ‘agency for sustainability’ as&#xD;
professional identity for sustainability, the shaping of which is analysed in Finnish public catering. The&#xD;
paper identifies eased and positive, troubled and critical as well as delimited and distancing approaches&#xD;
for sustainability, with respective views and efforts for sustainable food systems. The shaping of&#xD;
professional identity for sustainability could serve as co-operative platform for future contextual&#xD;
developments towards more sustainable food systems. Such progress could result in better alignment&#xD;
with political guidelines for sustainability and caterers’ satisfaction due to their heightened professional&#xD;
position reaching beyond ‘kitchen walls’ to construct everyday sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17146/1/Mikkola2009Appetite.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkola, Minna   (2009) Shaping professional identity for sustainability. Evidence in Finnish public catering.   Appetite, 53, pp. 56-65.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17146/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>