<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Variations in the composition of the major elements of wheat varieties in industrial and organic farming systems: initial results</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>PIQUET, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>SAUVAT, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BRANLARD, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A nutritional analysis was added to the study of the characterization of wheat varieties in organic and industrial farming systems for the year 2005-2006. The experimental design consisted of three wheat varieties (Atrium, Ataro and Renan) and three densities (200, 400 and 600 grains/m2) on two soils representative of the Auvergne region. The parameters studied were productivity, technological suitability and nutritional value (N, P, K, Ca, Mg). The yield was particularly low for organic farming (23 q/ha), following unfavorable climatic conditions. In spite of the low yield under organic farming conditions, the Mg and P contents in the grains were normal. The low thousand-grain weight and the early maturity of Atrium did not make it possible to increase the nutritional density of the grains in 2006. These results must be confirmed so that we can propose a typology of varieties with high nutritional density linked to cropping practices and the environment. This typology will be used to make breads that are beneficial to our health.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15484/1/26-Piquet.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>PIQUET, A. ; SAUVAT, S.  and BRANLARD, G.    (2009) Variations in the composition of the major elements of wheat varieties in industrial and organic farming systems: initial results.  [Variations de la composition en éléments majeurs de variétés de blé conduites en modes biologique et conventionnel : premiers résultats.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 197-201.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15484/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>