<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Concepts for a multi-criteria sustainability assessment of a new more biobased economy in rural production landscapes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, Tommy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Uffe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, I.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gylling, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dejgaard, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubgaard, Alex</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turner, K.G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christen, Ben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, P.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study presents a new approach to model the biophysical potentials for increased biomass harvest in Denmark, and a multi-criteria sustainability assessment of the socio-economic and environmental effects of different scenarios for such increased production and new biobased economy in rural landscapes. Thereby the results serve as input to the ongoing productivism – post-productivism debate related to rural spaces in Europe.&#xD;
Empirical results from a case study of large scale conversion to biorefenery technologies, aiming to increase the total Danish harvest of biomass by 10 million tonnes via the conversion to new types of crop production and land management, is used as an example, and will be related to the common conceptual model presented by the workshop convenors, and a so called “Traffic-light” multi-criteria sustainability assessment scheme introduced and exemplified in the present paper. The aim is to contextualize how the problems in relation to the concrete scenario results can be considered with the landscape as the meeting basis, and used as input for a discussion of innovative models for future farming systems, landscape research and management.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Aarhus Universisty</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21222/4/21222.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dalgaard, Tommy; Jørgensen, Uffe; Kristensen, I.T.; Gylling, M.; Dejgaard, J.; Dubgaard, Alex; Kjeldsen, Chris; Hermansen, J.E.; Turner, K.G.; Christen, Ben and Andersen, P.S.    (2012) Concepts for a multi-criteria sustainability assessment of a new more biobased economy in rural production landscapes.       Paper at:   International Farming Systems Association Conference, Aarhus, Denmark, July 1-4.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21222/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>