<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results of an experiment on storage diseases at the apple variety Pinova</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barbara, Pfeiffer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Tema-Extrakt, a yeast preparation, FZB 24 (Bacillus subtilis) and a malt extract were prooled on their suitability for control 01 storage diseases in autumn 2000 in an organic orchard at Lake Konstanz. The preparations were sprayed three times belore harvest on the apple variety 'Pinova'. In December 2000, February 2001 and at the end 01 March 2001 the decay through Gloeosporium was evaluated. At the end 01 March in the control only 12 % 01 the Iruits were without or with only very weak symptoms. The best treatment were malt-extract (23%) and Bacillus subti/is (24 % in the lowest classes 01 disease). But the efficiency is too weak to advise this preparations lor organic Iruit growers. Attention should be payed in the orchards on the kind 01 growing of the trees, how long it lasts, unti! the trees drie up, and especially on the sources 01 inlections on the wood.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14599/1/pfeiffer_58.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barbara, Pfeiffer    (2002) Results of an experiment on storage diseases at the apple variety Pinova.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 58-62.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14599/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>