<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effects of different cattle manure levels and branch management methods on organic production of Cucurbita pepo L.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jahan, Instructor Mohsen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koocheki, Professor Alireza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nassiri Mahallati, Associated Prof. Mehdi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dehghanipur, Instructor Forugh</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To study the effects of different manure levels and two branch management methods on organic production of Schneider squash, a field experiment was conducted during 2005 and 2006. Treatments were four manure levels (10, 15, 20, 25 ton ha-1) and two branch management methods (with and without a wood pole), which were allocated to main plots and subplots, respectively. Results showed that the crop performed better in branch management without a wood pole than with a wood pole. Results showed that in the first year, manure level had a significant effect on fruit and seed yields. However, these traits were not significantly affected by manure levels in the second year. For both years, there were no differences in seed numbers due to manure levels. Seed oil content was slightly increased when the manure level was increased from 10 to 25 ton ha-1.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11437/1/Jahan_11437_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jahan, Instructor Mohsen; Koocheki, Professor Alireza; Nassiri Mahallati, Associated Prof. Mehdi and Dehghanipur, Instructor Forugh    (2008) The effects of different cattle manure levels and branch management methods on organic production of Cucurbita pepo L.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11437/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>