<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Similarity of technical logics of cropping systems organization between conventional and recently converted organic farmers in a water catchment area</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gratecap, J.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wezel, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casagrande, Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martin, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is considered as a solution to preserve water quality in drinking water catchments. For local managers of these catchments it is thus important to identify conventional farmers for potential conversion to organic farming. The aim of this article is to assess technical similarity of conventional farmers concerned by a water catchment to organic farming. We build a typology of farmers based on technical logics related to cropping systems organization. We differentiated five types of farmers among 18 conventional dairy farmers and three recently converted organic farmers. According to our results, only two farmers can be considered as close to technical logics identified in organic farms. Nevertheless, we could identify partial technical similarities for two other farmer groups. These similarities may be useful for catchment managers to initiate transitions towards organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26278/1/Gratecap_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gratecap, J.B.; Wezel, A.; Casagrande, Marion and Martin, P.   (2013) Similarity of technical logics of cropping systems organization between conventional and recently converted organic farmers in a water catchment area.  [Une typologie d’agriculteurs pour étudier les proximités techniques à l’agriculture biologique à l’échelle d’une zone à enjeu eau.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 509-524.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26278/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>