<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Study and assessment of organic potato production in relation to fertilization and varietal  aspect</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>FARES, Roula</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The adaptation of potato (Solanum tuberosum) under organic farming is an object of several important researches worldwide. To evaluate potato adaptation under organic farming in Lebanon, the performances of the mostly used three varieties, Remarka, Spunta and Folva, were compared in correlation to 2 fertilizers, an on-farm compost and commercial one (Siforga). A  fertilized control was also used. A Split Plot Design with three replicates was applied. The measured parameters were germination rate, resistance to pathogens, yield, quality control and panel test. Remarka gave the best performances under both the commercial and the on-farm compost: high germination (100%), high resistance to the bacteria Erwinia carotovora and to the fungus Rhizoctonia sp., high yield (13.12 t ha-1), and showed to be good for both French fries and grill, while as Folva and Spunta had different behaviour under the three fertilizations, giving fair performances</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6675/1/RoulaFares03.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>FARES, Roula   (2003) Study and assessment of organic potato production in relation to fertilization and varietal aspect.  [Etude et évaluation de la production biologique de la pomme de terre en relation avec la fertilisation et l’aspect variétal.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Tesi Master of Science, no. 325. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6675/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>