<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results from scab trials with Armicarb in the years 2006 and 2007</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pfeiffer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organically cultivated orchards of the LVWO Weinsberg in the years 2006 and 2007&#xD;
trials were carried out about new products and their efficacy against apple scab. In the&#xD;
year 2006 (variety ‘Gala’) Armicarb and BioPluss sprayed preventively during primary&#xD;
ascospore season could not convince, also not in combination with lime sulphur as stopapplication.&#xD;
Armicarb showed at ‘Gala’ a tendency to increase russetting of the fruits. In&#xD;
the year 2007 (Variety ‘Elstar’) different combinations of wetting sulphur with yuccasaponin&#xD;
and stop-applications (lime sulphur, Armicarb) were tested with focus on the time&#xD;
immediately after blossom. The effect of Armicarb as stop-application was weaker than of&#xD;
lime sulphur at an infection-period with extreme high ascospore potential. The differences&#xD;
between the tested combinations were low. Wetting sulphur+yucca-saponin showed&#xD;
interesting tendencies in the year 2007, but should not be combined with lime sulphur as&#xD;
stop-application because of significantly increased reticular russetting of the apples.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13640/1/041-046.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pfeiffer, B.    (2008) Results from scab trials with Armicarb in the years 2006 and 2007.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 41-46.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13640/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>