<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Netzschwefel als Multitalent zur Behandlung von Krankheiten und Schaderregern im ökologischen Kernobstanbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klopp, Karsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kruse, Petra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palm, Gerd</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the last eight years research work has been done at the Fruit Research and Extension Centre Jork (OVB Jork) on strategies to control apple scab (Venturia inaequalis), powdery mildew of apple (Podosphaera leucotricha), sooty blotch(several fungis) and apple rust mite (Aculus schlechtendali) on organic grown pome fruit.&#xD;
Since 1997 different control strategies with reduced copper use and copper substitutes and sulphur with different application rates were tested in several trials on trees in organic apple orchards near Hamburg, Germany. The strategies were tested on the cultivar `Elstar´. The results show that sulphur has significant effects to control fruit scab, leave scab, powdery mildew, sooty blotch and rust mite.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3765/1/3765.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klopp, Karsten; Kruse, Petra; Maxin, Peter and Palm, Gerd    (2005) Netzschwefel als Multitalent zur Behandlung von Krankheiten und Schaderregern im ökologischen Kernobstanbau.  [Sulphur in research work on organic grown pome fruit.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3765/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>