<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Promotion of Organic Vegetable Production through Farmers’ Field School in Chitwan, Nepal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rana Bhat, Mr Basanta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ghimire, Mr Rajan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic vegetable production is important for economic uplifting of farm community. Research and development activities were carried out to promote organic vegetable production in Chitwan. Activities were carried out in four farmers groups in Chitwan district. Sidhuwa modality of group farming was followed for effective implementation of activities. Farmers’ Field School was conducted to evaluate the effect of different organic pesticides on winter vegetables. Different biopesticides had differential effects in yield and disease suppression of winter vegetables but mixture of more than one biopesticide was effective in controlling major diseases and better yield of crops. Thus, this study showed that there is wide scope for use of biopesticides in organic vegetable production. However, this result should be verified by repeating same experiments for at least three seasons.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9815/1/Rana_Bhat_9815_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rana Bhat, Mr Basanta and Ghimire, Mr Rajan    (2008) Promotion of Organic Vegetable Production through Farmers’ Field School in Chitwan, Nepal.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9815/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>