<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Akzeptanz von Futterpflanzen mit Vorkommen von kondensierten Tanninen bei Schafen und ihre Gehalte an nutzbarem Rohprotein</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Scharenberg, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arrigo, Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gutzwiller, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soliva, Carla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perroud, Aurélia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzer, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dohme, Frigga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plants with moderate contents of condensed tannins are assumed to have anthelmintic Plants with moderate contents of condensed tannins are assumed to have anthelmintic properties and to improve protein supply of ruminants by reducing its ruminal degradability. In the present study, birdsfoot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus), chicory (Cychorium intybus) and sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia), suitable to be grown in Central Europe, were tested for their suitability as feed for ruminants. Sainfoin proved to be the most promising forage plant since it was very well accepted by the sheep and presented the highest content of utilizable crude protein as determined in vitro. Only few condensed tannins were detected in chicory. Further in vivo studies are required to confirm a better metabolic protein supply of ruminants when fed sainfoin.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3401/1/3401.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Scharenberg, Anna; Arrigo, Yves; Gutzwiller, Andreas; Soliva, Carla; Perroud, Aurélia; Wyss, Ulrich; Kreuzer, Michael and Dohme, Frigga    (2005) Akzeptanz von Futterpflanzen mit Vorkommen von kondensierten Tanninen bei Schafen und ihre Gehalte an nutzbarem Rohprotein.  [Palatability of plants containing condensed tannins by sheep and their content of utilizable crude protein.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3401/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>