<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Setting up a control and certification system for organic farming in developing countries: the case of Algeria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>ZIANE, Mrs Djamila</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main objective of this work is to define the steps and the procedures to set up an effective control and certification system for Algeria, that is compatible with local peculiarities and realities and which complies with the International Regulations. The aim of this initiative is to offer a cost-efficient and credible inspection and certification for organic products to farmers, processors and traders. Doing so, the access to export and domestic markets should be facilitated. Furthermore, it is expected to boost the development of the organic sector in Algeria.For the analysis of the Algerian agricultural sector some relevant factors are defined in order to make the state of the art that shows what has to be done and what are the pre-conditions to fulfil before starting the project.A study of the experience of another developing country in setting up a certification program was carried out. This case study is intended to present some key experiences in the field, and to extract lessons learnt which could serve as support for new initiatives.An action plan is proposed with the main steps and actions to undertake in order to reach the main objective of this work.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6377/1/ZianeDjamila02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ZIANE, Mrs Djamila   (2002) Setting up a control and certification system for organic farming in developing countries: the case of Algeria.  [Mise au point d’un système de contrôle et de certification en agriculture biologique dans les pays en voie de développement: le cas de l’Algérie.]  Thesis, IAMB - Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari. Tesi Master of Science, no. 272. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6377/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>