<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Societal Demand for Commodity and Non-commodity Outputs – A Regional Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wasilewski, Jakub</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Societal demand for the multifunctionality of agriculture was analysed in four case-study regions by studying stakeholders’ perceptions of regional priorities. We used the Stakeholder Delphi Approach, which is a qualitative, two-step procedure, based on revealed preferences of a principal consisting of stakeholders and experts from the regions. The results of our case studies imply that demand for functions of agriculture is generally strong. Comparing the priorities among the case studies, we found different demand patterns in each region. Further discussion of the Wielkopolska case study, with a production-focussed demand pattern, and the River Gudenå case study, with a post-productivist pattern, illustrates the regional characteristics that have shaped the distinct demand pattern in these regions.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer-Verlag</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17945/1/Schader-etal-2009-rural-landscapes-agricultural-policies-europe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schader, Christian; Moschitz, Heidrun; Kjeldsen, Chris; Wasilewski, Jakub and Stolze, Matthias   (2009) Societal Demand for Commodity and Non-commodity Outputs – A Regional Perspective.   Rural Landscapes and Agricultural Policies in Europe (1), pp. 53-72.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17945/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>