<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Udder health concepts that comply with organic principles - how to reduce therapies?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Notz, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spranger, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heil, Fritz</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Both the consumers and the legislators expect products from healthy organic livestock. Consequently, keeping farm animals healthy has the highest priority in veterinary work on organic farms. Different Swiss FiBL projects on bovine mastitis in recent years were aimed at health concepts that comply with organic livestock production principles. This paper summarises some of the work carried out.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sundrum, Albert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Padel, Susanne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3157/1/walkenhorst-et-al-2004-udder-health-concepts.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Walkenhorst, Michael; Notz, Christophe; Klocke, Peter; Spranger, Jörg and Heil, Fritz    (2004) Udder health concepts that comply with organic principles - how to reduce therapies?    In: Hovi, Malla; Sundrum, Albert and Padel, Susanne (Eds.)   Organic livestock farming: potential and limitations of husbandry practice to secure animal health and welfare and food quality. Proceedings of the 2nd SAFO Workshop 25-27 March 2004, Witzenhausen, Germany; University of Reading.  SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project, pp. 71-75.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3157/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>