<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Auswirkungen einer einmalig variierten Bodenbearbeitung auf Ertragsbildung, Verunkrautung und Nitratauswaschung unter ökologischen Produktionsbedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häberle, Dipl.agr.ing. Annette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pekrun, PD Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Prof. Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prade, Dipl.Geologe Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stahr, Prof. Karl</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Field experiments were conducted to investigate the effect of timing and method of cultivation after the harvest of legumes and crops with high-N crop residues on N mineralization, nitrate leaching, crop growth, diseases and weeds in wheat crops. The study is designed to compare effects of reduced and conventional tillage in autumn and to compare different times of conventional tillage in winter and spring in three different areas of Baden-Württemberg with typically soil types (Main-Tauber-Gebiet = Keuper and shell lime, Gäu-Region = Löss, Schwäbische Alb = limestone). In the results of October 2002 till October 2003 there was no significant influence of timing and method of cultivation on N mineralization, nitrate leaching, crop growth, diseases and weeds in wheat crops. But there was an extreme influence of the different areas which is the result of different soil types, different weather and different farm manager. The study will be continued for one year to verify this results.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3262/1/3262.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häberle, Dipl.agr.ing. Annette; Pekrun, PD Carola; Claupein, Prof. Wilhelm; Prade, Dipl.Geologe Christoph and Stahr, Prof. Karl    (2005) Die Auswirkungen einer einmalig variierten Bodenbearbeitung auf Ertragsbildung, Verunkrautung und Nitratauswaschung unter ökologischen Produktionsbedingungen.  [The results of a short-term variation on yield, weed population and nitrate leaching in organic farming.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3262/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>