<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production of Organic Ornamentals in Germany – a Status Quo Analysis of the Industry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Billmann, Bettina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaser, Jutta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlüter, Dietmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schorn, Wolfgang</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Ornamentals, flower bulbs and tree nurseries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the German Federal Organic Farming Scheme (BÖL) project “Organic production of ornamental plants and nursery trees – structure of the industry, development, problems and required policy initiatives” a qualitative and quantitative survey of certified organic and conventional / integrated nurseries was carried out. The aim was to assess the current status of production and marketing of organic ornamentals in Germany and to provide an overview of the general framework of this industry.&#xD;
The results show that organic production of ornamentals, trees and shrubs is technically feasible but still difficult. For further development this sector needs improvement of the basic conditions such as market structure, advisory services, subsidies and research activities</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4390/1/Billmann_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Billmann, Bettina; Schaser, Jutta; Schlüter, Dietmar and Schorn, Wolfgang    (2005) Production of Organic Ornamentals in Germany – a Status Quo Analysis of the Industry.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - First Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture ISOFAR, Adelaide, South Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4390/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>