<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quelle sélection fruitière pour une production durable, à faible niveau d’intrants ?&#xD;
Méthodologie pour un réseau de sélection variétale décentralisée</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brun, Laurent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Warlop, François</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mercier, Vincent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Broquaire, Jean-Michel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clauzel, Guy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomez, Christelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Parveaud, Claude-Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Audergon, Jean-Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In France Fruit production is cultivated on 140 thousand hectares, mainly conducted on intensive training system. Very few elements are available on low input training systems while they have to integrate the Global rule under the frame of Ecophyto 2018. In order to evaluate if another system of cultivation will be possible, a project has been developed to highlight the main factors to be integrated in low input training system. A low input multilocal experimental design has thus been investigated on apricot in two main regions of production: Rhone valley and Roussillon. A set of 9 common cultivars with 20 replications each, planted in a complete single-tree randomization design has been established.&#xD;
As already observed in apple orchard, a larger set of disease has been observed in our experimental plots by comparison with conventional training orchards. A large genetic variability has been set-up among the observed cultivars, but if some of them expressed components of resistance against the observed diseases no one appeared widely resistant to all the diseases. Taking in consideration the longevity of the orchard, a huge concern exists with the tested germplasm because the observed dieback was in between 10 and 80% of the trees according to the cultivars after only 6 years of observation. On the methodological point of view, a clear optimization of the experimental design is expected on the base of the observed results.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26983/1/Audergon_2011_IA_Vol15.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brun, Laurent; Warlop, François; Mercier, Vincent; Broquaire, Jean-Michel; Clauzel, Guy; Gomez, Christelle; Parveaud, Claude-Eric and Audergon, Jean-Marc   (2011) Quelle sélection fruitière pour une production durable, à faible niveau d’intrants ? Méthodologie pour un réseau de sélection variétale décentralisée.  [What kind of fruit cultivar selection for a sustainable production under a low input level ?]  Innovations Agronomiques, 15, pp. 105-115.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26983/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>