<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>WEEDS PROMOTE THE DEVELOPMENT OF ARBUSCULAR MYCORRHIZAL FUNGI IN ORGANIC WHEAT FIELDS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kubota, Hiroshi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spaner, Dean</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quideau, Sylvie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hucl, Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Understanding the interaction between aboveground vegetation and arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) in organic agriculture is of great importance to develop more efficient and sustainable agricultural production systems. This study was conducted to evaluate the effect of weeds on AMF and the effect of AMF on wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) grain quality in an organic field in the weed-free and weedy conditions. The soil microbial profile was characterized using phospholipid fatty acids (PLFA) analysis. We found that the presence of weeds increased the proportion of AMF. The enhanced activity of AMF did not affect the quality of wheat grain grown with sufficient soil phosphorus (P).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23530/1/23530_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kubota, Hiroshi; Spaner, Dean; Quideau, Sylvie and Hucl, Pierre    (2014) WEEDS PROMOTE THE DEVELOPMENT OF ARBUSCULAR MYCORRHIZAL FUNGI IN ORGANIC WHEAT FIELDS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 105-108.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23530/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>