<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Weaknesses of the emmer wheat genetic resources and possibilities of its improvement for low-input and organic farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Emmer wheat is suitable for organic and low-input farming systems, as it contributes to the enhancement of agrobiodiversity and an extension of the range of crop species with a higher added value. Although it has been grown for a very long time, it is now rarely utilised. The results of research into and examination of six cultivars coming from the genetic resources of the gene bank in Prague are presented. Particular morphological, biological, economic and quality characteristics were examined in respect of a cultivar’s ideotype for the organic farming system. A number of criteria for selection were proposed on the basis of an examination of particular characteristics and relationships. They respect the principles of breeding of cultivars for the organic farming system and are likely to lead to more frequent growing of the emmer wheat cultivars. Attention should be paid to the selection of cultivars having long and dense spikes. Long plants are more suitable, as they are resistant to lodging. Tolerance to wheat diseases has also to be taken into consideration, and such resistant material is an important part of the choice. The reduction of crude protein in grain, which has been noted in soft wheat, has to be limited in the selection of material in order to provide a high yield level. A positive correlation would allow enhancement of spike productivity via the selection of cultivars which have a higher thousand grain weight, and total number and weight of grains in the spikes. In addition to the high protein content in grain, high wet gluten content and low starch content in grain should also be criteria for selection.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Konvalina, Petr; Capouchova, Ivana; Stehno, Zdenek; Moudry, Jan (Jr.) and Moudry, Jan   (2010) Weaknesses of the emmer wheat genetic resources and possibilities of its improvement for low-input and organic farming systems.   Journal of Food, Agriculture &amp; Environment, 8 (3-4), pp. 376-382.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20767/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>