<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vitamins and selenium in bulk tank milk of organic and conventional dairy farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Emanuelson, Ulf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fall, Nils</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Vitamins in milk are important for the human consumer, the calf and the cow. They are also important for the dairy industry because some of them affect the risk for off-flavour. Studies indicate that milk from organic and conventional dairy farms may differ in these aspects. The aim of this study was therefore to investigate whether there are differences in the concentration of vitamins and selenium in milk between organic and conventional farms in Sweden. Bulk tank milk was sampled in 20 organic and 20 conventional dairy farms at three occasions during the indoor season. Concentrations of α-tocopherol, β-carotene and retinol were determined by HPLC and selenium by hydrid generation inductively coupled plasma atomic emission spectrometry. Herd characteristics were collected by questionnaires and from the official milk recording scheme. Multivariable linear mixed models were used to evaluate the associations between milk composition and type of farm, while adjusting for potential confounders and the repeated observations within farm. Average levels of α-tocopherol, β-carotene, retinol and selenium were 0.84 µg/ml, 0.18 µg/ml, 0.32 µg/ml and 13.6 µg/kg, respectively. There were no differences between organic and conventional farms in β-carotene, retinol or selenium concentration. Concentration of α-tocopherol was also similar, but was significantly lower in organic farms if differences in amount of roughage were accounted for in the statistical model.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>van der Honing, Y</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11163/1/Paper_e-vit_EAAP_07.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Emanuelson, Ulf and Fall, Nils    (2007) Vitamins and selenium in bulk tank milk of organic and conventional dairy farms.   In: van der Honing, Y (Ed.)  Book of Abstracts of the 58th Annual Meeting of the EAAP (13), p. 35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11163/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>