<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improved Contribution of local feed to support 100% Organic feed supply to Pigs and Poultry</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Due to the request for using entirely organically produced feed for livestock by 31st December 2017 there is a need to explore and evaluate the practical possibilities in doing that from a production and animal welfare point of view. Thus, this work was initiated to suggest economical viable feeding strategies based on 100% organic feed across Europe, which will supply poultry and pigs the required level of nutrients in different phases of production and support high animal health and welfare. &#xD;
Through co-operation between 11 partners, a range of feeding experiments were carried out with pigs (sows, piglets and finishers) and poultry (layers and broilers) focused on concentrate feedstuffs, roughage, and foraging from the range. In addition, three crosscutting activities have supported the overall interpretation; these worked on availability of relevant feeds across Europe, comparable information on feeding values of new feed stuffs for practical planning, and economic and environmental assessment of new strategies.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Jo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gerrard, Catherine L</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hermansen, John E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28078/7/28078.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smith, Jo; Gerrard, Catherine L and Hermansen, John E. (Eds.)    (2014) Improved Contribution of local feed to support 100% Organic feed supply to Pigs and Poultry.    Organic Research Centre.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28078/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>