<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung verschiedener Nutzungsintensitäten auf montane Goldhaferwiesen im Biolandbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Angeringer, Wolfgang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karrer, Gerhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2012 about 25 % of permanent Austrian grasslands were managed organically. At the same time the farms enlarged their average field areas especially in Alpine regions. In order to investigate intensification limits of montane meadows, an on-farm field experiment at the Upper Styrian Pöls valley was established in 2008. The triannual case study consisted of a balanced incomplete block design with 30 sub-plots at two autochthonous meadows of the Trisetetum association. These examined six treatments with different cutting regimes (2, 3, 4 cuts per year) and either slurry or solid manure for organic fertilization. Three years of investigation describe changes in coverage of grassland species as well as yield quantity and quality. The results show changes in abundance of widespread meadow species after three years due to management intensification. Whereas net energy and protein content rise according to earlier growth stage, the undesirable grass Poa trivialis accelerated too. On the other hand, valuable species, e.g. Poa pratensis agg., declined in abundance. Hence, there will be limits to intensification on permanent grassland, dependent on site condition and species composition.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21433/1/21433_angeringer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Angeringer, Wolfgang; Starz, Walter and Karrer, Gerhard    (2013) Wirkung verschiedener Nutzungsintensitäten auf montane Goldhaferwiesen im Biolandbau.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21433/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>