<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results of the EISfOM project investigation into the current situation of data collection and processing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Toralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conclusion&#xD;
- Currently few public data collection and processing systems on an international level exist with regard to the organic agriculture and food sector (however FAO, EUROSTAT, IFOAM have startes activities).&#xD;
- Less activities  aree run to harmonise national organic data collection systems on an international level.&#xD;
- Investment decisions of market actors and support decisions of policy makers are taken under conditions of great uncertainty.&#xD;
- Organic data know-how in most countries concentrated on less and private minds.&#xD;
- Public demand for organic data presently often are just statements and action plan points to support organic farming in theory.&#xD;
- Partly the link is missing between political objectives (on national and international level) and realisation by statistic authorities.&#xD;
- The EU-project European Inforamtion Systems for Organic Markets will assist all national and international efforts to improve organic data collecting in next two years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2613/1/richter-2004-EISfOM_Presentation_Plenary_Session.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Richter, Toralf    (2004) Results of the EISfOM project investigation into the current situation of data collection and processing.       Speech at:   1st EISfOM Seminar Development of European Information Systems for Organic Markets - improving the availability, quality and comparability of statistical data, Germany, Berlin, 26.-27.04.2004.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2613/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>