<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Potential Risk of Acrylamide Formation in Different Cultivars of Amaranth and Quinoa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Graeff, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stockmann, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weber, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berhane, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mbeng, K.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohitrattana, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salazar, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shoko, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaul, H.-P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Acrylamide (AA), a potential human carcinogen, is formed in strongly heated carbohydrate-rich food as a part of the Maillard-reaction. The amino acid asparagine (Asn) and reducing sugars are considered to be the main precursors for AA formation. So far, research in AA has mainly focused on potato and cereal products, indicating the relevance of species, cultivars, amount of N fertilizer, and climatic conditions. Potential additional sources of acrylamide in food products might be pseudocereal grains (e.g. amaranth, quinoa). As amaranth and quinoa are often cultivated as cash crops in organic production systems, the aim of this study was to investigate the potential of acrylamide formation in different amaranth and quinoa cultivars. Grain samples were collected from field trials in Germany and Austria consisting of 6 amaranth and 3 quinoa cultivars. The results indicated significant differences in the potential for acrylamide formation of quinoa cultivars and also slight differences between tested amaranth cultivars. It is obvious that the selection of cultivars with a low AA formation potential would offer a suitable strategy for the minimization of AA in foodstuffs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11650/1/Graeff_11650_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Graeff, S.; Stockmann, F.; Weber, A.; Berhane, B; Mbeng, K.J.; Rohitrattana, R.; Salazar, P.; Shoko, P.; Kaul, H.-P. and Claupein, W.    (2008) Potential Risk of Acrylamide Formation in Different Cultivars of Amaranth and Quinoa.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11650/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>