<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Growing a local organic movement: The Mexican Network of Organic Markets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nelson, Erin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwentesius, Rita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tovar, Laura Gómez</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cruz, Manuel Gómez</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Over the past several years, in response to the rapid growth in global demand for organic goods, the amount of organic production in Mexico has increased dramatically. Indeed, while Mexican agriculture as a whole has suffered severe crises, the organic sector has boomed, and today more than 83 000 producers farm organically on over 300 000 hectares of land. Of these producers, 98 percent are small scale, farming an average of three hectares, and over 50 percent are indigenous people. Unfortunately, as is the case in many developing countries, the vast majority of organic production remains focused on export crops – particularly coffee, but also cocoa, coconut, and other fruit and vegetables – with 85 percent of organic goods being sent to foreign markets. From an environmental point of view, exportoriented production is extremely damaging because of the amounts of fossil fuels required for transportation. In addition, packaging for export consumes precious resources and creates mountains of waste. Moreover, an export-oriented focus constrains the degree to which domestic markets are developed, and it leaves Mexican producers highly vulnerable to international market fluctuations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>LEISA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13879/1/13879.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nelson, Erin; Schwentesius, Rita; Tovar, Laura Gómez and Cruz, Manuel Gómez   (2008) Growing a local organic movement: The Mexican Network of Organic Markets.   LEISA Magazine, 24 (1), pp. 24-27.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13879/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>