<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklungsstand und Funktionsweise der &#xD;
Beschaffungs- und Lieferantenmärkte für ökologische Lebensmittel in der deutschen Außer-Haus-Verpflegung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic food market in Germany has shown continual growth throughout the last decade. This development has been accompanied by increasing research, certification, consulting services and wholesale activity with respect to this market sector. Nevertheless, implementing organic food in eating out facilities (EOF) faces several challenges. Within a recently completed research project, we examined the reasons for the adoption or rejection of the supply of organic food in EOFs. The empirical base consists of 26 case-studies on EOFs using expert-interviews with several persons-in-charge. The reasons for the adoption or rejection of the supply of organic food vary, and depend on internal and external factors concerning the organizations and their business environments. One of the most important results of this research project shows problems of EOFs with the procurement of organic produce, as well as with the suppliers. Several constraints and problems within the supply chain regarding procurement were determined. EOFs face diverse challenges, such as shortages in service and the quality and quantities of produce corresponding to EOFs special needs. The results point out a need for further development and maturation of this specialized organic food market.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17695/3/Niessen_17695.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niessen, Jan    (2011) Entwicklungsstand und Funktionsweise der Beschaffungs- und Lieferantenmärkte für ökologische Lebensmittel in der deutschen Außer-Haus-Verpflegung.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17695/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>