<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An LC inventory based on representative and coherent farm types</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, I.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a need for valid and representative data regarding the production, resource use and emissions from typical farming systems in Denmark for analysis of the environmental impact of different systems and as input to product oriented analyses such as Life Cycle Assess-ments of basic food items. An inventory of 31 farm types was constructed on the basis of 2138 farm accounts from 1999 selected and weighted to be representative for the Danish farming sector. The farm accounts were grouped according to the major soil types, the num-ber of standard working hours, the most important enterprise (dairy, pig, different cash crops) and the stocking rate (livestock units per hectare). For each group the account data on the average inputs and outputs, land use and herd structure was used to establish a farm type model with coherency between livestock production, total feed use, land use, yields, im-ported feed, home-grown feed, manure production, fertiliser use and crop production. The set of farm types were scaled up to national level thus representing the whole Danish agricul-tural sector for the included products. The sum of area and yield by crop, number and pro-duction by livestock type and the use of fertiliser, energy and concentrated feed was checked against national level statistics and corrected accordingly across all farm types. Resource use and emissions in each farm type was established using standard nutrient concentrations and models for nutrient cycling, energy use and emissions of e.g. ammonia, nitrous oxides and methane. For LCA the product oriented inventory was established using system expan-sion rather than allocations to account for the secondary enterprises in the livestock farm types. Data are made available on a web-based database and may be used for analyses of the primary production systems or as input for LCA across the whole production chain.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Danish Institute of Agricultural Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Halberg, N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15491/1/15491.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dalgaard, R.; Halberg, N.; Kristensen, I.S. and Larsen, I.    (2004) An LC inventory based on representative and coherent farm types.   In: Halberg, N. (Ed.)  Life Cycle Assessment in the Agri-food sector, Danish Institute of Agricultural Sciences (61), DIAS Report, Animal Husbandry, pp. 98-106.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15491/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>