<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigation on the Biocontrol of Phytophthora diseases on strawberry based on antagonism</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Anandhakumar, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zeller, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>After screening of several rhizosphere bacteria against the soilborne pathogens of&#xD;
red core and crown rot disease of strawberry Phytophthora fragariae var. fragariae&#xD;
and Phytophthora cactorum under in vitro conditions, three of the most active isolates&#xD;
which produced up to 63% of reduction in mycelium growth, such as Raoultella&#xD;
terrigena (G-584), Bacillus amyloliquefaciens (G-V1) and Pseudomonas fluorescens&#xD;
(2R1-7) were selected for further studies under in vivo conditions. In a greenhouse&#xD;
and field experiments, mentioned above three isolates were tested against both&#xD;
Phytophthora diseases under artificial infested soil conditions. Root dip treatment&#xD;
with these bacterial antagonists produced a control effect on both fungal diseases&#xD;
between 27 to 55 % and were in some cases comparable with the chemical fungicide&#xD;
Aliette.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14548/1/46_Anandhakumar_240_243.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Anandhakumar, J. and Zeller, W.    (2004) Investigation on the Biocontrol of Phytophthora diseases on strawberry based on antagonism.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 240-243.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14548/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>