<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interrelation of food supply, environment and security - a life cycle assessment approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kurppa, Sirpa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>LCA is giving us a profile of the categorised environmental impacts of a product or&#xD;
service through the whole production chain or chain of service activities. How&#xD;
comprehensive this is, depends on the system boundaries of the particular&#xD;
assessment. And at its best, LCA is not only restricted to principal system but covers&#xD;
or makes linkages to periferic systems of production of process inputs (for instance&#xD;
energy) and further processing of secondary or waste based products. LCA is a good&#xD;
tool for development of zero-waste or carbon neutral systems. LCA is a highly&#xD;
potential tool in benchmarking between various activity areas of society or economy&#xD;
(Nissinen et al 2007), and in a few years it will be developed as a tool to benchmark&#xD;
different food products and various brands of one category of food stuffs. By LCA such&#xD;
new issues as virtual water will be easily handled.&#xD;
LCA can be used in communication between food supply and demand. For that&#xD;
purpose, results of LCA must be carefully modified to the cognitive frame and decision&#xD;
making framework of consumer groups and stakeholders of a food chain. The&#xD;
information based on LCA thinking has to be given from different sources and variable&#xD;
aspects to consumers. The strongest progress will be taken if LCA is integrated into&#xD;
integrated product policy (IPP) and IPP would be taken as an approach to reorient&#xD;
environmental policy of food production. In that case, environmental policy would be&#xD;
directly linked to food product quantity and quality, and as such linked to food&#xD;
security.&#xD;
But, LCA and the other neighbouring assessment systems are linking food supply&#xD;
chain into more or less ‘unified’, standard environment. LCA is as poor in taking into&#xD;
account diversity in natural ecological framework and in human society. Therefore it is&#xD;
a fortune, that many progressive companies that first started to publish environmental&#xD;
reports have very quickly extended their approach to corporate social responsibility&#xD;
report. In terms of environmental assessment there is now a big challenge on one&#xD;
hand in trying to develop LCA towards assessment of impacts on biodiversity and&#xD;
natural resilience or ecosystem services and on the other hand to develop the&#xD;
qualitative environmental assessment and integrated that into socioeconomic/cultural&#xD;
approach of CRS assessments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15788/1/LCa.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kurppa, Sirpa    (2008) Interrelation of food supply, environment and security - a life cycle assessment approach.   In:     NJF Report, 4 (7), pp. 47-50.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15788/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>