<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SOLUTION OF RESIDUE SUSPICION IN ORGANIC CUMIN AND ANISEED</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nemli, Yildiz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaynar, Ahmet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kayandan, Akın</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Er, Tülin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>BIRLIK produce and export mostly organic aniseed, cumin and fennel. Other than these products, the company also produce poppy seed, gorund oregano, thyme, sage, rosemary and chickpea in 7 different project areas. A research project is prepared beetween EU Agricultural Faculty Plant Protection Department and BIRLIK to solve the suspicions occured due to linuron and isoproturon herbicide metabolites formation in organic cumin and linuron formation in aniseed. This project was started in 2009 and samples were collected in different periods of times from organic and conventional farms and analyzed in Dr. Specht Laboratories. As a conclusion, a resembling metabolite of isoproturon metabolite is reviewed to be occured close to and after harvest of cumin. The laboratory was informed about the results and the outcome was approved by their own studies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25214/7/25214.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nemli, Yildiz; Kaynar, Ahmet; Kayandan, Akın and Er, Tülin    (2014) SOLUTION OF RESIDUE SUSPICION IN ORGANIC CUMIN AND ANISEED.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25214/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>