<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DOES ORGANIC FOOD INTERVENTION IN SCHOOL LEAD TO CHANGED DIETARY PATTERNS?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During adolescence food habits, physical activity, and life style of young people are easily influenced by a number of actors and phenomena in the environment including parents, friends, advertisements and all of the changes occurring in society. The meal patterns formed during adolescence will be continuously influenced into their adulthood even following generations in the future. Since school increasingly is taking a role in both food provision and in health, environment and nutrition education of young people by implementing healthy and environmental friendly policies, it is relevant to investigate the relation between the different components of such interventions. In other words it is relevant to ask the question: does organic food supply police go hand in hand with healthy eating policies. This study that has been made possible through the iPOPY project looks at the relationship in Danish and Norwegian school food setting by asking school headmaster about their policies and operational procedure in relation to school food. The purpose of the study is to explore the relationship “green” food policies &amp; praxises to “healthy” food policies &amp; praxises in public school food settings. The outcome of the research/questionnaire will be a mapping of serving practices in relation to healthy eating and the relation to attitudes and practices of organic procurement and policies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14062/1/14062.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>He, Chen and Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg    (2008) DOES ORGANIC FOOD INTERVENTION IN SCHOOL LEAD TO CHANGED DIETARY PATTERNS?       Poster at:   IFOAM, Modena, Italy, Modena., 2008-06-19.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14062/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>