<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Toxicity of oil from Anacardium humile Saint Hill (Anacardiaceae), on Bemisia tuberculata (Bondar, 1923) (Hemipttera: Aleyrodidae) on cassava plants.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Andrade Filho, Nézio Neri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roel, Antonia Railda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yano, Mami</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cardoso, Claudia Andreia Lima</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matias, Rosemary</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim was to evaluate the toxic effects of essential oil of Anacardium humile, in different concentrations, on survival and development of the whitefly Bemisia tuberculata on the cassava plants, Manihot esculenta Crantz. The experiment was carried out in a greenhouse at a temperature of 26±4º C. Twenty adults were confined in cages, which contained a leaf of cassava plant and removed after 24 hours. The oil was sprayed in the concentrations of the 0.006%, 0.05%, 0.8% and 2%, when the nymphs were attached to the leaves. Data was collected daily by counting nymphs, pseudopupae and adults and the passages of each stage. All treatments increased the juvenile phase. The mortality in the nymphal stage decreased with the oil concentration, respectively, 79.81 (2%), 77.89 (0.8%), 79.98 (0.05%) and 67.14% (0.006%). The total mortality of pseudopupae followed the same tendency. The essential oil from the leaves of A. humile is a supplier of molecule(s) insecticide(s) and causes a deleterious effect on B. tuberculata with increased of the the juvenile phase, nymphal and total mortality of pseudopupae.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25296/1/Andrade%20Filho_Toxicity%20of%20oil%20from%20Anacardium%20humile%20Saint%20Hill.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Andrade Filho, Nézio Neri; Roel, Antonia Railda; Yano, Mami; Cardoso, Claudia Andreia Lima and Matias, Rosemary   (2013) Toxicity of oil from Anacardium humile Saint Hill (Anacardiaceae), on Bemisia tuberculata (Bondar, 1923) (Hemipttera: Aleyrodidae) on cassava plants.  [Toxicidade do óleo de Anacardium humile Saint Hill (Anacardiaceae) em Bemisia tuberculata (Bondar, 1923) (Hemiptera: Aleyrodidae) em plantas de mandioca.]  Revista Brasileira de Agroecologia, 8 (2), pp. 185-190.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25296/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>