<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Schutz der Ostsee durch Umstellung auf ökologisch kreislauforientierte Landwirtschaft: Praxisleitfäden und Software-Tools als Umstellungshilfe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reckling, Moritz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stein-Bachinger, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bachinger, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The ecological status of the Baltic Sea is endangered. The high nutrient surplus from intensive agriculture is the main reason for the pollution. In a joint project with all countries around the Baltic Sea, the EU funded project BERAS Implementation (Baltic Ecological Recycling Agriculture and Society) supports the conversion to ecological recycling agriculture (ERA) to ensure a sustainable protection of the Baltic Sea. The project aims to stimulate exchange of knowledge and experiences across countries, to build a network of experts including stakeholders from science, advisory services, ministries, and the food sector and to enhance the demand for organic products. Practical guidelines and software-tools were developed to support farmers in the conversion process to ERA farming. These materials provide guidelines for sustainable production of crops and livestock, farm economics and marketing, and farm management tools for crop rotation planning and on-farm nutrient management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21271/1/21271_Reckling.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Reckling, Moritz ; Stein-Bachinger, Karin and Bachinger, Johann    (2013) Schutz der Ostsee durch Umstellung auf ökologisch kreislauforientierte Landwirtschaft: Praxisleitfäden und Software-Tools als Umstellungshilfe.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21271/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>