<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Food Soybean Varieties in Low Input Conditions. Grain Yield and Quality from three NE Italy Environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miceli, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Centa, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Infanti, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Signor, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soybean has been diffusely grown in northern Italy since early 1980s. Indeed, at present the organic area (less than 3% of the total) and the practical absence of certified non-GM productions are key issues for farmers and food processors. In 2013, four food-grade varieties were tested under organic or low-input conditions in three environments of Friuli, NE Italy. Environments had a large impact on grain yields, genotype on grain composition. Late planting resulted in low yields and high-protein seeds. Seed protein levels were associated to visual seed quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Chable, Véronique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Goldringer, Isabelle</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Howlett, Sally</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Barberi, Paolo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Miko, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mendes-Moreira, Pedro</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rakszegi, Marianna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ostergaard, Hanne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Borgen, Anders</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pedersen, Tove</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bocci, Riccardo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28177/1/Miceli-etal-2014-Food%20Soybean%20Varieties-SOLIBAM-Final-Congress.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Miceli, F.; Centa, M.; De Infanti, R. and Signor, M.    (2014) Food Soybean Varieties in Low Input Conditions. Grain Yield and Quality from three NE Italy Environments.   In: Chable, Véronique; Goldringer, Isabelle; Howlett, Sally; Barberi, Paolo; Miko, Peter; Mendes-Moreira, Pedro; Rakszegi, Marianna; Ostergaard, Hanne; Borgen, Anders; Finckh, Maria R.; Pedersen, Tove and Bocci, Riccardo (Eds.)  Book of Abstracts of SOLIBAM final congress, pp. 65-66.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28177/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>