<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of some organic fertilizers on yield and quality of round seedless (=round sultana)&#xD;
Grape variety</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Altindisli, Ahmet</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study was conducted in two 0.5 ha-organic vineyards in Manisa Province in 2000 and 2001 to determine the effects of different manuring programs on yield and quality of fresh and dried grapes in the Round seedless (= Round sultana) variety. Different combinations of farmyard manure, green manure and E-2001 tested in the trial did not have any statistically significant effect on table grape yield, average bunch weight, 100 berry weight, total soluble solids, and titratable acidity in both vineyards. The highest increase in fresh grape yield compared to non-treated plots was measured as 12.8 % in GM+E-2001 application in the grafted vineyard, compared with as 25.4 % in GM+FM+E-2001 application of self-rooted vineyard. Different manuring treatments did not have statistically significant effects on investigated parameters of dried grape in both vineyards with the exception of 100 dried berries weight in 2001 and expertise score in 2000 of the non-grafted vineyard. However, taking into consideration the improvements obtained by the tested manure applications compared to non-treated controls in two years, higher performance with statistical significance can be expected on the long term.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4421/2/Altindisli_2005_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Altindisli, Ahmet    (2005) Effects of some organic fertilizers on yield and quality of round seedless (=round sultana) Grape variety.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4421/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>