<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigation on the influence of nematophagous fungi as feed additive on nematode infection risk of sheep and goats on pasture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Epe, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holst, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmann, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schnieder, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Samson-Himmelstjerna, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Gastrointestinal nematodes in small ruminants cause high economic losses. Thus on most farms anthelmintic treatment is required. In response to increasing problems with anthelmintic resistance, biological control, for example the use of nematophagous fungi, has received significant attention. The aim of this study was to investigate the effect of Duddingtonia flagrans orally applied to small ruminants on natural infection with gastrointestinal nematodes in a field study in Northern Germany.&#xD;
20 goats and 20 sheep were fed daily for 3 months with 5x105 spores of D. flagrans per kg bodyweight. Differences in body weight, faecal egg count and larval development in faeces and on pasture in comparison with same-sized control groups were analysed. After 3 months the control goats showed significantly higher mean faecal egg count than the fungus-fed group. No significant difference was found between the two sheep groups. The maximum in larval reduction in faeces was 81.3 % in the sheep groups and 67.9 % in the goat groups (not significant). At the end of the study the body weight gain in the fungus-treated groups was 1.7 kg higher in goats and 0.7 kg higher in sheep than in the control groups (not significant). Regarding the first-year-grazing goats only, the bodyweights revealed significant differences (p&lt;0.05). No statistically significant differences were observed in pasture larval counts.&#xD;
In the study presented here, no clear effect of fungus could be observed. A modified feeding regimen, perhaps with permanent release boluses or feed blocks, may improve the efficacy. Furthermore, it seems that climatic conditions during the study period could have influenced the results and displayed how sensitive the fungus application may be on such parameters.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut (vTI), D-Braunschweig</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14751/1/LBF-2008-3_Art05_Epe-Koopmann-1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Epe, C.; Holst, C.; Koopmann, R.; Schnieder, T.; Larsen, M. and von Samson-Himmelstjerna, G.   (2008) Investigation on the influence of nematophagous fungi as feed additive on nematode infection risk of sheep and goats on pasture.   Landbauforschung vTI - Agriculture and Forestry Research, 58 (3), pp. 191-202.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14751/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>