<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regional marketing for organic retailers: Status quo and capabilities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stockebrand, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiller, Achim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The market for organic food is still growing. The entrance of conventional supermarkets as well as discounters into the market and the increase of organic supermarkets are responsible for the organic boom in Germany and more price competition. These developments raise the question of new competitive strategies for small and medium sized organic retailers. The combination of organic and regional marketing might provide an opportunity to render small organic shops more successful again. The following paper discusses the opportunities for regional organic marketing strategies.&#xD;
First, this contribution gives an impression of the current situation and problems in the organic food branch, before continuing with theoretical research concerned with regional marketing. In the conclusion, the authors will underline different aspects with the aid of empirical results.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14724/1/stockebrand-spiller-2007-IFOAM_Conference_2007_Tagungsband.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stockebrand, Nina and Spiller, Achim    (2007) Regional marketing for organic retailers: Status quo and capabilities.   In:     Proceedings of the 1st IFOAM International Conference on Marketing of Organic and Regional Values.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14724/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>