<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Milk fatty acids in relation to feeding practices on Dutch organic farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>de Wit, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wagenaar, Jan Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Vries, Anneke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baars, Ton</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Various recent studies have indicated positive interactions between organic animal production and poly-unsaturated fatty acids, particularly CLA and omega-3. In this paper, we present the monitoring results of 15 organic farms concerning the rela-tionship between feeding practices and fatty acid pattern. The results indicate a strong negative effect of maize and grass silage and concentrate feeding on CLA levels in milk fat. On the other hand, feeding fresh grass has a positive effect. Omega-3 levels in milk fat seem less related to feed characteristics: similar relations to those with CLA seem to exist, but feed composition explains the variation in omega-3 levels only to a limited extent, while there is a large farm influence. This might be related to the energy balance of the cows. A comparison of measured CLA and omega-3 levels in organic milk with common levels in conventional milk shows a small difference during the stable period. Effects of adding oil - as a possibility to improve the level of CLA and omega-3 in a way that is organically acceptable - are explored, but effects remain small.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7320/1/jan_de_witodense_papermilkdef.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7320/2/7320_Wit.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>de Wit, Jan; Wagenaar, Jan Paul; de Vries, Anneke and Baars, Ton    (2006) Milk fatty acids in relation to feeding practices on Dutch organic farms.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7320/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>