<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fruitgrowers towards a new approach to enhance biodiversity in organic orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the frame of the project “Arbeitsnetz zur Weiterentwicklung der Anbauverfahren des&#xD;
ökologischen Obstbaus” (BOEL-project Nr. 03OE178) a group of fruitgrowers and advicers&#xD;
started to discuss new measures and new concepts to enhance biodiversity in organic&#xD;
orchards. Strips with flowering plants that can be integrated in the normal mulching system&#xD;
and thus, do not originate vole problems, are actually tested on the farms. Other measures&#xD;
as single bushes at the top and end of the rows are in discussion.&#xD;
If such measures are to be integrated successfully in the practice of organic fruit growing,&#xD;
the impulse must spring from growers themselves and their requirements regarding the&#xD;
different risks must be considered. Otherwise, an acceptance in practice is not very&#xD;
probable. This activites are reported here since we want more people to join us.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13746/1/339-342.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.    (2008) Fruitgrowers towards a new approach to enhance biodiversity in organic orchards.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 339-349.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13746/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>