<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Yersinia ruckeri challenge on rainbow trout fed different diet types</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, Lone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalsgaard, Inger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A challenge for sustainable rainbow trout production is an  increasing use of plant sources in fish feed due to shortage of marine protein and oil sources. Diets with high plant content are known to cause enteritis and injury to the intestine, which will affect the absorption of nutrients, affecting the overall health status and welfare of the fish. The result is a higher risk of disease following exposure to pathogenic microorganisms. The aim of this study was to elucidate how different feed types with varying amounts of marine versus organic plant protein and oil sources affected the survival of rainbow trout in connection with an infection. Enteric redmouth disease caused by Yersinia ruckeri is an economically important disease which causes problems in rainbow trout. Experimental infections (intraperitoneal injection of 150-200 g fish fed the different diets over a two month period) were done and mortalities in the different diet groups were recorded. Two weeks post challenge the mortalities in the different groups were between 50 and 89 %. The mortalities were lowest in the group fed the diet where half of the fish oil was replaced by organic plant oil. Unfortunately, the results were blurred due to a natural infection with Y. ruckeri that had occurred in the diet groups two months prior to the experimental infection (mortalities between 2 and 9 % in the different groups), and the half fish oil half plant oil group had had the highest cumulative mortality percentage in connection with this natural infection.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Aquatic Pathobiology Lab Press 2010</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Kane, Andrew S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Poynton, Sarah L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18314/1/18314.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Madsen, Lone and Dalsgaard, Inger    (2010) Yersinia ruckeri challenge on rainbow trout fed different diet types.   In: Kane, Andrew S. and Poynton, Sarah L. (Eds.)  Proceedings of the Sixth International Symposium on Aquatic Animal Health, September 5-9, 2010, Tampa, Florida USA, Aquatic Pathobiology Lab Press 2010, Gainesville, FL USA, pp. 1-220.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18314/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>