<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sensory Analyses and Nutritional Qualities of Hand-Made Breads with Organic Grown Wheat Bread Populations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vindras-Fouillet, Camille</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ranke, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anglade, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taupier-Létage, Bruno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chable, Véronique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goldringer, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Population varieties can meet the needs of organic farming as they are composed of diverse genotypes and have nutritional and sensory characteristics of interest. Their intra-specific genetic variability helps to adapt to the diversity of soil and climate conditions, management practices and needs. Moreover, an integrated organic bread sector has emerged willing to use more wheat populations. To explore sensory and nutritional potential of bread wheat populations, hedonic tests, sensory profile and nutritional analyses were implemented on eight wheat population varieties and one modern variety. Hedonic tests revealed consensus among consumer when ranking according to specific sensory characteristics and showed preferences for red wheat breads. Descriptive sensory test showed significant differences between genotypes on 6 out of 11 descriptors and confirmed the sensory specificity of red wheat accessions. Nutritional analyses showed differences especially on minerals content. Sensory differences between breads from different genotypes can be perceived both by trained and untrained panels as suggested by results. Moreover, red accessions showed specific sensory characteristics which are well-perceived by the two panels.&#xD;
Breeding effort should be maintained for high diverse genotypes with improved sensory and nutritional qualities adapted to organic farming conditions. Indicators like kernel colour should be sought to help integrate such criteria.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27842/1/Vindras_FNS_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vindras-Fouillet, Camille; Ranke, O.; Anglade, Jean-Pierre; Taupier-Létage, Bruno; Chable, Véronique and Goldringer, I.   (2014) Sensory Analyses and Nutritional Qualities of Hand-Made Breads with Organic Grown Wheat Bread Populations.   Food and Nutrition Sciences, 5, pp. 1860-1874.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27842/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>