<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECT OF ORGANIC TURMERIC (Curcuma longa) FEEDING ON TESTICULAR HISTOLOGY OF RABBITS EXPOSED TO ULTRAVIOLET RADIATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Togun, V.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amao, O.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adebisi, J.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Okwusidi, J.I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williams, O.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Thirty six male rabbits of 450-600g weight range fed with mostly organic ingredient feed, were weight-balanced into six treatment groups that received rabbit diets either without (D1) or with organic turmeric (D2) at varying periods within a nine- week experimental period. The treatments were T0, T1, T2, T3, T4 and T5 for control, D2 plus exposure to Ultraviolet (UV) radiation, D2 until radiation, D2 after radiation, D1 throughout the experimental period with UV radiation and D2 throughout the experimental period without UV radiation, respectively. Testicular histology revealed that feeding organic turmeric in the diet before exposure conferred some protection on the testicular tissue while the feeding of organic turmeric in the diet after exposure corrected some of the damage inflicted by exposure to UV radiation. The group (T4) that did not receive organic turmeric showed conspicuous damage in the testicular tissue on exposure to ultraviolet radiation. It was concluded that the inclusion of organic turmeric, simply boiled, dried and powdered in the diet without any sophisticated processing to extract curcumin, could alleviate the histological damage on account of exposure to ultraviolet radiation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23882/1/23882_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Togun, V.A.; Amao, O.A.; Adebisi, J.A.; Okwusidi, J.I. and Williams, O.S.    (2014) EFFECT OF ORGANIC TURMERIC (Curcuma longa) FEEDING ON TESTICULAR HISTOLOGY OF RABBITS EXPOSED TO ULTRAVIOLET RADIATION.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 867-870.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23882/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>