<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic school food policies are supportive for healthier eating behaviours – results from an observational study in Danish schools</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chen, He</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Purpose – The purpose of this study was to examine whether organic food intervention strategies in Danish school meal systems can support the development of healthier eating patterns among pupils. &#xD;
Design/methodology/approach – This paper investigates the interrelation between the two trends: healthy eating and organic consumption. The study was undertaken among school food coordinators through a web-based questionnaire in selected Danish public primary schools. Food strategies of “organic” schools were compared to those of “non organic” schools. The questionnaire explored the attitudes, policies/intentions and actions in relation to organic and healthy foods served in the schools. &#xD;
Findings – Results indicate that organic food intervention strategies can be supportive for strategies to increase the healthiness of school eating patterns.&#xD;
Social implications – The municipalities and other public bodies increasingly recognize their responsibility to support sustainable food production methods, such as organic agriculture, by choosing this kind of foods in public institutions. &#xD;
Originality/value – This paper provides the organic food strategies in schools that may increase the availability of healthier food options and promote healthy eating habits for pupils.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-08-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17422/1/Organic_school_food_policies_are_supportive_for_healthier_eating_behaviours_%282%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chen, He; Løes, Anne-Kristin and Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg   (2010) Organic school food policies are supportive for healthier eating behaviours – results from an observational study in Danish schools.   British Food Journal.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17422/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>