<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Food Processing - Principles, Concepts and Recommendations for the Future. Results of a European research project on the quality of low input foods</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>“Organic Food Processing – principles, concepts and recommendations for the future” is the concluding volume based on four reports on the processing of organic and low input food. It was produced within the framework of the Integrated Project on “Quality Low Input Food” (QLIF), funded by the European Commission under the 6th Framework Programme for Research and Technological Development. Within the QLIF project a work package  focused on developing a framework for the design of “minimum” and “low input” processing strategies that guarantee food quality and safety. &#xD;
This publication summarises the main findings and conclusions generated by the research team. It includes results of a literature survey on the underlying principles of organic and low input food processing. It reports the results of a Delphi survey on “Approaches Used in Organic and Low Input Food Processing – Impact on Food Quality and Safety”, involving more than 100 food processors and specialists in 13 European countries. &#xD;
A key result is that more guidance needs to be given to private operators and firms on how to implement EU regulation 2092/91 on organic food and farming at company level. A Code of Practice for the organic food sector is described as a possible instrument that would help to prevent the EU regulation from becoming over-prescriptive. &#xD;
Furthermore, four concept papers outline parameters for further developing organic food processing. These provide: a “quality of origin” concept for ingredients; proposals for criteria and procedures for evaluating additives for organic food processing; recommendations for a more environmental orientation of companies processing organic foods; proposals for improved labelling systems as well as clearer separation practices in mixed organic and non-organic operations.&#xD;
The final recommendations for the development of organic food processing are addressed to a range of actor groups, in particular the private sector, national authorities and the European Commission. &#xD;
Detailed project information is available at www.qlif.org/research/sub5/. &#xD;
The reports can also be downloaded at www.orgprints.org/view/projects/eu_qlif_sub5.html.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Beck, Alexander</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schmid, Otto</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8914/1/beck-etal-2006-report-LowInputFood.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Beck, Alexander; Kretzschmar, Ursula and Schmid, Otto (Eds.)      (2006) Organic Food Processing - Principles, Concepts and Recommendations for the Future. Results of a European research project on the quality of low input foods.  [With contributions from Angelika Ploeger, Marita Leskinen, Marjo Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Monika Roeger, Thorkild Nielsen and Niels Heine Kristensen.]   FiBL-Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8914/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>