<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Qualitative und quantitative Analyse der Biosaatgutproduktion&#xD;
bei Getreide in Österrreich</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weinhappel, Manfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leonhardt, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, Dr. Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diethart, Ivoneta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the scope of a research project, official data from the certification of organic seed in&#xD;
Austria from 1999 to 2007 were analysed to determine the most important factors&#xD;
effecting seed quality and leading to rejection of certification. Data from 4684 seed&#xD;
multiplication fields and 3262 seed lots were analysed.&#xD;
Weed seeds and wild oats (Avena fatua) have little effect on the quality of finished&#xD;
seed due to highly effective seed processing plants and risk-based seed testing. In&#xD;
cereal seeds the most frequent reason for rejection of certification in the category&#xD;
Other Seeds by Number is Other Cereal Seeds. An important criterion resulting in&#xD;
frequent non-certification of organic seed is the level of infection from seed-borne and&#xD;
seed-transmitted diseases. Although the field inspection data show only a very small&#xD;
number of multiplication fields with evidence of relevant seed-borne diseases, those&#xD;
diseases were nevertheless identified at a higher rate in the finished seed lots.&#xD;
Especially loose smut (Ustilago nuda) and leaf stripe (Drechslera graminea) on spring&#xD;
barley as well as bunt (Tilletia caries) have been increasing in Austria during the&#xD;
period studied. The main reasons for this development were nearby fields that&#xD;
harboured these diseases due to use of poor quality farm saved seed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14422/1/Weinhappel_14422.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weinhappel, Manfred; Leonhardt, Charlotte; Hartl, Dr. Wilfried and Diethart, Ivoneta    (2009) Qualitative und quantitative Analyse der Biosaatgutproduktion bei Getreide in Österrreich.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14422/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>