<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of alternative strategies for the disinfection of tomato seed infected with bacterial canker (Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. michiganensis)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kasselaki, A. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goumas, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cooper, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently there is a lack of effective seed treatments for bacterial pathogens, with Cu-based compounds (the only chemical treatments permitted under organic farming standards) only providing partial control.&#xD;
The aim of this study was to quantify the effect of alternative treatments for the control of bacterial canker (Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. michiganensis), a major seed-borne bacterial disease in tomato.&#xD;
Treatments assessed were acidified nitrite (a treatment previously shown to control the seed-borne fungal disease Didymella lycopersici), antagonistic strains of Bacillus spp. and compost extracts, which were not previously evaluated as treatments for seed-borne diseases. Efficacy of treatments was determined in a seed disinfection assay. Ten-minute immersion of seed in 300 mmol l−1 acidified nitrite resulted in 98% being pathogen free. Copper hydroxide, certain strains of Bacillus spp. and all compost extracts resulted in 100% pathogen free seed.&#xD;
© 2011 Royal Netherlands Society for Agricultural Sciences. Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19610/1/kasselaki-etal-2011-clavibacter-NJAS.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kasselaki, A. M.; Goumas, D.; Tamm, L.; Fuchs, J.; Cooper, J. and Leifert, C.   (2011) Effect of alternative strategies for the disinfection of tomato seed infected with bacterial canker (Clavibacter michiganensis subsp. michiganensis).   NJAS - Wageningen Journal of Life Sciences, 58 (3-4), pp. 145-157.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19610/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>