<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Disease management in organic apple orchards is more than applying the right product at the correct time</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jansonius, Pieter Jans</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The relative importance of diseases on apple is varying with cultivar, management, time,&#xD;
and climate. Many aspects of the cropping system influence the development of diseases.&#xD;
The choice of the variety determines the disease management during the lifetime of the&#xD;
orchard. Cultural practices improve the growth and nutrial status of the tree, and therewith&#xD;
influence the susceptibility of the plant and fruits to diseases directly. Prolonged growth&#xD;
can also have an indirect effect by causing a microclimate and growing pattern that&#xD;
favours infection of tree, leafs and fruits by various diseases. Sanitation measures are&#xD;
common practise for most organic fruit growers and help to make other measures more&#xD;
effective by reducing infection inoculums. Despite all preventive measures, disease control&#xD;
in organic orchards at an economically feasible level still largely depends on the&#xD;
application of fungicides. Measures that allow reduction of fungicidal applications on key&#xD;
diseases, lead to the development of a secondary disease complex that can cause severe&#xD;
losses when not managed effectively and make a well thought-out control strategy&#xD;
necessary.&#xD;
In research, advisory and practical decision making, disease management in organic&#xD;
orchards should always be seen in the perspective of the management of the total growing&#xD;
system. With all factors that contribute to disease management in organic orchards&#xD;
optimized, we are able to successfully implement new materials and methods that may not&#xD;
be as effective as common fungicides in themselves, but add to the effectiveness of the&#xD;
disease management system as a whole.&#xD;
This total system approach makes organic fruit growing what it is.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13633/1/016-022.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trapman, Marc and Jansonius, Pieter Jans    (2008) Disease management in organic apple orchards is more than applying the right product at the correct time.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 16-22.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13633/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>