<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Seminar report: Organic foods in Nordic catering - a multidisciplinary challenge</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Catering is expected to become an important sales channel for organic foods in the Nordic countries in the future. But there are many obstacles to be overcome before organic foods flow easily through the catering chain. Therefore Nordic partners representing industry, organizations and research have established a Nordic network for Organic Foods in Catering. The Nordic network has through a grant from Nordic Industrial Fund, with the support from Danish Veterinary &amp; Food Administration and Danish Technical University as well as from the Nordic partners, been able arrange a seminar on Organic foods in Nordic catering – a multidisciplinary challenge which was held in Copenhagen 28-29 September 2001. This report contains the papers from the conference.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Danish Veterinary and Food Administration. Nutrition Department - The Danish Catering Centre</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2746/1/Organic_foods_in_Nordic_catering.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg; Kristensen, Niels Heine and Nielsen, Thorkild (Eds.)    (2002) Seminar report: Organic foods in Nordic catering - a multidisciplinary challenge.   Danish Veterinary and Food Administration. Nutrition Department - The Danish Catering Centre.  Proceedings of Organic foods in Nordic catering - a multidisciplinary challenge, Copenhagen, 28-29 September 2001.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2746/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>