<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Overwinter transplant production for extended season organic cropping (OF 0144)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stopes, Christopher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>et al,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objectives of this project (Defra project OF0144), lead by EFRC, were to:&#xD;
•	identify acceptable organic fungicide products to control mildew in transplant production &#xD;
•	produce integrated organic transplant production systems for brassica, allium and lettuce over the autumn and winter period by identifying optimum cell/block sizes in relation to nutrient requirements and sources, growing media formulation, and supplementary feeding and watering &#xD;
•	evaluate developed transplant production protocols during the winter period &#xD;
•	undertake technology transfer and dissemination of the results &#xD;
Results:&#xD;
Protocols were tested for a range of crop species and varieties, growing media, cell size and feeding regimes over the three seasons under experimental and commercial conditions. It is possible to produce transplants of a suitable quality over the winter period although propagation time is generally longer than at more favourable times of year.&#xD;
With respect to identifying acceptable fungicide products&#xD;
•	a range of fungicidal products was identified including L-Carvone, Mycosin, fennel and clove oils that showed potential in controlling mildew on a range of crop species. However the work also raised the question of the suitability of the use of such materials in organic systems which has not been resolved. &#xD;
•	work on spectral filters found no benefits to their use in transplant production &#xD;
•	cell size has minimal effect on disease spread &#xD;
As far as integrated organic transplant production systems are concerned:&#xD;
•	production time was longer overwinter than in spring &#xD;
•	lettuce was relatively easy to produce in a range of media and block sizes with no supplementary feed being necessary &#xD;
•	similarly cabbage was relatively easy to produce although feeding was required &#xD;
•	cauliflower was produced using smaller cell size and full nutrient compost</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7973/1/OF0144_2145_FRP.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stopes, Christopher and et al,          (2001) Overwinter transplant production for extended season organic cropping (OF 0144).    Elm Farm Research Centre.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7973/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>