<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The quality of organic products</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LAIRON, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The sustainable development of ecological agriculture productions (AB) should be based on their overall quality, in the framework of nutritional recommendations and public action plans. In France, the PNNS (Nutrition and health national plan) advises to increase intake of fruits and vegetables, unrefined cereals, fibres and calcium and to reduce saturated fat. In addition, healthy foods should avoid any microbiological or chemical contaminants. The question arose of the adequacy of organic productions. For that purpose, the AFSSA (the French food safety agency) established an expert group headed by the author to conduct a sounded review of international scientific literature. The AFSSA report (2003) made conclusions as summarized here. Regarding the nutritional value of organic products, a trend was found for higher dry matter, iron and magnesium contents in vegetables, and noticeably higher contents in phytoconstituants (polyphenols, flavonols, resveratrol) in fruits or vegetables. Lower total fat and higher poly-unsaturated fatty acids were found in chicken meat. Concerning the sanitary value, organic products were found almost devoid of pesticide residues (only 2-6% contaminated compared with about 40% in general), with comparable levels of mycotoxins and about half contents in nitrates in vegetables. The challenge for the ecological agriculture future is to sustain such good results by developing a strategy based not only on production and transformation standards but also on end-products quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15494/1/38-Lairon.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LAIRON, D.    (2009) The quality of organic products.  [La qualité des produits de l’agriculture biologique.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 281-287.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15494/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>