<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Contributions of organic farming to a sustainable environment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pfiffner, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H채ring, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piorr, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Summary and Conclusions&#xD;
For each indicator organic farming is ranked at least equal to conventional farming, while in the majority of environmental indicators organic farming performs better or much better. In two cases, the subjective confidence interval could allow conventional farming to appear as the preferable system (partly due to the lack of evident data). However, when considering the aggregation level of the indicator categories, the analysis becomes more uniform. With the exception of climate and air, organic farming performs better than conventional farming in all categories. None of the indicator categories showed that organic farming performed worse.&#xD;
A summary assessment of all indicator categories was not carried out in the table, however, the result is clear: organic farming is, in an area-related comparison, more environmentally friendly than conventional farming. This result confirms one of the basic assumptions of the political support for organic farming, as mentioned in the introduction.&#xD;
On the one hand, the environmental performance of farms depends on the farming intensity, while on the other hand it depends on bio-tope management of nonproductive areas.&#xD;
The combination of organic farming with the conservation of semi-natural habitats and valuable field margins offers a real option to meet many environmental goals, especially biodiversity, on agricultural land.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>D채nish Ministry for Food, Agriculture and Fisheries</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2943/1/pfiffner-2001-proceedings-copenhagen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pfiffner, Lukas; H채ring, Anna; Dabbert, Stephan; Stolze, Matthias and Piorr, A.    (2001) Contributions of organic farming to a sustainable environment.   In:     Organic Food and Farming. Towards Partnership and Action in Europe. 10-11 May 2001, Copenhagen, Denmark, D채nish Ministry for Food, Agriculture and Fisheries, pp. 115-123.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2943/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>