<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effectiveness of entomopathogenic nematodes in the control of Cydia pomonella larvae in Northern Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Curto, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reggian, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vergnani, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caruso, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ladurner, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 2006, a large scale research on the effectiveness of entomopathogenic nematodes&#xD;
(EPN) in the control of codling moth (CM), Cydia pomonella, overwintering larvae has&#xD;
been performed on about 35 ha of pear orchards per year in Emilia-Romagna, Northern&#xD;
Italy. Steinernema carpocapsae and Steinernema feltiae activity was checked after spray&#xD;
applications of EPNs to the trunk and branches. In 2006, the treatment was applied either&#xD;
in spring or in autumn at different doses, before CM pupation; in 2007 the EPN treatment&#xD;
was applied only in autumn at 1.5 x 109 I.J. ha –1. Every year it was distributed by means of&#xD;
a conventional mist blower. The larval mortality was assessed directly on sentinel larvae in&#xD;
card boards on the trunks and indirectly on the eggs laid by the females of the first CM&#xD;
generation in spring. Moreover, each year, a trial was performed applying only S.&#xD;
carpocapsae on sentinel larvae with the aim of testing this nematode at suitable&#xD;
temperatures but at different water volumes.&#xD;
The CM sentinel larvae were effectively parasitized after autumnal EPN application.&#xD;
Moreover, the egg assessment demonstrated a good decrease in CM population in spring&#xD;
2007, when EPNs had been applied at the best weather conditions (t° 12-14 °C and rain)&#xD;
in the previous autumn.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13711/1/271-276.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Curto, G.; Reggian, A.; Vergnani, S.; Caruso, S. and Ladurner, E.    (2008) Effectiveness of entomopathogenic nematodes in the control of Cydia pomonella larvae in Northern Italy.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 271-276.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13711/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>