<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECTS OF COVER CROP MANAGEMENT AND COMPOST APPLICATION ON SOIL FERTILITY OF ORGANIC MELON</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tittarelli, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Campanelli, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Farina, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Napoli, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ciaccia, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Testani, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leteo, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Canali, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A field experiment was carried out in Central Italy on growing melon (Cucumis melo L.) after barley (Hordeum vulgare L.). Three different systems of cover crop termination (green manure, roller crimper and fallow, as control) were combined with three doses of compost (0, 15  and 30 t ha-1 d.m.) in a strip plot design. The main objective of the research was to evaluate their effects on organic melon production and on short and long term soil nitrogen (N) fertility. Marketable yield and quality and soil N availability along the melon cycle were determined and a simplified N budget calculated. Green manure (GM) treatment showed the highest total and marketable yield, followed by fallow (FA), while roller crimper (RC) was characterized by a significant lower yield respect to the other two treatments (45% and 62% of the marketable yield of GM and FA, respectively). On the other side, long term soil N fertility of GM and FA were characterized by N deficit unless combined with compost application at the dose of 15 t ha-1 d.m.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-09-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23596/1/23596_Tittarelli_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tittarelli, F.; Campanelli, G.; Farina, R.; Napoli, R.; Ciaccia, C.; Testani, E.; Leteo, F. and Canali, S.    (2013) EFFECTS OF COVER CROP MANAGEMENT AND COMPOST APPLICATION ON SOIL FERTILITY OF ORGANIC MELON.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 709-712.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23596/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>