<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Attitudes Towards Conversion To Organic Production Systems: A Study Of Farmers In England</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Midmore, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McCalman, Heather</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Isherwood, Jon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Susan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lamkpin, Nic</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report describes the attitudes of converting and conventional producers in England to organic production. In 2000, a telephone survey was conducted of farmers in three groups: those who were converting, those who had contacted OCIS but decided not to convert, and a random sample of conventional farmers. The majority of converting farmers gave concerns about agrochemicals and fears about the future profitability of conventional farming as their main reasons for going organic. Marketing was not seen as an obstacle to conversion. Conventional farmers thought that advice and information on organic production were easily obtained, but converting farmers did not agree, suggesting that there was a shortage of more advanced knowledge. Non-converters gave financial viability, environmental aspects and the Organic Farming Scheme as important factors in any future decision to convert.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10817/1/Attitude_survey.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Midmore, Peter; Padel, Susanne; McCalman, Heather; Isherwood, Jon; Fowler, Susan and Lamkpin, Nic         (2001) Attitudes Towards Conversion To Organic Production Systems: A Study Of Farmers In England.    University of Wales, Aberytwyth, Institute of Rural Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10817/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>