<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic livestock farming systems in the Massif Central: evolution (2008-2011) and analysis of the technical and economic performances and drivers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Veysset, Patrick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tauriac, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benoit, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Belvèze, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patout, O</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reuillon, J.-L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morin, E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vallas, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The “Organic Farming Massif Central” hub and fifteen partners lead a program on sustainability and on the technical and economic operation of OF livestock systems in the Massif Central. This systemic and multi-year study (2008-2011) is based on data from a constant sample over four years, from 56 farms comprising four types of products: cattle and sheep, dairy and meat. Over 4 years, the technical and economic results are quite stable, and at a good level, but with great variability inter-farms. With lower labor productivity, but with a more diversified crop rotation, a good food self-sufficiency and good technical skills, the farms with the highest income get an income more than four times higher than the farms with the lowest income .</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26782/1/Veysset_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Veysset, Patrick; Tauriac, R; Benoit, M.; Belvèze, J; Patout, O; Reuillon, J.-L.; Morin, E and Vallas, M   (2013) Organic livestock farming systems in the Massif Central: evolution (2008-2011) and analysis of the technical and economic performances and drivers.  [Les systèmes d’élevage agrobiologiques du Massif Central : évolution (2008-2011) et analyse transversale (trans-productions)des résultats technico-économiques et de leurs déterminants.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 317-331.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26782/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>