<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulierung annueller Samenunkräuter durch den Einsatz von Grünguthäcksel unter Bedingungen des ökologischen Landbaus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lux, Guido</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pötzsch, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtke, Knut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The cultivation of grain legumes is important for sustaining nitrogen availability in organic farming systems, but poses often problems with weed suppression. To improve soil conditions, nutrient availability and biological weed control for growing grain legumes in organic farming, green chop was applied to faba beans, peas and lupins into six field tests between 2009 and 2012. Equivalent yield performance after application of green chop was found compared to the control (without fertilization) and in 10 of 12 cases strong suppressive effects on the growth of annual weeds were observed and a reduced weed infestation resulted. A test with 10 different species of woody plant material shows the influence of the application rate of green chop and the kind of placement with regard to the sowing depth of the legumes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21233/1/21233_lux.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lux, Guido; Pötzsch, Frank and Schmidtke, Knut    (2013) Regulierung annueller Samenunkräuter durch den Einsatz von Grünguthäcksel unter Bedingungen des ökologischen Landbaus.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21233/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>