<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic grassland extension in Wales – experiences</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McCalman, Heather</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Evans, Bryan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morgan, Charlie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Duller, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Courtney, Deborah</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Grassland is the backbone of Welsh agriculture and agri-environmental policy incentives are encouraging organic farming across Wales. The Grassland Technology Transfer Project at IGER has offered a dedicated organic grassland extension service within Wales. In this paper the main activities and experience gained from working with farmers, scientists and other industry groups on grassland related issues are described. The role of the IGER organic dairy unit in the extension process is explored. Conversion to organic farming and interest in greater 'self sufficiency' by organic farmers in response to changes in organic standards and derogations required by 2003 have prompted enquiries on particular key issues which include crop rotations, cropping, reseeding and grassland improvement options.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8375/1/McCalman_grassland_extension_Wales.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>McCalman, Heather; Evans, Bryan; Morgan, Charlie; Duller, Chris and Courtney, Deborah    (2002) Organic grassland extension in Wales – experiences.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 109-112.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8375/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>