<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Moisture tempers impairment of adult Otiorhynchus sulcatus (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) climbing ability by fluoropolymer, talc dust, and lithium grease</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bomford, Michael K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vernon, Robert S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As part of a project to develop tools for the physical exclusion of flightless root weevils, adult black vine weevils (BVW), Otiorhynchus sulcatus (F.), were placed in open enclosures with smooth walls of glass, plastic or aluminum to test their ability to escape by climbing. Enclosure walls were left untreated or were treated with substances known to reduce insect climbing ability: fluoropolymer, powdered talc and lithium grease. No BVW escapes were observed under dry conditions, but all treatments allowed some escapes under wet conditions, suggesting that moisture helps BVW adults scale treated surfaces. The results help explain the ability of root weevils to overcome physical barriers under field conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Entomological Society of British Columbia</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8067/1/8067.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bomford, Michael K. and Vernon, Robert S.   (2005) Moisture tempers impairment of adult Otiorhynchus sulcatus (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) climbing ability by fluoropolymer, talc dust, and lithium grease.   Journal of the Entomological Society of British Columbia, 102, pp. 13-19.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8067/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>