<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Adoption and Abandonment of Organic Farming: An Emperical Investigation of the Irish Drystock Sector</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Läpple, Doris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a considerable literature about the adoption of organic farming. However,&#xD;
possible abandonment of organic farming has received scant attention.&#xD;
Thus, relatively little is known about the exit decisions of farmers. In addition,&#xD;
most studies are based on a static framework where it is not possible to account&#xD;
for changes in farmer decisions over time. This article attempts to fill this gap in&#xD;
the literature by investigating the determinants that affect both adoption and&#xD;
abandonment of organic drystock farming over time. The use of duration analysis&#xD;
allows for the consideration of cross-sectional and time-varying factors over&#xD;
the study period from 1981 to 2008. Using this dynamic econometric framework&#xD;
revealed a significant time effect on entry and exit decisions. Overall, the results&#xD;
highlight that where no attempt is made to account for exit decisions and time&#xD;
effects, important information about sustainable farmer decisions may not be&#xD;
taken into consideration.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Läpple, Doris   (2010) Adoption and Abandonment of Organic Farming: An Emperical Investigation of the Irish Drystock Sector.   Journal of Agricultural Economics, 61 (3), pp. 697-714.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22268/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>