<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How can we achieve 100% organic diets for pigs and poultry?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The question of quantity and quality of inputs that may be used is of high importance for the development of organic livestock production in light of the current revision of the European regulation on organic food.  The paper is based on the EU funded project Organic Revision and presents selected results concerning the question of independence from conventional inputs in relation to organic feed. Fundamental differences in the structure and in the relationship between input and output lead to completely different agro-ecosystems. This limits the relevance of recommendations derived form nutritional research in conventional systems for organic animal husbandry. The limitation of protein supply in organic systems represents not only a challenge but also an opportunity for improved quality. It is possible to formulate diets for pigs and poultry with only organic ingredients, although availability of protein can be problematic. Farmers can adopt a range of measures to reduce the demand for high quality protein sources in the diet of pigs and poultry.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Association of Applied Biologists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8956/1/Padel_Sundrum_100%25organic_feed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne and Sundrum, Albert    (2006) How can we achieve 100% organic diets for pigs and poultry?       Poster at:   What will organic farming deliver COR 2006, Edinburgh, 18-20 September 2006.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8956/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>