<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies for controlling Cirsium arvense in organic crop production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lukashyk, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berg, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract - Three strategies for controlling Cirsium arvense including (1) repeated stubble tillage with subsequent forage crop cultivation, (2) repeated mowing of a grass-clover ley, and (3) forage crop cultivation following a grass-clover ley ploughed in May/June were investigated in field experiments over 3 years. The development of C. arvense shoot density was regularly assessed on subplots with defined thistle densities. In the medium-term (9 months), repeated stubble tillage (treatment 1) decreased shoot density of C. arvense more effectively than a once mowed grass-clover ley (2). However, after 22 months, treatments 1 and 2 resulted in a similar strong reduction of C. arvense shoot density of 95 % and 97 %, respectively. At this time, the efficacy of treatment 3 was lower (89 %), however, not signifi-cantly different to that of treatments 1 and 2. After 26 months, the effect of all treatments was still appar-ent; however, the efficacy of treatment 3 was signifi-cantly lower than that of treatment 2. Generally, the different strategies showed only minor differences, thus delivering options for optimal strategies of this-tle control under given specific conditions of site and cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7251/1/C.arvense_Daenemark.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lukashyk, P.; Berg, M. and Köpke, U.    (2006) Strategies for controlling Cirsium arvense in organic crop production.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7251/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>