<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings 6th International Congress on Organic Viticulture</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The 6th International Congress on Organic Viticulture, held in Basel, Switzerland from the 25th to 26th of August 2000 in conjunction with the 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference, was organised by the Swiss Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau&#xD;
(FiBL), together with Schweizerischer Bioweinbauverein Biovin Suisse, Ecovin and Stiftung Ökologie &amp; Landbau (SÖL).&#xD;
The Congress had as its theme “Organic Viticulture - Quality, the key factor to success” and the importance of variety choice, soil management, plant protection and biodiversity for organic wine quality were discussed at this congress. An overview of organic viticulture world-wide was also given.&#xD;
The 6th International Organic Viticulture Congress in Basel is in the tradition of the organic viticulture congresses, the first of which was held in 1985 in Geisenheim (D), organised by the German organic wine growers’ association Ecovin. At this congress, the German standards for the production of organic grapes, grape juice, wine and champagne were launched. The 4th congress in Würzburg 1994 dealt with marketing, market development and the labelling of organic wine. The fifth congress, held in Bad Dürkheim 1995, was the first one to be organised by all German organic producer organisations&#xD;
and by Stiftung Ökologie &amp; Landbau, and it was also the first international organic viticulture congress. It dealt with questions of soil management and wine quality as well&#xD;
as farm management aspects. The proceedings of the 3rd, 4th and 5th conference were published by Stiftung Ökologie &amp; Landbau.&#xD;
&#xD;
Contents&#xD;
&#xD;
Vorwort Preface &#xD;
Preface of the Editors &#xD;
&#xD;
Session 01  - Marketing Opportunities and Consumer Expectations &#xD;
Chair: Randolf Kauer and Paulin Köpfer&#xD;
&#xD;
Biowein: Chancen der Vermarktung &#xD;
Thomas Vaterlaus&#xD;
&#xD;
Session  02 - Organic Viticulture World-Wide &#xD;
Chair: Helga Willer&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture World-Wide &#xD;
Bernward Geier Uwe Hofmann, Helga Willer&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Europe&#xD;
Helga Willer &amp; Raffaele Zanoli&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Austria &#xD;
Eva Schinnerl&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Croatia &#xD;
Jasminka Karoglan Kontic, Sonja Karoglan Todorovic, Ranko Tadic&#xD;
&#xD;
Ökologischer Weinbau in der Tschechischen Republik &#xD;
Jiri Sedlo&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in the Czech Republic&#xD;
Jiri Sedlo&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in France &#xD;
Monique Jonis&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Italy&#xD;
C Bazzocchi, S Tellarini, R Zanoli&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Georgia &#xD;
Tamaz Tourmanidze&#xD;
&#xD;
Ökologischer Weinbau in Deutschland &#xD;
Paulin Köpfer und Eva Gehr&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Germany &#xD;
Paulin Köpfer und Eva Gehr&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Greece&#xD;
Marios Dessyllas&#xD;
&#xD;
Ökoweinbau in Ungarn &#xD;
L Szõke, K Németh- J Mikulás&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant Protection in Organic Viticulture in New Zealand &#xD;
Andreas Welte&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Portugal&#xD;
Ana Firmino&#xD;
&#xD;
Developments in Organic Viticulture in South Africa &#xD;
Rupert van der Merwe&#xD;
&#xD;
Bioweinbau in der Schweiz &#xD;
Andreas Häseli&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Switzerland &#xD;
Andreas Häseli&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture in Turkey&#xD;
Ahmet Altýndiºli&#xD;
&#xD;
Traditional Viticulture in Southern East Anatolia:&#xD;
A case study for Siirt, Turkey&#xD;
ÝYýldýrým and ENYardým&#xD;
&#xD;
Session 03 - Soil Management – Care and Quality &#xD;
Chair: Uwe Hofman&#xD;
&#xD;
Comparisons of Chemical Analysis and Biological Activity of Soils Cultivated by Organic and Biodynamic Methods &#xD;
Claude Bourguignon and Lydia Gabucci&#xD;
&#xD;
Function of the Soil in the Expression of the "Terroir" &#xD;
Claude Bourguignon and Lydia Gabbucci&#xD;
&#xD;
Cover Cropping in California Vineyards: Part of a Biologically Integrated&#xD;
Farming System &#xD;
Robert L Bugg, Richard W Hoenisch&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant Biodiversity and Biological Control of Insect Pests in a Northern California Organic Vineyard&#xD;
Clara I Nicholls and Miguel A Altieri&#xD;
&#xD;
Standortgerechte Bodenpflege und die Vitalität und Bonität im Wein- und Obstbau &#xD;
Franz Solar&#xD;
&#xD;
Role of Nature in Soil Management and Quality&#xD;
Anjani Suchde, Deepak Suchde&#xD;
&#xD;
The Use of Recycled Organics Compost in Viticulture- A review of theinternational literature and experience - &#xD;
Johannes Biala&#xD;
&#xD;
Biological Activity of Upper Vaucluse Soils &#xD;
Marc Duplan, François Warlop&#xD;
&#xD;
Dry Stone Walls in Switzerland&#xD;
Martin Lutz, Theodor Schmidt, Gerhard Stoll&#xD;
&#xD;
Soil Microbial Biomass and Soil Quality in Vineyards&#xD;
Stephan Reuter and Roland Kubiak&#xD;
&#xD;
Session 04 - Plant Protection and Quality - New Findings and Future Hazards &#xD;
Chair: Lucius Tamm&#xD;
&#xD;
Principles for Managing the Foliage Diseases of Grapevine with low Input of Pesticides &#xD;
PA Magarey, RD Magarey and RW Emmett&#xD;
&#xD;
Management of Major Arthropod Pests in Organic Viticulture &#xD;
S Kreiter&#xD;
&#xD;
Biodiversity of Phytoseiid Mites and Outbreaks of Tetranychid Mites in Vineyards with Different Protection Management&#xD;
G Bigot and P Zandigiacomo&#xD;
&#xD;
Efficacy Evaluation of Different Low-rate Copper Formulations and Acupric Compounds Against Grapevine Downy Mildew (Plasmopara viticola) in Piedmont (Northwestern&#xD;
Italy) During the Period - &#xD;
D Ferrari, E Bassignana and G Pensabene&#xD;
&#xD;
Contributions to Environmentally Safe Plant Protection Systems in Grapevine Cultivation&#xD;
Dr B Fischer-Trimborn, Prof Dr HC Weltzien, Dr G Schruft&#xD;
Kupferminimierung und Einsatz von Tonerden zur &#xD;
&#xD;
Peronosporabekämpfung im ökologischen Weinbau&#xD;
Dr Uwe Hofmann&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant Protection Strategies Against Downy Mildew in Organic Viticulture Copper Reduction and Copper Replacement - Results and Experiences of Years on Farm Research &#xD;
Dr Uwe Hofmann&#xD;
&#xD;
Investigations on the Effect of Extremely Low Copper Doses&#xD;
and Different Copper Formulations &#xD;
W K Kast&#xD;
&#xD;
Salicylic and Phosphorous Acid – Possible Alternative of Copper? &#xD;
W K Kast&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Viticulture Without Sulfur?  Years of Experience With Sodiumand Potassiumbicarbonate&#xD;
RKauer , BGaubatz , MWöhrle , UKornitzer , HRSchultz , BKirchner&#xD;
&#xD;
Reduced Root Damage in Organically Managed Phylloxera-Infested Vineyards in California&#xD;
Donald W Lotter, PhD&#xD;
&#xD;
Controlling Vine Powdery and Downy Mildews with the Urticum Preparation&#xD;
V Robotić, R Bosančíć and M Mojić&#xD;
&#xD;
Side Effect of Pesticides Used in Organic Viticulture and Based on Copper, Sulphur and Bacillus thuringiensis on the Populations of the Predatory mite Phytoseius finitimus&#xD;
IC Rumbos, PPapaioannou-Souliotis, I Adamopoulos and D Markoyiannaki- Printzioy&#xD;
&#xD;
Use of weather stations in organic viticulture&#xD;
L Tamm, A Häseli, and D Levite&#xD;
&#xD;
Session 05 - Varietes for Organic Viticulture an Quality&#xD;
Chair: Pierre Basler&#xD;
&#xD;
Pilzwiderstandsfähige Rebenneuzuchten -Ein möglicher Beitrag zum umweltschonenden Weinbau &#xD;
Dr Norbert Becker&#xD;
&#xD;
The Development of Interspecific Grapevine Hybrids in Ontario, Canada&#xD;
K Helen Fisher&#xD;
&#xD;
Gegen Pilzkrankheiten resistente Traubensorten und ihre Qualität&#xD;
Hajdu, E, - Ésik, E, - Borbás, É, - Pernesz, Gy&#xD;
&#xD;
Testage et sélection de cépages résistants&#xD;
Groupe suisse pour la sélection de variétés résistantes aux maladies (not available in the internet version)&#xD;
Results From new Fungus-tolerant Grapevine Varieties for Organic Viticulture &#xD;
A L Schwab, R Knott and W Schottdorf&#xD;
&#xD;
Neue Rebsorten und Sortenkandidaten im umweltschonenden Weinbau &#xD;
L Szőke, P Kozma und K Németh&#xD;
&#xD;
The Autochthon Grape ”Shesh” and the Potential for Organic Wine &#xD;
Zigori Vangjel and Zigori Klod&#xD;
&#xD;
Session 06 - Determining Wine Quality &#xD;
Chair: Norbert Drescher&#xD;
&#xD;
Quality of Organic Wines &#xD;
Nicolas Joly&#xD;
&#xD;
Quality is More Than Actual Natural Sciences can Define &#xD;
Hartmut Heilmann&#xD;
&#xD;
Verknüpfung von Tradition und Moderne im ökologischen Weinbau am Beispiel des Mondes - Praktische Umsetzung von längst genutzten sowie neueren wissenschaftlichen Parametern &#xD;
Frank E Neufing&#xD;
&#xD;
Production of Wine Without Sulphur Dioxide Using Appropriate Processing Technology&#xD;
Franco Battistutta, Emilio Celotti, Roberto Zironi&#xD;
Differentiation of Wines Produced by Organic or Conventional Viticulture&#xD;
&#xD;
According to Their Sensory Profiles and Aroma Composition&#xD;
Isabelle Dupin; Pascal Schlich; Ulrich Fischer&#xD;
&#xD;
Öko-Weine elektrochemisch betrachtet&#xD;
Hoffmann, M&#xD;
&#xD;
Novel Methods to Characterise Wine Quality -Examinations with Wines from Exact Field Experiments (Organic Viticulture – Integrated Viticulture)&#xD;
RKauer , HRSchultz , JBolanz&#xD;
&#xD;
Preliminary Results on Contents of Resveratrol in Wine of Organic and Conventional Vineyards&#xD;
D Levite, M Adrian and L Tamm&#xD;
&#xD;
Appendix&#xD;
Conference proceedings of the Organic Viticulture Congresses &#xD;
&#xD;
Sponsors, Steering Committee, Club of Chairpersons,&#xD;
&#xD;
Task Force Wine Tasting</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL) und Stiftung Ökologie &amp; Landbau (SÖL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Meier, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/548/1/willer-meier-2000-winecongress.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga and Meier, Urs (Eds.)    (2000) Proceedings 6th International Congress on Organic Viticulture.   Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL) und Stiftung Ökologie &amp; Landbau (SÖL), SÖL-Sonderausgabe, no. Nr. 77.  Proceedings of 6th International Congress on Organic Viticulture, Convention Center Basel, 25 and 26 August 2000.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/548/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>