<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Probleme konventioneller Hersteller beim Einstieg in die Öko-Vermarktung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dienel, Dr. Wolfram</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Large food companies rarely produce organic products in Germany. Core problems on the economic level are:&#xD;
•	The target groups of the organic market are too small. Market increase requires the exploration of new target groups beyond the typical consumer of organic food.&#xD;
•	Small units lead to high costs per unit and to a vicious circle of too high prices and buying abstinence (in spite of “eco-affinity”).&#xD;
•	Organizational deficits in the marketing chain and inside enterprises hamper a proactive eco-marketing.&#xD;
There are also problems at the psychological level: The management in conventional food industry fears discrimination of their conventional range and therefore a loss in total turnover. However, this fear is not supported by any empirical experience. In contrast, positive image spill-over effects from the organic range towards the conventional range could be observed. We observed two reasons for this virtual threat:&#xD;
•	No conviction in the potential for demands of organic products.&#xD;
•	Emotional resistance against the lifestyle criticism of the organic movement.&#xD;
Prospect: Marketing and organizational problems require an active Marketing-Chain-Management inside and outside of enterprise borders. In a horizontal cooperation processors should develop a joint eco-marketing for their organic supplies. Motivational resistance has to be solved before looking for technical or economical solutions.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3608/1/3608.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dienel, Dr. Wolfram    (2005) Probleme konventioneller Hersteller beim Einstieg in die Öko-Vermarktung.  [Problems of Food Industry in the Transition toward Organic Markets.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3608/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>