<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>P, K, Mg, S und N-Versorgung von Mischfruchtanbausystemen mit Ölpflanzen im ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paulsen, Hans Marten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schochow, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Oil crops can be integrated in organic crop rotations in mixed cropping with other crops. The cropping system achieves only low oilseed yields but increases productivity per area in total yield. In theory soil nutrients in mixed cropping systems can be used more efficiently due to different root architecture and growing times of the plants. But even the nutrient demand should increase with higher productivity. In the study nutri¬ent content and uptake of seeds and straw of mixtures of winter rape with winter-barley, peas, or rye, of spring peas with spring rape, mustard or false flax, of blue lupine with safflower or false flax, of spring wheat with linseed or false flax and of linseed with false flax were screened. Productivity per area was increased in many cases and nutrient contents of plants in the mixtures were frequently elevated com-pared to sole cropping systems. Nutrient demand of mixed cropping is elevated due to its higher productivity and often determined by the suppressive partner.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9513/1/9513_Paulsen_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paulsen, Hans Marten and Schochow, Martin    (2007) P, K, Mg, S und N-Versorgung von Mischfruchtanbausystemen mit Ölpflanzen im ökologischen Landbau.  [P, K, Mg, S and N-supply of organic mixed cropping systems with oil crops.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9513/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>