<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Phytosanitary protocol for the establishment of grapevine certified organic mother plant fields</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>IYED, Kacem</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In Europe, similarly to propagation material for conventional agriculture, the grapevine organic propagating material must have a certified sanitary status and comply with the requirements of the legislation (EU Reg. 193/68 and Italian D.P.R. N°1164). In organic farming considering the low availability of means to control virus and virus-like disease vector populations and potential virus sources (herbaceous species) it is important to evaluate and prevent all risks of vine reinfection. In three potential suitable fields the following risks have been analysed and evaluated: a) presence of transmissible viruses in spontaneous herbaceous flora (by ELISA and biological assays) and in the surrounding vineyards (by ELISA); b) presence of virus and phytoplasma vectors through monitoring  of populations (nematodes by soil nematological analysis, leafhoppers and planthoppers by chromatotrophysm capturing, mealybugs by direct observation of vine plants). A study on the efficiency of biorational pesticides in controlling mealybug populations has been carried out in vitro and in vivo using 5 different commercial products.The three fields selected for the absence of vector populations and alternative grapevine virus sources, resulting free from grapevine virus and phytoplasma reinfection risks are suitable to establish grapevine certified organic mother blocks.Only rotenone and mineral oil showed a limited efficiency (less than 50% of mortality) in controlling mealybug populations and neither significant differences nor phytotoxic effects have been observed between the recommended dose and the double dose.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6473/1/KacemIyed02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>IYED, Kacem   (2002) Phytosanitary protocol for the establishment of grapevine certified organic mother plant fields.  [Protocole phytosanitaire pour l’établissement de parcelles de plantes mères biologiques certifiées.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Tesi Master of Science, no. 278. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6473/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>