<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hydrothermisch behandelte Lupinen zur Eiweißversorgung der Milchkuh</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schöneborn, Frau Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freitag, Frau Mechtild</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pries, Herr Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauswald, Frau Anja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiekers, Herr H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to producer statements hydrothermal treatment of lupines increases the amount of rumen undegradable protein (UDP) from 20 % to 45 % and nXP values from 196 to 245 g/kg thus providing sufficient protein for dairy cows. To evaluate the effects of hydrothermal treatment on nutritive value of lupines, intestinal protein supply and lactation performance as well as economical and ecological efficiency, a nine months feeding trial was carried out at the Agricultural Centre Haus Riswick, Kleve. Two groups of 20 cows blocked by milk yield, parity and expected calving date were fed a forage diet of grass-clover and corn silage enriched with 3 kg of concentrates (46 % blue lupine, 41 % triticale, 10 % wheat bran, 2 % mineral feed, 1 % rape oil), sufficient for 25 kg ECM (DLG, 2001). Nutrient values per kg dry matter were as follows (control/experiment): 6,8 / 6,8 MJ NEL, 168 / 168 g XP, 144 / 148 g nXP, 3,9 / 3,2 g RNB. Nutritive value of lupines was determined by feeding wethers according to standard procedure (GfE, 1991). Protein fractions were analysed according to Shannak et al. (2000). Experimental groups varied only in lupine treatment (Börde Kraftkorn, Gröningen, GER). &#xD;
Yield of natural and energy corrected milk (ECM), milk fat and milk protein were higher in cows fed treated lupines (p &lt;0,001). Urea nitrogen concentration was marginally lower compared to controls (p &lt;0,001). Improvement of lactational performance was slightly higher during the first 100 days of lactation, but persisted during the whole lactational period. Body weight and condition were not affected by treatment. Improved lactational performance resulted in an overall better economic result.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3739/1/3739.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schöneborn, Frau Angelika; Freitag, Frau Mechtild; Pries, Herr Martin; Hauswald, Frau Anja and Spiekers, Herr H.    (2005) Hydrothermisch behandelte Lupinen zur Eiweißversorgung der Milchkuh.  [Hydrothermically Treated Lupines to Ensure Protein Supply for Dairy Cows.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3739/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>