<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Profitability of sow husbandry in organic farming– &#xD;
Performance and construction costs for group housing of lactating sows</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lange, Dipl-Ing. agr. Katja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Prof. Dr. Detlev</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The group housing of lactating sows represents an economically interesting and also animal welfare alternative to the otherwise usual individual housing in this phase. Aim of this study is to fill existing information gaps and create more planning security.&#xD;
The performance efficiency of the housing system is determined on the basis of biological parameters, based on empirical data of a co-operation project. The influ-ence of the housing system on the construction costs for housing sows is examined by construction models, which are defined on the basis of empirical data and by an expert interview.&#xD;
Better performance data are reached by the group housing system analysed here compared to other studies. The results show that the housing system is both suitable and efficient on farm level.&#xD;
The group housing of lactating sows causes a reduction of construction costs. This difference is especially noticeable when modifying existing buildings. The saving potential is 993 € per housing place.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11686/1/Lange_11686_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lange, Dipl-Ing. agr. Katja and Möller, Prof. Dr. Detlev    (2008) Profitability of sow husbandry in organic farming– Performance and construction costs for group housing of lactating sows.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11686/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>