<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil heath: a comparison between organically and conventionally managed arable soils in the netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Diepeningen, Anne D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blok, Wim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Korthals, Gerhard W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Bruggen, Ariena H.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A comparative study of 13 organic and 13 neighboring conventional arable farming systems was conducted in the Netherlands to determine the effect of management practices on chemical and biological soil properties and soil health. Soils were analyzed using a polyphasic approach combining traditional soil analysis, culture-dependent and independent microbiological analyses, a nematode community analysis and an enquiry about different management practices among the farmers. Organic management resulted in significantly lower levels of both nitrate and total soluble nitrogen in the soil, higher numbers of bacteria of different trophic groups, as well as larger species richness in both bacteria and nematode communities and more resilience to a drying-rewetting disturbance in the soil. All factors together indicating a higher level of soil health under organic management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4336/4/vanDiepeningen_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Diepeningen, Anne D.; Blok, Wim; Korthals, Gerhard W. and van Bruggen, Ariena H.C.    (2005) Soil heath: a comparison between organically and conventionally managed arable soils in the netherlands.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4336/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>