<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Flourescence Excitation Spectroscopy for the Evaluation of Seeds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strube, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The measurement of the emission of light from entire samples is a non-destructive system that is already in use for inspecting foods. The biophoton flourescence excitation spectroscopy presented here differs from the classical biophoton evaluations in that its evaluation follows excitation by different wavelengths of light. Selected groups of foods generate typical spectral distributions. These are suitable as the basis for evaluation when inspecting foods, especially seeds such as grains, peas and beans, oilseeds etc. from test cultures using a variety of cultivation methods. In 1997 and 1998, Markus Buchmann and Christian Hiss performed comparative plantings of beans both without earth (hydroponics) and with earth (biodynamic). Coded samples from these test plantings were examined using induced luminescence. The individual growing procedures were able to be markedly differentiated statistically. There were demonstrable differences in the seeds after two generations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IFOAM</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2331/1/2331-strube-j-et-al-2000-spectroscopy-ifoam.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strube, Jürgen and Stolz, Peter    (2000) Flourescence Excitation Spectroscopy for the Evaluation of Seeds.   In: Alföldi, Thomas; Lockeretz, William and Niggli, Urs (Eds.)  Proceedings 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference, IFOAM, pp. 306-309.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2331/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>