<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erarbeitung von Schwellenwerten zur gezielten Bekämpfung&#xD;
von Zwergsteinbrand (Tilletia controversa) und Steinbrand&#xD;
(Tilletia caries) sowie deren praktische Umsetzung im Öko-&#xD;
Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dressler, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sedlmeier, Berta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Voit, Benno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Büttner, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Killermann, Berta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Dwarf bunt of wheat (Tilletia controversa) and common bunt of wheat (Tilletia caries)&#xD;
are the most important pathogens in organic cereal production. The aim of this&#xD;
research work is to find out whether a threshold value for seed is sufficient or whether&#xD;
the infection potential in the soil must be considered additionally.&#xD;
For dwarf bunt of wheat two-years-lasting field trials are performed at 3 sites with&#xD;
susceptible and low-susceptible wheat and spelt cultivars, 4 infection levels and 4&#xD;
replications. The field trials are designed in a randomized split-block design with&#xD;
additional marginal-plots, so (1) sowing and harvest will be possible without greater&#xD;
interaction between the field plots, (2) spore contamination of the soil during harvest&#xD;
will be assured and (3) the determination of spore inoculum density in the soil after&#xD;
harvest will be enabled. Only fields with natural spore contamination are chosen. The&#xD;
field trials for common bunt of wheat are carried out in a similar design with 4&#xD;
replicates at 4 sites with susceptible and low-susceptible wheat cultivars and two&#xD;
different sowing times.&#xD;
For an infestation with dwarf bunt of wheat, diffuse light is sufficient. The wheat&#xD;
cultivar Capo showed a significantly lower infestation than the cultivar Saturnus. The&#xD;
infestation of the spelt cultivar Franckenkorn was significantly lower than that of the&#xD;
cultivar Oberkulmer Rotkorn, with the infestation of spelt cultivars being in principle&#xD;
lower because of morphological features. The greatest significant number of infested&#xD;
spikes per m² was found in the variant soil infection. With the dwarf bunt of wheat&#xD;
results from the first year no threshold values can be determined neither for seed nor&#xD;
for soil.&#xD;
In the case of infestation with common bunt of wheat, there were no significant&#xD;
differences between the early and late sowing dates, nor between the cultivars Capo&#xD;
and Tommi. The highest bunt spore potential in the soil was found at the field trial site&#xD;
in Saxony; however, the highest number of infested spikes per m² was not found&#xD;
there.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14193/1/Dressler_14193.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dressler, Markus; Sedlmeier, Berta; Voit, Benno; Büttner, Peter and Killermann, Berta    (2009) Erarbeitung von Schwellenwerten zur gezielten Bekämpfung von Zwergsteinbrand (Tilletia controversa) und Steinbrand (Tilletia caries) sowie deren praktische Umsetzung im Öko- Landbau.  [Elaboration of threshold values for efficient control of dwarf bunt (Tilletia controversa) and common bunt of wheat (Tilletia caries) and their transformation into practice in organic farming.]      Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14193/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>