<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimizing nitrogen utilization by integrating crop and animal production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seuri, Pentti</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The farm model was built according to the data from 9 Finnish organic farms. 20% of area produced cash crop and 80% was used as fodder in milk production on the farm.  The model indicates that there is high potential (up to 30% compared to Finnish average) to reduce nitrogen losses in agriculture. The key factors are integration between crop and animal production, limited nutrient intensity according to the system itself and BNF. &#xD;
&#xD;
The crop rotation used in model can support milk production with relative high intensity. In this  model no external fodder is used, however, it may be necessary to have a small amount of high quality processed protein concentrate, if the annual milk yield exceeds 8000 kg/cow. Crop yield by means of nitrogen yield was about 10% lower compared to Finnish average.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24062/1/24062.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seuri, Pentti    (2014) Optimizing nitrogen utilization by integrating crop and animal production.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 259-262.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24062/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>