<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumers of organic products in France: first results of the Nutrinet-Santé cohort</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kesse-Guyot, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Péneau, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Méjean, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szabo de Edelenyi, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Galan, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hercberg, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lairon, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lifestyle, dietary patterns and nutritional status of organic food consumers have rarely been described, while interest for a sustainable diet is markedly increasing. Consumer attitude and frequency of use of 18 organic products were assessed in 54,311 adult participants in the Nutrinet-Santé cohort. Cluster analysis was performed to identify behaviors associated with organic product consumption. Cross-sectional association with overweight/obesity was estimated using polytomous logistic regression. Five clusters were identified: 3 clusters of non-consumers (35%) whose reasons differed, occasional (OCOP, 51%) and regular (RCOP, 14%) organic product consumers. RCOP were more highly educated and physically active than others. They exhibited dietary patterns with more plant foods and less sweet and alcoholic beverages, processed meat or milk. Their nutrient intake profiles (fatty acids, most minerals and vitamins, fibers) were healthier and closer to dietary guidelines. In multivariate models (after accounting for confounders, including level of adherence to nutritional guidelines), compared to those not interested in organic products, RCOP participants showed a markedly lower probability of overweight (excluding obesity) and obesity :-36% and -62% in men and -42% and -48% in women, respectively (P&lt;0.0001). OCOP participants generally showed intermediate figures. In conclusion, regular consumers of organic products exhibit specific socio-demographic characteristics, and an overall healthy profile.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26297/1/Lairon_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kesse-Guyot, E.; Péneau, S.; Méjean, C.; Szabo de Edelenyi, F.; Galan, P.; Hercberg, S. and Lairon, D.   (2013) Consumers of organic products in France: first results of the Nutrinet-Santé cohort.  [Profil des consommateurs de produits bio en France : premières données de l’Etude Nutrinet-Santé.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 15-20.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26297/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>