<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Current situations in organic cereal seed offer in the Czech Republic</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huda, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmers are obliged, in compliance with the valid legislation, to use seed originating from the organic production when establishing the crop stands. In a survey we found certified organic cereal seed is used on 6 %, conventional untreated seed on 37 %, and farm seed on 57 % (of the organically farmed area in the Czech Republic). The main reasons for that are as follows: the insufficient surface of land intended for the reproduction of organic seed, the low proportion of accepted seed coming from the accepted reproduction surface. Therefore, low-quality farm seed is used on a large proportion of organically farmed land, which has a negative effect on the yield level of the cereals. These observations were also confirmed by results obtained in a farmer survey. Farmers indicated that they are interested in certified organic seed if it is available. However, the sufficient supply and favourable prices are important for them.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioinstitut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sarapatka, Borivoj</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20758/1/CZU_2011_PK_Aktu%C3%A1ln%C3%AD_situace__-_bioosiva.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Konvalina, Petr; Stehno, Zdenek; Capouchova, Ivana; Huda, Petr; Moudry, Jan and Moudry, Jan (Jr.)    (2011) Current situations in organic cereal seed offer in the Czech Republic.   In: Sarapatka, Borivoj (Ed.)  Proceedings, Bioinstitut, Olomouc, 1, pp. 33-37.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20758/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>