<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of condensed tannins on established populations and on incoming larvae of   Trichostrongylus colubriformis and Teladorsagia circumcincta  in goats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Virginie, PAOLINI</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andrey, FRAYSSINES</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>France, DE LA FARGE</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Philipe, DORCHIES</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hervé, HOSTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The use of tanniferous plants or tannins represents one alternative approach to the&#xD;
control of gastrointestinal parasites in ruminants but most data have been obtained in sheep. The&#xD;
current study was therefore performed in goats with two objectives: firstly, to investigate the effects&#xD;
of condensed tannins (CT) on adult populations of Trichostrongylus colubriformis and Teladorsagia&#xD;
circumcincta; secondly, to examine their effects on the establishment of infective larvae of these&#xD;
two species. In experiment 1, two groups of kids were infected with 6 000 L3 of T. colubriformis&#xD;
and 6 000 L3 of T. circumcincta. After 7 weeks, quebracho extracts were administered per os for&#xD;
8 days to one group. A comparable group which did not receive tannins was included as the control.&#xD;
The kids were slaughtered on week 11. Parasitological and pathophysiological parameters were&#xD;
measured weekly. Worm counts were assessed and mast cells, globule leukocytes and eosinophils&#xD;
were counted in the abomasal and intestinal mucosae. Tannin administration was associated with a&#xD;
decrease in egg excretion, and a decrease in female fecundity, but with no changes in worm numbers.&#xD;
These changes were associated with an increased number of intestinal mast cells. In experiment&#xD;
2, 24 goats were used according to a 2  2 factorial design, depending on infection and tannin&#xD;
administration. Two groups were either infected with 6 000 L3 of T. colubriformis or T. circumcincta.&#xD;
Within each group, the goats were either drenched or undrenched with tannin extracts.&#xD;
Pathophysiological parameters were measured weekly. Twelve days after the cessation of tannin&#xD;
administration, the goats were slaughtered. Worm counts and female worm fecundity were determined.&#xD;
Tannin consumption was associated with a significant reduction (P &lt; 0.001) of Trichostrongylus&#xD;
populations and a close to significant reduction for Teladorsagia. No effect on fecundity&#xD;
was observed. Our results (1) confirm the consequences of condensed tannins on nematodes in goats&#xD;
as in sheep and (2) indicate divergent effects depending on the parasitic stage exposed to the condensed&#xD;
tannins.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6993/1/V3303e1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Virginie, PAOLINI; Andrey, FRAYSSINES; France, DE LA FARGE; Philipe, DORCHIES and Hervé, HOSTE   (2003) Effects of condensed tannins on established populations and on incoming larvae of Trichostrongylus colubriformis and Teladorsagia circumcincta in goats.   Vet. Res. (34), pp. 1-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6993/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>