<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Final report for Project no. 1904.&#xD;
Prevention of selected diseases and parasites in organic pig hreds - by means of HACCP based management and surveillance programme (CorePig)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rousing, Tine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project partners comprised about 20 researchers from 9 research institutes in eight countries (DK, DE, SE, UK, CH, IT, AU and FR). The project is composed of three work packages:  WP1 „Coordination of the project, dissemination and Knowledge synthesis‟,  WP2: „Epidemiological study in organic herds‟ and  WP3: „Development and evaluation of a HACCP based surveillance and management system‟. WP1 and WP2 started in 2007, while WP3 that built on the results from WP1 and WP2 started later - in 2008. The UK and CH-partners only participated in WP1 and WP3 while the remaining partners participated in all three WP‟s.   The project was initiated at the project kick-off meeting in Denmark, August 30-31st 2007, where all project partners met to discuss the planning of the project in detail. Further 6 project meetings were carried out in the project period. The second project meeting was organised in Austria, December 10-11th 2007, the third project meeting in Denmark, February 18-19th 2008, the fourth in France, July 7-9th 2008, the fifth in Italy, December 4.-7th 2008, the sixth in Sweden, June 29-30th 2009 and the final and seventh project meeting took place in Germany, April 7-10th 2010.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20573/1/20573.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rousing, Tine         (2011) Final report for Project no. 1904. Prevention of selected diseases and parasites in organic pig hreds - by means of HACCP based management and surveillance programme (CorePig).    University of Aarhus.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20573/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>