<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison between the effect of compost teas and copper on potato crop protection</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Khorchani,  Slaheddine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This work consists in studying the efficiency of various compost teas prepared from 4 different types of compost and according to various methods (aerobic and anaerobic) for the protection against the principal fungal diseases of potato. This is through two separate tests: the first, carried out in the field, consists to compare the treatments by compost tea with those by copper on organic potato crop against the late blight (Phytophthora infestans). The second, conducted in the laboratory, consists in the experimentation of these same compost teas in comparison with copper against two other fungi of potato: Rhizoctonia solani and Alternaria sp. on medium. With the field test, copper supported the best-obtained results. The best compost is compost 4 as well as the anaerobic preparation is more effective than that aerobic. However, we can note that aerobic treatments could present average outputs higher than those of the anaerobic treatments.Concerning the laboratory tests, the extracts of compost 4 were most effective among the other composts used with a very satisfying capacity of limitation. In fact, in the case of Alternaria sp., the anaerobic extract of compost 4 (T4N) and in the second place that aerobic (T4A) were comparable with copper whereas for R. solani, these compost teas had a good level of efficiency but while remaining always lower than copper.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6861/1/6861.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Khorchani, Slaheddine   (2003) Comparison between the effect of compost teas and copper on potato crop protection.  [Eude comparative de l’effet de compost liquide et de cuivre sur la protection de la culture de pomme de terre.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 327. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6861/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>