<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Marketing-Chain-Management auf Ökomärkten in Mittel- und Osteuropa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reuter, Katharina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study focuses on chances and risks for the further development of the organic sector in Central and Eastern European countries and also provides recommendations for the implementation of marketing chain management tools. Domestic markets for organic products in most countries focused on are only at the stage of emerging, organic products cover no more than a niche. Limited capital resources and problems with liquidity among producers and processing enterprises obstruct investments. At present, strong supply dynamics and limited domestic demand are being observed in these countries. Regarding the supply with organic raw material these countries will become more important. But only export-oriented production with a competitive price strategy cannot - on a long-term basis - guarantee a sound growth of the organic sector and secure income from organic agriculture. &#xD;
The development of the organic markets lacks networking between policy makers, farmers, market actors and scientists. For the successful advancement of the organic sector following actions are necessary: an increase of processing capacities and the development of trade channels. Clear support from national policy makers can stabilize and develop the growth of the organic market. Only those countries that succeed in developing a domestic market for organic products will be able to produce independently of importing countries and of pricing pressure.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3614/1/3614.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Reuter, Katharina    (2005) Marketing-Chain-Management auf Ökomärkten in Mittel- und Osteuropa.  [Marketing chain management on organic markets in central- and eastern Europe.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3614/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>