<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Indikatoren zur Erfassung genetischer Vielfalt in biologischen und nicht-biologischen Landwirtschaftssystemen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Last, Luisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arndorfer, Michaela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bailey, Debra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Balázs, Katalin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dennis, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dyman, Tetyana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fjellstad, Wendy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garchi, Salah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geijzendorffer, Ilse</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herzog, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeanneret, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jongman, Rob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kainz, Maximilian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Gisela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moreno, Gerado</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nkwiine, Charles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paoletti, Maurizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pointereau, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarthou, Jean Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stoyanova, Siyka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfrum , Sebastian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kölliker, Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetic variability is the fundament of life. Large genetic variability within species is the basis for adaptation to changing environmental conditions. Farmers and breeders have developed a multitude of crop cultivars and animal breeds to stabilize and increase quality and productivity. This study evaluated genetic diversity within different organic and non-organic farming systems using crop-cultivar and livestock-breed information as simple indicators. Data was collected using on-farm surveys in 15 case study regions in Europe and beyond. Selected indicators revealed strong differences of cultivar diversity between different countries and farming systems across Europe. No or only small differences were detectable between organic and non-organic farming systems. Landraces, as on-farm genetic resources, were under-represented in European case study regions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21281/1/21281_Last.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Last, Luisa; Arndorfer, Michaela; Bailey, Debra; Balázs, Katalin; Dennis, Peter; Dyman, Tetyana; Fjellstad, Wendy; Friedel, Jürgen K.; Garchi, Salah; Geijzendorffer, Ilse; Herzog, Felix; Jeanneret, Philippe; Jongman, Rob; Kainz, Maximilian; Lüscher, Gisela; Moreno, Gerado; Nkwiine, Charles; Paoletti, Maurizio; Pointereau, Philippe; Sarthou, Jean Pierre; Schneider, Manuel; Stoyanova, Siyka; Wolfrum , Sebastian and Kölliker, Roland    (2013) Indikatoren zur Erfassung genetischer Vielfalt in biologischen und nicht-biologischen Landwirtschaftssystemen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21281/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>