<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Australian Organic Market Report 2008</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristiansen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smithson, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monk, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henryks, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Being four years since the publication of a similar research document, the Australian Organic Market Report (AOMR) 2008 is a landmark report for the organic industry. The report will be invaluable for monitoring and planning the industry development during a period of high growth. &#xD;
  Delivering consistent data for benchmarking growth across the various sectors of the industry, it will be a key tool for decision making by organic producers and marketers, along with interested parties such as government and media, in assisting in understanding the nature, size and development of the organic industry in Australia. &#xD;
  Supply chain development has been hindered over many years by a lack of basic information about volumes, seasonality, continuity and quality, not only making it difficult for potentially new members of industry to feel confident about investing in organic, however also likely to cause overseas buyers to look for other countries with more comprehensive industry information.&#xD;
  The report is an important base research document required by any growing industry. It has been commissioned by Biological Farmers of Australia (BFA), and has been carried out independently by the University of New England’s Organic Research Group. The report has the financial support of major sponsor Westpac Bank, all State Governments in Australia as well as many dedicated industry businesses.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14039/1/14039.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristiansen, P.; Smithson, A.; Monk, A. and Henryks, J.         (2008) Australian Organic Market Report 2008.    Biological Farmers Australia, Brisbane.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14039/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>