<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Administration of Silver Fir (Abies alba Mill.) to goats and its potential to control gastro-intestinal parasites</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giebler-Schubert, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fertig, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamburger, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Potterat, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valle-Zárate, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Gastrointestinal nematodes (GIN) substantially impact on goat health. Because of the widespread development of GIN, resistant to allopathic drugs, further research into alternative parasite control methods is required [1]. Silver fir, Abies alba MILL (SF), is traditionally used by Swiss farmers in order to control GIN infections of goats but also to improve animal welfare. A survey among goat farmers revealed that goat farmers use SF in winter during a period of approximately five months. The SF-ration per animal and day differ between approximately 8.2 g dry matter (DM) to 600 g DM [2].&#xD;
&#xD;
As there is scientific evidence neither for an anthelmintic potential nor for the feed intake and milk performance of SF, we conducted a study with 30 goats. For a 20 days feeding experiment one group of 15 goats (A) was, additionally to their basic ration, daily fed with SF. The remaining 15 goats (group B) were fed with the basic ration only. Individual faecal egg counts (FEC) were conducted of all goats. Furthermore the effects of SF on the intake of the basic ration, milk yield and ingredients were tested. Total phenols (TP) and essential oils (EO) of 12 representative samples of the administered SF were determined by steam distillation and GS-MS-Analytic, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
SF contained 1,8 % TP. Limonene, bornyl acetate and beta caryophyllene were identified as the main EO. SF-feeding did not result in a reduction of GIN FEC (Fig 1). The intake of SF per animal and day was 261 +/- 0.22 g DM. Although SF reduced the basic forage intake significantly, SF increased the total DM intake significantly (A: 1948 +/- 93 g DM; B: 1797 +/- 93 g DM). SF feeding showed no effect on milk yield and milk components (Tab 1) [2].&#xD;
Although farmers are convinced of the anthelmintic potential of SF, our short term study could not point to such an effect. It is possible that a prolonged period of SF administration is necessary in order for such effects to become apparent.&#xD;
&#xD;
[1] Jackson, N. F. und Coop, R. L. (2000). The development of anthelmintic resistance in sheep nematodes. Parasitology, 120(07):95&#xD;
&#xD;
[2] Giebler-Schubert, Frauke (2013). Einsatz von Weißtanne zur Reduktion des Magen-Darm-Strongyliden-Befalls bei Ziegen: In-vivo-Versuche und Erfahrungswissen, Universität Hohenheim</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Geogr Thieme Verlag KG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23306/1/Silver_Fir_Planta_Medica_2013_79_1239.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heckendorn, F.; Giebler-Schubert, F.; Walkenhorst, M.; Fertig, O.; Hamburger, M.; Potterat, O. and Valle-Zárate, A.    (2013) Administration of Silver Fir (Abies alba Mill.) to goats and its potential to control gastro-intestinal parasites.   In:     Planta Medica, Geogr Thieme Verlag KG, Stuttgart, New York, 79, p. 1239.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23306/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>