<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The post-infection activity of hydrated lime against conidia of&#xD;
Venturia inaequalis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Montag, Jurith</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schreiber, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schönherr, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The post-infection activity of hydrated lime against conidia of Venturia inaequalis was evaluated using an in&#xD;
vitro test system based on isolated apple leaf cuticles. Experiments were conducted at 20°C and treatments&#xD;
were applied 24 or 48 h after inoculation. Experiments were assessed by counting living primary stromata 72&#xD;
h after inoculation using fluorescence microscopy and fluorescein diacetate (FDA) as a vital stain. At the&#xD;
conditions of the in vitro test system hydrated lime had a post-infection activity. Suspension of 5 g l-1 applied&#xD;
24 h after inoculation (16 h after infection) killed all primary stromata and stopped their further development.&#xD;
Treatments 48 h after inoculation reduced the number of vital primary stromata to 60% of control.&#xD;
Treatments with saturated solutions of hydrated lime (pH 12.45) and with KOH solutions of different pH&#xD;
showed that a pH higher than 12.4 was needed to be 100% effective. Suspensions of calcium carbonate&#xD;
(6.75 g l-1) had no effect.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13797/1/ecofruit_12th_14.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Montag, Jurith; Schreiber, Lukas and Schönherr, Jörg    (2006) The post-infection activity of hydrated lime against conidia of Venturia inaequalis.  [Die postinfektionelle Wirkung von Calciumhydroxid auf Konidien von Venturia inaequalis.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 77-82.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13797/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>