<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control strategies for late blight in organic potato production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zarb, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ghorbani, Reza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Juntharathep, Pintip</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shotton, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santos, Joanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilcockson, Steve</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Litterick, Audrey M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bain, Ruaridh A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Protective copper fungicides are currently used to control late blight in most organic production systems, but approval for their use in organic farming will be revoked in 2002. Evidence suggests that organic potato production will not be reliably economic in the absence of Cu. Current controls for late blight are reviewed including: variety selection/breeding for blight resistance, diversification strategies, agronomic strategies for the management of late blight, and alternative treatments to Cu-fungicides.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8405/1/zarb_Control_strategies_late_blight_potatoes.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zarb, John; Ghorbani, Reza; Juntharathep, Pintip; Shotton, Peter; Santos, Joanna; Wilcockson, Steve; Leifert, Carlo; Litterick, Audrey M; Bain, Ruaridh A and Wolfe, Martin    (2002) Control strategies for late blight in organic potato production.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 221-222.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8405/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>