<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>COMPARISON OF HEALTH STATUS BETWEEN ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL PRODUCTS</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper reports results of to trial carried out to estimate the hygienic-sanitary of samples obtained from organic farming in comparison with products obtained from conventional agriculture. &#xD;
In three years of activity were carried out analysis on samples common or durum wheat, and processing products like flour, bran, macaroni and bread, obtained from biological and conventional method. Also samples of vegetables and fruits were analysed. &#xD;
The laboratory analyses have been focalized qualitative on quantitative and evaluation of fungal contamination and surveying of pesticide residues level.  &#xD;
The great size of collected dates have not highlighted substantial differences between the two analyzed typologies. &#xD;
About pesticide residues levels, generally they proved to be contained under legal limit, so both these products can be considered healthy under hygienic-sanitary profile.&#xD;
The trials should be extended also to other cultivations like herbs, fruit-tree and vegetables to improve our knowledges about qualitative the and hygienic differences of the two methods of production and defence</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Ghent</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>La Torre, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leandri, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lolletti, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18253/1/Comparison_of_health_status_between_organic_and_conventional_products.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>La Torre, A.; Leandri, A. and Lolletti, D. (Eds.)    (2005) COMPARISON OF HEALTH STATUS BETWEEN ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL PRODUCTS.   University of Ghent, Ghent.  Proceedings of 57th International Symposium on Crop Protection, Ghent, Belgium, May 10, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18253/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>