<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Etablierung Panel basierter Marktforschung auf dem deutschen Öko-Markt</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To date, it is difficult to get reliable and detailed data on real consumer purchasing behaviour and market structure in general for the German organic food market. This deficit can be solved by using methods of tracking research. Consumer panels and retail tracking are the most established types to obtain useful information on marketing and sales controlling. Thus, the recent development of panel research on the organic food market is analysed in this paper. Main focus is given to running retail tracking and to already completed but solely consumer panels for the organic food market in Ger-many. The identified strength and weaknesses will then provide an outlook on possi-bilities and future development of these marketing research instruments.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3372/1/3372.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niessen, Jan    (2005) Etablierung Panel basierter Marktforschung auf dem deutschen Öko-Markt.  [Establishment of panel based market research at the German organic market.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3372/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>