<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Milchleistung und BCS-Verlust zu Laktationsbeginn bei einer&#xD;
Milchleistungs- und einer Doppelnutzungsrasse</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schaub, Dagmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this study was to compare the breeds German Holstein (HF,&#xD;
30 animals) and German Red Pied (dual purpose) (RBT, 33 animals) in terms of milk&#xD;
yield, BCS and weight and the fat-protein ratio in milk during the first five weeks of&#xD;
lactation. HF had a higher mean daily yield than RBT (28.7 vs. 24.3 kg ECM). The&#xD;
mean dry matter intake of the mixed ration was 1 kg/d higher for the HF than the RBT,&#xD;
but this additional energy intake could not compensate fully the higher energy output&#xD;
via milk. Therefore the HF had a more negative energy balance than the RBT, but the&#xD;
expected higher loss of BCS or weight was not observed. Both breeds lost a mean of&#xD;
0.2 BCS-points. A possible reason for this might be breed differences in the distribution&#xD;
of body fat reserves. But a higher mean fat-protein ratio in the HF (1.45 vs. 1.27)&#xD;
and a value above the reference value, indicating a higher risk of ketosis, for the HF&#xD;
cows were signs of higher metabolic stress. Nonetheless the number of diseased&#xD;
animals was similar in both breeds. A possible higher incidence of subclinical metabolic&#xD;
or udder diseases in the HF is studied currently.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14326/1/Schaub_14326.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schaub, Dagmar; Barth, Kerstin and Aulrich, Karen    (2009) Milchleistung und BCS-Verlust zu Laktationsbeginn bei einer Milchleistungs- und einer Doppelnutzungsrasse.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14326/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>