<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Multicriteria Assessment and Communication of Effects of Organic Food Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kastberg, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic agriculture is an alternative food system based on consumer trust and credibility. Consumers buy organic goods and citizens and politician support organics, to some degree, because they believe it is a better alternative. And they believe this because the organic form of production seeks to meet many considerations for society, nature and environment. The possibilities for growth in organic agriculture therefore depends on whether it, overall, makes a credible and attractive alternative, and whether the development of organics is positive with regard to organic principles and the key societal goals for environment, health and welfare. It is, however, extremely difficult to determine whether a specific technological, management or organizational development is positive or negative, overall. In other words, if we want to assess and evaluate organic food systems (or aspects thereof) it becomes evident that it is indeed not possible to base such an assessment solely on one criterion. We need multiple criteria; there are however, no established methods with which to conduct overall, multicriteria assessments or organic food systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25596/3/25596.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kastberg, Peter    (2014) Multicriteria Assessment and Communication of Effects of Organic Food Systems.   ICROFS news, 2014, 1, pp. 6-8.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25596/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>