<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A framework for assessing crop production from rotations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Topp, Cairistiona F E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Doyle, Chris J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine A</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
Organic farming systems rely on the management of biological cycles for the provision of nutrients, which are crucial to maximising the production from the system. Rotations based on the use of grass-legume leys are central to the concept of organic farming systems, because they have the potential to support both animal production, and a subsequent, exploitative, arable cropping phase. A major challenge in organic farming is managing the supply of nitrogen, since it has a key role in governing both productivity and environmental impact. Hence, within a rotational system, there is a need to understand the complex interactions that are occurring between crop species and management, livestock production system and the impact of soil and climate on these processes. To understand these interactions, a framework is being developed for rotational farming systems that describes the soil nitrogen, crop growth and livestock production. The framework must address questions that are relevant to researchers and extensions workers. Typical questions relate to the management of nutrients in the short and long-term. Additionally, there are concerns over the impact of weeds, pests and diseases on productivity, as well as the impact of adopting new strategies or crops on the farming system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8295/1/topp_Framework_assessing_crop_production.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Topp, Cairistiona F E; Doyle, Chris J and Watson, Christine A    (2002) A framework for assessing crop production from rotations.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 33-36.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8295/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>