<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ashes for organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kousa, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heinonen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suoniitty, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peltonen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nowadays only eight percent of the cultivated field area is used for organic farming. The Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry has published the guidelines for the program of organic farming to diversify the supply and the consumption of organic food. The aim is to increase organically arable land to 20% by the year 2020.The demand of organic fertilizer products is strongly increasing. Interest in forestry by-products (ash, bark, zero fiber, etc.) for use in organic production has recently been exceptionally high. For example, development of pelleted fertilizers with zero fiber, ash and a nitrogen-containing fertilizer material is in progress.The ash fertilizer contains many valuable nutrients in fairly optimal ratios: these include phosphorus, potassium, manganese, magnesium, sulfur, zinc, calcium, boron, cobalt, copper and smaller amounts of other trace elements. Ashes contain phosphorus in large amounts, which is useful in organic production. More important nutrients than phosphorus and potassium are apparently trace elements. Neutralizing value of the ash is quite rapid comparedto many liming materials allowed in organic farming. The price quality ratio of ash as a liming material is also good.The use of clean wood ash is permissible in organic production. Peat and straw ash cannot be used in organic production because of the fact that in the EU peat is not considered a renewable resource. Restrictions include only inputs from outside of the organic farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24525/1/24525.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24525/2/24525p.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kousa, T.; Heinonen, M.; Suoniitty, T. and Peltonen, K.    (2013) Ashes for organic farming.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 53-54.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24525/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>