<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The impact of legumes incorporation on the yield formation in organic crop rotation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kadziuliene, Zydre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarunaite, Lina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A whole range factors and their influence the potential of legumes as nitrogen suppliers to subsequent crops. The experiments were aimed to assess the impact of several legumes  to crop yield in organic crop rotation. Diferent field studies were conducted on a loamy Endocalcari-Epihypogleyic Cambisol in Dotnuva (55o 24' N). The effect of differ-ent legume/grass swards on the subsequent winter wheat crop depended on sward composition, and highest grain yield was obtained after ploughed-in lucerne. Spring wheat following lucerne/grass swards produced a higher grain yield than that red clover swards. Pre-crop of white clover and conventional drilling significantly affected winter wheat grain yield and the yield of triticale was higher following wheat after pre-crops that included white clover.  The high-est winter wheat and following barley grain yield was achieved on the ploughed-in legumes plots using conventional sowing method.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7556/1/KadziulieneJOC2006.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kadziuliene, Zydre and Sarunaite, Lina    (2006) The impact of legumes incorporation on the yield formation in organic crop rotation.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7556/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>