<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Landschaftsseminare in der Sozialen Landwirtschaft -&#xD;
Neue Impulse zur Kulturlandschaftsentwicklung&#xD;
durch Ökolandbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Elsen, Dr. Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Social farming adopts a multifunctional view of agriculture: the main products, in&#xD;
addition to saleable produce, are health and employment, education or therapy. Social&#xD;
farming includes agricultural enterprises and market gardens integrating people with&#xD;
physical, mental or emotional disabilities; farms which offer openings for the socially&#xD;
disadvantaged, for young offenders or those with learning difficulties, people with drug&#xD;
dependencies, the long-term unemployed and active senior citizens; school and&#xD;
kindergarten farms and many more. Prevention of illness, inclusion and a better&#xD;
quality of life are features and aims of social agriculture. Landscape seminars were&#xD;
carried out on social farms in order to elaborate aspects for landscape development&#xD;
and nature protection on farm level in a participatory way. Because of additional&#xD;
manpower such farms offer special opportunities for landscape care through many&#xD;
helping hands, but support and advice are needed. Landscape seminars appear to be&#xD;
a method to strengthen intrinsic motivation of people involved to improve their&#xD;
landscape and biotopes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14287/1/vanElsen_14287.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Elsen, Dr. Thomas    (2009) Landschaftsseminare in der Sozialen Landwirtschaft - Neue Impulse zur Kulturlandschaftsentwicklung durch Ökolandbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14287/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>