<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Intérêt du pâturage mixte entre ovins et bovins dans la gestion du parasitisme digestif en système d’élevage  Agriculture Biologique</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>H., HOSTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>J.-P., GUITARD</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>J.-C., PONS</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Gastrointestinal trichostrongylosis represent one of the main constraint associated with the  breeding of ruminants  on pastures  which is associated with Organic Farming. Besides the repeated use of anthelmintic treatments, the control of these parasitic infections can also be based on  an improvement of the host response and on the reduction of animal infection by decreasing the contact with infective larvae through pertinent  grazing management.   Mixed grazing between  different hosts species, particularly  between cattle and small ruminants, represents one of the method to  reduce  the infestivity of pastures.  This method is based on the relatively high specificity of  many nematode species  for one host. The  advantages and limits of mixed grazing practices, either by alternate or simultaneous mode,  are discussed both in regard of parasite infection and production measurements.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6966/1/fourrages1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>H., HOSTE; J.-P., GUITARD and J.-C., PONS    (2003) Intérêt du pâturage mixte entre ovins et bovins dans la gestion du parasitisme digestif en système d’élevage Agriculture Biologique.  [Interest of mixed grazing between cattle and sheep in the control of gastrointestinal nematodes.]  In:     Fourrages (176), pp. 425-436.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6966/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>