<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performance of pea, lupin and faba bean, in organic cropping systems in France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dibet, Audrey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aveline, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Crozat, Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organically farmed pea, lupin and faba bean were compared in terms of dry matter (DM), grain yield and nitrogen (N) production, as well as for their competitive ability against weeds. Adjacent strips of pea, lupin and faba bean were set up at eight sites throughout the Pays de la Loire region. Soil conditions and weed pressure differed between sites. In general, faba bean produced slightly more grain yield and grain N than pea. Lupin was the least productive grain legume and the weakest competitor against weeds, though it provided grains with the highest N contents. However in most situations, pea was shown to be the most efficient until flowering for DM and N accumulation as well as for light interception and crop height. A faster development of aboveground plant parts at early growth stages and a better soil N uptake were likely explanations for the lowest weed DM of pea. However DM of pea, lupin and faba bean were equally limited by weeds despite the differences in weed biomass between these species.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7442/1/organic_congress_Dibet.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dibet, Audrey; Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle; Aveline, Anne and Crozat, Yves    (2006) Performance of pea, lupin and faba bean, in organic cropping systems in France.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7442/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>