<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ergebnisse der Anwendung einer neuen Humusbilanzmethode&#xD;
in Dauerfeldversuchen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brock, Christopher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoyer, Uta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof.Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hülsbergen, Prof.Dr. Kurt-Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Humus balance methods aim at the assessment of humus reproduction in cropping&#xD;
systems as an effect of cropped plant species and management. They do not intend to&#xD;
predict actual humus dynamics, which are strongly dependent on land-use history and&#xD;
environmental site conditions. Therefore, the validation of humus balance methods is&#xD;
a methodical challenge. This paper presents results from the validation of a new&#xD;
method for humus balancing with different approaches. The first validation approach is&#xD;
relating humus balance saldi to humus content development in long-term field&#xD;
experiments. The second approach is relating humus balance saldi differences&#xD;
between field experiment treatments under similar site conditions to differences in&#xD;
humus dynamics indicators. In both validations the model performed satisfactory.&#xD;
Compared to standard humus balance methods applied in organic farming, the new&#xD;
method proved comparable quality in the validation. However, there is a clear demand&#xD;
for methodical improvement of validation approaches for humus balance methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14565/1/Brock_14565.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brock, Christopher; Hoyer, Uta; Leithold, Prof.Dr. Günter and Hülsbergen, Prof.Dr. Kurt-Jürgen    (2009) Ergebnisse der Anwendung einer neuen Humusbilanzmethode in Dauerfeldversuchen.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14565/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>