<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessment and comparisons of the environmental, economic and social&#xD;
performances of organic and conventional cattle systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pavie, Jérome</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chambaut, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madeline, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Experton, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main objective of "CedABio" was to estimate the environmental and socioeconomic benefits&#xD;
anticipated in the bovine farming systems adopting an organic production mode. Beyond some obvious&#xD;
advantages, the goal was to measure and ascertain the real contributions of a change to organic&#xD;
farming for the dairy and beef farms. To lead this assessment, strong and technically accessible&#xD;
indicators were selected, tested, and then looked for in 144 livestock farms, located in varied contexts to&#xD;
take into account territorial diversity. Half of the farms were in organic mode. Their results are compared&#xD;
with the other half producing in conventional mode, situated in the same zones, with similar structures.&#xD;
The results and the observations performed in this network of commercial farms are completed by&#xD;
additional measures on two experimental farms in organic production in the INRA station of Mirecourt in&#xD;
J. Pavie et al.&#xD;
28 Innovations Agronomiques 30 (2013), 27-40&#xD;
dairy production and in Thorigné d’Anjou in beef production. The observations and studies took into&#xD;
account three axes of the sustainability: environmental, economic and social. The environmental axis&#xD;
includes the analysis of mineral balances, energy consumptions, biodiversity, gas emissions,&#xD;
consumptions of sanitary and phytosanitary products as well as management of waste. The social axis&#xD;
took into account workload and animal welfare. If some outputs confirmed results of previous works and&#xD;
the anticipated profit of a conversion to organic farming, all do not show the same degree of interest for&#xD;
a conversion to organic farming. Some elements of context, localization, quality of the surroundings,&#xD;
levels of technical control observed in some conventional farms, reduce the interest expected from a&#xD;
conversion to organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26211/1/Pavie_2013_CIAG_Vol30.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pavie, Jérome; Chambaut, H.; Madeline, L.  and Experton, Catherine   (2013) Assessment and comparisons of the environmental, economic and social performances of organic and conventional cattle systems.  [Evaluations et comparaisons des performances environnementales, économiques et sociales des systèmes bovins biologiques et conventionnels dans le cadre du projet CedABio.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 30, pp. 27-40.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26211/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>