<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Practical experience with the use of Baking Powder (potassium bicarbonate) for the control of Apple Scab (Venturia ineaqualis)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In small plot trials, performed by several institutes in the past years, potassium bicarbonate&#xD;
proved to be a promising alternative to the use of copper for the control of apple scab in&#xD;
organic orchards. Feasibility, effectiveness, consequences, and side effects of the&#xD;
replacement of copper by bicarbonate under practical conditions are largely unknown. In&#xD;
2007 Five Dutch organic apple growers compared a bicarbonate based scab management&#xD;
strategy with their standard spray program. The use of 5 kg potassium bicarbonate + 2 kg.&#xD;
wettable sulphur shortly before rain or during infection development, was the core of the&#xD;
strategy. It was concluded that the control of apple scab with the potassium bicarbonate&#xD;
strategy was as effective as the standard spray plan, provided lime sulphur was available&#xD;
tot cover extreme situations. The applications did not lead to any phytotoxic damage on&#xD;
leafs or fruits. Potassium bicarbonate tank mixed with a Mn leaf fertilizer however resulted&#xD;
in severe leaf drop, and necrotic spots on the remaining leafs.&#xD;
The use of potassium bicarbonate did not increase the potassium content of the fruits.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13646/1/068-075.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trapman, M.    (2008) Practical experience with the use of Baking Powder (potassium bicarbonate) for the control of Apple Scab (Venturia ineaqualis).   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 68-75.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13646/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>