<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence on the ileal and fecal digestibility of forages inclusion in the diet</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Henry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carlson, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lærke, H.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present investigation aimed to study the ileal and fecal digestibility of three forages (Clover grass, Clover grass silage and Pea-Barley silage) supplemented to a basal diet. A total of 24 pigs, adapted to eating forages by supplementing a basal feed with clover grass silage from weaning, were fitted with a T-cannula at the terminal ileum at approximate 30 kg LW. For each of the three types of forage, two balance trials with 4 weeks interval were carried out. Two pigs in each test were fed the basal diet while 6 others were fed the basal diet plus forage throughout the whole experiment. The intake of forages was relative low and quite variable and accounted on average for only 10-12 % of the daily dry matter intake. Ileal digestibility estimated by collection from the T-cannula was higher than the digestibility estimated by the slaughter technique indicating some separation of the digesta collected from the T-cannula. The forages had, as expected, a lower fecal DM and energy digestibility than the basal diet (P&lt;0.05). The fresh clover grass had a higher energy digestibility than the two silages (60 vs 48 %, P&lt;0.05). Inclusion of 10 % of gross energy in the diet from clover grass reduced the rations energy digestibility relatively by 2.2 %, while clover grass silage and the pea-barley silage to reductions of 3.4 and 5.0 % (P&lt;0.05), respectively.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20930/4/20930.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jørgensen, Henry; Carlson, D. and Lærke, H.N.   (2012) Influence on the ileal and fecal digestibility of forages inclusion in the diet.   Journal of Animal Science,   ( ),  - .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20930/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>