<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrogen and sulphur management: challenges for organic sources in temperate agricultural systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McNiel, A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bergström, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, K.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marstorp, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirschmann, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nilsson, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A current global trend towards intensification or specialization of agricultural enterprises has been accompanied by increasing public awareness of associated environmental consequences. Air and water pollution from losses of nutrients, such as nitrogen (N) and sulphur (S), are a major concern. Governments have initiated extensive regulatory frameworks, including various land use policies, in an attempt to control or reduce the losses. This paper presents an overview of critical input and loss processes affecting N and S for temperate climates, and provides some background to the discussion in subsequent papers evaluating specific farming systems. Management effects on potential gaseous and leaching losses, the lack of synchrony between supply of nutrients and plant demand, and options for optimizing the efficiency of N and S use are reviewed. Integration of inorganic and organic fertilizer inputs and the equitable re-distribution of nutrients from manure are discussed. The paper concludes by highlighting a need for innovative research that is also targeted to practical approaches for reducing N and S losses, and improving the overall synchrony between supply and demand.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5470/1/5470.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>McNiel, A.M.; Eriksen, J.; Bergström, L.; Smith, K.S.; Marstorp, H.; Kirschmann, H. and Nilsson, I.   (2005) Nitrogen and sulphur management: challenges for organic sources in temperate agricultural systems.   Soil Use and Management, 21, pp. 82-93.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5470/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>