<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Changes in sensory profile and microbiological quality during chill storage of cured and uncured cooked sliced emulsion-type sausages</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lücke, Friedrich-Karl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raabe, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hampshire, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nine batches of cooked sliced emulsion type sausages, produced from organic meat with or without the use of nitrite, were packed under N2/CO2 (7:3) and vacuum, respectively, and stored at 8°C. During two weeks of storage, the microbiological quality was determined, as well as the sensory quality by using profile analysis. The spoilage flora consisted of lactic acid bacteria and Brochothrix thermosphacta, without clear evidence of an inhibitory effect of nitrite on the growth of these organisms. The sensory profile showed an increase of the sour and rancid aroma and flavour, in parallel to the growth of these microorganisms. These changes were more pronounced in the batches prepared without nitrite. Spots of red discolourations were occasionally observed during storage of uncured sausage slices. These may have been caused by reduction of traces of nitrate from spices by psychrotrophic Enterobacteriaceae.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9757/1/luecke-etal-2007-sausage_storage.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lücke, Friedrich-Karl; Raabe, Christina and Hampshire, Jörg    (2007) Changes in sensory profile and microbiological quality during chill storage of cured and uncured cooked sliced emulsion-type sausages.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9757/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>