<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving the quality and shelf life of fruit from organic production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alföldi, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since the mid-1990s important key markets like the EU, USA and Japan have demonstrated a growth in the organic sector of around 20% per year. This strong growth of organics is underpinned by consumer concern over genetic engineering, food safety, health and nutrition (is it safe and healthy to eat?) and greater awareness of environmental issues (Torjusen, and Sangstad, 2004; Granatstein and Kirby, 2006). For farmers this provides an important opportunity in the ‘search for’ and ‘development of’ niche, new and nontraditional premium earning markets.&#xD;
However on-going improvements in conventional food production systems in terms of visible produce quality, but also with respect to environmental criteria, require a clear demonstration of the additional values that organic food can provide for the consumers and for the sustainability of food production and the environment (see Chapter 2). Sound scientific studies quantifying ‘added values’ play a key role in the marketing of organic produce if appropriately communicated to consumers, but are also important in gaining continued political support for an expansion of organic agriculture.&#xD;
Organic fruit production is one of the most important and challenging areas of organic production for a variety of reasons.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Woodhead Publishing Limited, Cambridge, England</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Cooper, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Leifert, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13340/1/weibel-2007-OrganicFoodBook_Leiffert_Chapt16.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, Franco P. and Alföldi, Thomas    (2007) Improving the quality and shelf life of fruit from organic production systems.    In: Cooper, J.; Niggli, U. and Leifert, C. (Eds.)   Handbook of organic food safety and quality.  Woodhead Publishing Limited, Cambridge, England, chapter 16, pp. 330-352.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13340/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>