<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Oekologischer Ackerbauversuch Gladbacherhof - Effekte von Fruchtfolge und Bodenbearbeitung in der ersten Rotation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Harald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a long term trial at the University of Giessen three organic crop rotation systems with and without livestock and four soil tillage treatments (deep plough, 2 x two layer plough and cultivator/rotary harrow) are investigated since 1998. Compared to the other two rotations the stockless rotation without annual green manure showed lower cash crop yields, a negative N-balance and rising weed coverage. The highest cash crop yields were mostly achieved with deep ploughing. Two layer tillage caused N and C accumulation in the upper soil layer (0-15 cm). The weed coverage was highest in these treatments. Especially exclusive tillage with cultivator/rotary harrow resulted in a distinct increase of thistles and high coverage with annual weeds.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3307/1/3307.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmidt, Harald and Leithold, Günter    (2005) Oekologischer Ackerbauversuch Gladbacherhof - Effekte von Fruchtfolge und Bodenbearbeitung in der ersten Rotation.  [Organic farming trial Gladbacherhof - effects of crop rotation and soil tillage in the first rotation.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>