<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Buffers for biomass production in temperate European agriculture: A review and synthesis on function, ecosystem services and implementation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Christen, Ben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, Tommy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In addition to their potential for biomass production, buffer strips on agricultural land have been shown to protect surface water quality by reducing erosion and nutrient leaching, and can play a key role in nature and flood protection, and the design of bioenergy landscapes resilient to climate changes, and the environmental pressures from intensive agriculture. Use of conservation buffers by farmers outside of designated schemes is very limited to date, but the increasing demand for bioenergy and the combination of agricultural production with nature protection calls for a much wider implementation. This paper reviews the knowledge on buffer functioning, socioeconomics and practical farming aspects. It describes how a defined three-zone buffer design, with upland arable fields buffered&#xD;
 by a combination of 1) grassland, 2) short rotation forestry (SRF) or coppice (SRC), and 3) undisturbed (semi-natural) vegetation along water courses, can be incorporated into bioenergy landscapes as productive nature protection elements in a way acceptable to farmers.&#xD;
Of great importance to nutrient cycling is that land use plays a much greater role in determining catchment hydrology than soil type: shelterbelts or buffer strips have markedly higher infiltration capacity than arable or pasture land. Root architecture of trees, shrubs and herbaceous plants&#xD;
differs between species and is important for the extent of 1 hydrological changes after establishment. Riparian buffers retain 30-99% of nitrate N and 20-100% of phosphorous from&#xD;
 runoff and shallow groundwater. Such buffers are also highly effective for pesticide removal, and there is a high potential for low-input fuel, feed, or fiber production, while many synergies in daily management can be realized. Landscape amenities, sporting opportunities, and a highly visible display of farming skills are additional benefits. Buffers therefore have potential for helping to manage nutrients and water on farmland in a sustainable way.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18937/4/18937.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Christen, Ben and Dalgaard, Tommy   (2013) Buffers for biomass production in temperate European agriculture: A review and synthesis on function, ecosystem services and implementation.   Biomass and Bioenergy, 55, pp. 53-67.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18937/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>