<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mikrobiologische Sicherheit und Sensorik von zwei Rindfleisch-Reifesystemen unter handwerklichen Produktionsbedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kramer, Eckart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bandick, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seidler, Tassilo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schl, Oliver</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mautschke, Hans-Hagen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Microbial status, and organoleptic properties of matured beef are relevant quality parameters. Alternative maturation methods with low microbial risk over a longer ageing period are of interest. For this work, three Highland Cattles from organic husbandry were slaughtered in an external slaughterhouse. Cooled cattle halves were transported to a butcher in another location. Boned beef was packed in two different maturation systems: (i) vacuum maturation in sealed plastic bags („bag“), and (ii) maturation in a maturation box („box“). Samples were taken after 15, 21, 28 and 34 days. Microbial test results were assessed according to DGHM guidelines. Recommend level for total germ counts were exceeded in six samples from the maturation in „bag“, and in four from the „box“. Regarding Enterobacteriaceae, critical level was achieved in six samples („bag“), resp. four („box“). Staphylococcae were found in both systems, no Salmonellae were found. In addition, samples were analysed by use of spectroscopy, to obtain data for the development of rapid detection methods. Organoleptic tests were conducted on samples but non-processed beef (except short-roasing for testing the taste) according to a DLG scheme. The average overall scores show little differences: bag 4,47, and box 4,29. As well, no clear trend for any criterion in function of time was found. The results suggest the microbial and organoleptic suitability of both maturation systems in decentralised small-scale beef production systems, if hygienic practice is observed. It is intended to exceed these maturation tests for a period of about 60 days.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21386/1/21386_kramer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kramer, Eckart; Bandick, Niels; Seidler, Tassilo; Schl, Oliver and Mautschke, Hans-Hagen    (2013) Mikrobiologische Sicherheit und Sensorik von zwei Rindfleisch-Reifesystemen unter handwerklichen Produktionsbedingungen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21386/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>