<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Learning our way towards a sustainable agri-food system Three cases from Sweden: Stockholm Farmers market, Ramsjö Community Supported Agriculture and Järna Initiative for Local Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adler, Steffen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fung, Stephanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Gwendolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Young, Lee</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Networks and ownership</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This research is based on case studies of the Stockholm Farmers Market, Ramsjö Community Supported Agriculture, and Järna Initiative for Local Production. These cases are examples of alternative consumerproducer links in the Swedish agri-food system. An adapted SWOT analysis highlights key strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and constraints in each case from the multiple perspectives of producers, consumers, the organization, as well as the environment and society. Diagrams show where learning opportunities exist in the three systems, and how the structure of the consumer-producer link influences learning processes. Implication assessments consider how each link may affect surrounding ecosystems and social aspects of the agri-food system. A framework for assessing a process of development identifies six components that contribute to agri-food system development. Four key issues are discussed in terms of their potential to significantly affect the development of the agri-food system: the length of the food chain linking producers and consumers, the definition of “local”, learning in the system, and what is really being sold – is it food, or values? Critical research questions are highlighted and recommended for future research.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2838/1/ekolantbruk38.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Adler, Steffen; Fung, Stephanie; Huber, Gwendolyn and Young, Lee         (2003) Learning our way towards a sustainable agri-food system Three cases from Sweden: Stockholm Farmers market, Ramsjö Community Supported Agriculture and Järna Initiative for Local Production.   Ekologiskt lantbruk, no. 38. Centre for Sustainable Agriculture.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2838/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>