<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic chains in the United Kingdom and Germany: lessons for Dutch organic agribusiness</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meeusen, Marieke JG</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. This paper presents lessons for Dutch organic agribusiness based on a study of the UK and Germany. The following lessons are drawn: public-private cooperation is desirable for the sake of further development; the supermarket chain is necessary in order to achieve a large market share; consumers and supermarket chains subject organic products to at least the same demands that they have for regular products; communication: [1] a task for the government and market parties, [2] striving for one mark of quality [3] health is the driving motivation, although not communicated as such; organic agriculture has more chains and more segments.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8446/1/meeusen_chainsUK_Germany.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meeusen, Marieke JG    (2002) Organic chains in the United Kingdom and Germany: lessons for Dutch organic agribusiness.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 331-332.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8446/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>