<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Determination of storage stability of butter enriched with unsaturated fatty acids/conjugated linoleic acids (UFA/CLA) using instrumental and sensory methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mallia, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piccinali, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rehberger, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Badertscher, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Escher, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlichtherle-Cerny, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The oxidative stability of butter enriched with unsaturated fatty acids and conjugated linoleic acids (UFA/CLA butter) was evaluated by chemical, sensory and microbiological analyses during 8 weeks of storage at 6 °C and compared with that of conventional butter. The odour-active compounds were analyzed by gas chromatography–mass spectrometry combined with olfactometry, using solid phase microextraction.&#xD;
Olfactometric analysis showed that both, fresh UFA/CLA butter and fresh conventional butter had similar aroma profiles. After 6–8 weeks of storage, UFA/CLA butter showed stronger fatty (butanoic and 3-methyl butanoic acid), metallic [(E,E)-2,4-nonadienal], green [(E)-2-hexenol] and creamy (2-pentanone) notes compared with the conventional samples. A sensory panel described the two fresh butter types as having a similar sensory profile, except for a stronger creamy aroma, a less intense cooked milk aroma and a significantly higher spreadability of the UFA/CLA butters. Sensory descriptive analysis showed also that both butter types aged in a very similar way, with an increase in rancid and oxidized notes.&#xD;
(c) 2008 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16013/2/mallia-etal-2008-Int_Dairy_J-18.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mallia, S.; Piccinali, P.; Rehberger, B.; Badertscher, R.; Escher, F. and Schlichtherle-Cerny, H.   (2008) Determination of storage stability of butter enriched with unsaturated fatty acids/conjugated linoleic acids (UFA/CLA) using instrumental and sensory methods.   International Dairy Journal, 18, pp. 983-993.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16013/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>