<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Agriculture Research in Uganda</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ssekyewa, Charles</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Development of Organic Agriculture stem from the demand for safe and environmentally friendly food, which arose from outcome mistakes made by the Green Revolution that failed to achieve sustainable food security. Organic Agriculture awareness started from the north where severe negative impacts of the Green Revolution exist. In order to counteract such negative effects to the environment, together with early awareness of the need to conserve the environment, Organic Agriculture spread to the south at a fairly fast rate. The result is that Organic Agriculture support systems, such as research, extension and education, as well as related policies are lacking. However, the south and Uganda in particular has a favorable environment for the growth of Organic Agriculture, which already existed among the many small holder farmers who dominate the Ugandan Agricultural sector. There are also institutions and individuals who view the way forward to  sustainable agricultural development, lasting food security, and better health to be in adopting Organic Agriculture. As such the limited Organic Agriculture development in Uganda now requires immediate refocusing of research priorities, extension of environment friendly technologies, offering of Organic Agriculture as part of training curricula at all educational levels, and above all putting in place an Organic Agriculture Policy.&#xD;
&#xD;
This paper gives a detailed review of the status quo Organic Agriculture research in Uganda, and gives recommendations on the way forward.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7687/1/ssekyewa-2005-research-uganda.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ssekyewa, Charles    (2005) Organic Agriculture Research in Uganda.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - First Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture ISOFAR, Adelaide, South Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7687/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>