<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessing the public goods provided by organic agriculture: lessons learned from practice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Laurence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pearce, Bruce</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nic</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gerrard, Catherine L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Woodward, Lawrence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Sue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Measures, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The role of farms as providers of public goods has long been recognised, and measuring performance in this area is of increasing interest to policy makers, in light of the approaching Common Agricultural Policy reform. The Organic Research Centre has been working on this topic in recent years, through the development of sustainability assessment tools. The latest outcome from this process is a ‘Public Goods’ assessment tool, developed through a Natural England funded project which aimed to evaluate the benefits accruing from organic management and entering into an Organic Entry Level Stewardship (OELS) agreement. This paper describes the development of the Public Goods (PG) tool, and what has been learned in the process.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-11-17</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19761/1/smith_9591_revised.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smith, Laurence; Padel, Susanne; Pearce, Bruce; Lampkin, Nic; Gerrard, Catherine L; Woodward, Lawrence; Fowler, Sue and Measures, Mark    (2011) Assessing the public goods provided by organic agriculture: lessons learned from practice.   In:     Proceedings of the third scientific conference of ISOFAR: Organic is life - knowledge for tomorrow, 2, pp. 59-63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19761/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>