<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Romanian system of subsidies for organic farming: support for the development of &#xD;
rural areas</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chis, PhD. Margareta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mihai, PhD. Gheorghe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pentelescu, PhDr. Ovidiu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Romania</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Romanian legislation regarding the organic agro-food products, harmonized with community requirements, intends to create an organic agriculture according to the European systems. In the period 2004-2005 the stimulation of organic agriculture development was achieved generally through the accordance of subsidies on organic product over the level production realized in conventional system. The year 2006 bring important modifications in the subsidies accordance starting with the principle of decoupled subsidies from the volume of production. Diversification of the organic subsidies system and extinction for conversion steps too, can contribute to the increases of the certified organic farms and their profitability altogether representing a real support for the sustainable development of the Romanian rural area.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7301/2/Chis_Mihai_Pentelescu_poster.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chis, PhD. Margareta; Mihai, PhD. Gheorghe and Pentelescu, PhDr. Ovidiu    (2006) The Romanian system of subsidies for organic farming: support for the development of rural areas.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7301/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>