<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breast blisters in groups of slow-growing broilers in relation to strain and the availability and use of perches</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Birte L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>1. The relationship between perching behaviour, availability of perches and the incidence and severity of breast blisters in broilers was investigated together with a comparison between two slow-growing broiler strains.  &#xD;
&#xD;
2. Sixteen single strain groups (n=60) of Labresse and i657 broilers were subjected throughout the experiment to one of three perch availabilities: 15 cm per bird (Labresse and i657), 7.5 cm per bird (i657 only), and 0 cm per bird (i657 only) with four replicates per treatment. The birds were housed indoors from day-old, and at 43 days of age 52 birds from each group were moved to outdoor housing facilities with access to grass-covered outdoor areas until slaughter at 84 days of age.  &#xD;
&#xD;
3. The use of perches was monitored via video recordings throughout the experimental period. The severity of breast blisters were recorded on a scale from 0 to 2 at slaughter.  &#xD;
&#xD;
4. Groups of i657 with 15 cm perch per bird used these more than groups with 7.5 cm perch per bird (19% vs. 8% of birds perching at midnight; P&lt;0.001). A significant association between access to perches and severe breast blisters (score 2) was found in the groups of i657, with odds ratios of 3.1 (P=0.031) and 3.4 (P=0.020) for 7.5 and 15.0 cm per birds, respectively, relative to the no-perch treatment.  &#xD;
&#xD;
5. Labresse were more likely to develop breast blisters than i657 (odds ratio 3.5; P&lt;0.001), but used the perches significantly less (0.1 vs. 9.5 birds perching at midnight; P&lt;0.001) and weighed less (2011g vs. 2246g; P&lt;0.01) than i657.  &#xD;
&#xD;
6. Males had a higher incidence of breast blisters than females (odds ratio 12.2; P&lt;0.001), and this was most prominent in the Labresse strain (odds ratio 40.0; P&lt;0.001).  &#xD;
&#xD;
7. In some broiler strains access to perches may be associated with an increase in the occurrence of severe breast blisters, but strain and sex of broiler chickens appear to have a much larger influence than access to perches on the incidence of breast blisters</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1355/1/Breast_blisters_2004.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nielsen, Birte L.   (2004) Breast blisters in groups of slow-growing broilers in relation to strain and the availability and use of perches.   British Poultry Science, 45 (3), pp. 306-315.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1355/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>