<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Food and nutrition status of households with homegardens in the Nuba Mountains of Sudan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grieb, Beatrice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiehle, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gebauer, Jens</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ploeger, Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buerkert, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sudan is one of the least developed countries and many people particularly in South Kordofan suffer from food insecurity. Food production from homegardens (HG) and wild collections are seen as key elements in strategies to overcome nutrient deficiencies. Food intake 24h-recalls were conducted to evaluate the status quo of households (HHs) and the contribution from four HG and wild collection during three seasons in Sama in South Kordofan, Sudan.&#xD;
Dietary diversity as well as nutrient intake was determined and food samples were taken. On average people consumed 16 food items belonging to eight food groups, which is adequate or higher than reported in other studies. Mean daily intake was 1438 kcal energy, 36 g protein, 182 μg vitamin A, 23 mg vitamin C, 9 mg iron and 5 mg zinc. This indicates a nutrient deficiency, especially in vitamins. Differences between traditional and commercial (marketoriented) HGs were small. Households which considered HGs to be important for their daily life had a better nutrient intake, but less diverse diet than those with a reduced importance of HGs. Thus the perceived importance of the HGs seemed to affect HH nutrition more than the level of their commercialization. &#xD;
In total twelve food items from HGs (mostly green leafy vegetables, high in vitamin A) and seven from the wild (mainly Ziziphus spina-christi (L.) Willd, high in vitamin C) were used within the three weeks interview period. The results show the importance of the HG to HH´s nutrition and also indicate the importance of wild collection for the dietary status of HH in the Nuba Mountains of Sudan.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26557/1/2013_Grieb-etal-Hidden_Hunger_Abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26557/7/2013_Grieb-etal-Hidden_hunger_poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Grieb, Beatrice; Wiehle, Martin; Gebauer, Jens; Ploeger, Angelika and Buerkert, Andreas    (2013) Food and nutrition status of households with homegardens in the Nuba Mountains of Sudan.       Poster at:   Hidden Hunger - From Assessment to Solutions, Stuttgart, Germany, 06. - 09. 03. 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26557/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>