<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interdisziplinär betrachtet: Gesundheit- und Leistungsfähigkeit&#xD;
von Milchkühen im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Dr. Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Mastitis, metabolic disorders and lameness are still the most important diseases in&#xD;
German organic dairy herds and cause enormous financial losses as well as pain in&#xD;
the animals suffering from these diseases. This project focuses on the development of&#xD;
prevention-oriented health management strategies in organic dairy farms and aims to&#xD;
validate this approach through an interdisciplinary on-farm intervention study. In total&#xD;
14 institutions are involved. To assess the risk of metabolic disorders and mastitis a&#xD;
national field survey of 100 organic dairy farms is used considering the system of&#xD;
production from the plant populations of the grassland, the quality of feedstuff to housing&#xD;
conditions and milk quality to name but a few examples of the data recorded&#xD;
during farm visits. The study relies on a small team of scientists and consultants and is&#xD;
complemented by investigations carried out on experimental stations. These experiments&#xD;
deal with the improvement of grassland, feed intake, and the relation between&#xD;
metabolic disorders and udder infections.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14027/1/Barth_14027.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barth, Dr. Kerstin and Brinkmann, Jan    (2009) Interdisziplinär betrachtet: Gesundheit- und Leistungsfähigkeit von Milchkühen im Ökologischen Landbau.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14027/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>