<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Bestimmungsgründe der deutschen Landpachtpreise in Abhängigkeit vom Flächenstatus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtner, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lippert, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The BÖLN-funded project assesses the current situation of the land rental market in Germany and, thereby, accounts for spatial aspects. We will draw on secondary data from the official German farm census conducted in 2010 to analyse determinants of land rental prices and their potential differences in space. Using spatial econometric methods we aim at analysing information on organic and conventional farms. To fill gaps in knowledge and experience and to ensure the practical relevance of the results, we will additionally perform explorative interviews with organic landlords and conduct a one-day workshop with experts from the organic farming sector. Based on two different empirical approaches, recommendations enhancing the competitiveness of organic farming shall be given</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21212/1/21212_schmidtner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmidtner, Eva; Lippert, Christian and Dabbert, Stephan    (2013) Die Bestimmungsgründe der deutschen Landpachtpreise in Abhängigkeit vom Flächenstatus.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21212/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>