<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wild Collection and Cultivation of Native Species in Iceland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Whitney, Cory</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gebauer, Jens</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anderson , Molly</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Based on an MSc thesis submitted to the joint Master program between University of Kassel and University of Goettingen and later published: WHITNEY C.W., GEBAUER J. &amp; ANDERSON M. 2012. A Survey of Wild Collection and Cultivation of Indigenous Species in Iceland. Human Ecology. &#xD;
&#xD;
This paper outlines a survey of Icelanders who use local plants. Some of the species (e.g. Angelica spp. and Betula spp.) were very important. However, great potential exists for a more diverse harvest and for sustainable management (e.g. Organic certification). There is also potential for the spreading native plant use knowledge and the inherent associated conservation culture. The data also suggests that cultural conservation should focus on food, which appears to be paramount in increasing the cultural importance of a plant.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22897/1/22897%20Wild%20Collection%20and%20Cultivation%20of%20Native%20Plants%20in%20Iceland_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Whitney, Cory; Gebauer, Jens and Anderson , Molly    (2014) Wild Collection and Cultivation of Native Species in Iceland.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 607-610.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22897/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>