<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Does Thule III have resistance gene Bt-13?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borgen, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>All over the world, Thule III is used as differential variety for the resistance gene Bt-13 against common bunt. It can therefore be strange that I can question whether Thule III have Bt-13, so let me elaborate the question. I also use Thule III as a standard for Bt-13, and I got this variety from GRIN PI 181463. This variety does indeed have a major gene against common bunt and since we all use it as a standard for Bt-13 this gene is per definition Bt-13. What still puzzles me is that this variety does not look like Thule III. It says in the GRIN database that it is of Swedish origin with the pedigree Thule II/Sammet. PI 181463 is a short, lodging and weak variety with a very poor winter hardiness, and it does not at all look like a Swedish winter wheat. I therefore ordered Thule III (NGB6714) and Thule II and Sammet from NordGen, and they are all very different from PI 181463. The varieties show different resistance pattern to the common bunt than PI-181463. The question is therefore not whether PI 181463 carry Bt-13, but whether PI 181463 is really Thule III?</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-02-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28140/7/28140.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borgen, Anders    (2014) Does Thule III have resistance gene Bt-13?   In:     Proceedings of the XVIII Biennial International Workshop on the Smuts and Bunts.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28140/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>