<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>From grain to feed – process development concerning production of high protein fractions from grain and legum  products to be used in extruded fish feed pellets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tolderlund Rasmussen, Hanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Danish project “Organic Aquaculture” the link between sustainable production and superior products” is examining the availability of relevant organically produced crops with a high protein content to be used as raw materials for fish feed. Fish meal is the main source of protein for fish feed. On a global scale the production of fish meal will not increase. There is a demand for developing sustainable protein sources as a substitution for fish meal. Protein from crops and legumes is an obvious solution, however, the crops and legumes need to be processed into fractions with a higher protein content in order to compete with fish meal. &#xD;
The process development was carried out at The Danish Technological Institute’s pilot plant located in Sdr. Stenderup, Denmark. Sweet lupine seeds were processed among other grains and legumes. A dehulling process was developed based on three process steps: knife mill grinding, vibration sifting and zig zag air classifying. &#xD;
The protein content was concentrated from 34 % to 43 % protein on dry matter and fat free basis. 90,5 % of the hull was removed. The dehulled lupines were grinded so that 84 % of the fraction was below 250 µm. The grinding was carried out using a hammer mill with a 2.0 mm and a 1.0 mm sieve at 2950 rpm and finally using an Alpine 160 Z pine mill at 18.900 rpm. &#xD;
The grinded product was air classified by using a MP 400 Alpine Air Classifier. A protein fraction of 62 % protein on dry matter and fat free basis was reached. The relation between the particle size of the protein product and the protein content in the fraction was investigated. A linear relation was found and demonstrated; when the protein content in the product was increased the amount of particles in the fraction below 70 µm also increased linearly. &#xD;
The lupine protein was incorporated into a recipe for fish feed and extruded into pellets on a Werner Pfleider Continua 37 Twin Screwed Extruder.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-09-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19727/6/19727.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tolderlund Rasmussen, Hanne    (2009) From grain to feed – process development concerning production of high protein fractions from grain and legum products to be used in extruded fish feed pellets.       Poster at:   American Association of Cerial Chemists (AACC), Baltimore, USA, 13 - 16 September 2009.      [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19727/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>