<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A new integrative assessment indicator for damage caused by major pests and diseases in the vineyard</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Delbac, L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Constant, N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laveau, E</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thiéry, D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smits, N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roudet, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mérot, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wéry, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fermaud, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An original and integrative evaluation indicator has been developed to quantify the cumulated damage from major pests and diseases affecting grape bunches: downy mildew, powdery mildew, gray mould and tortricid moths. It made it possible to estimate the associated crop losses and to relate them to the plant protection strategy in different modes of production (organic farming, in-transition, conventional). Thus, overall plant losses were higher in 2012 than in 2011. The in-transition growers’ strategy, with reduced copper doses but increased numbers of sprays, led to a 20% increase in average severity on bunches (essentially due to Downy mildew). The more pragmatic approach of experienced organic growers and conventional ones (higher doses and fewer sprays) reduced the yield losses. The proposed indicator is used for two purposes, i) evaluating the quantitative losses due to pest attacks and ii) differentiating them from other non-pest ones. A more detailed analysis including the impact on performance will be achieved and published soon.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26240/1/Delbac_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Delbac, L; Constant, N; Laveau, E; Thiéry, D; Smits, N; Roudet, J; Mérot, A; Wéry, J and Fermaud, M   (2013) A new integrative assessment indicator for damage caused by major pests and diseases in the vineyard.  [Un nouvel indicateur intégré d’évaluation des dégâts occasionnés aux grappes par des bioagresseurs majeurs au vignoble.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 61-71.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26240/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>