<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of crop management factors and the environment on pest and disease incidence in vegetables</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Cooper, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, C.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lueck, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shotton, P.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Nafferton Factorial Systems Comparison (NFSC) experiments are part of a long-term field trial that compares organic and conventional systems of crop rotation, crop protection and fertility management, in a factorial design.  Pest and disease incidence in vegetables in the 2005, 2006 and 2007 season are reported.  Cabbage root fly damage was always reduced under organic crop protection, but there were no consistent trends for the effects of fertility management on this pest.  Sclerotinia in lettuce was consistently higher under conventional fertility management.  Blight in potatoes was enhanced in the 2007 season by the combination of conventional fertility management and organic crop protection practices.  Mechanisms for these effects, including the role of plant nutrition and the environment, are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11747/1/Cooper__11747_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Cooper, J.M.; Schmidt, C.S.; Lueck, L.; Shotton, P.N. and Leifert, C.    (2008) Effects of crop management factors and the environment on pest and disease incidence in vegetables.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11747/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>