<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic farming in Khartoum</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alkhalifa, Batoul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elkhatim, Azza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Awouda, Elhag</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tawfig, Suad</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Interest in organic agriculture and its products has widely grown in the world, mainly because of the increasing environmental and health hazards associated with the intensive use of chemicals in agriculture. Sudan, in spite of its high potential of organic agricultural production along the shores of the Nile, rivers, and the seasonal streams, has not been able to widely invest in organic production. Over the last years, the paradigm of organic agriculture as a sustainable mode of production has strongly grown among the Sudanese community. Furthermore, the importance of this type of production is progressively increasing amongst researchers, as well as policy makers as a good sign for a healthy thinking lead to take serious steps toward organic production in all the states of Sudan especially Khartoum state as a horticultural state and where the Capital of Sudan located. This paper reviews the potentials and current situation of organic agriculture in Khartoum and the running organic farming projects in different States are highlighted. The main directives in the Sudanese Standard of Organic Agriculture are pointed out. The complete lack or gabs in legislation for organic production in Sudan, besides the absence of national or international offices of inspection and certification bodies are focused.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23236/7/23236.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alkhalifa, Batoul; Elkhatim, Azza; Awouda, Elhag and Tawfig, Suad     (2014) Organic farming in Khartoum.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23236/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>