<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Grassland carbon sequestration and emissions following cultivation in a mixed crop rotation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Acharya, B.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Grasslands are potential carbon sinks to reduce unprecedented increase in atmospheric CO2. Effect of age (1 to 4-yr-old) and management (slurry, grazing multispecies mixture) of a grass phase mixed crop rotation on carbon sequestration and emissions upon cultivation was compared with 17-yr-old grassland and a pea field as reference. Aboveground and root biomass were determined and soils were incubated to study CO2 emissions after soil disturbance. Aboveground biomass was highest in 1-yr-old grassland with slurry application and lowest in 4-yr-old grassland without slurry application. Root biomass was highest in 4-yr-old grassland, but all 1 to 4-yr-old grasslands were in between the pea field (0.81±0.094 g kg-1 soil) and the 17-yr-old grassland (3.17±0.22 g kg-1 soil). Grazed grasslands had significantly higher root biomass than cut grasslands. There was no significant difference in the CO2 emissions within 1 to 4-yr-old grasslands. Only the 17-yr-old grassland showed markedly higher CO2 emissions (4.9 ± 1.1 g CO2 kg-1 soil). Differences in aboveground and root biomass did not affect CO2 emissions, and slurry application did not either. The substantial increase in root biomass with age but indifference in CO2 emissions across the age and management in temporary grasslands, thus, indicates potential for long-term sequestration of soil C.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22041/7/22041.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Acharya, B.S.; Rasmussen, J. and Eriksen, J.   (2012) Grassland carbon sequestration and emissions following cultivation in a mixed crop rotation.   Agriculture, Ecosystems &amp; Environment, 153, pp. 33-39.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22041/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>