<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative study of total phenolic content and radical scavenging activity of conventionally and organically grown herbs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trendafilova, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Todorova, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vassileva, Elka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivanova, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the present study was to measure the relative phenolic content in commonly available conventionally and organically grown herbs and to evaluate their antioxidant capacity. Sage (Salvia officinalis), lemon balm (Melissa officinalis) and peppermint (Mentha x piperita) leaves, corriander  (Corriandrum sativum) and fennel (Foeniculum vulgare) seeds were used in the present investigation.&#xD;
Total phenolic content (TPhC), measured by Folin-Ciocalteu method, and radical scavenging activity (RSA), using DPPH method were determined in infusions prepared from above mentioned herbs. TPhC ranged from 75.9 to 1126.5 gallic acid equivalents (GAE) mg/l infusion and RSA – from 7.03 to 91.65%. The obtained data also showed that infusions prepared from organically grown sage, peppermint and lemon balm were slightly higher than those obtained from conventionally grown herbs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23663/1/BotanicaSerbica2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trendafilova, A.; Todorova, M.; Vassileva, Elka and Ivanova, Daniela   (2010) Comparative study of total phenolic content and radical scavenging activity of conventionally and organically grown herbs.   Botanica Serbica, 34 (2), 133 -136.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23663/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>