<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The assessment of some crop management methods in barley and potato seed production for organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skrabule, Ilze</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Legzdina, Linda</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of investigation was to evaluate different crop management methods in production of qualita-tive seed material of barley and potato. The late blight damages on potato leaves depended on genotype resistance; more resistant variety had less damaged leave area. The genotype determined potato yield and average weight of tubers. The tuber pre-sprouting before planting accelerated plant germina-tion and promoted formation of bigger yield tubers. Presprouting influence on yield was not observed. Higher yield and smaller tuber weight was obtained if seed material was planted with shorter distance. Influence of planting distance on late blight develop-ment on leaves was not observed. The best yielding barley genotype was breeding line PR-2797, which is resistant to loose smut. The optimum seed rate for barley ‘Idumeja’ and PR-2797 was 400 germinating seeds per m2, but for variety ‘Ruja’ seed rate 550 germinating seeds per m2 increased yield. Seed treat-ment with warm and hot water was effective for reduction of loose smut infection of susceptible vari-ety ‘Ruja’</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7422/1/skrabule.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Skrabule, Ilze  and Legzdina, Linda     (2006) The assessment of some crop management methods in barley and potato seed production for organic farming.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7422/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>