<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Micro-economic instruments for impact assessment of multifunctional agriculture to implement the Model of European Agriculture: Work package 6: Subsidiarity, governance, and social demand issues</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Common Agricultural Policy reform aims at higher international trade compatibility and better targeting of social, environmental and consumer concerns, while seeking to ensure the sustainable development of EU agriculture. To optimise the effectiveness .and efficiency of CAP reform options towards multi functionality implementations, tools are required to assess the impacts of agricultural production on the multiple functions of European landscapes.&#xD;
The Euroepan Model of European Agriculture (MEA) has a multifunctional perspective but policy makers lack multi functionality impact assessment tools. MEA-Scope will develop such a tool and thus will close the existing gap between pure ecological or social process models and sectoral macro-econometric or equilibrium models. To ensure compatibility with the MEA, a specific interpretation of multi functionality will be devised and used in the design of MEA-Scope. MEA-Scope will be spatially explicit and will perform impact assessments of agricultural land use modifications at farm and landscape level. This will be achieved by linking three existing micro-economic models that simulate different aspects of farm structure. economics, production and environmental impact. Appropriate scope and detail will be ensured by simultaneous analyses of the regional demands for multiple landscape functions and of end user information needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
DESCRIPTION OF WP 6&#xD;
&#xD;
WP6: Subsidiarity, governance, and social demand issues&#xD;
Work package 6 will contribute to the project providing a participatory approach at two levels. Level 1 is dedicated to the regional case-study areas and aims at valuating and analysing social demand for multifunctionality. Level 2 deals with end-user involvement at EU level and therefore acts as an integrative feedback tool for the entire project.&#xD;
&#xD;
D 6.1 Agricultural EU gouvernance structures: status/trends&#xD;
Here, a review of EU governance structures particularly of the EU Commission is developed. A review of academic and grey literature as well as EU administration documents will be conducted. The literature review will be complemented by a survey of 5 to 10 key-informants at EU level in order to identify upcoming trends and information demands at the prospective end user level.&#xD;
&#xD;
D 6.2 Rules for “down-scaling” types of CAP reform measures&#xD;
Subtask 6.2 combines the results of the literature and document review (D6.1.) with the results from CAP reform evaluation processes, and with the insights gained from the analysis of regional demand priorities for different multifunctionality aspects (D6.3). These sources shed light on the regionally different norms that influence the way in which CAP policy options are implemented regionally within the EU subsidiarity framework. The generation of formalised rules closes a gap in policy impact analysis that otherwise exists within the system of signal transmission from Brussels in to the European regions.&#xD;
&#xD;
D 6.3 Case study on regional multifunctionality demand&#xD;
Analysis and valuation of social demand for multifunctionality will be based on the expert valuation method (EVM). EVM assumes that consumers implicitly endow public authorities with the representation of their interests in the provision of public goods, e.g. their interest in attractive landscapes. Consequently, consumers delegate all decisions to a principal. In turn, the principal has to carry out a formal valuation procedure in order to assess and fulfil the demand of the consumer. The EVM process therefore includes principals, or “experts” respectively with close regional ties to their consumer “constituency”.&#xD;
EVM will be performed in 4 case-study regions. In order to consider the potential differences in the demand for multifunctionality, and to cover the European dimension of the project DE, IT, DK and PL will be chosen for EVM case-studies. EVM will be conducted in two steps analogue to the well known Delphi-Method. Step one comprises a semi-structured survey of approximately 20 regional experts (case-study level). There will be regional decision-makers to be surveyed as well as experts form regional administration authorities, farmers associations, nature conservation organisations, tourist offices, parties etc. Step two will confront the experts with the group results gained in step one and will generate conclusions and orders of magnitude (priorities) to regional social demand for multifunctionality. The case study surveys will include a gender dimension to account for genderspecific perceptions and demands regarding land use and settlement in rural areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
D 6.4 End user workshops&#xD;
Subtask 6.4 will first of all identify relevant end-users on the EU level. End users will participate in subtask 6.4 in a series of three workshops. The first workshop will focus on the end users’ information needs, requirements and EU policy priorities with respect to MEA-Scope. The outcome allows (a) for outlining the most relevant CAP reform scenarios for which multifunctional impact assessments are needed, and (b) for the definition of technical specifications of the MEA-Scope tool, particularly with respect to the functions/indicators to be covered. A second workshop will be conducted to evaluate and to discuss the mid-term project results. The aim of this workshop is to identify potential needs for project adjustments on the one side. On the other side, this workshop will formulate tentative suggestions for policy recommendations that can will make the MEA-compatible multifunctionality interpretation (conceptually developed at WP 2) more tangible. Recommendations may include preferred institutional arrangements as well as modifications to existing or planned CAP policy measures.&#xD;
A third workshop will bring the integration process of the project results to a first climax as the integration is performed as a joint end user-project scientist policy impact analysis. By outlining the potential policy consequences of the MEA-Scope findings at the EU level, the development of a targeted policy model is further enhanced.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    MEASCOPE, WP 6: Micro-economic instruments for impact assessment of multifunctional agriculture to implement the Model of European Agriculture: Work package 6: Subsidiarity, governance, and social demand issues.  [Politikoptionen für multifunktionale Landwirtschaft (MEA Scope).]   Runs 2004 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Stolze, Matthias, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6224/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>