<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Checkliste der Kurzflügelkäfer der Schweiz (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae ohne Pselaphinae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luka, Henryk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nagel, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feldmann, Benedikt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luka, Agata</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonseth, Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within the context of the project «Pilot Study for a Red List of Staphylinids of Switzerland (Coleoptera, Staphylinidae)» of the Swiss Federal Office for the Environment (BAFU), the checklist of rove beetles (excluding the subfamily Pselaphinae) in Switzerland is compiled. It accounts for all species that 1) have a record in the database of the Centre Suisse de Cartographie de la Faune, 2) are listed in the unpublished species list compiled by C. Besuchet, and 3) are listed for Switzerland in the catalogue by Löbl &amp; Smetana (2004).&#xD;
In all, 1421 staphylinid taxa (1414 species and 7 additional subspecies) (excl. Pselaphinae) have been recorded from Switzerland, among them 1297 monotypical species, 110 polytypical species represented by only one subspecies in Switzerland, and 7 polytypical species represented by two subspecies each.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Schweizerischen Entomologischen Gesellschaft</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18167/1/luka-etal-2009-checkliste-staphylinidae.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Luka, Henryk; Nagel, Peter; Feldmann, Benedikt; Luka, Agata and Gonseth, Yves   (2009) Checkliste der Kurzflügelkäfer der Schweiz (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae ohne Pselaphinae).  [Checklist of Staphylinids of Switzerland (Coleoptera: Staphylinidae excl. Pselaphinae).]  Mitteilungen der Schweizerischen entomologischen Gesellschaft, 82, pp. 61-100.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18167/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>