<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2006</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From the IFOAM press release of February 14, 2006:&#xD;
&#xD;
According to the survey, currently more than 31 million hectares of farmland are under organic management worldwide, a gain of around five million hectares in a single year. A major increase of organic land has taken place in China, where nearly three million hectares of pastoral land were recently certified. &#xD;
&#xD;
In terms of organic land, excluding wild collection, Australia leads pack with 12.1 million hectares, followed by China (3.5 million hectares) and Argentina (2.8 million hectares). Most of the world’s organic land is in Australia / Oceania (39%), followed by Europe (21 %), Latin America (20%), Asia (13%), North America (4 %) and Africa (3 %). Regarding the share of organic farmland in comparison with the total agricultural area, Austria, Switzerland and Scandinavian countries lead the way. In Switzerland, for example, more than ten percent of the agricultural land is managed organically. The editors of the study Minou Yussefi (SOEL) and Helga Willer (FiBL) note that “the continued increase in the organic land area over the last years is not just due to the ever greater interest in organic farming, but also a result of improved access to information and data collection each time the study is updated.” &#xD;
&#xD;
In 2004, the market value of organic products worldwide reached 27.8 billion US$, (23.5 billion EUR), the largest share of organic products being marketed in Europe and North America. Ongoing growth of the market and organic land area is expected for the foreseeable future, in part due to an increased support of governments and development organizations. Angela B. Caudle, IFOAM Executive Director, emphasizes “as markets for organic products continue to develop throughout the world, including in key markets outside of Europe and North America, such as Brazil and the Middle East, the benefits of organic agricultural systems on a large scale will become increasingly evident.”&#xD;
&#xD;
This global study about organic farming will be presented for the 8th time at BioFach. For the first time “The World of Organic Agriculture” includes not only information on total organic area but also on land use and on major crops, and features an updated chapter on the market situation and emerging trends for all continents, provided by renowned experts in the organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), Bonn, Germany and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yussefi, Minou</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5161/1/yussefi-2006-overview.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5161/2/willer-yussefi-2005-world-of-organic.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5161/3/parrot-et-al-2006-africa.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga and Yussefi, Minou (Eds.)      (2006) The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2006.     International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), Bonn, Germany and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5161/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>