<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ALTERNTIVE PROTECTION OF BIOPOTATOES IN ORGANIC FARMING</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tomasek, Jaroslav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dvorak, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There were tested water extracts from Syringa vulgaris and Pyrethrum parthenium. They did not prove significant differences of decrease of the air attack of Colorado potato beetle (Leptinotarsa decemlineata), the activity of eggs – laying and the occurrence of larvae in comparison to the control. Interesting trends of lower-eggs lying and a lower larvae occurrence were discovered. The liquid spray against the late blight (Phytophthora infestans) did not significantly decrease neither occurrence of late blight or the yield.&#xD;
The production of the bio-potatoes is only 0,2 % of all potatoes production in the Czech Republic. The aim of this experiment was to try alternative methods of regulation of Colorado potato beetle and late blight (the biggest harmfull organisms of potatoes). &#xD;
For biological agriculture could be also suitable water extracts. These are possible to use as protection of potatoes against unfavorable factors (Colorado potate beetle and late blight) and increase yield and quality of production.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20584/1/%C4%8Dl%C3%A1nek_Rumunsko_Tom%C3%A1%C5%A1ek%2C_2009._52_1%2C_133-135..pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tomasek, Jaroslav and Dvorak, Petr   (2010) ALTERNTIVE PROTECTION OF BIOPOTATOES IN ORGANIC FARMING.   Lucrări Ştiinţifice, 52, pp. 133-135.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20584/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>