<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Procedure for the Implementation of the Precautionary Principle in Biosafety Commissions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ammann, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hilbeck, Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lanzrein, Beatrice</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hübner, Philipp</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oehen, Bernadette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to fulfil their responsibilities under the precautionary principle, biosafety commissions should lay down guidelines concerning the understanding and application of this principle and work towards an operational procedure. With this contribution, we propose a step-wise procedure that aims to establish the understanding of the precautionary principle within biosafety commissions and to provide a methodological approach for the application of this principle to specific cases in the course of risk assessment. This approach is based on systematically investigating the consensus view within a group of 15 biosafety experts with the help of sets of checklists. For step 1, we propose a checklist of 13 criteria aimed at defining the understanding of the precautionary principle. For step 2, we propose 4 criteria for the decision on whether or not to use the precautionary principle. For step 3, 11 criteria for the use of the precautionary principle are presented. In step 4, additional criteria for specific applications could be included. In step 5, possible recommendations to decision-making authorities are proposed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25735/1/Ammann%20et%20al%20%202007.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ammann, Daniel; Hilbeck, Angelika; Lanzrein, Beatrice; Hübner, Philipp and Oehen, Bernadette   (2007) Procedure for the Implementation of the Precautionary Principle in Biosafety Commissions.   Journal of Risk Research, 10 (4), pp. 487-501.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25735/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>