<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison of Polyacetylene Content in Organically and  Conventionally Grown Carrots Using a Fast Ultrasonic Liquid Extraction Method</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Søltoft, Malene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, M.R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Träger, A.W.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, Kristian Holst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halekoh, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knuthsen, Pia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A rapid and sensitive analytical method for quantification  of polyacetylenes in carrot roots was developed. The traditional extraction method (stirring) was compared to a new ultrasonic liquid processor (ULP)-based methodology using high-performance liquid chromatography−ultraviolet (HPLC−UV) and mass spectrometry (MS) for identification and quantification of three polyacetylenes. ULP was superior because a significant reduction in extraction time and improved extraction efficiencies were obtained. After optimization, the ULP method showed good selectivity, precision [relative standard deviations (RSDs) of 2.3−3.6%], and recovery (93% of falcarindiol) of the polyacetylenes. The applicability of the method was documented by comparative analyses of carrots grown organically or conventionally in a 2 year field trial study. The average concentrations of falcarindiol, falcarindiol-3-acetate, and falcarinol in year 1 were 222, 30, and 94 μg of falcarindiol equiv/g of dry weight, respectively, and 3−15% lower in year 2. The concentrations were not significantly influenced by the growth system, but a significant year−year variation was observed for falcarindiol-3-acetate.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19121/4/19121.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Søltoft, Malene; Eriksen, M.R.; Träger, A.W.B.; Nielsen, J.; Laursen, Kristian Holst; Husted, Søren; Halekoh, Ulrich and Knuthsen, Pia   (2010) Comparison of Polyacetylene Content in Organically and Conventionally Grown Carrots Using a Fast Ultrasonic Liquid Extraction Method.   J Agric Food Chem , 58, pp. 7673-7679.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19121/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>