<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impacts of climate change on plant diseases – opinions and trends</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pautasso, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garbelotto, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pellis, L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeger, MJ</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There has been a remarkable scientific output on the topic of how climate change is likely to affect plant diseases in the coming decades. This review addresses the need for review of this burgeoning literature by summarizing opinions of previous reviews and trends in recent studies on the impacts of climate change on plant health. Sudden Oak Death is used as an introductory case study: Californian forests could become even more susceptible to this emerging plant disease, if spring precipitations will be accompanied by warmer temperatures, although climate shifts may also affect the current synchronicity between host cambium activity and pathogen colonization rate. A summary of observed and predicted climate changes, as well as of direct effects of climate change on pathosystems, is provided. Prediction and management of climate change effects on plant health are complicated by indirect effects and the interactions with global change drivers. Uncertainty in models of plant disease development under climate change calls for a diversity of management strategies, from more participatory approaches to interdisciplinary science. Involvement of stakeholders and scientists from outside plant pathology shows the importance of trade-offs, for example in the land-sharing vs. sparing debate. Further research is needed on climate change and plant health in mountain, boreal, Mediterranean and tropical regions, with multiple climate change factors and scenarios (including our responses to it, e.g. the assisted migration of plants), in relation to endophytes, viruses and mycorrhiza, using long-term and large-scale datasets and considering various plant disease control methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21902/1/2012.Pautasso%20et%20al.EJPP.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pautasso, Marco; Döring, Thomas F.; Garbelotto, M; Pellis, L and Jeger, MJ   (2012) Impacts of climate change on plant diseases – opinions and trends.   European Journal of Plant Pathology, 133, pp. 295-313.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21902/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>