<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>China's Organic Revolution</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>China</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agriculture in China is at the onset of an Organic Revolution. From 2000 to 2006, China has moved from 45th to 2nd position in the world in number of hectares under organic management. China now has more land under organic horticulture than any other country. In the year 2005/2006, China added 12% to the world’s organic area. This accounted for 63% of the world’s annual increase in organic land, and China now has 11% of the world’s organically managed land. The antecedents to China’s Organic Revolution are examined, and reveal further growth potential in the Chinese organic sector. Longitudinal analysis of China’s food production statistics reveals explosive growth, and the consequent capacity for export has implications for food exporting nations. China has adopted an innovative path, via Green Food, towards achieving an organic future. This transition strategy may be a model for other countries seeking a rapid expansion of organics. Food exporting countries can expect in future to have their chemi-agricultural produce competing with certified organic produce of China.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>The Icfai University Press, Hyderabad, India</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Bhaskaran, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mohanty, Suchitra</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14846/1/14846.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John    (2008) China's Organic Revolution.    In: Bhaskaran, S. and Mohanty, Suchitra (Eds.)   Marketing of Organic Products: Global Experiences.  The Icfai University Press, Hyderabad, India, chapter 17, pp. 260-275.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14846/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>