<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The challenge of producing organic vegetable seeds of high quality in Denmark</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Deleuran, L.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boelt, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Production of organic vegetable seeds is possible in Denmark for some of the late maturing vegetable species - when performed in tunnels. At the Danish Institute of Agricultural Sciences (DIAS) different growing systems in tunnels have been studied in carrot (Daucus carota L.), cauliflower (Brassica oleracea var. oleracea) and leek (Allium porrum L.).&#xD;
Tunnel production of carrot and leek seed increases yield and germination percentages compared to normal field conditions. Yields in the range of 100 –250 g seeds/m2 can be obtained in both species. A hybrid cauliflower seed production is possible in tunnels with a yield range of 9,7 – 67,6 g seeds/plant. In cauliflower problems with fungi on the seeds and a following low germination percentage often occur and improved ways to reduce this problem is needed. &#xD;
The lightweight tunnel production system can be widely used and modified for small-scale producers in e.g. developing countries.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7967/1/7967.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Deleuran, L.C. and Boelt, B.    (2005) The challenge of producing organic vegetable seeds of high quality in Denmark.   In:     Congress Handbook of 15th IFOAM Organic World Congress.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7967/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>