<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Compost and digestate: sustainability, benefits, impacts for the environment and for plant production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kupper, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>SCHENK, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This proceedings volume contains the papers presented at the CODIS 2008 congress held on 27 - 29 February 2008 in Solothurn (Switzerland).The composting and digestion of biogenic waste materials and the subsequent application of compost and digestate to soil contributes to nutrient recycling and renewable energy production. Moreover, compost and digestate can improve soil fertility and suppress plant diseases. On the other hand, compost and digestate may also contain a variety of pollutants hazardous to soil, such as heavy metals and organic contaminants.Compost and digestate have been thoroughly investigated in the framework of two associated projects entitled Organic Pollutants in Compost and Digestate in Switzerland and Effects of Composts and Digestate on the Environment, Soil Fertility and Plant Health. These projects yielded new insights into the properties of compost and digestate, mainly with regard to biological parameters and the occurrence of both classic and emerging organic pollutants.The CODIS 2008 congress was the final event of these two projects.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kupper, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tamm, Lucius</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schenk, Karina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25267/1/1495-proceedings-codis2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fuchs, Jacques G.; Kupper, Thomas; Tamm, Lucius and Schenk, Karina (Eds.)    (2008) Compost and digestate: sustainability, benefits, impacts for the environment and for plant production.  [Proceedings of the international congress CODIS 2008. February 27-29, 2008, Solo.]  Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25267/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>