<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluating inputs for organic farming – a new system. Proposals of the ORGANIC INPUTS EVALUATION project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Speiser, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blake, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Micheloni, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stopes, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baker, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bywater, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Canali, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, R. Ø.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonzalvez, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hozzank, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jespersen, L. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, L. N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kleeberg, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmans, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kromp, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manstretta, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer da Costa, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monnier, MC.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pauler, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schreyer, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slabe, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Fragstein, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This volume contains proposals for criteria for evaluation of plant protection products, fertilisers and soil conditioners1 to be used in organic agriculture. These ideas were developed in the course of the European Union (EU) Concerted Action project ‘ORGANIC INPUTS EVALUATION’ (QLK5-CT-2002-02565). For more information on this project see the end of this volume or visit the project website www.organicinputs.org. The documents in this volume are proposals elaborated by the project consortium and external experts. They were discussed with a broader audience at a public conference held in Brussels on October 13, 2005, and have been amended accordingly.&#xD;
Our proposals also include a “criteria matrix”, which is in Microsoft Excel format, and therefore stands as a separate file. The criteria matrix is discussed in section 5, but we strongly recommend that you consult the original document. To illustrate the use of the matrix, we have further prepared two case studies, which are also separate Excel files. All of these files are contained on the CD, and can also be downloaded from the project website.&#xD;
Currently, Regulation 2092/91 is under revision. We hope that our ideas can be incorporated into the regulation during this revision! In addition, we strongly encourage national institutions to make use of our proposals at the national level.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8551/1/Speiser_etal_2005-a-new-system_finalreport.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Speiser, B.; Blake, F.; Micheloni, C.; Stopes, C.; Andersen, M.; Baker, B.; Bywater, S.; Canali, S.; Eriksen, R. Ø.; Gonzalvez, V.; Hozzank, A.; Jespersen, L. M.; Jørgensen, L. N.; Kelderer, M.; Kleeberg, H.; Koopmans, C.; Kromp, B.; Manstretta, M.; Maurer da Costa, A.; Monnier, MC.; Pauler, A.; Schmid, O.; Schreyer, A.; Slabe, A.; Tamm, L.; Trapman, M. and von Fragstein, P.         (2005) Evaluating inputs for organic farming – a new system. Proposals of the ORGANIC INPUTS EVALUATION project.   Final Report. Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL) CH-Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8551/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>