<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The role of CLA content of organic milk in consumers’ healthcare</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Szente, Viktória</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szakály, Sándor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bukovics, Zsolt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szigeti, Orsolya</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Polereczki, Zsolt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Székely, Olivér</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berke, Szilárd</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Takács, Györgyi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nagyné Farkas, Rita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Szakály, Zoltán</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to the results of human health researches the causes of the leading diseases (heart- and cardiovascular system, malignant tumours) show a close relation with human nutrition. Therefore the topic of animal origin product quality affecting the human health receives increasing attention. The content and proportion of the saturated and unsaturated fatty acids and the content of vitamins and macro- and micro elements are in the centre of interest, which justify the present study. &#xD;
In the background of the consumers’ decision making concerning organic food. They are wholesomeness, together with it high quality and being chemical-free, so that is why they can be considered primary consumers expectations. Due to the composition of organic milk it can meet the demands, and the nutritional benefits (supported by researches) can be put in the centre of marketing communication. From the point of view of other elements of marketing-mix, the nutritional value must also be highlighted. The controlled, first-class organic product should be placed in the product strategy, which meets the consumers’ expectations because of the high rate of the conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) and vitamins. The price sensitivity of the consumers may be reduced by higher added value of the „curative” organic milk.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7207/3/Szente_milk_quality_revised.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Szente, Viktória; Szakály, Sándor; Bukovics, Zsolt; Szigeti, Orsolya; Polereczki, Zsolt; Székely, Olivér; Berke, Szilárd; Takács, Györgyi; Nagyné Farkas, Rita and Szakály, Zoltán    (2006) The role of CLA content of organic milk in consumers’ healthcare.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7207/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>