<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analyse der Fruchtbarkeit und ihrer Kontrolle in biologisch&#xD;
wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelch, Manuela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A retrospective study was performed including 54 Swiss dairy farms of an udder&#xD;
health extension project. The objective was to evaluate additional effects on fertility&#xD;
parameters in the first two project years (y1, y2) compared to the year before (y0). Of&#xD;
1494 lactations 251 diagnoses associated to reproduction and obstetrics were performed&#xD;
(17 per 100 Lactations). Ovary disorders (29%), retentio secundinarum (25%)&#xD;
and metritis (20%) were the most common items. Ovary disorders could be treated by&#xD;
homeopathy as successful as by hormones. Uterine disorders (ret sec., metritis) were&#xD;
followed by significantly better fertility parameters (days to first insemination 60 vs. 84&#xD;
days, calving conception interval 68 vs. 118 days) after homeopathic treatment compared&#xD;
to antibiosis. Fertility parameters have been significantly enhanced from y0 to&#xD;
y2. Homeopathic treatment proportion increased from 4% to approx. 30%. This indicates&#xD;
that an udder health programme can lead to improved fertility parameters and&#xD;
therapy concept conversion as well.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14475/1/Klocke_14475.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klocke, Peter; Kelch, Manuela and Ivemeyer, Silvia    (2009) Analyse der Fruchtbarkeit und ihrer Kontrolle in biologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14475/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>