<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mortality in organic free-range chickens and molecular characterization of the involved pathogens</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maag Eigaard, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Permin, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, J.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bisgaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Longitudinal investigations on causes of mortality were carried out at one organic layer farm with four flocks of Lohman Brown and Lohman White chickens producing table eggs. All flocks were housed separately. One flock of each breed were followed from September 2001 to August 2002. Post mortem examinations were performed on a total of 16% of the dead chickens over the entire period. Of these 346 (96%) of the Lohmann Brown and 315 (91%) of the Lohmann White chickens were subjected for bacteriology.&#xD;
High mortality rates, 91% and 63% were observed in Lohman Brown and Lohman White chickens, respectively and were found to be due to infections with mainly Pasteurella multocida, Erysipelothix rhusiopathia and Escherichia coli. E. rhusiopathia, P. multocida and E. coli were isolated from 46%, 19% and 17%, respectively of the Lohmann Brown chickens. In the flock of Lohmann White chickens P. multocida and E. coli were isolated from 46% and 15%, respectively while E. rhusiopathia was not recorded. P. multocida and E. rhusiopathia isolates were characterized by Restriction Endonuclease Analysis (REA), Restriction Fragment Length Polymorphism (RFLP) and Pulse Field Gel Electrophoresis (PFGE). It was demonstrated that all the P. multocida isolates were genotypic identical over time. The E. rhusiopathia isolates obtained were also identical.&#xD;
It was concluded that the outbreaks caused by P. multocida and E. rhusiopathia were clonal and these two pathogens may cause severe losses in free-range chickens.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1878/1/Denver_2003_endelig_version.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Maag Eigaard, N.; Permin, A.; Christensen, J.P. and Bisgaard, M.    (2003) Mortality in organic free-range chickens and molecular characterization of the involved pathogens.       Poster at:   XIII Congress of the World Veterinary Poultry Association, Denver, Colorado, July 19-23, 2003.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1878/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>