<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic protein feed and edible oil from oilseed crops</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>"Organic protein feed and edible oil from oilseed crops" is a four year research project with the aim of obtaining new knowledge for secure production of high-quality proteins for livestock feeds and edible oil for human consumption in Norwegian organic farming based on oilseed crops. This will be done by investigating 1) potential for use of winter rape (Brassica napus L. var. oleifera Metzg.) and winter turnip rape (Brassica rapa L. var. olieifera Sinsk.) in Norway, 2) problems with volunteers of spring turnip rape, 3) cultivation practices on nutrient supply for organic oil-seed crops, 4) feed quality of organically grown protein crops and 5) content and fatty acid composition of organically grown oil seed crops. Throughout the project period efforts will be made to implement the new knowledge in improved and new products in the participating industry, and new management methods for organic farming of oil-seed crops. The project, which is involving the whole production chain for production of protein feed and edible oil from&#xD;
oil-seed crops, is lead by the Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research in co-operation with the Norwegian University of Life Science, the Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Norwegian Institute for Land Inventory, Norwegian Meteorological Institute, Matforsk and the companies 'Felleskjøpet Fôrutvikling', 'TINE produsentrådgivning' and 'Norsk Matraps AB'.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9388/1/Oilseed_4_%282%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9388/2/Protein_crops_Norway.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    OILPROT: Organic protein feed and edible oil from oilseed crops.    Runs 2006 - 2010.      Project Leader(s): Eltun, Senior researcher Ragnar, Bioforsk Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9388/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>