<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cost driver in the organic meat market in Germany -  specific problem of the organic sector?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Beukert, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simons, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartmann, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>High prices for organic meat and meat products in Germany are caused especially by small scale production schemes and the special behaviour of the market participants. Special requirements for organic production systems play a minor role. The German market for organic meat is a co-ordinated market with restricted access, as an analysis based on expert interviews shows. Prevalent forms of co-ordination are contract production and the pooling of output and prices. Due to this situation, the margin between the producer and the consumer price is higher than on a competitive market. But the conditions on organic markets are changing as it becomes more difficult to restrict market access. For the future, the generation of demand could help to overcome the problems of this market. Existing networks in the organic meat market could be used to co-ordinate necessary activities.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4505/3/Beukert_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Beukert, Christoph; Simons, Johannes and Hartmann, Monika    (2005) Cost driver in the organic meat market in Germany - specific problem of the organic sector?       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4505/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>