<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of plant extracts on downy mildew of vine-Laboratory and field experiments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kast, Walter K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Extracts made from leaves, bark, flowers or roots of 23 different plant species using water, alcohol or acetone were tested against downy mildew of vine in laboratory, glasshouse and vineyards. Highest effects were found for Hedera helix (leaves in water), Quercus spec.(bark in alcohol), Primula veris (roots in water), Rhamnus frangula (roots in alcohol), Solidago spec (leaves in alcohol), Salix spec. (bark in water). Extracts of Rhamnus and Primula had significant curative effects (30 - 35%). In the laboratory and glasshouse test protective effects were much better (70- 90% reduction of infection) than the results in field experiments (30 - 40%). Single use of these extracts is insufficient for practical use in viticulture. The use in combinations with stone-meals and low doses of copper should be tested in future.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14619/1/kast_157.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kast, Walter K.    (2002) Effects of plant extracts on downy mildew of vine-Laboratory and field experiments.  [Wirkung von Pflanzenextrakten in Labor- und Freilandversuchen gegen Rebenperonospora.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing and Viticulture. Proceedings to the Conference from 4th to 7th Feb. 2002 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 157-162.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14619/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>