<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Wahrnehmung von Leistungen direktabsetzender Betriebe des ökologischen Landbaus durch Verbraucher</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>König, Ingo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinborn, Patricia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deubele, Theresa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raupach, Valeria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reelfs, Torben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zieger, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a holistic approach customers were asked in qualitative interviews about their perception of organic farms which run their own shops. Besides the organic quality they like the competent service, the traditional look and details. They regard the farms shops as pleasant. Many customers visit the farm and animals. Other consumers living near the farm like a wide range of products contact to their neighbourhood and exchange information. The seasonal fluctuations in supply are accepted. Most customers, though different in age and motivation, are aware of ecological and health topics. Customers praise the good taste, the real freshness and good quality. In a second series of Interviews customers of organic shops were asked to define the farm shop related meaning of the word “atmosphere”. They regard it as the classical idyllic small farm agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3782/1/3782.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>König, Ingo; Steinborn, Patricia; Deubele, Theresa; Raupach, Valeria; Reelfs, Torben and Zieger, Martin    (2005) Die Wahrnehmung von Leistungen direktabsetzender Betriebe des ökologischen Landbaus durch Verbraucher.  [Perception of direct marketing organic farms through the customer.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3782/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>