<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards Grower-friendly Apple Crop Thinning by Tree Shading</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Widmer, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kockerols, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwan, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stadler, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bertschinger, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Light management with shading nets, which reduce sunlight by 74%, might be an&#xD;
alternative to chemicals commonly used for thinning on apple trees. To study the effect of&#xD;
shading on crop load and fruit quality, trials were conducted in field experiments with the&#xD;
cultivars Golden Delicious and Elstar in 2006. Trees were either covered 25 days after full&#xD;
bloom (DAFB) with a net during three days, or until the peak of fruit fall, observed after&#xD;
seven days shading. Ideal time length for optimal crop yield was seven days shading for&#xD;
Elstar and three days shading for Golden Delicious. Alternate bearing could be decreased&#xD;
as flower initiation counts the following year showed. In both experiments, inner quality of&#xD;
fruit such as sugar and firmness showed good values at optimal shading duration&#xD;
compared with chemical + hand thinning. In 2007, a second field trial was conducted with&#xD;
cultivars Golden Delicious and Topaz to study the time period for shading in further detail.&#xD;
Shading was done for three days at 19, 26 and 33 DAFB using two net types (three- and&#xD;
two-meter-net width, covering the trees entirely or only down to 50 cm above ground). For&#xD;
Golden Delicious, shading after 19 and 26 days reduced fruits per 100 flower cluster to the&#xD;
same extent as with chemical + hand thinning. There was no difference between the two&#xD;
net types. For Topaz, shading after 19 days showed the best results. Regarding inner&#xD;
quality of both cultivars, only sugar content for Golden Delicious could be significantly&#xD;
improved after 19 and 26 days shading. Further analyses are still under way (e.g. for&#xD;
acidity).&#xD;
This study is part of an effort for increasing European consumption with fruit from&#xD;
sustainable production systems, the ISAFRUIT-EU-project.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13738/1/314-318.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Widmer, A.; Kockerols, K.; Schwan, S.; Stadler, W. and Bertschinger, L.    (2008) Towards Grower-friendly Apple Crop Thinning by Tree Shading.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 314-318.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13738/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>