<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Susceptibility of olive cultivars to the Camarosporium dalmaticum (Thum) infections</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iannotta, dr. Nino</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noce, dr. Maria Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perri, sig. Luigi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scalercio, dr. Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vizzarri, dr. Veronica</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The C.R.A. Experimental Institute for Olive Growing has been performing for many years the study of olive germplasm in order to identify genetic resistance sources to the olive parasites. Some pathogens are particularly noxious for olive table production because they attack and disfigure the outward appearance of the fruits. Camarosporium dalmaticum (Thum) is a pathogen widespread in Southern Italy determining the olive fruit rot in many genotypes particularly susceptible to its infection. The object of the present study is an investigation carried out in Calabria in an experimental field, analysing 25 cvs cultivated under the same environmental and growing conditions. The observations were performed on olive fruit samples (200 per thesis) and the infection percentage was determined. The obtained data were submitted to statistical test by analysis of variance. The results displayed a different susceptibility of the investigated cultivars. “Ascolana tenera”, “Nostrana di Brisighella”, “Gordal sevillana” and “Ogliarola del Vulture” showed an high susceptibility to the pathogen while “Frantoio”, “Tonda di Strongoli” and “Ogliarola garganica” turned to be less susceptible. The remaining cultivars showed intermediate values of infection percentage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12762/1/Iannotta_Scalercio_et_al_2006g.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Iannotta, dr. Nino; Noce, dr. Maria Elena; Perri, sig. Luigi; Scalercio, dr. Stefano and Vizzarri, dr. Veronica    (2006) Susceptibility of olive cultivars to the Camarosporium dalmaticum (Thum) infections.       Paper at:   ond International Seminar on "Biotechnology and Quality of Olive tree Products around the Mediterranean basin", Olivebioteq, Marsala-Mazara del Vallo, 5th-10th November 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12762/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>