<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>RESULTS OF TWO-YEARS EXPERIMENTAL TRIALS WITH NATURAL&#xD;
PRODUCTS AGAINST PLASMOPARA VITICOLA IN ORGANIC VITICULTURE</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming the copper compounds are the only substances that can be used against&#xD;
downy mildew. As the copper causes problems of environmental impact, the Regulation EC&#xD;
n. 473/2002 fixed a ceiling on its use. Two-years experimental trials (2007-2008) were&#xD;
carried out in organic vineyard in order to evaluate anti-downy mildew effectiveness of&#xD;
natural products. Homeopathic products, resistance promoters, plant extracts and potassium&#xD;
bicarbonate have been tested. In 2007, a year of limited infection pressure, these products&#xD;
were able to control the disease, whereas in 2008, a year of high risk of disease, the natural&#xD;
products were scarsely effective. In conclusion, the natural products can be used in&#xD;
alternative to copper in condition of low or medium risk of infection, while, in conditions of&#xD;
high infection pressure, it is possible to use the natural products in combination with copper&#xD;
just to reduce the copper input</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>La Torre, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Talocci, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pinto, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18256/1/Results_of_two_years_experimental_trials__with_natural_products_against_Plasmopara_viticola.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>La Torre, A.; Talocci, S. and Pinto, L. (Eds.)    (2009) RESULTS OF TWO-YEARS EXPERIMENTAL TRIALS WITH NATURAL PRODUCTS AGAINST PLASMOPARA VITICOLA IN ORGANIC VITICULTURE.    . Proceedings of 9TH INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON PLANT DISEASES - AFPP, TOURS – FRANCE, 8 AND 9 DECEMBER 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18256/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>