<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The potential of ecological recycling agriculture (ERA) for improved nature resource conservation and reduced environmental impacts in the Baltic Sea drainage area</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Granstedt, Artur</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seuri, Pentti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsson, Olof</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>By integrating crop and animal production on a farm or farms in closed cooperation combined with soil formation legume crops in balanced crop-rotations it will be possible to maximize the efficient use of nutrients in manure, minimize inputs of limited nutrient resources, minimize nutrient surpluses and reduce the input of nutrients to the Baltic Sea by more than 50 %. This will be the basis for recommendation to convert the agriculture in the Baltic drainage area.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM); National Association for Sustainable Agriculture, Australia (NASAA); International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5949/1/GranstedtA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Granstedt, Artur; Schneider, Thomas; Seuri, Pentti and Thomsson, Olof    (2005) The potential of ecological recycling agriculture (ERA) for improved nature resource conservation and reduced environmental impacts in the Baltic Sea drainage area.   In:     CD Proceedings, International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM); National Association for Sustainable Agriculture, Australia (NASAA); International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), pp. 1-4.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5949/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>