<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fungal/bacterial ratios in grasslands with contrasting nitrogen management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>de Vries, Franciska T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hofland, Ellis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Eekeren, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brussaard, Lijbert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bloem, Jaap</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It is frequently hypothesised that high soil fungal/bacterial ratios are indicative for more sustainable agricultural systems.Increased F/B ratios have been reported in extensively managed grasslands.To determine the shifts in fungal/bacterial biomass ratio as in ﬂuenced by grassland management and to ﬁnd relations with nitrogen leaching potential,we sampled a two-year-old ﬁeld experiment at an organic experimental farm in the eastern part of The Netherlands.The effect of crop (grass and grass-clover),N application rate (0, 40, 80,120 kg N/ha 1 )and manure type (no manure,farm yard manure and slurry)on the F / B ratio within three growing seasons was tested, as well as relations with soil and crop characteristics,nitrate leaching and partial N balance. Biomass of fungi and bacteria was calculated after direct counts using epi ﬂuorescence microscopy. Fungal and bacterial biomass and the F B ratio were higher in grass than in grass-clover.The F/B ratio decreased with increasing N application rate and multiple regression analysis revealed a negative relationship with pH. Bacterial activity (measured as incorporation of [3H]thymidine and [14C]leucine into bacterial DNA and proteins)showed the exact opposite:an increase with N application rate and pH. Leaching increased with N application rate and was higher in grass-clover than in grass. Partial N balance was more positive at a higher N application rate and showed an inverse relationship with fungal biomass and F/B ratio.We conclude that the fungal/bacterial biomass ratio quickly responded to changes in management. Grasslands with higher N input showed lower F/B ratios.Grass-clover had a smaller fungal biomass and higher N leaching than grass.In general,a higher fungal biomass indicated a lower nitrogen leaching and a more negative partial N balance (or smaller N surplus), but more observations are needed to con ﬁrm the relationship between F/B ratio and sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9382/1/De_Vries_et_al._2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>de Vries, Franciska T; Hofland, Ellis; van Eekeren, Nick; Brussaard, Lijbert and Bloem, Jaap   (2006) Fungal/bacterial ratios in grasslands with contrasting nitrogen management.   Soil Biology &amp;Biochemistry (38), pp. 2092-2103.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9382/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>