<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The nutritive value of lupins in sole cropping systems and mixed intercropping with spring cereals for grain production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Berk, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bramm, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rühl, Gerhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In total 572 experimental plots were established at two sites during three years with different grain legume species, such as lupins, field beans and peas as well as mixed intercropping of different legumes or legumes with spring cereals for grain production. From all plots yield as well as quality and energy parameters of grains were analysed and the feed values calculated. &#xD;
Compared to soy bean meal yellow lupins have higher protein content but a low yield. While the energy content of lupins as feed for pigs, cattle and milking cows was only slightly higher than of soy bean meal, its feed energy for poultry was nearly comparable.&#xD;
In the case of mixed intercropping with spring cereals the feed energy content for pigs and cattle by using spring wheat or- barley as partner was higher than a comparable mixture of wheat and soy bean meal. The lowest feed energy contents were achieved with mixtures of legumes and oats.  From the view of animal nutrition the parts of lupins in the mixed intercropping grains should be higher in the relation to spring cereals to increase especially the protein content.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Lupin Association</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Palta, Jairo A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Berger, Jens D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16533/1/Berk_etal_lupins_nutritive_value-tagband.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Berk, Andreas; Bramm, Andreas; Böhm, Herwart; Aulrich, Karen and Rühl, Gerhard    (2008) The nutritive value of lupins in sole cropping systems and mixed intercropping with spring cereals for grain production.  [Der Nährwert von Lupinen in Reinsaat und in Mischkultur mit Sommergetreide zur Körnerproduktion.]   In: Palta, Jairo A. and Berger, Jens D. (Eds.)   Lupins for Health and Wealth - Proceedings of the 12th International Lupin Conference, Fremantle, Western Australia.  International Lupin Association, Canterbury, New Zealand, pp. 66-70.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16533/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>