<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Multi-elemental fingerprinting of plant tissue by semi-quantitative ICP-MS and chemometrics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, Kristian Holst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Thomas Hesselhøj</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Persson, Daniel Pergament</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjørring, Jan Kofod</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The multi-elemental capacity of Inductively Coupled Plasma-Mass Spectrometry (ICP-MS) is rarely fully utilized in traditional full-quantitative analysis. The main obstacles are limited availability of multi-elemental standards and the need for time-consuming external calibrations. In this study, a novel semi-quantitative quadrupole ICP-MS based method for multi-elemental fingerprinting of plant tissue was developed as a high-throughput alternative to full-quantitative analysis. The main analytical objectives were low data acquisition time (&lt;60 seconds), detailed coverage of the atomic mass range from 7Li to 238U and discrimination power similar to full-quantitative analysis based on chemometric data analysis. The method was tested on grains of different rice (Oryza sativa) genotypes. The semi-quantitative rice fingerprints consisted of 30 elements based on the limit of detections as inclusion criteria. Fourteen of these were determined with an accuracy &gt;70%. In conjunction with chemometrics, the discrimination power of the semi-quantitative results was better than that of full-quantitative analysis. The superior discrimination power of semi-quantitative analysis was maintained, even when it was combined with a high-throughput digestion procedure, which represented a 5 fold reduction in analytical labour consumption. Thus, the large amount of elemental information obtained using semi-quantitative ICP-MS fully outweighed the lack of accuracy compared to full-quantitative analysis. For the first time it is demonstrated that semi-quantitative ICP-MS in combination with chemometrics provides a fast and powerful alternative to traditional full-quantitative ICP-MS. The method developed here constitutes a promising novel analytical tool, which has the potential to mature into a routine procedure for testing e.g. the authenticity and adulteration of food products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19086/1/Laursen_2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Laursen, Kristian Holst; Hansen, Thomas Hesselhøj; Persson, Daniel Pergament; Schjørring, Jan Kofod and Husted, Søren   (2009) Multi-elemental fingerprinting of plant tissue by semi-quantitative ICP-MS and chemometrics.   Journal of Analytical Atomic Spectrometry, 24, pp. 1198-1207.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19086/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>