<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth (iPOPY). Lessons learned from implementing organic into European school meals – policy implications.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Mette Weinreich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The introduction of organic food offers new dimensions to school meals, and schools offer new dimensions&#xD;
to organic food – when tackled properly. In this paper we present findings from the iPOPY research&#xD;
project that is funded by the ERA-Net, CORE-Organic-I funding body network. It is based on studies of&#xD;
school food policies in Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway. The embedded food traditions and cultures have&#xD;
had different attention in these countries, why also food related consumption, institutions and markets are&#xD;
quite heterogeneous and dynamic. Whereas school food services are relatively widely embedded in the&#xD;
school systems in Finland and Italy, the Danish and Norwegian school food is predominantly defined by the&#xD;
packed lunch brought from home when it comes to organic food the pattern is different. To analyse the&#xD;
strategies used in these countries we have selected a number of cases where in-depth studies have been&#xD;
conducted. The concept of embedding has been used in these studies and it has been informed by policy&#xD;
and actor network theories. The results of this analysis show a complexity in implementing organic food in&#xD;
existing school food aims, in embedding school food policies and in comprising also aims and policies for&#xD;
organic food purchasing in these. The variety amongst the analysed countries in strategies and success is&#xD;
identified, covering both structural and stakeholder related findings. A major finding is pointing at the&#xD;
challenge of “multi-embedding” processes when including organic food in school meal procurement.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Strassner, Carola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-02-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17143/1/CORE_Proc_BioFach_2010_ipopy_VF_NHKetal.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristensen, Niels Heine; Hansen, Mette Weinreich and Nielsen, Thorkild    (2010) innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth (iPOPY). Lessons learned from implementing organic into European school meals – policy implications.   In: Strassner, Carola; Løes, Anne-Kristin; Nölting, Benjamin and Kristensen, Niels Heine (Eds.)  Organic Food for Youth in Public Settings: Potentials and Challenges. Preliminary Recommendations from a European Study. Proceedings of the iPOPY session held at BioFach Congress 2010. CORE Organic Project Series Report. , ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report, Tjele, Denmark, pp. 11-16.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17143/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>