<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A Modelling Approach for Evaluating Agri-Environmental Policies at Sector Level</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schader, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nemecek, T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, N. H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents a new approach to evaluate the cost effectiveness of agri-environmental policies at sector level. Policy uptake, cumulative environmental effects and public expenditure are identified as the main determinants of cost-effectiveness. On the basis of the sector-consistent, comparative-static, farm group model FARMIS, the determinants of policy cost-effectiveness at sector level are addressed. Firstly, intensity levels for the FARMIS activities are defined in order to model uptake of agri-environmental policies with FARMIS, secondly, life-cycle assessment data is attached to these intensity levels to determine environmental effects of the policies and thirdly, public expenditure is calculated under consideration of transaction costs. This paper concludes delineating the strengths and limitations of the approach.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20331/1/Schader-etal-SGA-yearbook_2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schader, C.; Sanders, J.; Nemecek, T; Lampkin, N. H. and Stolze, M.   (2008) A Modelling Approach for Evaluating Agri-Environmental Policies at Sector Level.   Yearbook of Socioeconomics in Agriculture , 2008, pp. 93-132.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20331/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>