<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bekämpfung von Microdochium nivale (Schneeschimmel) auf Weizen mit Präparaten auf Pflanzenbasis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vogelgsang, Dr. Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bänziger, Irene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krebs, Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Legro, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, Dr. Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Snow mold, caused by the fungal pathogen Microdochium nivale, is an important&#xD;
seed-borne disease of various cereals and fodder plants, leading to reduced stands&#xD;
after emergence. No agricultural measures are known to prevent snow mold, hence,&#xD;
direct control measures are needed. For organic agriculture, seed dressing with plantbased&#xD;
products could be an alternative. In contrast to spray treatments onto the crop,&#xD;
the formulation and application of plant preparations onto seeds represents a greater&#xD;
challenge in terms of adhesion, persistence, and lasting efficacy. In the current study,&#xD;
three plant-based powders applied with two different seed coating materials were&#xD;
tested for their efficacy against MN of wheat. Both adjuvants demonstrated equally&#xD;
satisfying adhesion and showed no differences in terms of disease control. One of the&#xD;
plant-based preparations reduced in vitro the MN infestation of a naturally infected&#xD;
seed lot by 50%, whereas in vivo, it increased emergence of wheat seedlings by 71%.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14852/1/Vogelgsang_14852.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vogelgsang, Dr. Susanne; Bänziger, Irene; Krebs, Heinz; Legro, Robert and Forrer, Dr. Hans-Rudolf    (2009) Bekämpfung von Microdochium nivale (Schneeschimmel) auf Weizen mit Präparaten auf Pflanzenbasis.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14852/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>