<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Is organic food a quality attribute or a product category?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Denver, Sigrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, Tove</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present study investigates the relationships between  consumer categorization of organic versus non-organic food products, consumers' underlying perceptions of organic food, and their propensity to consume organic foods. A choice experiment is used to test these relations in a case study involving consumer preferences for attributes relating to milk. First and foremost, we find a strong link between how consumers categorize food and their organic profile. Second, we find that knowledge concerning a claim stating that milk from grazing cows is healthier, serves as a way to categorize consumers according to their organic profile. Third, our study supports earlier findings which indicate that socio-demographic factors, such as living in a big city and being well educated, are important drivers of organic demand, together with beliefs in organic foods possessing positive attributes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-10-18</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18794/4/18794.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Denver, Sigrid and Christensen, Tove    (2010) Is organic food a quality attribute or a product category?    Working paper, Institute of Food and Resource Economics, University of Copenhagen.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18794/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>