<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil nitrate N as influenced by annually undersown cover crops in spring cereals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Känkänen, Hannu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksson, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Räkköläinen, Mauri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vuorinen, Martti</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cover crops can reduce leaching and erosion, introduce variability into crop rotations and fix nitrogen (N) for use by the main crops. In Finland, undersowing is a suitable method for establishing cover crops in cereals. The effect of annual undersowing on soil nitrate N was studied at two sites. Red clover (Trifolium pratense L.), white clover (Trifolium repens L.), a mixture of red clover and meadow fescue (Festuca pratensis Huds.), and westerwold ryegrass (Lolium multiflorum Lam. var. westerwoldicum) were undersown in spring cereals during six successive seasons, and a pure stand of cereal was grown in two years after that. In all years, the soil nitrate N was measured in late autumn, and in addition in different times of the season in last four years. The effect of undersowing on soil NO3-N content was generally low, but in one season when conditions favoured high N leaching, westerwold ryegrass decreased soil NO3-N. The negligible increase of N leaching risk in connection with undersowing clovers, associated with late autumn ploughing, supports the use of clovers to increase the cereal grain yield. The highest levels of soil NO3-N were recorded at sowing in spring irrespective of whether a crop was undersown or not. NO3-N contents were higher in sandy soil than in silt. Undersowing can be done annually in cereal cultivation either to fix or catch N. No cumulative effects on soil nitrate N were associated with undersowing after six years.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16745/1/k%C3%A4nk%C3%A4nen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Känkänen, Hannu; Eriksson, Christian; Räkköläinen, Mauri and Vuorinen, Martti   (2003) Soil nitrate N as influenced by annually undersown cover crops in spring cereals.   Agricultural and Food Science in Finland, 12 (3-4), pp. 165-176.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16745/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>