<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organising supply chains of organic products for Italian school meals - The case of the province and of the city of Piacenza</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bocchi, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spigarolo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarti, Valerio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noelting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper is part of the proceedings of an iPOPY seminar. The authors describe, how supply chains of organic school food might be organised in a sustainable way in order to serve high quality food to pupils. They present a best practice case of controlled food chains (filiera controllata) from Italy, the European champion of organic school food. From the province and the city of Piacenza in the region of Emilia-Romagna, we can learn a lot about a short and certified organic food-chain, a wide range of regional and organic products provided through a shared logistic organisation among local partners, and specific tender procedures.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Noelting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15543/1/iPOPY_Proceedings_BioFach_2009_Bocchi_et_al.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bocchi, Stefano; Spigarolo, Roberto; Sarti, Valerio and Noelting, Benjamin    (2009) Organising supply chains of organic products for Italian school meals - The case of the province and of the city of Piacenza.   In: Noelting, Benjamin (Ed.)  Providing organic school food for youths in Europe - Policy strategies, certification and supply chain management in Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway. Proceedings of the iPOPY seminar held at the BioFach February 20th 2009 in Nuremberg, Germany, International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), CORE Organic Series Report, pp. 23-29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15543/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>