<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Knowledge Transfer in the Animal Health Planning Process: Putting Research into Practice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, Dr Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ellis, Dr Kathryn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bassett, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Animal health plans are now widely accepted as a tool that can provide a structured approach to health promotion and positive welfare. This requires a partnership between farmer and veterinary advisor as well as a good knowledge of organic farming practice by animal health professionals. &#xD;
This paper describes an electronic compendium of information relevant to animal health and welfare in organic farming, the main aim of which is to provide resource material and a training tool for those working with organic livestock farmers. The approach involved an extensive and detailed literature search, synthesis to provide advisory material and the development of a website. The compendium is divided into species specific sub-sections covering Disease Management, Veterinary Management and Health and Welfare and includes over 2500 references and web-site links. The compendium covers 45 cattle, 44 sheep, 32 poultry and 27 pig diseases and conditions as well as extensive sections pertaining to each species’ behavioural requirements. Throughout there are links to relevant elements of organic farming legislation.&#xD;
By providing information on new research and practical solutions to treating and avoiding disease it is expected that the compendium will contribute to improved knowledge amongst farmers, veterinarians and advisors and thereby enabling the development of animal health plans that promote high standards of animal health and welfare in organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12468/1/Roderick_12468_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Roderick, Dr Stephen; Ellis, Dr Kathryn and Bassett, Anna    (2008) Knowledge Transfer in the Animal Health Planning Process: Putting Research into Practice.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12468/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>