<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Complementary Financing for Environment in the Context of Accession – Innovative Resources: National Report Croatia. A project for the European Commission (contract 070201/2006/443879/MAR/E3)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Karoglan Todorović, Sonja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Znaor, Darko</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This publication is a part of a five case studies exploring the possibility to establish payment for ecosystem services (PES) schemes for biodiversity conservation in two new EU&#xD;
Member States and three candidate countries, namely Bulgaria, Croatia, Former Yugoslavian Republic of Macedonia, Romania and Turkey. The report forms a part of a project "Complementary Financing for Environment in the Context of Accession – Innovative Resources" (070201/2006/443879/MAR/E3) that has been carried out by&#xD;
the WWF Danube-Carpathian Programme and IEEP for the European Commission in 2006-2007. &#xD;
&#xD;
The report on Croatia assesses the value and discusses possibilities of payments for ecosystem services of the Lonjsko Polje Nature Park - the largest maintained inundation area in the Danube river catchment. The opportunity costs and proposed payments for environmental services (PES) in the Lonjsko Polje Nature Park have been calculated using the most likely development scenarios for the three major land use categories: grassland, arable land and forest. In all scenarios transaction costs have been taken into account.&#xD;
&#xD;
Various options have been assessed, including six scenarios assuming conversion to organic farming management: &#xD;
1) Conversion of the current grazing practice to organic management. &#xD;
2) Abandoned pastures conversion to organic management. &#xD;
3) Conversion of current meadows management to&#xD;
organic.&#xD;
4) Abandoned meadows conversion to organic&#xD;
management&#xD;
5) Conversion of maize production to organic management.&#xD;
6) Conversion of wheat production to organic management.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Ecologica</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26402/7/26402.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Karoglan Todorović, Sonja and Znaor, Darko         (2007) Complementary Financing for Environment in the Context of Accession – Innovative Resources: National Report Croatia. A project for the European Commission (contract 070201/2006/443879/MAR/E3).    Ecologica, Zagreb.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26402/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>