<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer attitudes toward new technique for preserving organic meat using herbs and berries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Haugaard, Pernille</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grunert, Klaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Flemming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study aims to explore consumers´ attitude toward a new preservation technique using herbs and berries in organic meat production. This seems relevant both for the organic as well as the conventional meat producers, as this technique enable the organic producers to reduce the salt content in meat products and for the conventional producers to minimize the amount of chemical additives. Consumer acceptability toward the preservation technique using herbs and berries and further the willingness to buy products preserved with herbs and berries were exploited through a qualitative approach by means of three focus groups. We found that in general, most of the participants are positive toward the preservation technique using herbs and berries and there are only few concerns related to the technique. Some of the words they express their attitude toward the concept is that it is more natural and healthier, especially avoiding artificial additives is seen as a positive outcome. The concerns are related not as much to the technique but more toward the end products. Four factors seem important in this relation; these are shelf life, taste, appearance and texture. The willingness to buy products preserved with herbs and berries, is generally high, but is dependent on especially appearance, information and price level, whereas repeated buying depends mainly on taste.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-01-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24195/19/24195.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Haugaard, Pernille; Grunert, Klaus; Hansen, Flemming and Jensen, Martin   (2014) Consumer attitudes toward new technique for preserving organic meat using herbs and berries.   Meat Science,  96 ( 1),  126- 135.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24195/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>