<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einflussfaktoren auf Soziale und Gesellschaftliche Lernprozesse im Wissenssystem Biolandbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rutz, Dominik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rist, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Flurina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Networks and ownership</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Improved organic farming methods that enable more sustainable use of natural resources are numerous and are applied in almost every region of this planet. However, when it comes to spreading and adapting these methods to specific ecological and socio-economic contexts, we know only little about what factors influence the learning processes involved. This study aims at a thorough assessment of factors that are enabling or hindering knowledge co-production in organic farming in general and of sustainable rice farming in particular. Following a qualitative multilevel analysis, special emphasis is placed on understanding how the socio-economic, cultural and ecological context is constituted (macro-level), how key stakeholder groups collaborate and enhance societal and social learning processes (meso-level), and to what degree these processes lead to enhancement and integration of organic rice farming methods in the farmers’ livelihood systems (micro-level). Case studies in South Korea and Cambodia show that capacity building and institutionalization of key actors such as farmer promoters and farmer researchers, as well as farmer group maintenance with diverse incentives for sustained participation are vital enabling factors.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17736/3/Rutz_17736.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rutz, Dominik; Rist, Stephan and Schneider, Flurina    (2011) Einflussfaktoren auf Soziale und Gesellschaftliche Lernprozesse im Wissenssystem Biolandbau.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17736/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>