<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results in research on lime sulphur and other products to control apple scab under northern German climate conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klopp, Karsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kruse, Petra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palm, Gerd</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2003 six apple scab control strategies were tested, three with only lime sulphur in&#xD;
different application strategies, another three strategies with different amounts of&#xD;
copper. The strategies were tested in an organic apple orchard near Hamburg,&#xD;
Germany, on a 15 year old `Elstar´ plantation. Due to the recorded infection periods&#xD;
and the infection load the different strategies were tested. The results show that a&#xD;
proper lime sulphur strategy is quite successful to fight apple scab (&lt; 4% infected&#xD;
fruit), has good side effects on apple mildew (&lt; 2%) and only little russetting (&lt; 5%)&#xD;
compared to strategies with copper fungicides. ablto fight fruit scab as well as leave&#xD;
scab. A proper strategy means no application later than 15 hours after infection,&#xD;
enough spraying water (drip off), usage of a 1,5-2% lime sulphur-solution and only&#xD;
very little direct sunlight.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14443/1/19_Klopp_96_100.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klopp, Karsten; Kruse, Petra; Maxin, Peter and Palm, Gerd    (2004) Results in research on lime sulphur and other products to control apple scab under northern German climate conditions.  [Versuchsergebnisse zum Einsatz von Schwefelkalkbrühe und anderen Produkten in der Bekämpfung des Apfelschorfes unter norddeutschen Klimabedingungen.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 96-100.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14443/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>