<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Roots below one meters depth are important for nitrate uptake by annual crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Hanne L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The root depths of annual crops vary from 0.2 m to more than 2 m depending on root growth rate and length of growing season. However, studies of root growth and N uptake are often restricted to a depth of 1 m or less, as root biomass is assumed to be negligible below this depth. We have studied the importance of root growth and N uptake to a depth of 2.5 m in fully grown field vegetables and cover crops by use of minirhizotrons and deep point placement of 15N. Deep rooted crucifereous crops were found to have high root densities to a depth of 1.5-2 m and high 15N uptake to this depth. The work shows that knowledge of the interactions between root growth and soil N below a depth of 1 m are important to understand crop N uptake and nitrate leaching from agro-ecosystems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11461/1/Deep_Roots_and_N_Uptake.htm</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristensen, Hanne L. and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian    (2006) Roots below one meters depth are important for nitrate uptake by annual crops.  [Rødder under 1 meters dybde er vigtige for et-årige afgrøders optagelse af nitrat.]  In:     CD-rom "The American Society of Agronomy - Crop Science Society of America - Soil Science Society of America International Annual Meetings, November 12-16, 2006, Indianapolis, USA. No. 205-9., CD-rom "The American Society of Agronomy - Crop Science Society of America - Soil Science Society of America International Annual Meetings, November 12-16, 2006, Indianapolis, USA., no. Abstract No. 205-9..</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11461/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>