<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Baumstreifenpflege im Obstbau</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To control weed competition in organic fruit orchards there are only few and expensive devices on the market. Alternatives with mulching methods or weed burners do satisfy only in specific conditions. Tillage systems that provide sufficient, reliable weed competition control over a large range of soil and site conditions and for low costs are still to be developed.&#xD;
&#xD;
In order to ensure a sufficient supply of water and nutrients in orchards it is necessary to regulate weed growth in the in-row strips. In organic fruit growing this is achieved by keeping the soil open with special tillage equipment (very costs intensive), or by mulching with organic material, such as bark, wood shavings and straw (high costs and high deposition of potassium, which increase the risk of bitter pit) or water permeable synthetic ground covers. The mulching systems can considerably increase mice damage and are suited only for specific soil and site conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
i) to develop and validate an alternative system (Sandwich System) that allows a sufficient supply of water and nutrients, but needs a lower input of resources; &#xD;
ii) comparing growth and yields of the trees under Sandwich-System versus usual tillage over the whole width of the tree strip.&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
The systems were compared in 7 apple cultivars. Two repetitions in each cultivar. Collected data was yield, trunk perimeter, nutrients contained in fruits and leaves (T-Stage). For the statistical analysis we used the Program JMP 4.02 (SAS incorp.), ANOVA model; variety, System, repetition, variety*system, variety*repetition, system*repetition&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
-	No significant differences in the yields of both systems were observed (annually and accumulated)&#xD;
-	The accumulated vegetative growth of the trees was significantly higher under sandwich-system (11%).&#xD;
-	In leaf and fruit analysis for mineral uptake (from 2000 to 2003) there was no consistent tendency to be found that could indicate any better or less optimal nutrient availability between the two systems. From totally 74 data sets, there were 14 significantly different but of a low practical relevance.&#xD;
-	Due to its low costs (60 % cheaper than good usual tillage devices) and its high performance (up to 9 km working speed) the Swiss Sandwich–System is an interesting alternative to the usual tillage devices.&#xD;
-	If with the Sandwich System, the establishment of a low growing vegetation in the centre aisle is difficult (as in the case of our investigation), it becomes necessary to mulch the central green strip 1-3 times a year. &#xD;
-	Due to passive tools, only, the Sandwich acts very softly to soil structure.&#xD;
-	Together with the industry (Santini and Braun, CH-Sulgen) we could develop a now commercially available tillage device for the Sandwich-System Our results show, that with the Sandwich System tree performance is equal to whole-width tillage. The advantages are: i) about 60 % cheaper than usual good tillage devices, ii) high working speed (6-9 km/h); iii) soft to soil structure due to passive tools, only.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    In-row strip, sandwich system, weed management: Baumstreifenpflege im Obstbau.  [Soil management in Orchards(phase I: in row weed competition control; phase II: between row soil management).]   Runs 1999 - 2008.      Project Leader(s): Suter, Francisco; Weibel, Franco; Häseli, Andi and Tschabold, Jean-Luc, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6207/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>