<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PARTICIPATORY DEVELOPMENT AS A WAY TO INNOVATIONS: FIVE KEY ELEMENTS FOR SUCCESS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koopmans, Chris J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Veluw, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wijnands, F.G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In recent years, in the Netherlands, the organic sector gained much experience with a partnership focusing on innovations. Industry, knowledge institutions and government worked closely together within a demand-driven context. The partnership is characterised by a high degree of active participation. Practice and research participated actively and contributed to the development. The aim of the partnership is to contribute to growth, innovation and the strengthening of the sector. &#xD;
In the participatory development of the organic sector five elements appear to play a key role: ownership, heterogeneity, sharing knowledge and experience, value driven and a system approach. It is recommended to identify the five key elements in each research based on a participatory development and handle consciously according to them.&#xD;
Participatory development has been shown to be an effective tool to sustain and innovate the organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23816/1/23816%20OWC14%20Koopmans_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koopmans, Chris J.; van Veluw, K. and Wijnands, F.G.    (2014) PARTICIPATORY DEVELOPMENT AS A WAY TO INNOVATIONS: FIVE KEY ELEMENTS FOR SUCCESS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 791-794.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23816/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>