<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>STATUS OF ORGANIC COTTON PRODUCTION IN TURKEY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erdal, Ülfet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gürel, Aynur</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cotton production has been improved in respect to amount and quality with&#xD;
contributions of scientific and technological innovations. Increased sensitivity to health and&#xD;
environmental issues has caused development of new subjects such as organic agriculture.&#xD;
Organic production systems are based on specific standards that combine tradition, innovation&#xD;
and science. It sustains human and animal health and maintains ecosystem and soil quality.&#xD;
Organic agriculture stops the use of pesticides and nutrient pollution.&#xD;
Turkey has a good knowledge on organic farming and is one of the leading countries&#xD;
in this regard. Organic cotton is grown in 23 countries around the World. India, Syria and&#xD;
Turkey in can be seen in the rank of the countries related with organic cotton production in&#xD;
2011. Textile Exchange Organic Cotton Farm and Fiber Report in 2011 announced that&#xD;
organic cotton production increased 15 percent from 209.950 metric tons (MT) in 2008 - 09 to&#xD;
241.276 MT (1.1 million bales) grown on 461.000 hectares (1.14 million acres) in 2009 -&#xD;
2010 in the world. Organic cotton now represents approximately 1.1 percent of global cotton&#xD;
production. In the future, it is anticipated that demand for organic cotton fiber will be greater&#xD;
than supply. Organic cotton is considered as a niche product or niche-market product up to&#xD;
now, but textile sector relevant to organic cotton with the effects of consumer awareness is&#xD;
start to move from a niche market to mainstream with contributions of many clothing&#xD;
companies.&#xD;
In Turkey, organic cotton production faced with fluctuations from year to year due to&#xD;
several difficulties such as pest and disease intensity, marketing and contracting problems,&#xD;
demand and supply balance, etc. Taking into consideration demands of producers and&#xD;
consumers of cotton and also textile manufacturers, several product types including organic&#xD;
and also natural colored cottons have to be created in order to provide progress in this field.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Alay Vural, Ayşen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-11-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22083/1/04-STATUS-OF-ORGANIC-COTTON-PRODUCTION-IN-TURKEY021.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Erdal, Ülfet and Gürel, Aynur    (2012) STATUS OF ORGANIC COTTON PRODUCTION IN TURKEY.  [TÜRKİYE'DE ORGANİK PAMUK ÜRETİM DURUMU.]          Inter-Regional Cooperative Research Network on Cotton for the Mediterranean and Middle East Regions, Antalya, Turkey, 5-7 November, 2012.     [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22083/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>