<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pflanzenbauliche Nutzung von Bioporen im Unterboden</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Perkons, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Küpper, Paul Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kautz, Timo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biopores act as pathways for the roots of following crops to access water and nutrients stored in the subsoil. Their role for nutrient management is especially important under the conditions of Organic Agriculture. In a field trial on Haplic Luvisol, chicory (Cichorium intybus L., tap root system) and tall fescue (Festuca arundinacea, fibrous root system) were grown as precrops. Effects on biopore density, root-length density (RLD), leaf area index (LAI), biomass, transpiration and photosynthesis of following winter barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) were measured.&#xD;
Biopore density and RLD declined with soil depth. In all depth levels biopore density was higher after chicory in comparison to fescue. Between 95 and 125 cm soil depth the difference was significant. From 135 – 200 cm soil depth RLD of winter barley after chicory was significantly higher compared with RLD after fescue (BBCH 92 – 93). LAI and by trend biomass of winter barley gave higher values after chicory, whereas rates of photosynthesis and transpiration did not show differences.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21634/1/21634_Perkons.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Perkons, Ute; Küpper, Paul Martin; Kautz, Timo and Köpke, Ulrich    (2013) Pflanzenbauliche Nutzung von Bioporen im Unterboden.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21634/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>