<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Arthropod pest management in organic crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zehnder, Geoff</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gurr, Geoff M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kühne, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wade, Mark R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wratten, Steve D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Burgeoning consumer interest in organically produced foods has made organic farming one of the fastest growing segments of agriculture. This growth has not been supported adequately by rigorous research to address challenges such as arthropod pest management. The research that has been conducted, however, is complemented by research in aspects of conventional agriculture that may have applicability in organic systems, as well as by research in underpinning ﬁelds such as applied ecology. This article synthesizes the available literature in relation to a conceptual model of arthropod pest management strategies suitable for organic systems. The present work uses the four phases of the model to review the strategies in an agroecological context and provides a synthesis of the factors that inﬂuence the success of each phase. Rather than constituting a fringe science, pest management research for organic systems draws on cutting edge science in ﬁelds such as landscape and chemical ecology and has a bright future.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13126/1/Zehnder-etal-2007-Annuals_of_Entomology.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zehnder, Geoff; Gurr, Geoff M.; Kühne, Stefan; Wade, Mark R.; Wratten, Steve D. and Wyss, Eric   (2007) Arthropod pest management in organic crops.   Annual Review of Entomology, 52, pp. 57-80.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13126/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>