<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Research collaboration between China and Denmark for  development of systemic approaches to agro-ecological pest management without pesticides with focus on vegetable, fruit and berry crops. Proceedings and recommendations &#xD;
from two network workshops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andreasen, Lise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ravnskov, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steenberg, Tove</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Enkegaard, Annie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eilenberg, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Munk, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langer, Vibeke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Korsgaard, Maren</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wu, Wenliang</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Qiao, Yuhui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhang, Long</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guo, Yanbin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liu, Yunhui</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zhu, Zengrong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Jianwu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report is the result of a network project which was established to discuss the potential for collaboration on development of systemic approaches to pest management without pesticides between Chinese and Danish researchers. The focus is on systemic approaches rather than input substitution of synthetic chemicals with agents of natural origin, however, the latter is considered as an integrated tool for the development and design of systemic approaches. The discussions were, furthermore, limited to management of invertebrate pests as well as diseases, while other pests such as weeds have not been included in the discussions. The discussions took place at two workshops and were based on presentations of research from the two countries and field visits in China and Denmark.&#xD;
&#xD;
After the first workshop that took place in China, it was agreed that Chinese and Danish researchers in this particular field had mutual interests and priorities and that there was a potential for creating collaboration that could yield results beneficial for the agricultural/horticultural sectors in both countries. It was also agreed that in spite of the many differences between variation in climate and ecosystems, as well as in farming systems and their organization in China and Denmark, there were many similarities in the production of high-value crops in the two countries, such as vegetables, fruit and berries and, therefore, an obvious focus for joint research efforts. It was also agreed that joint research efforts could aim at specific crops as well as aiming at the development of specific research approaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
Based on the observations and the agreements of the first workshop, the second workshop, which took place in Denmark, focused more specifically on the development of a research framework with specified research questions/topics. Two groups were formed – one working with vegetables and one with fruit and berries working in parallel – both looking into what kind of research is needed for development of systemic approaches to pesticide-free pest management should include both well-known practices and new practices.&#xD;
&#xD;
Although the discussions in the two groups took separate routes and unfolded and described the research topics in each their way, there was a clear consistency between the outputs of the work of the two groups. Each had identified three main research themes that more or less followed the same line and has been merged into three specific recommendations on themes for collaboration, namely:&#xD;
1) ‘Research to provide the biological foundation and understanding of mechanisms and interactions for development of non-chemical solutions and to improve efficiency of new and existing control methods for severe pest problems’. &#xD;
2) Research in ‘How best to integrate multifunctional plants (and crops) and use diversification to create a more healthy and productive farming system which is resilient to pests?’ &#xD;
3) Research in ‘How to design and integrate pest management in eco-functional cropping systems at field and farm/landscape level?’</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Andreasen, Lise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22350/7/22350.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Halberg, Niels; Andreasen, Lise; Ravnskov, Sabine; Steenberg, Tove; Enkegaard, Annie; Sigsgaard, Lene; Eilenberg, Jørgen; Munk, Lisa; Langer, Vibeke; Korsgaard, Maren; Wu, Wenliang; Qiao, Yuhui; Zhang, Long; Guo, Yanbin; Liu, Yunhui; Zhu, Zengrong and Wang, Jianwu     (editor): Andreasen, Lise (Ed.)    (2013) Research collaboration between China and Denmark for development of systemic approaches to agro-ecological pest management without pesticides with focus on vegetable, fruit and berry crops. Proceedings and recommendations from two network workshops.    International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22350/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>