<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Developing Energy Plants for Biofuels Production may Comply&#xD;
to Organic Principles</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Akinyemi, Okoro Monday</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Jensen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biofuels are the only source of renewable environmentally friendly fuel currently suitable for road transport without any negative traits associated with traditional biodiesel or other green energy alternatives. The combustion of petrol and diesel produces many different types of local air  pollutants, but the use of biofuels may result in the reductions in emissions of greenhouse gas carbon dioxide up  to 70%. Impacts on land use require careful planning to maximise the gains and minimise the losses. The role of biofuels in organic farming will solve three significant problems: 1) waste will become valuable resources; 2) low quality forage products can be utilized for biofuels and thus get value-added; and 3) the trafficable damage on soil fertilities will be reduced by the minimized recirculation rate of bulky watery waste products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-06-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23018/1/akinyemi_abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Akinyemi, Okoro Monday and Høgh-Jensen, Jensen    (2008) Developing Energy Plants for Biofuels Production may Comply to Organic Principles.       Poster at:   16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Modena, Italy, Mondena, Italy,  June 16-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23018/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>