<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of the spatial distribution of organic farming in the Provence-Alpes-Côte d’Azur (PACA) region of France: building a methodology for observation and prospective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>GENIAUX, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>LAMBERT, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BELLON, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Networks and ownership</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Analysis of the distribution of organic farming and its determinants is a major challenge for the construction of scenarios related to the evolution of organic farming that take the set of factors that limit or facilitate conversions and their sustainability into account. In order to support different development scenarios for organic farming in view of environmental and marketing challenges, an econometric and geostatistic study was initiated in the PACA region. The approach consists of three stages. The first stage involves the construction, over a 20-year period, of a longitudinal spatial database concerning certified organic producers and distributors. This database is georeferenced at the plot level. It will then be necessary to statistically analyse the trends and the determinants of the organic farming distribution process over time and space. Finally, this knowledge will be used to build scenarios for the development of organic farming production on the medium term. Intermediary results presented within this framework well be based on the georeferencing of producers and distributors at the community level in 2007, without drawing on farm data issued by the MRA (French farmers mutual insurance system), and on the results of an exhaustive survey of all organic distributors implemented in 2008 in the PACA region.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15505/1/50-Geniaux.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>GENIAUX, G. ; LAMBERT, M.  and BELLON, S.    (2009) Analysis of the spatial distribution of organic farming in the Provence-Alpes-Côte d’Azur (PACA) region of France: building a methodology for observation and prospective.  [Analyse de la diffusion spatiale de l’agriculture biologique en région Provence-Alpes-Côte d’Azur (Paca) : construction d’une méthodologie d’observation et de prospective.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 417-426.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15505/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>