<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heritage plants in museum environment - three museum gardens in south western Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heinonen, Maarit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartikainen, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Antonius, Kristiina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kinnanen, Hilma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pihlman, Sirkku</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Heritage plants are not commonly presented to visitors in museum gardens. In&#xD;
many cases, there is not much knowledge of the plants. For example, there is&#xD;
lack of knowledge of their cultivation history or variety names.&#xD;
In the pilot museum gardens we combine gathered knowledge (e.g. plant&#xD;
identification data to cultivation history) and utilize it in designing demonstration&#xD;
material for presenting heritage plants, their histories and their potential for&#xD;
present and future use. Demonstration material includes exhibitions, thematic&#xD;
and drama guidance, www-pages, brochures, maps, signs for individual plants or&#xD;
parts of the garden.&#xD;
18&#xD;
Heritage plants maintained and demonstrated in museum gardens enable to&#xD;
mediate information of plant genetic resources to visitors through different&#xD;
senses: touching, tasting and smelling and with visual perception. Information&#xD;
received from different angles and with concrete ways may help visitors to better&#xD;
understand the value of plant genetic resources. The abstract concept of&#xD;
agrobiodiversity can became more tangible to laypersons and they can make their&#xD;
own thoughts on agrobiodiversity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19710/1/Heritage.docx</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heinonen, Maarit; Hartikainen, Merja; Antonius, Kristiina; Kinnanen, Hilma and Pihlman, Sirkku    (2011) Heritage plants in museum environment - three museum gardens in south western Finland.       Paper at:   Biodiversity in agriculture - lessons learned and future directions, NJF seminar 436, Ulvik in Hardanger, Norway, 24-26 May 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19710/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>