<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of organic wine market needs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jonis, Monique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hofmann, Uwe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trioli, Gianni</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the last years the market for organically produced wine has developed significantly. But until now only few data are available about the actual organic wine market and market needs as well as future market trends. Therefore, the conduction of a trans-national study was seen as necessary within the ORWINE project. The aim of this market study was to get a clear picture about the national structure as well as the development and the potential of the domestic and international organic wine market. This report gives the results and main trends concerning organic wines markets of the first step of this study: status quo analysis from experts’ survey and literature analysis and operators’ market survey with qualitative and quantitative data. The second step of the study will be end, in December 2007, more interviews will be led with operators from other countries: producing European countries and European and non European consuming countries.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12161/1/Orwine_market_study.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jonis, Monique; Stolz, Hanna; Schmid, Otto; Hofmann, Uwe and Trioli, Gianni    (2008) Analysis of organic wine market needs.       Paper at:   IFOAM OWC 2008, Modena, Italy, 18-20 June 2008.     [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12161/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>