<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic matter addition in organic farming – Impact on root development and yields in maize and cowpea over dry seasons</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sangakkara, Dr Ravi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bandaranayake, Mr P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dissanayake, Ms U</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gajanayake, Ms J</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic matter and its proper management are vital in tropical organic farming to maintain productivity. A field study thus placed rice straw or Gliricidia leaves on the soil surface or the material was incorporated into soil. The impact of these treatments on soil moisture, root development and yields of organically grown maize or cowpea were evaluated in an Asian dry season. Incorporation increased soil moisture retention in the soil and hence induced better root growth, culminating in higher yields. The impact was greater in maize, especially with Gliricidia leaves. The benefits of incorporating organic matter in dry seasons for tropical organic farming are presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12525/1/Sangakkara_12525_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sangakkara, Dr Ravi; Bandaranayake, Mr P; Dissanayake, Ms U and Gajanayake, Ms J    (2008) Organic matter addition in organic farming – Impact on root development and yields in maize and cowpea over dry seasons.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12525/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>