<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reduction of net photosynthesis after blossom: a possibility to control alternate bearing in organic orchards?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Prantl, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grapadelli, Luca Corelli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conventional and integrated fruit growers have the possibility to use Carbaryl and&#xD;
Benzyladenin 2 thinning agents, which allow crop regulation at a relatively late stage (10 –&#xD;
16 mm of fruit size). At that stage, organic fruit growers can only thin by hand, which is&#xD;
quite time-consuming. A few surveys show that reducing net photosynthesis after blossom&#xD;
increases the June drop. This could be an interesting new approach for organic apple&#xD;
orchards. In 2003 a trial was carried out at the Laimburg Research Station to understand if&#xD;
application of high amounts of bentonite could achieve that goal. The results were&#xD;
encouraging, but still not recommendable to practical growers.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14544/1/40_Kelderer_217_221.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Prantl, Markus; Lardschneider, Ewald; Grapadelli, Luca Corelli and Kelderer, Markus    (2004) Reduction of net photosynthesis after blossom: a possibility to control alternate bearing in organic orchards?  [Reduktion der Photosyntheseleistung in der Nachblüte: Eine neue Möglichkeit der Fruchtausdünnung in biologisch bewirtschafteten Obstanlagen?]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 217-221.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14544/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>