<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CAP Reform and Innovation: The Role of Learning and Innovation Networks</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brunori, Gianluca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barjolle, Dominique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dockes, Anne-Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hemle, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ingram, Julie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klerkx, Laurens</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nemes, Gustáv</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tisenkopfs, Talis</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The technological and organizational solutions the agricultural sector has undertaken in the past are not always compatible with the constraints and opportunities that the rural economy and society will face in the future. There is growing agreement that the goal of sustainability cannot be fulfilled without a profound change in the way the economy is organized. Innovation policies are among the most suitable instruments for this purpose. The article, based on the SOLINSA conceptual framework, adopts a network approach to innovation policies. Based on empirical evidence collected from case studies across Europe in the first phase of the project, the paper proposes the concept of Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture (LINSA). LINSA are defined as ‘networks of producers, customers, experts, Non-Governmental Organisations, Small and Medium Enterprises, local administrations and components of the formal Agricultural Knowledge System (AKS), that are mutually engaged with common goals for sustainable agriculture and rural development — cooperating, sharing resources and co-producing new knowledge by creating conditions for communication’. The article proposes that LINSA be considered as policy devices — in line with the European Innovation Partnership initiative — to foster innovation in the direction of sustainability goals as advocated by Europe 2020 strategy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22703/1/brunori-etal-2013-CAP-Reform-EuroChoices-online.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brunori, Gianluca; Barjolle, Dominique; Dockes, Anne-Charlotte; Hemle, Simone; Ingram, Julie; Klerkx, Laurens; Moschitz, Heidrun; Nemes, Gustáv and Tisenkopfs, Talis   (2013) CAP Reform and Innovation: The Role of Learning and Innovation Networks.   EuroChoices,  ,  - .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22703/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>