<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Options for enabling policies and regulatory environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Izac, A.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Egelyng, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferreira, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Duthie, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hubert, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Louwaars, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>al., et</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Based on the International Assessment of Agricultural Knowledge, Science and Technology for Development (IAASTD), this chapter (7) of the “Global Report” identifies a range of policy options for future support for agricultural knowledge, science and technology (AKST) to pursue environmentally and socially sustainable development. Presenting its analysis in sections covering “Natural resources and global environmental change”, “Trade and Markets”, “Food Safety and Plant Health”, “Knowledge and Knowledge Management” as well as “Pro-Poor innovation” the chapter identifies an array of areas of possible interventions where governments and public policy must play an active role, in order to allow AKST to help fulfill development goals. The policy options identified include options for reforming institutional environments to become more conducive to sustainable agricultural methods and certified organic agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Island Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>McIntyre, B.D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Herren, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Watson, R.T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14752/1/14752.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Izac, A.-M.; Egelyng, H.; Ferreira, G.; Duthie, D.; Hubert, B.; Louwaars, N. and al., et    (2009) Options for enabling policies and regulatory environments.    In: McIntyre, B.D.; Herren, H. and Watson, R.T. (Eds.)   Agriculture at a Crossroads.  Volume I: The Global Report - International Assessment of Agricultural Knowledge Science and Technology for Development. Island Press, chapter 7.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14752/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>