<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results from a Research Project about foliar fertilizers in organic fruit-growing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Belz, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfeiffer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The intention of this research project, which was supported within the "Bundesprogramm Ökologischer&#xD;
Landbau", was to investigate in 2003 the situation on organic apple farms of nutrition of&#xD;
leaves and fruits of the variety 'Topaz' and 'Elstar'. The contents of N, P, K, Ca and Mg were determined&#xD;
in the leaves in April, June and August, micronutrients like Fe, Mn, Zn, B and Cu in April and&#xD;
August. The number of flower-clusters per tree, the fruit-setting and the yield were investigated.&#xD;
There were great differences between the orchards, the yield per tree varied between 3 and 24 kg,&#xD;
depending from the age and height of the trees. Field trials were done to proof the effect of the foliar&#xD;
fertilizers Vinasse, Biokal, Phytoamin, Wuxal Ascofol and Humulus. Effects on the fruit-setting (apples&#xD;
per flower-cluster) were low after application for one season. The average fruit-weight did not&#xD;
vary heavily, some differences were found in the percentage of flowerbuds in December 2003.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14529/1/28_Belz_150_156.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Belz, J. and Pfeiffer, B.    (2004) Results from a Research Project about foliar fertilizers in organic fruit-growing.  [Ergebnisse aus einem Forschungsprojekt zu Blattdüngern im ökologischen Obstbau.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 150-156.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14529/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>