<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>15 years of research in organic food systems in Denmark – effects on the sector and society</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, I.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An analysis of the effect of 15 years of research in organic food systems in Denmark showed that it has had a high impact on the development of the sector. There are three main reasons: First of all, the content of research programs and the funded projects have been closely aligned with the needs of the industry as expressed by farmers, advisors and organizations. Second, many of the projects have had close contact to advisors and farmers securing continuous dissemination resulting in rapid application of results. Third, due to the close contact between researchers and users the research design has been adapted to ensure that treatments to be tested are as relevant and practical as possible, without compromising the scientific standards. Besides the practical applications the number of scientific products has been above average. Our results underpin and exemplify the general recommendations in recent international discussions on the need to improve the relationships between research, extension and agricultural production from a linear to a more complex knowledge interaction.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23220/8/23220a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23220/14/23220b.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, I.A. and Halberg, N.    (2013) 15 years of research in organic food systems in Denmark – effects on the sector and society.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 99-100.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23220/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>