<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pisum sativum as alternative protein source in diets for buffalo cows in middle and late stage of lactation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Masucci, Dr Felicia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Di Francia, Prof Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Rosa, Dr Giuseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romano, Prof Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varicchio, Dr Maria Luisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grassi, Dr Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A study was carried out at an organic buffalo farm in order to examine the effect of feeding peas (Pisum sativum L.) as an alternative protein source for buffalo cow diets during middle and late stage of lactation. Two concentrates were formulated to contain, as fed basis, either 350 g/kg of soybean cake (control concentrate, CC) or 450 g/kg of peas (experimental concentrate, ExpC) as the main protein sources. The two concentrates were almost isonitrogenous (on average, crude protein 240 g/kg DM). Twenty buffalo cows were blocked into two groups according to lactation number and previous milk yield and were assigned to one of two dietary treatments from 10° day in milk onwards: control group was offered in the milking parlour 3 kg of CC, while treatment group was offered the same quantity of ExpC. All cows were fed a total mixed ration containing 3 kg of CC. The experimental period was from 100° day in milk onwards. Daily milk yield was not affected by treatment, as well as, milk fat and protein percentages, somatic cell count, urea content, fatty acid composition and clotting properties. Results support the partial substitution of soybean meal with peas in diets for buffalo cows with no negative effects on milk yield and composition.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12167/1/Masucci_12167_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Masucci, Dr Felicia; Di Francia, Prof Antonio; De Rosa, Dr Giuseppe; Romano, Prof Raffaele; Varicchio, Dr Maria Luisa and Grassi, Dr Carlo    (2008) Pisum sativum as alternative protein source in diets for buffalo cows in middle and late stage of lactation.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12167/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>