<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrative Ansätze und bildgestützte Methoden für&#xD;
den Umgang mit Wertekonflikten und Entscheidungsdilemmas im biologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Patzel, Nikola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The integrity of organic agriculture and its promises are seriously questioned in discussions in the media, as well as in the internal conventionalization debate. To overcome situations which undermine credibility and development opportunities, there is a need for better dealing with value conflicts and faced dilemmas. For this purpose, science can provide more holistic approaches and methods for analysis and development processes, which better integrate human factors of the system. As neurobiology and psychology underline, emotions, inner images and unconscious drivers are influential factors of thinking and behaviour. With the development of the “value-image method”, the authors made experiences supporting this approach. Now there is a need to further develop more integrative, also images-supported tools and process design for dealing with value conflicts and decision dilemmas in a creative and constructive way. This also aims at the development and integration of a fourth dimension of sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21576/1/21576_Patzel.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Patzel, Nikola and Schmid, Otto     (2013) Integrative Ansätze und bildgestützte Methoden für den Umgang mit Wertekonflikten und Entscheidungsdilemmas im biologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21576/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>