<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving barley yields in organic stockless farming systems through innovations in green manure management</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Low and fluctuating yield levels of barley on stockless farms converted to organic farming shows that organic feed barley production in Norway is a challenge. This is mainly because of insufficient nitrogen (N) supply, but also problems with soil structure in intensive arable cropping systems. The main source of plant nutrients in organic stockless cereal production is from soil organic matter and leguminous green manure crops within the crop rotation. Due to high N concentrations in green manure crops, and current practice with repeatedly mowing and leaving these as green mulch on the stubble, substantial amounts of N from green manure is at risk of being lost from the cropping system. Such losses represent a reduction in fertilizer value of the green manure, and increases potential N pollution to the atmosphere and watercourses. &#xD;
 &#xD;
The main objective of the project is to improve yields of feed barley on stockless organic farms. This is to be achieved through investigations on how selected green manure management and biogas slurry application from digested green manure herbage can improve N cycling and N utilization, and how these management strategies will affect soil structure and key grain quality parameters. The results will be implemented in tools for practical fertilization planning, and contribute towards increased domestic feed barley production to supply the growing market for organic meat and dairy products.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13490/1/vedlegg_2a_soknad_sendt_inn_6__juni_2007.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    BYGGRO: Improving barley yields in organic stockless farming systems through innovations in green manure management.  [Økte byggavlinger i økologisk drift gjennom bedret grønngjødselhandtering.]   Runs 2008 - 2011.      Project Leader(s): Hansen, Sissel, Bioforsk Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13490/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>