<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sortenprüfung pilzwiderstandsfähiger (PIWI) Rebsorten</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Today only few commercial vine grape cultivars are commercially cultivated. Their potential is still behind the standard but highly susceptible varieties. &#xD;
&#xD;
Organic viticulture in a humid climate like in Switzerland is difficult to achieve, mainly due to the high disease pressure of Plasmopora viticola and Unicula Necator. Beside improved natural plant protection spray strategies and products, we put emphasis on disease resistant cultivars to overcome the problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims&#xD;
- To find grape vine cultivars showing at the same time high wine quality and disease resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology&#xD;
- At Frick, under 100 % organic conditions we carry out a “Top-Ten-Trial” with the 10 most promising cultivars in 4 replicates at 50 vine plants each. Thus, there is enough must available to carry out a proper vinification. In addition to this, we are involved in the evaluation of selections growing in field trials at the Federal Reseach Stations of Agroscope at Wädenswil and Pully.&#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
- From different newer breeding sources in central Europe (Freiburg, Pully, Soyhère etc.), there is increasingly very interesting material available.&#xD;
&#xD;
Involved organisations, project partners:&#xD;
Agroscope FAW, Wädenswil; Agroscope RAC, Changins; Arbeitsgruppe PIWI, Pully(CH)</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    PIWI-Prüfung: Sortenprüfung pilzwiderstandsfähiger (PIWI) Rebsorten.  [Testing of fungus resistant vine cultivars.]   Runs 1997 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Tuchschmid, Andreas; Levite, Dominique; Häseli, Andreas and Weibel, Franco, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6209/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>