<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Foodservice at events as a strategy for sustainable food consumption. Workshop held as a part of the conference: Joint Actions on Climate Change, Aalborg Congress &amp; Culture Centre, Denmark, June 9th-10th, 2009.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a part of the Joint Actions on Climate Change conference held on June 9th and 10th 2009 in the Aalborg Congress &amp; Culture Centre, Denmark, the Danish iPOPY group organized a workshop on “Food service at events as a strategy for sustainable food consumption.”   The workshop was part of the Conference’s fourth Theme, Governance &amp; Climate Mitigation. &#xD;
&#xD;
The workshop was held on June 10th from 11.30-13.00 as part of the iPOPY project (innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth). The iPOPY-project (2007-2010) is one out of eight transnational pilot projects funded by the CORE Organic funding body network within the context of the European Research Area. &#xD;
&#xD;
The papers and the PowerPoint presentations from the event are presented in this publication along with the conclusions from the workshop. Thanks to Mia Brandhøj and Sofie Husby for coordinating and to Niels H. Kristensen for moderating the workshop. Thanks also to the Presenters for making their papers and presentations available.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Farming Systems</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Husby, Sofie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Brandhøj, Mia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16799/1/Joint_actions_in_core_FINAL100210.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg; Husby, Sofie and Brandhøj, Mia (Eds.)    (2010) Foodservice at events as a strategy for sustainable food consumption. Workshop held as a part of the conference: Joint Actions on Climate Change, Aalborg Congress &amp; Culture Centre, Denmark, June 9th-10th, 2009.   ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Farming Systems, Tjele, Denmark, CORE Organic Project Series Report.  Proceedings of Joint Actions on Climate Change, Aalborg Congress &amp; Culture Centre, Denmark,  June 9th-10th, 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16799/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>