<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving nutrient uptake in wheat through cultivar specific interaction with Azospirillum</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hoagland, Dr. Lori</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murphy, Dr. Kevin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carpenter-Boggs, Dr. Lynne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Dr. Steve</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Obtaining sufficient plant available nitrogen in organic dryland wheat cropping systems is difficult.  This study was conducted to determine whether inoculation with Azospirillum could improve nitrogen uptake and increase crop yield, and whether there are differences among wheat cultivars in the ability to benefit from inoculation of these diazotrophic bacteria.  Seed from twenty historic and modern wheat cultivars were either left untreated, or treated with a commercial inoculant of Azospirillum, and planted at two locations under certified organic management.  In one location with lower fertility, inoculation significantly increased yield and protein, and clear differences existed among individual cultivars in response to the inoculant.  In another location with higher fertility, none of the cultivars responded as favorably to the inoculant, and yield in some cultivars was reduced.  Plant breeders should be able to select for beneficial cultivar interactions with Azospirillum to increase wheat yield and protein levels.  Additional research is needed to determine the impact of site-specific soil conditions on the effectiveness of Azospirillum in organic systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12325/2/Hoagland_12325_ed.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hoagland, Dr. Lori; Murphy, Dr. Kevin; Carpenter-Boggs, Dr. Lynne and Jones, Dr. Steve    (2008) Improving nutrient uptake in wheat through cultivar specific interaction with Azospirillum.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12325/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>