<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Long-term effects of cropping system on N2O emission potential</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Petersen, Søren O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ambus, Per</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elsgaard, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjønning, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The potential for N2O emissions outside the main growing season may be influenced by long-term effects of cropping system. This was investigated by collecting intact soil cores (100 cm3, 0-4 cm depth) under winter wheat in three organic cropping systems and a conventional reference within a long-term crop rotation experiment. Average annual inputs of C in crop residues and manure ranged from 1.7 to 3.3 Mg ha-1. A simulated freeze-thaw cycle resulted in a flush of CO2 during the first 48 h, which could be mainly from microbial sources. Other samples were adjusted to approximately –10, -30 or –100 hPa and amended with excess 15NO3- prior to freezing and thawing. Denitrification was the main source of N2O during a 72-h incubation at 22C, as judged from N2O and total 15N evolution. Although the input of C in the conventionally managed cropping system was significantly less than in the organic cropping systems, it showed higher N2O evolution at all three matric potentials. Estimates of relative gas diffusivity (DP/D0) in soil from the four cropping systems indicated that C input affected soil aeration. Soil from the two cropping systems with highest C input showed N2O evolution at DP/D0 in excess of 0.02, which is normally considered a threshold for development of anaerobic sites in the soil, presumably because the oxygen demand was also high. The study shows that cropping system affects both soil gas diffusivity and C availability, and that both characteristics significantly influence the N2O emission potential.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22014/1/22014.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Petersen, Søren O.; Ambus, Per; Elsgaard, Lars; Schjønning, P. and Olesen, Jørgen E.   (2013) Long-term effects of cropping system on N2O emission potential.   Soil Biology and Biochemistry, 57, pp. 706-712.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22014/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>