<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ein grünes Blatt? Verbraucherwissen und -einstellungen zur verpflichtenden EU-Kennzeichnung von Öko-Produkten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With the introduction of the mandatory EU organic logo for all organic food products in 2010, the European Commission aimed at supporting sustainable development and the effective functioning of the internal market for organic food. This approach presupposes consumers’ knowledge of the logo and their understanding of its meaning. By means of an online survey with 3000 participants in 6 European countries, knowledge of the logo and attitudes towards organic farming and European labelling, as well as organic food purchase behaviour and socio-demographic indicators were elicited. The results indicate that knowledge of the logo is low. Only about 15% of all respondents know its meaning. Factor and cluster analysis based on several statements on the test persons’ attitudes towards organic farming and corresponding EU legislation were conducted in order to segment consumers. Four clusters of consumers could be identified: ‘Committed organics’, ‘Pragmatic organics’, ‘Organic sceptics’ and Organic disinteresteds’. They differ in their knowledge of the EU organic logo and their purchasing behaviour with regard to organic food. With reference to the EU organic legislation’s aim of promoting the organic market, particularly ‘Organic sceptics’ should be addressed by emphasising the trustworthiness of the organic certification and labelling system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26824/1/26824_zander.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zander, Katrin    (2014) Ein grünes Blatt? Verbraucherwissen und -einstellungen zur verpflichtenden EU-Kennzeichnung von Öko-Produkten.  [A green leaf? Consumer knowledge and preferences for the mandatory EU organic logo.]      Paper at:   13. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde, 17. - 20. März 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26824/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>