<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sortenvergleich von Lolium multiflorum unter Anbaubedingungen des ökologischen- und integrierten Landbaus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suter, Dr. Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehmann, Dr. Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Briner, Hansueli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Dr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Forty-five varieties of Lolium multiflorum L. were examined in pure stands at three experimental sites over a three years period. One of these sites was on an organic farm, which was managed according to the “BIO SUISSE” guidelines. Due to the marked differences in management (weed control, N-fertilisation), the yield of the sown grass was clearly lower at the organic site. Nevertheless, there was an outstanding correspondence in terms of the yield of the different varieties among the experimental sites. The best varieties under integrated farming were also the best varieties in the organic system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3572/1/3572.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Suter, Dr. Daniel; Lehmann, Dr. Josef; Briner, Hansueli and Lüscher, Dr. Andreas    (2005) Sortenvergleich von Lolium multiflorum unter Anbaubedingungen des ökologischen- und integrierten Landbaus.  [Comparison of Lolium multiflorum cultivars under organic and integrated farming.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3572/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>