<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrating pigeonpea in maize based farming systems may increase food production and alleviate poverty</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Odgaard, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Myaka, F.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sakala, W.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adu-Gyamfi, J.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vesterager, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pressure on natural resources implies that millions of farmers in semi-arid eastern and southern Africa face very low and declining crop yields. Major natural constraints are the nitrogen and phosphorus supply together with insufficient and highly variable rainfall. This article addresses the possibilities for improved soil fertility, increased productivity and income opportunities among smallholders in semi-arid eastern and southern Africa through the integration of improved pigeonpea in maize-based cropping systems. Specifically farmers’ experiences with cultivation and integration of pigeonpea in maize-based cropping systems are discussed. This includes how the integration of pigeonpea affects the livelihood situation of rural smallholders – male as well as female in terms of increased food security, increased income, improved gender equity in access to resources etc. While many ‘blessings’ of integrating the multi-purpose crop pigeonpea in maize-based cropping systems are confirmed, it is also shown that socio-economic and biophysical diversity must be taken into account when evaluating impact of pigeonpea on livelihoods of different groups of farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11420/1/Hogh-Jensen_11420_ed.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Høgh-Jensen, Henning; Odgaard, R.; Myaka, F.A.; Sakala, W.D.; Adu-Gyamfi, J.J. and Vesterager, J.M.    (2008) Integrating pigeonpea in maize based farming systems may increase food production and alleviate poverty.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11420/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>