<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Observing the observers – uncovering the role of values in research assessments of organic food systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thorsøe, Martin H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noe, Egon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Assessing the overall effects of organic food systems is important, but also a challenge because organic food systems cannot be fully assessed from one single research perspective. The aim of the article is to uncover the role of values in assessments of organic food systems as a basis for discussing the implications of combining multiple perspectives in overall sustainability assessments of the food system. We explore how values are embedded in five research perspectives assessing organic food systems, 1) Food Science, 2) Discourse Analysis, 3) Phenomenology, 4) Neoclassical Welfare Economics and 5) Actor-Network Theory. The article shows that value has various meanings in different scientific perspectives, and that a strategy for including and balancing different forms of knowledge in overall assessments of the effects of food systems is needed. Based on the analysis, we propose five ecommendations: 1) Elucidate values as a necessary foundation for research assessment across perspectives. 2 The choice of perspective is decisive and should be openly discussed 3) Formulate common goals which can be translated into the different perspectives and 4) Consider assessment&#xD;
of food system sustainability a learning process and design it as such.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24620/7/24620.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thorsøe, Martin H.; Noe, Egon and Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted   (2013) Observing the observers – uncovering the role of values in research assessments of organic food systems.   Ecology and Society, 19 (2),  46- .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24620/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>