<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Mensch-Tier-Beziehung auf die Eutergesundheit bei Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This project is part of pro-Q-project (Promotion of udder health and quality of biologically produced milk in Switzerland; http://www.fibl.org/forschung/tiergesundheit/komplementaermedizin/pro-q.php)&#xD;
&#xD;
Mastitis is a disease with many factors. So there is not only one solution to solve the problem of mastitis. One hypothesis regards the human-animal-relationship as one factor influencing udder health. So it can be assumed that a calm interaction leads to behavioural balanced cows followed by more stable health parameters.&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
To investigate the importance of human-animal-relationship as a mastitis factor.&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
The project is carried out on 50 farms and consists three parts: &#xD;
1. Observation of vocalisation and tactile interaction during milking&#xD;
2. Observation of the approach reaction of the cows to an unfamiliar person (avoidance distance)&#xD;
3. Questionnaire of stockperson’s attitude&#xD;
&#xD;
Involved organisations, project partners:&#xD;
-Susanne Waiblinger, University of  Veterinary Medicine Vienna, Austria&#xD;
-Ute Knierim, University of Organic Agricultural Sciences, Kassel-Witzenhausen, Germany&#xD;
-Christoph Winckler, University of Natural Resources and Applied Life Sciences, Vienna, Austria&#xD;
Literature:&#xD;
Walkenhorst, M., F. Heil, S. Ivemeyer, P. Klocke, C. Notz und J. Spranger (2005): Pro-Q: Strategien zur Verbesserung der Eutergesundheit und Minimierung des Antibiotikaeinsatzes in schweizerischen Biomilchviehbetrieben, Beitrag zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Kassel, http://orgprints.org/3876/01/3876.pdf&#xD;
WAIBLINGER, S., MENKE, C.,  COLEMAN, G. (2002): The relationship between attitudes, personal characteristics and behaviour of stockpeople and subsequent behaviour and production of dairy cows, Applied Animal Behaviour Science, 79: 195-219</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    MTB: Einfluss der Mensch-Tier-Beziehung auf die Eutergesundheit bei Milchkühen.  [Impact of Human-Animal-Relationship on udder health of dairy cows.]   Runs 2002 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Ivemeyer, Silvia, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6271/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>