<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Motivational Profile of Organic Food Consumers: a Survey of Specialized&#xD;
Stores Customers in Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Idda, Lorenzo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madau, Fabio A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pulina, Pietro</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic food demand is becoming increasingly important throughout the world. Despite this relevance, however, not many attempts have been carried out to profile this food market segment. This paper aims to investigate on motivations that drive consumers towards purchasing organic foods in Italy. Through a survey carried out in some organic specialized stores sited in Sardinia, we explored organic consumer behaviour with specific emphasis on understanding  consumer reasons to buy organic products. A Multiple Correspondence Analysis has obtained four consumers’ motivational profiles and several findings. Furthermore, a Logit regression allowed us to evaluate the relationships between individual motivations and some socio-demographic characteristics of organic consumers. Some marketing and policy implications arise from the obtained results.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14143/1/EAAE_950.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Idda, Lorenzo; Madau, Fabio A. and Pulina, Pietro    (2008) The Motivational Profile of Organic Food Consumers: a Survey of Specialized Stores Customers in Italy.   In:     Conference Proceedings (CD-ROM).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14143/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>