<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic food in schools and kindergartens&#xD;
in Trondheim. A case study report.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bårdsen, Mari Greta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In October 2007, the municipality of Trondheim, Norway decided to increase the public&#xD;
consumption of organic food. The share of public schools and kindergartens offering organic food&#xD;
should be increased by 20 % within 2011, as compared to 2007. Trondheim has for several years had&#xD;
an ambitious aim to increase the consciousness among children and youth about environmental&#xD;
issues, and the project “Children‟s Green City” had been an important tool in this work. The&#xD;
decision made it relevant for the research project “innovative Public Organic food Procurement for&#xD;
Youth” (iPOPY) to use Trondheim as a research case. This report describes the background for the&#xD;
municipal decision about organic food, and what has been done to implement it. Several employees&#xD;
in the municipality and other stakeholders have been interviewed. Even if the decision puts up a&#xD;
quite modest goal, there are several challenges to achieve it. The point of departure (how much&#xD;
organic food was served by kindergartens and schools in 2007) is unknown, and hence the progress&#xD;
is difficult to measure. In the public purchasing agreement, the municipality has obliged its&#xD;
appointed wholesaler to offer organic products. The intention was that the units (e.g. schools)&#xD;
would get easier access to organic food, and that the demand would increase, making it possible for&#xD;
more local farmers to convert to organic. Purchasing agreements are an important tool, but they&#xD;
have to be carefully designed and developed with time. The largest challenge to achieve the&#xD;
organic goal in Trondheim is to motivate actors who may influence the purchase of food, and to&#xD;
anchor the intentions in the decision in such a large organisation as the municipality is. A&#xD;
committed and continuous effort is required. Education and training of staff in charge of food&#xD;
serving in schools and kindergartens is a fruitful</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioforsk</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16681/1/Trondheim_with_layout_Dec09_final_%28AL%29_for_web.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bårdsen, Mari Greta  and Løes, Anne-Kristin         (2010) Organic food in schools and kindergartens in Trondheim. A case study report.    Bioforsk, Tingvoll, Norway.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16681/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>