<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Praxiserhebung zur Mineralstofffütterung &#xD;
in der biologisch-dynamischen Milchviehhaltung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Usage of mineral supplements regarding avoidance of lacks in supply (especially phosphor or selenium) and fulfilling the ideal of a closed materials cycle within a farm is controversial discussed among bio-dynamic farmers. A representative survey in Swiss and German bio-dynamic dairy farms was conducted to investigate the mineral feeding strategies of bio-dynamic farmers and the relationships between farm characteristic and usage of mineral supplements. It was shown that 30% of the dairy herds were fed without external mineral supplements whereas 97% were fed with salt. Farms in highlands, with loamy soils, a high amount of permanent grassland and lower yielding dairy cows were associated with lower use of mineral supplements. Alternatively most often feeding of fresh or dried leaves of trees and hedges were mentioned in the questionnaire. The survey results demonstrated the differences in usage of mineral supplements in bio-dynamic farms and determined further need of research in the area of mineral supplementation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17520/3/Ivemeyer_17520.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivemeyer, Silvia and Walkenhorst, Michael    (2011) Praxiserhebung zur Mineralstofffütterung in der biologisch-dynamischen Milchviehhaltung.       Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17520/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>