<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimierung der Proteinversorgung durch Maissilage auf ökologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben im Grünland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Velik, Margit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baumung, Roswitha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knaus, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the present study was to investigate and optimize the protein supply of organic dairy cows kept in Austrian grassland regions through the inclusion of maize silage into the diet. Therefore, two feeding trials were carried out. Trial I examined the effect of a partial substitution of purchased concentrates with home grown maize silage on feed and nutrient intake, milk performance and feed efficiency. Trial II was conducted to investigate the effect of maize silage or grain as an energy supplement to grass-clover silage based diets. In trial I milk yield decreased by 10%, however concentrate intake per kg milk was markedly reduced and dietary N efficiency and energy balance tendencially improved. Trial II revealed that even a small amount of maize silage supplementation had a marked influence on nutrient (protein, fibre) intake, ruminal N balance (RNB) and milk composition (milk fat and milk urea concen-tration).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9304/1/9304_Velik_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Velik, Margit; Steinwidder, Andreas; Baumung, Roswitha; Zollitsch, Werner and Knaus, Wilhelm    (2007) Optimierung der Proteinversorgung durch Maissilage auf ökologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben im Grünland.  [Optimization of the protein supply through maize silage on organic dairy farms in grassland regions.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9304/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>