<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of deep-rooted plant species on 15Nitrogen uptake and herbage yield in temporary agricultural grasslands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pirhofer-Walzl, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen , Jim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soegaard, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Aim is to ncrease of plant diversity has been suggested to enhance grassland productivity and resource use efficiency. Most studies on agricultural grasslands have focused on functional diversity of mixtures comprising legumes and non-legumes, but there is little knowledge of plant nutrient acquisition from deep- and shallow-rooted grassland plant species. To investigate whether deep-rooted (chicory: Cichorium intybus L.; Lucerne: Medicago sativa L.) and shallow-rooted (perennial ryegrass: Lolium perenne L.; white clover: Trifolium repens L.) grassland plant species  differ in herbage yield and depth dependent soil N-access, we investigated in the field if 1) a mixture comprising shallow- and deep-rooted grassland plant species has greater herbage yields than a shallow-rooted binary mixture and pure stands, 2) deep-rooted grassland plant species (chicory and lucerne) are superior in terms of accessing soil N from 1.2 m soil depth compared with shallow-rooted plant species, 3) shallow-rooted grassland plant species (perennial ryegrass and white clover) are superior in terms of accessing soil N from 0.4 m soil depth compared with deep-rooted plant species and 4) a mixture of deep- and shallow-rooted plant species has access to greater amounts of soil N compared with a shallow-rooted binary mixture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20647/4/20647.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pirhofer-Walzl, K.; Eriksen, Jørgen; Rasmussen , Jim; Soegaard, Karen; Høgh-Jensen, Henning and Rasmussen, Jesper   (2012) Effect of deep-rooted plant species on 15Nitrogen uptake and herbage yield in temporary agricultural grasslands.   Plant and Soil,  ,  - .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20647/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>