<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison of effect of zinc-enriched pod of Phaseolus vulgaris and inner rice husk composts with zinc sulphate and zinc 14% chelate on zinc availability in maize plant in a calcareous soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasouli, Mrs. Shabnam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azizi, Prof. Pirouz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forghani, Dr. Akbar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Asghar Zade, Dr. Ahmad</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Mixtures of Zn salts and organic matter have been used successfully in controlling zinc deficiency in various crops. The aim of the present study was to optimize the effectiveness, on zinc availability in maize, of natural organic substances by enriching them with zinc sulfate. For this purpose pod of Phaseolus vulgaris and inner rice husk, as abundant organic wastes in the north of Iran, were incubated with increasing quantities of zinc sulphate. The effect of these zinc-enriched composts, zinc sulphate, and zinc 14% chelate on zinc availability in maize in a calcareous soil was studied in a greenhouse experiment. DTPA-extractable zinc of the soil, total zinc concentration, and chlorophyll of plant leaves were measured. Soil applications of all treatments, especially zinc-enriched composts, increased DTPA-extractable zinc more than control treatment, but this increase is not significant for zinc chelate. The plant analysis indicated that zinc-enriched composts of both organic matters significantly increased total zinc concentration in plant leaves more than control treatment, and their effects increased by increasing the level of enrichment until toxic level, even over that of zinc chelate.  Non-enriched of both organic matters and zinc chelate had the most effect on leaf chlorophyll and significantly increased the amount of chlorophyll more than control treatment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12318/1/Rasouli_12318_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasouli, Mrs. Shabnam; Azizi, Prof. Pirouz; Forghani, Dr. Akbar and Asghar Zade, Dr. Ahmad    (2008) Comparison of effect of zinc-enriched pod of Phaseolus vulgaris and inner rice husk composts with zinc sulphate and zinc 14% chelate on zinc availability in maize plant in a calcareous soil.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12318/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>