<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zum Vorkommen von Staphylokokken mit Methicillin-/&#xD;
Oxacillinresistenz auf Nasenschleimhäuten,&#xD;
Handflächen melkender Personen&#xD;
und in Rohmilch in ökologischen Milchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paduch, Jan-Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zinke, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volling, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krömker, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this pilot prevalence study was to investigate the Oxacillin resistance of 73&#xD;
Staphylococcus (S.) strains from 29 organic dairy farms in Lower Saxony. The strains&#xD;
were isolated from nasal mucosa and hand skin of milkers, herd bulk milk and mastitis&#xD;
milk samples. After strain identification, the Oxacillin resistance was measured by Etest.&#xD;
23 strains were identified as S. aureus, four as S. hyicus, 15 as S. xylosus and 31&#xD;
as other coagulase negative staphylococci. Because of their minimum inhibition concentration&#xD;
(mic) between 0.5 and 1 mg/mL four S. aureus isolates were assigned to&#xD;
borderline Oxacillin resistant S. aureus. Nine coagulase negative isolates had this&#xD;
property too. In total 19 staphylococci isolates had a mic &gt; 1 mg/L and were classified&#xD;
as Oxacillin resistant according to DIN 58940-4 Bbl 1:2004-02. Three of the resistant&#xD;
four S. aureus strains were isolated from nasal mucosa and one from hand skin. To&#xD;
confirm the results the Oxacillin resistance status need to be analysed in a greater&#xD;
number of organic farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14110/1/Paduch_14110.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paduch, Jan-Hendrik; Zinke, Claudia; Volling, Otto and Krömker, Volker    (2009) Zum Vorkommen von Staphylokokken mit Methicillin-/ Oxacillinresistenz auf Nasenschleimhäuten, Handflächen melkender Personen und in Rohmilch in ökologischen Milchviehbetrieben.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14110/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>