<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC ANIMAL HUSBANDRY DEVELOPMENT IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES: CHALLENGES, CONTENTIOUS ISSUES &amp; OPPORTUNITIES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chander, Mahesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, Sanjay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mondal, Shymal Kumar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mukherjee, Reena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rathore, Ramswarup</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic agriculture is rapidly growing around the world (37.2 Million ha in 162 countries) with 1.8 million producers including significant number of organic farmers in developing countries like India. The global market for organic products has reached to US$ 62.8 billion and 86 countries now have an organic legislation (Willer et al, 2013). It is also well recognized now that the organic animal husbandry has not grown as faster as cereal crops, fruits, nuts, spices, tea, coffee and cotton. While organic farming is rapidly gaining ground in developing countries  the research and development (R&amp;D) activities in organic animal husbandry is confined to EU and a few other developed countries in North and Australia. There are opportunities as well as challenges in organic livestock production in developing countries which need to be addressed. The organic livestock development opportunities in developing countries in Asia, Africa and Latin America can be enhanced with more scientific research in organic livestock production under local conditions and strengthening institutional support (Chander et al 2011; Nalubwama et al, 2011; Rahmann &amp; Godinho, 2012; Chander et al, 2012). Further to this, here an effort has been made to analyze why animal husbandry is not coming up in developing countries despite good opportunities due to natural advantages, taking India as a case.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23689/1/23689%20OWC14-M.chanderfinalpaper_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chander, Mahesh; Kumar, Sanjay; Mondal, Shymal Kumar; Mukherjee, Reena and Rathore, Ramswarup    (2014) ORGANIC ANIMAL HUSBANDRY DEVELOPMENT IN DEVELOPING COUNTRIES: CHALLENGES, CONTENTIOUS ISSUES &amp; OPPORTUNITIES.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 659-662.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23689/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>