<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reply to Leifeld et al.: Enhanced top soil carbon stocks under organic farming is not equated with climate change mitigation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haeni, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skinner, Colin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buchmann, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Pete</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>El-Hage Scialabbad, Nadja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In their letter, Leifeld et al. (1) argue that our metaanalysis to identify differences in soil organic carbon (SOC) between organic (OF) and nonorganic farming [conventional farming (CF)] (2) selected CF systems that were nonrepresentative. This was not the case. We included data from all available pairwise field comparisons between OF and CF identified in the literature. The observed difference in external carbon (C) inputs between OF and CF did not result from a bias in the selection of studies/treatments but was attributable to the fact that the field comparisons we analyzed (2) were not from fertilization experiments but from pairwise farming system comparisons where the design and the underlying treatments reflected the current farming practices in the region in which the studies were conducted at the time the experiments were initiated.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-03-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25614/1/PNAS-2013-Gattinger-E985.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gattinger, Andreas; Müller, Adrian; Haeni, Matthias; Skinner, Colin; Fließbach, Andreas; Buchmann, Nina; Mäder, Paul; Stolze, Matthias; Smith, Pete; El-Hage Scialabbad, Nadja and Niggli, Urs    (2013) Reply to Leifeld et al.: Enhanced top soil carbon stocks under organic farming is not equated with climate change mitigation.   PNAS, 110 (11), E985.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25614/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>