<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Phosphorus budget and phosphorus availability in soils under organic and conventional farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oehl, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tagmann, H.U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Besson, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roth, H.-R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work was to assess to which extent organic farming practices would affect the accumulation of total and available phosphorus (P) in a cropped soil in comparison to conventional practices. In order to achieve this, soil samples were taken from a long-term field trial comparing a non-fertilised control (NON), two conventionally cultivated treatments (MIN, CON), and two organically cultivated treatments (ORG, DYN). Soil samples were taken from each treatment at two depths (0-20 and 30-50 cm) before starting the field trial (1977) and at the end of every three crop rotations (1984, 1991 and 1998). They were then analysed for total P (Pt ), total inorganic P (Pi ), total organic P (Po) and isotopically exchangeable Pi . After 21 years, the average P input-output budget reached -20.9 kg P ha−1 a−1 for NON, -7.8 for DYN, -5.7 for ORG, -5.0 for MIN and +3.8 for CON. Total P, Pi as well as the amount of Pi isotopically exchangeable within 1 minute (E1) were positively correlated to the P budget. Comparison between P budget and Pt in the top- and subsoils of the fertilised treatments suggested a net transfer of P from the 0–20 to the 30–50 cm layers between 13 and 26 kg P ha−1 a−1during the first rotation and between 3 and 12 kg P ha−1 a−1during the second rotation. During the third rotation a net upward movement of P from the subsurface to the topsoil ranging between 3.7 and 10.5 kg P ha−1 a−1was estimated. In the topsoil, E1decreased from an initial value of 12 mg P kg−1 to 11 in CON, 8 in MIN, 6 in ORG, 5 in DYN and 2 in NON after 21 years. In the subsoil, E1 increased from an initial value of 2 mg P kg−1 to 4 in MIN, ORG, DYN and NON and to 6 in CON. These results show that, with the exception of NON, all treatments had still an adequate level of available P after 21 years of trial and that, in this low to moderately P sorbing soil, an equilibrated input-output budget allows to maintain P availability at a constant level. In the organic systems, yields have so far partly been attained at the expense of soil reserves or residual P from earlier fertiliser applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26761/1/Oehl_et_al_2002_NCA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oehl, F.; Oberson, A.; Tagmann, H.U.; Besson, J.M.; Dubois, D.; Mäder, P.; Roth, H.-R. and Frossard, E.   (2002) Phosphorus budget and phosphorus availability in soils under organic and conventional farming.   Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems, 62, pp. 25-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26761/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>