<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung eines Mischanbaues von Weizensorten auf&#xD;
Anbaueigenschaften, Krankheiten, Ertrag und Qualität unter den&#xD;
Bedingungen des Biolandbaues</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Flamm, DI Clemens</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to literature varieties behave differently in mixtures than in pure populations.&#xD;
Two 2-component variety mixtures of Austrian winter wheat genotypes (Capo-Erla&#xD;
Kolben and Capo-Exklusiv) and their component varieties have been grown in five&#xD;
experiments in organic farming systems over 3 years. The genotypes were chosen on&#xD;
contrasting levels of resistance against diseases and differences in yield and quality&#xD;
parameters. In the experiments the appearance of diseases, yield and quality&#xD;
parameters of mixtures were compared to pure stands.&#xD;
No investigated parameter on the field (lodging, diseases, leaf ripening and yield)&#xD;
showed statistical approved differences (T-test) between the mixture and the&#xD;
calculated middle of the two components. The same applied to the quality parameters.&#xD;
Nevertheless, the character gluten content showed a trend to increase in the mixtures&#xD;
compared to the components. However, yield stability increased significantly due to&#xD;
the mixture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14445/1/Flamm_14445.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Flamm, DI Clemens    (2009) Wirkung eines Mischanbaues von Weizensorten auf Anbaueigenschaften, Krankheiten, Ertrag und Qualität unter den Bedingungen des Biolandbaues.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14445/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>