<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of long-term farmyard manure applications on soil organic matter, nitrogen mineralization and crop yield – a modeling study –</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dux, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fink, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To develop sustainable cropping systems we need to predict both short-term and long-term effects of management practices on soil fertility. For this purpose agro-ecosystem simulation models are valuable tools. We used the Daisy model to simulate a three-year crop rotation (beetroot, onion, white clover, potato) over a period of 40 years. With this rotation, three rates of farmyard manure were tested (0, 15, 28 t ha-1 year-1). After 40 years without manure soil organic matter carbon (SOM-C) decreased by approximately 40%, and increased by 27% with the highest application rate. SOM turnover did not reach equilibrium at the end of the experiment. Nitrogen mineralization from SOM followed in the long-term (40 years) the slowly changing time courses of SOM. However, manure applications affected mineralization and hence crop yield and nitrogen losses much more in the short-term (1 to 2 years) than in the long-term.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9827/1/dux-finck-2007-longterm_farmyard.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dux, J. and Fink, M.    (2007) Effects of long-term farmyard manure applications on soil organic matter, nitrogen mineralization and crop yield – a modeling study –.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9827/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>