<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Full case study report. PolarShiitake Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Risku-Norja, Helmi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>PolarShiitake Ltd. is a family enterprise cultivating organic shiitake mushrooms (Lentinus edodes) in the pure natural environment in northern Carelia, Finland. It is a small family enterprise with very specific niche product, the shiitake mushrooms. The enterprise was founded in 1999, but the history of PolarShiitake dates back to 1984, when shiitake production started in the same location in Eastern Finland. The production has continued in Rääkkylä without interruption since then. &#xD;
&#xD;
The initial product of PolarShiitake was fresh organic shiitake mushrooms, and this is still the main product. There are different packaging sizes and different types of fresh shiitake. Dried shiitake powder and dried slices as well as substrate for mushroom growing in households are nowadays also sold, but these are subordinate. The production volume is of the order 70 000 kilos fresh mushrooms a year, which is about 30% of the Finnish Shiitake production. The yearly turnover is under 1 million Euros, presently of the order of 600 000 Euros. The great majority of the products are exported and sold in the central European market. Domestic customers are retailers and fine dining restaurants mainly in the capital region. &#xD;
&#xD;
PolarShiitake is an interesting enterprise as it illustrates the significance of co-operation with the research institutes as one possible development trajectory for small producers. It also provides an example in overcoming the difficulties the independent small producers have in the highly competitive and concentrated Finnish food markets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28871/1/REPORT_FINLAND_POLARSHIITAKE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Risku-Norja, Helmi         (2015) Full case study report. PolarShiitake Finland.    Natural Resources Institute Finland, Society &amp; Economy.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28871/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>