<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ernährungs-Qualitäts-Studie (Klosterstudie): Auswirkungen einer vorübergehenden, konsequenten Ernährung mit biologisch-dynamischen Lebensmitteln auf das Befinden und das Ernährungsverhalten von Menschen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Dr Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hennig, Prof. Juergen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dlugosch, Dr. Gabriele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, Nikolai</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this pilotstudy the role was investigated whether switching from conventional to biodynamic food had any influence on eating behaviour, physical and psychological well-being, and objective parameters.  For this purpose, 17 sisters belonging to a religious order participated in a prospective study involving a period of conventional and biodynamic food. The results shows that biodynamic food in daily nutrition can help to enhance both physiological and psychological well-being.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3676/1/3676.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huber, Dr Karin; Hennig, Prof. Juergen; Dlugosch, Dr. Gabriele and Fuchs, Nikolai    (2005) Ernährungs-Qualitäts-Studie (Klosterstudie): Auswirkungen einer vorübergehenden, konsequenten Ernährung mit biologisch-dynamischen Lebensmitteln auf das Befinden und das Ernährungsverhalten von Menschen.  [Food Quality Study (Convent study):Impact on the well-being and nutrition pattern of human subjects during a consistent diet of biodynamic foods for a limited period.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3676/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>