<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Futterqualität, Vorfruchtleistung und Nitratauswaschung von&#xD;
über Winter beweideten Kleegrasbeständen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Dr Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Westphal, Dr Derk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In comparison to harvesting, grazing is less cost intensive. For economical reasons an&#xD;
extended duration of grazing period is recommended. Grazing during winter can&#xD;
cause pasture damages, which is of minor relevance for older grass clover grown on&#xD;
arable land, which will be ploughed in the following spring. Against this background&#xD;
yield and forage quality of 3 different legume species, i.e. white clover, red clover and&#xD;
alfalfa, grown in binary mixtures with two grass species, perennial ryegrass and tall&#xD;
fescue, respectively, were examined before grazing the third growth in autumn or&#xD;
winter. Nitrate leaching losses during winter and yield of the following spring wheat&#xD;
were recorded.&#xD;
Yield and forage quality of the total sward was not significantly influenced by grass&#xD;
species while the interaction of legume species and grazing date had a high impact on&#xD;
yield and quality of the swards. Before grazing in October, swards with white clover&#xD;
showed lower yields and through lower legume contents also lower crude protein&#xD;
concentrations compared to swards with alfalfa or red clover. Losses of leave material&#xD;
led to losses of crude protein concentration in swards with alfalfa or red clover as well&#xD;
as high losses of energy content in swards with alfalfa, which at the latest grazing date&#xD;
were significantly lower than in sward with white clover. Mulching the last growth and&#xD;
autumn grazing led to higher nitrate losses than late winter grazing. After ploughing,&#xD;
no effect of clover grass management on spring wheat yields was observed. Grazing&#xD;
in January led to higher grain crude protein contents in spring wheat than autumn&#xD;
gazing or cutting of the last growth for silage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14572/1/Loges_14572.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Loges, Dr Ralf; Westphal, Dr Derk and Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm    (2009) Futterqualität, Vorfruchtleistung und Nitratauswaschung von über Winter beweideten Kleegrasbeständen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14572/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>