<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The mineralization of commercial organic fertilizers at 8°C temperature</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thalheimer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andreaus, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Topp, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burger, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schiatti, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic production only organic fertilizers and soil conditioners can be used to supply&#xD;
the soil with nitrogen. The mineralization of these products is slow and so there can be&#xD;
problems with the supply of nitrogen, when the demand of the plants is high. The supply of&#xD;
nitrogen from organic products depends on the speed of their mineralization which is&#xD;
primarily influenced by the composition and formulation of their raw material.&#xD;
In apple production in the Alps-region especially during spring problems with nitrogen&#xD;
supply are common. In that period, the weather conditions are sometimes bad, the&#xD;
temperature in the soil is low and mineralization starts slowly - apple trees demand more&#xD;
nitrogen than the soil can deliver.&#xD;
To compensate the demand of the apple tree organic growers can not use mineral&#xD;
fertilizers but only organic fertilizers and soil conditioners whose mineralization rate is often&#xD;
unknown. There is a strong need in organic fruit production to receive more information&#xD;
about the behaviour of fertilizers in the soil especially concerning their N-release under&#xD;
different conditions.&#xD;
To acquire that information, incubation experiments under controlled conditions&#xD;
(temperature, type of soil, humidity of the soil) were carried out in the laboratory to&#xD;
determine the mineralization-rate of different organic fertilizers and soil conditioners which&#xD;
are available in our region.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13665/1/160-166.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, M.; Thalheimer, M.; Andreaus, O.; Topp, A.; Burger, R. and Schiatti, P.    (2008) The mineralization of commercial organic fertilizers at 8°C temperature.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 160-166.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13665/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>