<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results of the CoreOrganic-Workshop on animal based parameters in Trenthorst, Germany (04.02.08-08.02.2008)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gratzer, Lisi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winkler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It was the aim of this meeting to train the assessors of several CoreOrganic-Partners (i.e. Austria, Germany, Denmark and Norway) with regard to the methods which are going to be applied in the course of the project on-farm assessments. Training involved animal-based parameters, a resource checklist and a management questionnaire.&#xD;
After a theoretical and practical introduction, inter-observer reliability (IOR) of the main animal-based parameters was tested. This included gait scoring/lameness, body condition, cleanliness and integument alterations. The scoring systems for gait scoring, cleanliness and integument alterations had been adapted from the WelfareQuality® protocol; body condition was scored according to Metzner et al. (1993).&#xD;
Subjective scoring systems which are used in many epidemiological studies have the advantage that they do not require any equipment but - due to the subjectivity of the assessment - it is necessary to achieve acceptable inter-observer reliability (IOR) before and after the study to ensure valid data.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Vaarst, Mette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Roderick, Stephen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15915/1/15915.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>March, Solveig; Gratzer, Lisi; Brinkmann, Jan and Winkler, Christoph    (2009) Results of the CoreOrganic-Workshop on animal based parameters in Trenthorst, Germany (04.02.08-08.02.2008).    In: Vaarst, Mette and Roderick, Stephen (Eds.)  CORE Organic project nr: 1903 - Aniplan. Workshop report - The process of researching animal health and welfare planning. CORE Organic Project Series, no. 1903-2. Aarhus Universitet - Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, Departement of Animal Health and Bioscience, pp. 7-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15915/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>