<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nachhaltige Verhaltensweisen junger Erwachsener – &#xD;
Neue Perspektiven für suffizientes Handeln und nachhaltigen Konsum mit dem Fokus auf das Handlungsfeld Ernährung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grotstollen, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lukas, Melanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The enormous global consumption and waste of resources requires all in all a change in consumer behaviour and preferences. The strategy of sufficiency that demands a moderate behaviour provides a solution. The present study investigates how sustainable patterns of consumption and the multiple variation of sustainable behaviour schemes (e.g. consumption of organic food) are integrated and which role “modesty or refusal” play in the everyday life of young adults. The results of 14 qualitative interviews demonstrate that the barrier for an economically friendly and moderate behaviour in this phase of life occurs mainly because of the assumed costs. In addition it becomes clear that the knowledge about ecologically produced goods and the trust in certified organic food are lacking. In the same vein, the integrity for a moderate behaviour is only partially possible because personal belongings and independency have a higher significance in a young adult’s life. As a possible solution the organic food industry has to provide more information and explanations to gain more trust in organic products. Furthermore, the barriers for an ecologically friendly and moderate behaviour have to be broken by incentives and communication of user benefits as well as in improved education schemes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21348/1/21348_grotstollen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Grotstollen, Lisa; Lukas, Melanie and Strassner, Carola    (2013) Nachhaltige Verhaltensweisen junger Erwachsener – Neue Perspektiven für suffizientes Handeln und nachhaltigen Konsum mit dem Fokus auf das Handlungsfeld Ernährung.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21348/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>