<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Simplified and rapid method for extraction of ergosterol from natural samples and detection with quantitative and semi-quantitative methods using thin-layer chromatography</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Cand.scient Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ravn, Senior scientist Helle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Axelsen, Senior Scientist Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A new and simplified method for extraction of ergosterol (ergoste-5,7,22-trien-3-beta-ol) from fungi in soil and litter was developed using pre-soaking extraction and paraffin oil for recovery. Recoveries of ergosterol were in the range of 94 - 100% depending on the solvent to oil ratio. Extraction efficiencies equal to heat-assisted extraction treatments were obtained with pre-soaked extraction. Ergosterol was detected with thin-layer chromatography (TLC) using fluorodensitometry with a quantification limit of 8 ng. Using visual evaluation of images of TLC plates photographed in UV-light the quantification limit was 16 ng.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2510/1/Simplified_methods_for_quantification_of_ergosterol.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Larsen, Cand.scient Thomas; Ravn, Senior scientist Helle and Axelsen, Senior Scientist Jørgen   (2004) Simplified and rapid method for extraction of ergosterol from natural samples and detection with quantitative and semi-quantitative methods using thin-layer chromatography.   Journal of Chromatography A, 1026, 301 - 304.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2510/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>