<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ausstiegsabsichten und tatsächliche Ausstiegsgründe von Biobauern und Biobäuerinnen in Österreich - Analyse von Befragungsergebnissen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kirner, Dr. Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogel, Dr. Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneeberger, Dr. Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Austria established an environmental program (ÖPUL) for agriculture in 1995, including direct payments for organic farming. To participate in this measure farmers have to commit themselves to a five year period. In 1999 a survey was conducted to find out, to which extent organic farmers intended to drop out of the measure organic farming and to collect information about their reasons for this intention. In 2002 a new survey was carried out to compare the intentions with the actual developments. In 2004 additional information was collected through telephone interviews. The aim of this study was a) to compare the intended with the actual behaviour, b) to compare the ex ante and ex post expressed reasons for leaving the measure organic farming and c) to find out the arguments of these farmers who chose to continue farming organically.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3486/1/3486.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kirner, Dr. Leopold; Vogel, Dr. Stefan and Schneeberger, Dr. Walter    (2005) Ausstiegsabsichten und tatsächliche Ausstiegsgründe von Biobauern und Biobäuerinnen in Österreich - Analyse von Befragungsergebnissen.  [Plans and reasons to quit organic farming in Austria – an analysis of survey results.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3486/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>