<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Report on proposals for the development, harmonisation and quality assurance of organic data collection and processing systems (DCPS)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Recke, Guido</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitulano, Susanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olmos, Santiago</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report represents the conclusion of the European seminar on development, harmonisation and quality assurance of organic data collection and processing systems (Berlin, April 2004) as well as of the first phase of the EISFOM-project. &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
- In the first chapter the objectives and general approach of this workpackage are described. &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
- Chapter 2 focuses on quality assurance, the main results of WP2 and WP3 and the European Seminar in Berlin (see Recke et al. 2004; http://orgprints.org/2935/. Furthermore, the strengths and weaknesses of organic DCPS (data collection and processing systems) are analysed and the chapter closes with proposals for the development of organic DCPSs. &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
- Chapter 3 focuses on results of expert interviews on the main barriers for the implementation of improved organic statistical data collection and processing systems. &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
- Chapter 4 gives a summary and some general conclusions are drawn. This report provides perspectives on how the above mentioned issues of the European Action Plan might be implemented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3281/1/recke-et-al-2004-eisfom-d3.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Recke, Guido; Hamm, Ulrich; Lampkin, Nicolas; Zanoli, Raffaele; Vitulano, Susanna and Olmos, Santiago         (2004) Report on proposals for the development, harmonisation and quality assurance of organic data collection and processing systems (DCPS).   EISFOM-Report. European Information System for Organic Markets (EISFOM) // University of Kassel - Agricultural and Food Marketing, Germany.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3281/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>