<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Bedeutung der Saatgutqualität für Sortenvergleiche&#xD;
mit Sommergerste im ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Dr. Karl-Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The results show that thousand grain weight, protein content of seed, seed&#xD;
contamination with fungi and seed emergence influenced yield potential of organically&#xD;
produced seeds of spring barley in variety trials under organic farming conditions&#xD;
during three years. Certified organic seed on average had smaller grains, lower&#xD;
protein content and brought 5% less yield than conventionally produced seeds of the&#xD;
same variety offered for trials by breeders. Different susceptibilities of the seeds for&#xD;
contamination with fungi influenced the ranking of varieties and seed lots additionally.&#xD;
The more of the previos seed quality parameters reached acceptable levels during&#xD;
organic seed production, the better starting point for a better yield was obtained. The&#xD;
results indicate that by comparing conventionally produced seeds of one variety with&#xD;
organically produced seeds of another variety the probability will be three times higher&#xD;
to handicap instead of favouring the variety tested with organic seed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14227/1/M%C3%BCller_14227.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Müller, Dr. Karl-Josef    (2009) Die Bedeutung der Saatgutqualität für Sortenvergleiche mit Sommergerste im ökologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14227/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>