<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies, innovations and characteristics specific to organic farmers. Elements of sociological analysis related to professional organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LEROUX, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>How can we approach strategies and innovations specific to organic farmers? Is the appearance of new practices evidence of a modification of the structure of professional organic farming? On the basis of a field study carried out in the Midi-Pyrénées region in France, sociological analysis casts light on several examples of strategies and innovations specific to the world of organic farming and from which they arise. The strategic courses of action taken by organic farmers are therefore analysed in relation to organic farming characteristics, defined as the set of issues, interests, representations and other specific characteristics that structure this socio-professional field. Organic farming innovations are the result of interactions between the socio-technical framework, the result of how this field is structured, and the practices of organic farmers (having, to some extent, incorporated these same properties). The emergence of innovative practices as a result of new inputs (converted or used for the first time) is proof of the structural modifications taking place within the area of professional organic farming. Although they may appear to “enrich” organic farming diversity, these new practices are partially derived from traditional farming practices not used in organic farming. They raise the question of the use and the transformation of certain properties that characterise professional organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15503/1/46-Leroux.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LEROUX, B.    (2009) Strategies, innovations and characteristics specific to organic farmers. Elements of sociological analysis related to professional organic farming.  [Stratégies, innovations et propriétés spécifiques des agriculteurs biologiques. Éléments d’analyse sociologique du champ professionnel agrobiologique.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 389-399.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15503/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>