<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tools and Methods for data collection in ethnobotanical studies of homegardens</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vogl, C. R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogl-Lukasser, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Puri, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Owners and managers of homegardens have extensive knowledge of plants, their uses, and ecosystemic processes. This knowledge might be highly valuable for many purposes. To enhance ethnobotanical research on homegardens and encourage a discussion of proper methodology, this article presents tools and methods used to collect data in the multidisciplinary study of homegardens in Chiapas,Mexico; Eastern Tyrol, Austria; and Kalimantan, Indonesia. The article defines homegardens and gardeners and explains both the sampling process used in these studies and how contact and rapport was established. Also discussed are possible research questions and hypotheses, equipment used in the field, interviewing strategies, vegetation surveys, and data management. Interviews typically elicit information on preferred garden plants, plant management, homegarden management, and the history of gardening in the study area. It is concluded that homegardens present an excellent opportunity to use and experiment with both informal and formal techniques to collect qualitative as well as quantitative data.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7037/1/voglFM163.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vogl, C. R.; Vogl-Lukasser, B. and Puri, R.   (2004) Tools and Methods for data collection in ethnobotanical studies of homegardens.   Field Methodes, 16 (3), pp. 285-306.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7037/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>