<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of two Oat–legumes intercrop systems on weed flora under Mediterranean conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bilalis, Ass. Prof. D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konstantas, MSc A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Efthimiadou, MSc A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Papatheohari, Dr Y</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kakampouki, MSc I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The experiments were conducted in Greece in 2002 and 2003. The objective of this research was to investigate i) the effect of intercrop system on weeds and ii) if each intercrop system (oat-pea or cereal legume) is going to affect the weed control differently. The light penetration within the canopy measured during the first experiment (2002), was decreased up to 90%, due to the increase of the companion crops’ leaf area. In both years the decrease of the available light to the weeds, has led to the reduction of the weed dry matter, in comparison to the pure stands. Finally the oat-bean intercrop system gave better results than oat-peas system. As a result we can say that the intercrop system constitutes a new approach to weed control for low input agriculture under Mediterranean conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11554/1/Bilalis_11554_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bilalis, Ass. Prof. D.; Konstantas, MSc A.; Efthimiadou, MSc A.; Papatheohari, Dr Y and Kakampouki, MSc I.    (2008) Effect of two Oat–legumes intercrop systems on weed flora under Mediterranean conditions.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11554/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>