<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Compositional variation in fruits of currants as function of genotypes and their interactions with growth environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Yang, Baoru</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zheng, Jie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kallio, Heikki</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currants (Ribes spp.) are the second largest group of cultivated berries in Europe with&#xD;
an annual output of fresh berries over 700,000 tons. The major countries of currant&#xD;
cultivation include Nordic countries, Poland, Germany, France, Russia and the United&#xD;
Kingdom with different cultivars, growth environments, and cultivating techniques&#xD;
among these countries. Fruits of currants have been shown to have a wide range of&#xD;
beneficial effects on human health. The sensory properties and health effects are of&#xD;
crucial importance for the industrial utilisation of the berries. Genotypes and growth&#xD;
environments play an important role in modifying the composition of the berries that&#xD;
directly defines the nutritional and sensory qualities of the fruits.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18289/1/Kallio.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Yang, Baoru; Zheng, Jie and Kallio, Heikki    (2010) Compositional variation in fruits of currants as function of genotypes and their interactions with growth environments.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18289/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>