<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Field applications of entomopathogenic fungi against Rhagoletis cerasi</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keller, Siegfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two myco-insecticides, Naturalis-L (Beauveria bassiana) and PreFeRal®WG (Paecilomyces fumosoroseus), were applied against adult R. cerasi Loew (Diptera: Tephritidae) in two&#xD;
orchards in north-western Switzerland in summer 2006. Both products were applied at a concentration of 5.75x104 CFU/ml. With four applications at seven day intervals the whole flight period of R. cerasi was fully covered. During this period the relative humidity averaged 66.3% (5th June – 6th July), the temperature averaged 20.5°C. Under these conditions only Naturalis-L significantly reduced the number of damaged fruit (efficacy: 69-74%), whereas damaged fruits were not significantly reduced with PreFeRal (efficacy: 27%). For B. bassiana living fungal propagules were still detectable seven days after application, while the fungal propagules of P. fumosoroseus remained only three days. A control of R. cerasi with myco-insecticides seems possible under field conditions. However, application regime still has to be improved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20265/1/E_2008_08KifliFeldIOBC.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia; Keller, Siegfried and Wyss, Eric   (2008) Field applications of entomopathogenic fungi against Rhagoletis cerasi.   IOBC wprs Bulletin, 31, pp. 191-194.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20265/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>