<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of the purchase and consumer behaviour towards direct purchase of food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zenner, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wirthgen, Bernd</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Altmann, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper presented the methodic as well as selected results of own empiric research (face-to-face questionings in seven different questioning regions, n = 1488) to the analysis of the shopping behaviour and the attitudes towards direct purchase. To the analysis of the buying patterns a Kaufverhaltensindex (KVI) was introduced. In the regional comparison will be clear that the questioning regions of Baden-W端rttemberg and North Rhine-Westphalia show KVI by far highest, while the eastern questioning-regions (particularly Thuringia) are marked by the lowest KVI. &#xD;
Within the attitude measurement (factor analysis) six attitude-dimensions could be extracted. In particular are these: confidence in the emotional product quality, price-&#xD;
consciousness, socio-political motivation, confidence in the conventional food-offer, the orientation to convenience food and health consciousness. The analysis of the buying patterns-relevance (regression analysis) showed the distinct dominance of the attitude dimension to price consciousness. From the segmentation of the whole random check (cluster analysis) result four clusters (DV-sympathizers, price-conscious not-DV-&#xD;
buyers, direct buyers oriented to organic farming and a conventionally oriented DV-cluster). The analytic interpretation of buying patterns and soziodemographic variables as well as the regional affiliation allows a continuing characteristic and differentiation of the found clusters.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Landwirtschaftsverlag M端nster-Hiltrup</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1197/1/handbuch-kein-Dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zenner, Silvia; Wirthgen, Bernd and Altmann, M.    (2003) Analysis of the purchase and consumer behaviour towards direct purchase of food.   In:     Schriften der Gesellschaft f端r Wirtschafts- und Sozialwissenschaften des Landbaus e. V., Landwirtschaftsverlag M端nster-Hiltrup, 39.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1197/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>