<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Climate balance of organic and conventional foodstuffs compared</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lindenthal, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Markut, Theresia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hörtenhuber, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rudolph, Gwendolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hanz, Katharina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the discussion regarding the climate-relevance of foodstuffs, the terms regionalism and non-regionalism are often at the center of public debate. Hereby the often much higher CO2-emissions which are generated in agriculture and its inputs as well as in foodstuff processing are regularly neglected. It is also the case that many CO2-balances do not pay due attention – or just do not incorporate - land use change or the climate specific advantages of organic farming.&#xD;
Every foodstuff causes greenhouse gas emissions (CO2-eq), during production and processing, which contribute toward global warming.&#xD;
A broad study conducted by FiBL Austria – for the organic brand „Zurück zum Ursprung“of the supermarket chain Hofer/Aldi Süd, investigated the CO2-emissions of organic products and compared these with similar conventional products. In this process the value chain, from agriculture - including its inputs (i.e. the production of fertilizer) - to the supermarket shelf, was taken into account. 95 foodstuffs from organic and conventional agriculture respectively, were subject to comprehensive CO2-balancing. On the basis of the CO2-savings ascertained, a CO2-label has been established, which placed on the packaging of every „Zurück zum Ursprung“-product, makes the climate advantages apparent.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17998/1/lindenthal-etal-2010-oekologie-landbau-1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lindenthal, Thomas; Markut, Theresia; Hörtenhuber, Stefan; Rudolph, Gwendolyn and Hanz, Katharina    (2010) Climate balance of organic and conventional foodstuffs compared.   .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17998/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>