<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic in Europe - Prospects and Developments</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Baltic states</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bulgaria</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Finland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Hungary</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Italy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lithuania</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Netherlands</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sweden</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This publication provides an overview of developments and future prospects from the perspective of public policy support and market growth. EU agricultural and food policies continue to have a significant impact on the development of organic farming not only in the EU-28, but also across Europe influencing market trends in EU Candidate and Potential candidate countries as well as countries within the European Free Trade Association (EFTA).&#xD;
Divided into three sections the publication firstly assesses the latest developments in EU organic food and farming policy, secondly it considers case studies of organic farming policy in action both in the EU and other European countries and finally it provides a detailed overview of organic farming and market development in Europe from the latest market trends to detailed reports of the sector in different countries. We hope that the information presented in this publication will be a valuable resource for organic stakeholders, policymakers, journalists, and other interest parties.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IFOAM EU Group</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Meredith, Stephen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25649/1/willer-meredith-2014-organic-in-europe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meredith, Stephen and Willer, Helga (Eds.)      (2014) Organic in Europe - Prospects and Developments.     IFOAM EU Group, Brussels.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25649/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>