<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>OPTIMIZATION OF PLANT PROTECTION PRODUCTS&#xD;
TREATMENTS AGAINST PLASMOPARA VITICOLA</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plant protection in conventional farming, and even more so in organic farming, requires&#xD;
careful and prudent action agro-environmental monitoring and epidemic risk assessment.&#xD;
Often, however, the plant protection products are distributed in a non-targeted way, even&#xD;
when reduced incidence of pests do not require any treatment.&#xD;
In order to optimize the treatments against downy mildew, multi-annual field trials, both in&#xD;
conventional and organic vineyards, have been carried out.&#xD;
In all farms were considered 3 thesis: 1 untreated control thesis (Test), in order to follow the&#xD;
coarse of infection, 1 standard farm reference thesis (St), where the treatments were carried&#xD;
out according to the usual farm procedures and 1 experimental thesis (X).&#xD;
Guideline EPPO/OEPP PP 1/31 (3) have been carried out.&#xD;
We monitored different environmental parameters capable to influence Plasmopora viticola&#xD;
(Berk. and Curt.) Berl. and De Toni development. In fact by a network of RTUs (Remote Terminal&#xD;
Units) distributed all over the vineyards transmitting every 15 minutes via radio or via&#xD;
GPRS to a centralized Data Base 12 environmental parameters: time, data, precipitation, soil&#xD;
temperature, solar radiation, wind direction, wind speed, atmospheric relative humidity,&#xD;
atmospheric temperature, leaf wetness, soil humidity to cm 20 and soil humidity to cm 40.&#xD;
In different phenological growth stages we carried out careful disease assessments on leaves&#xD;
and bunches to evaluate the onset and development of P. viticola.&#xD;
We have studied the downy mildew infections through monitoring the environmental parameters,&#xD;
knowledge of P. viticola biological cycle, the evaluation of cultivar sensibility, the agricultural&#xD;
production method and the area characteristics, to try to optimize the anti- downy&#xD;
mildew treatments.&#xD;
The achieved results have underlined the possibility to obtain a satisfactory protection&#xD;
against P. viticola by correct placing of treatments.&#xD;
In experimental thesis (X) the number of treatments was generally lower than the number&#xD;
made on the thesis standard (ST), with efficacy comparable if not better.&#xD;
This result is most evident in conventional farms where surveillance is less accurate because&#xD;
is can also use plant protection products with a curative action.&#xD;
The trial showed the possibility of obtaining real cost containment management and a lower&#xD;
environmental impact associated with reduced fungicidal treatments.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Ghent University</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>LA TORRE, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>GIANFERRO, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SPERA, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18255/1/Optimization_of_plant_protection_products_tratments_against_Plasmopara_viticola.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LA TORRE, A.; GIANFERRO, M. and SPERA, G. (Eds.)    (2008) OPTIMIZATION OF PLANT PROTECTION PRODUCTS TREATMENTS AGAINST PLASMOPARA VITICOLA.   Ghent University, Ghent .  Proceedings of 60th International Symposium on Crop Protection, Ghent University, Belgium , Tuesday May 20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18255/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>