<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breeding strategies in poultry for genetic adaptation to the organic environment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Poul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Regarding access to breeding material for laying hens to organic egg production the following can be concluded:&#xD;
The breeding material available is genetically adapted to the cage systems. This cage adapted material has a shortcoming regarding behaviour in larger flocks that manifest in: too high tendency to feather pecking and cannibalism, and, independent of flock size, also to many mislaid eggs. Experiments has shown that feather pecking, cannibalism and nesting behaviour can be improved by selection. A search for alternative breeds/hybrids has not yet given the ideal "Organic hen". There seem to be a possibility for adaptation of laying bird to diets with lower crude protein that makes a production possible based on "home grown" crops even in Northern part of Europe.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Baars, Tom</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9/1/GENETIC_ADAPTATION_TO__ORGANIC.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sørensen, Poul    (2001) Breeding strategies in poultry for genetic adaptation to the organic environment.   In: Hovi, Malla and Baars, Tom (Eds.)  Breeding and feeding for animal health and welfare in organic livestock systems, Proccedings of the Fourth NAHWOA Workshop, pp. 51-62.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>