<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evolution of Organic Agriculture within Theoretical Frameworks of Structural Change and Transformation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Ole Horn</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This dissertation, "Evolution of Organic Agriculture within Frameworks of Structural Change and Transformation", represents a search for an understanding of the phenomenon of "Organic Agriculture". It is structured in six parts. In the first part, we investigate the agricultural economic contributions from different Danish theoretical approaches. These concepts are used as heuristic frameworks. We argue for a deductive study and a long-term approach. Using Denmark as example, the postulate is that agriculture has experienced three transformations since the end of the 18th century. This is why the theoretical concept of transformation is included. These considerations lead us to formulate the research question, How is it possible to understand the evolution of the phenomenon of organic agriculture from an economic theoretical perspective and within the framework of long-term agricultural structural change and transformation?</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16080/1/16080.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Ole Horn   (2008) Evolution of Organic Agriculture within Theoretical Frameworks of Structural Change and Transformation.    PhD thesis, Aalborg University, Department of Economics, Politics and Public Administration.  .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16080/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>