<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The application of homeopathic preparation as a prevention of diarrhoea of newborn calves</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kroupová, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Šoch, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Čermák, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work was to evaluate a possibility of using a polycomposite homeopathic preparation to prevent diarrhoea in calves. The effects were monitored in 343 newborn Holstein calves in total in two different experiments. In the first part of the experiment (experiment 1; administration of a ho-meopathic preparation on the first three days after birth) a marked tendency of reduced frequency of diarrhoea in calves was observed – one-sided p-value, assessed by the Χ–squared test, approached the level of statistical significance (0.0821). In the second part of the experiment (experiment 2; administration of a homeopathic preparation on the first, third and fifth day after birth), a tendency to reduced number of diarrhoea cases was also recorded, but with no statis-tically significant difference (0.2239). A shorter total time of diarrhoea occurrence was found in both ex-perimental groups compared to control groups for all observations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8154/1/Kroupov%C3%A1-edited.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kroupová, P.; Šoch, M. and Čermák, B.    (2006) The application of homeopathic preparation as a prevention of diarrhoea of newborn calves.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8154/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>