<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A matter of trust: How trust influences organic consumption</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smed, Sinne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Laura Mørch</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kærgård, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daugbjerg, Carsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper shows that general trust in the organic label as well as perceived positive health effects of eating organic products have positive causal effects on actual organic consumption. The data used is panel data for 830 households reporting actual purchases together with responding to a comprehensive concerning questionnaire attitudes in 2002 and 2007. The paper also shows that perceived positive environmental effects and perceived better animal welfare related to organic production have no significant effect on actual behaviour, whereas concern for artificial additives and low price sensitivity increases the organic budget share. Surprisingly enough, households who worry about GMO or pesticides do not seem to have a higher propensity to purchase organics. Even when differences in time varying attitudes have been controlled for there is still a rather large heterogeneity in the organic purchasing behaviour. Part of this heterogeneity can be explained by differences in urbanisation or level of education, while income does not seem to have any effect. This implies that the most efficient way of increasing organic consumption seems to be to continuously increasing the trust in the organic label or either to document the positive health effects of organic food or to focus more on the difference between organic and conventional foods in terms of measureable things as e.g. the frequency of finding of pesticides or the absence of GMO in organic foods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-04-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20793/4/20793.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smed, Sinne; Andersen, Laura Mørch; Kærgård, N. and Daugbjerg, Carsten   (2012) A matter of trust: How trust influences organic consumption.   Journal of Consumer Studies,  ,  - .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20793/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>