<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Design and multicriteria evaluation of regionalized test cases in organic crops without animal production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Garnier, J.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fontaine, Laurence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lubac, Stanislas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bouviala, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>What are the performances of different stockless organic crops systems? And more specifically, are there rotations more efficient than other for economic, technical and / or environmental criteria? This work aims to present the method of co-construction of simulated cases for an evaluation of economic, environmental and technical performances, at rotation and production system scale. Fifteen «test cases» have been defined in the partner regions of CASDAR projects ROTAB and ProtéAB and evaluated with a set of quantitative and non-aggregated indicators (tool Systerre ®). The results provided many references at different scales. In the current context, profitability was ensured for all cases studied, but the production environment had a major impact on the overall performance. Long rotations with multiannual crop rotation (often alfalfa), sometimes less economically efficient, had strong advantages regarding agricultural sustainability. They also seemed to be less sensitive to changes in economic conditions and provided that the crop harvest was performed by a company, (it requires less work time). The typical cases are upgradeable tools to be adapted to different simulations or prospective studies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26277/1/Garnier_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Garnier, J.F.; Fontaine, Laurence; Lubac, Stanislas and Bouviala, M.   (2013) Design and multicriteria evaluation of regionalized test cases in organic crops without animal production.  [Conception et évaluation multicritère de cas-types régionalisés en grandes cultures biologiques sans élevage.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 109-121.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26277/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>