<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Contributions of EU-project REPCO to apple scab control</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Köhl, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heijne, Bart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hockenhull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindhard Pedersen, Hanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trapmann, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eiben, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of REPCO is to contribute to the replacement of copper fungicides in organic agriculture by new measures for control of downy mildew (Plasmopara viticola) in grapevine and scab (Venturia inaequalis) in apple. Both major European organic crops strongly depend on copper fungicides. Permitted amounts will be reduced stepwise during the following years (Council Regulation (EEC) 2092/91, Annex II) to avoid environmental risks. In European countries where copper fungicides are already out of use, production of organic apples suffers severe economical problems because of insufficient scab control. &#xD;
Potentiators of resistance, organically based fungicides and biocontrol agents are screened and evaluated in apple. Effects of crop management practices in organic agriculture on overwintering of Venturia inaequalis are assessed. Novel disease control measures and knowledge are integrated into organic management systems. 'Pipeline' products already under development elsewhere are included and where necessary optimised in their use.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8820/1/ecofruit_12th_13.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Köhl, Jürgen; Heijne, Bart; Hockenhull, John; Lindhard Pedersen, Hanne; Trapmann, Marc; Eiben, Ute and Tamm, Lucius    (2006) Contributions of EU-project REPCO to apple scab control.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 73-76.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8820/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>