<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lucerne (Medicago sativa) or grass-clover as cut-and-carry fertilizers in  organic agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Burgt, Geert-Jan H.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eekeren, N. van</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scholberg, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmans, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On-farm nitrogen fixation is a driving force in organic agriculture. The efficiency with which this nitrogen is used can be increased by using lucerne (Medicago sativa) or grass-clover directly as sources of fertilizer on arable land: cut-and-carry fertilizers. In two arable crops, the use of lucerne and grass-clover as fertilizers was compared with the use of poultry manure and slurry. The nitrogen-use efficiency at crop level was comparable or better for the cut-andcarry fertilizers as compared to the animal manures. The relative P and K content of these fertilizers came closer to the crop demand than that of the poultry manure. Crop yields were comparable or better when using lucerne or grass-clover as fertilizer. It is concluded that cutand-carry fertilizers are a serious alternative for manure as part of an overall farm soil fertility strategy.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Helgadóttir, Á.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hopkins, Alan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22962/1/2790.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Burgt, Geert-Jan H.M.; Eekeren, N. van; Scholberg, Johannes and Koopmans, Chris    (2013) Lucerne (Medicago sativa) or grass-clover as cut-and-carry fertilizers in organic agriculture.  [Lucerne (Medicago sativa) of gras-klaver als maaimeststoffen in de biologische landbouw.]      Paper at:   EGF - The Role of Grasslands in a Green Future, Akureyri, Iceland, 26 June 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22962/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>