<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Greenhouse gas emissions from selected Austrian dairy production systems-model calculations considering the effects of land use change</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hörtenhuber, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindenthal, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amon, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Markurt, Theresia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirner, Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to analyze various Austrian dairy production systems (PS) concerning their greenhouse gas emissions (GHGE) in a life-cycle chain, including effects of land-use change (LUC). Models of eight PS that differ, on the one hand, in their regional location (alpine, uplands and lowlands) and, on the other hand, in their production method (conventional versus organic, including traditional and recently emerging pasture-based dairy farming) were designed.&#xD;
In general, the GHGE-reducing effect of a higher milk yield per cow and year in conventional dairy farming cannot compensate for the advantages of organic dairy production which requires lower inputs. This is shown both for GHGE per kg of milk and GHGE per ha and year of farmland. Especially when (imported) concentrates were fed, which had been grown on former forests or grassland, e.g. soybean meal and rapeseed cake, GHGE of conventional dairy farming rose due to the effects of LUC.&#xD;
GHGE per kg milk varied from 0.90 to 1.17 kg CO2-eq for conventional PS, while organic PS on average emitted 11% less greenhouse gases (GHGs), the values ranging from 0.81 to 1.02CO2-eq per kg milk. Within each production method, PS with a higher milk output generally showed better results for GHGE per kg of milk produced than PS with a lower milk output. Nevertheless the latter showed clearly better results for GHGE per ha of land used, ranging from 5.2 to 7.6Mg CO2-eq per ha and year for conventional PS and from 4.2 to 6.2MgCO2-eq per ha and year for organic PS. The results of this study emphasize the importance of a complete life-cycle assessment in the evaluation of impacts that dairy PS have on the climate.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Cambridge University Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17992/1/hoertenhuber-eta-2010-cambridge-uni-pressl.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hörtenhuber, Stefan; Lindenthal, Thomas; Amon, Barbara ; Markurt, Theresia; Kirner, Leopold and Zollitsch, Werner   (2010) Greenhouse gas emissions from selected Austrian dairy production systems-model calculations considering the effects of land use change.   Renewable Agriculture and Food Systems, 25 (4), pp. 316-329.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17992/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>