<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prevention of vole damage in organic pomiculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walther, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pelz, H.-J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Vole damage is one of the most difficult phytosanitary problems to solve in organic&#xD;
pomiculture. A survey conducted in 2002 among German fruit growers showed that 90&#xD;
% of the farms suffered from this damage. The water vole (A. terrestris) revealed to be&#xD;
the main pest in 80 % of the orchards. 61 % of the farmers announced a high interest in&#xD;
the development of new preventive and control methods. To stop immigration of voles&#xD;
into orchards a mechanical barrier system was developed and tested at two study sites&#xD;
in Baden-Wuerttemberg and Rhineland-Palatinate. At each location barrier systems with&#xD;
wire mesh (mesh size 10 mm) and polyolefine-foil were installed arround two 0.7 ha&#xD;
study plots. Two unprotected plots were used as a control. The barriers were anchored&#xD;
20 cm deep into the soil. 30 cm of the material protruded over the surface. Automatic&#xD;
gates were installed for the entrance of vehicles. 4 persons needed approximately one&#xD;
day to install a barrier around a plot with the size of 1 ha. Not only was the wire mesh&#xD;
cheaper than the foil, it was permeable for wind, water and small beneficial organisms.&#xD;
After installing the barrier systems, voles were removed from all plots. Snap trap boxes&#xD;
were ranged along the outside of the barriers to catch migrating voles. A total of 33&#xD;
water voles and 1263 common voles (M. arvalis) were captured on both study sites from&#xD;
October 2002 to November 2003. During the study period a total of 5 water voles&#xD;
immigrated into the first control plot and 6 settled into the other plot. Four water voles&#xD;
entered two of the barrier protected plots by using fresh mole galleries. The other&#xD;
protected plots stayed free from water voles. Simultaneous to the field studies, trials in&#xD;
two enclosures were carried out in Muenster. The barriers kept all water voles outside&#xD;
the protected plots. The results showed a high efficacy of the developed barrier system.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14034/1/10_Walther_55_55.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Walther, B. and Pelz, H.-J.    (2004) Prevention of vole damage in organic pomiculture.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, p. 55.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14034/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>