<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Presentation: Dropping organic certification - effects on organic farming in Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koesling, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flaten, Ola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lien, Gudbrand</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From 2002 to 06, the annual dropout rate of certified organic farmers averaged 7.3%. A project was started in 2007 to explore farmer’s reasons for opting out of certified organic production. Important factors seem to be public regulations including standards for organic farming, agronomy, economy, and farm exit. While many organic farmers with relatively small holdings have opted out, farmers with more land and larger herds tend to convert to organic agriculture. The trend towards larger-scale farms in organic than in conventional agriculture, encouraged by the design of the organic farming payments, challenges the organic principles of diversity and fairness. Means should be considered to ensure that small organic enterprises are also economically viable.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13747/1/Loes_et_al_2008_Presentation_Dropping_organic_certification.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin; Koesling, Matthias; Flaten, Ola and Lien, Gudbrand    (2008) Presentation: Dropping organic certification - effects on organic farming in Norway.       Speech at:   2nd Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), held at the16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Modena, Italy, June 16-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13747/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>