<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farming systems comparison study, Bioforsk Arable Crops Division, Apelsvoll</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A long-term farming systems comparison study was initiated at Bioforsk Arable Crops Division, Apelsvoll, in 1989. The aim was to compare on a model farm level differences in yields, nutrient runoff, nutrient balances and economical results for conventional, integrated and organic dairy and cash crop farming systems. The vision of the project was to develop farming systems that minimized the runoff of nutrients and pesticide residues, produced healthy crops with optimal nutritional value, and gave satisfying yields and economic results.  In 2000, the system was changed so that the term “integrated” was replaced by “optimal”, defined as the treatment that achieves the maximum yield per kilo leached nitrogen. The study comprises a field lysimeter with 12 plots, each 0.18 ha. Each plot is treated as a model farm, and six different farming systems (2 replicates per system) are compared as follows: &#xD;
1.	A reference cash crop farm with cereals and potatoes, managed as in the reference year of 1985&#xD;
2.	Optimal cash crop&#xD;
3.	Organic cash crop with 25% land as green manure&#xD;
4.	Optimal cash crop with animal manure  and 50% ley&#xD;
5.	Organic mixed crop with 50% ley &#xD;
6.	Organic mixed crop with 75% ley&#xD;
&#xD;
All model farms are managed with a 4-year crop rotation, where all crops are grown in each year (all plots are divided in four sub-plots). Please contact audun.korsaeth@bioforsk.no for further information and publications from the study.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Research facility description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7056/1/Korsaeth.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Facility}   DS-FELT APELSVOLL: Farming systems comparison study, Bioforsk Arable Crops Division, Apelsvoll.    Start 1989.       Facility Leader(s): Korsæth, Audun and Eltun, Ragnar, Bioforsk Norwegian Institute of Agricultural and Environmental Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7056/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>