<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zur Ausnutzung eines kompensatorischen Wachstumseffektes in der ökologischen Schweinemast</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weißmann, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berk, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Joost-Meyer zu Bakum, Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Due to a lack of organic feed with a high quality amino acid pattern it is difficult to achieve the required Lysine-Metabolisable-Energy-ratio in organic grower diets with the danger of reduced value creation. Hence, the present study should investigate whether a moderate oversupply of lysine in the finisher diet after a marginal lysine supply in the grower diet results in compensatory growth. 96 fattening pigs were divided into four groups characterised by different Lysine-ME-ratios in the grower/finisher diets (Experimental Group: 0.69/0.69; Negative Control Group: 0.69/0.59; Positive Control Group: 0.89/0.69; Regular Control Group: 0.89/0.59). Performance and carcass quality were recorded. The economic success was calculated under varying feed cost relevant organic pre-conditions. All groups were similar in performance. The experimental group and the negative control group showed similar but numerically lower lean meat percentages. The negative control group generated the best economic success. It is reasoned that fattening pigs show a certain degree of compensatory growth and that the conventional German lysine recommendations are too high for organic grower diets. Both key findings lead to the conclusion that 100 % organic pig fattening is a resolvable challenge.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17311/3/Weissmann_17311.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weißmann, Friedrich; Berk, Andreas and Joost-Meyer zu Bakum, Rudolf    (2011) Zur Ausnutzung eines kompensatorischen Wachstumseffektes in der ökologischen Schweinemast.  [About Compensatory Growth in Organic Pig Fattening.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17311/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>