<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECT OF CONSERVATION PRACTICES ON FUNCTIONAL DIVERSITY AND ASSEMBLY OF WEED COMMUNITIES: A DATABASE OF FUNCTIONAL TRAITS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sans, F. Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Armengot, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blanco-Moreno, José Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bocci, Gionata</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carlesi, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barberi, Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The incorporation of conservation agriculture techniques (e.g. reduced tillage and green manures) in organic farming systems brings many benefits to the environment and reduces energy use (Holland, 2004). One of the main drawbacks of the use of reduced tillage is the potential increase in weed infestation and shifts in the weed community composition, sometimes to the benefit of more difficult-to-control species (Bàrberi, 2002; Peigné et al., 2007; Sans et al., 2011). However, weeds have an important role in maintaining farmland functional biodiversity (Bàrberi et al, 2010; Caballero et al., 2010), and this should be balanced with their potential negative impact on crop yield and quality.&#xD;
Within the frame of the European project “Reduced tillage and green manures for sustainable cropping systems” (TILMAN-ORG), in 2012 we started a study with the aim of evaluating the effects of conservation agricultural methods on functional attributes of weed communities, taking into account both the potential detrimental effects of weeds on crop growth and yield and the potential ecological services or dis-services. Knowledge on the outcome of positive and negative effects will be useful in the context of evaluating soil conservation practices in organic farming. In this paper we highlight the approach used to build the weed functional traits database, the first step in this study.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23834/1/23834_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sans, F. Xavier; Armengot, Laura; Blanco-Moreno, José Manuel; Bocci, Gionata; Carlesi, Stefano and Barberi, Paolo    (2014) EFFECT OF CONSERVATION PRACTICES ON FUNCTIONAL DIVERSITY AND ASSEMBLY OF WEED COMMUNITIES: A DATABASE OF FUNCTIONAL TRAITS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 977-978.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23834/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>