<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improvement of the quality of propagation material for organic farming system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Groot, S.P.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jalink, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hospers-Brands, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köhl, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Veerman, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wenneker, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Wolf, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van den Bulk, R.W</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The use of organic propagation material is obligatory according to the current EU regulations for organic production. However, frequently difficulties are en-countered regarding the availability, the costs or the quality. In the Netherlands a national research program aims at developing solutions, needed for improving the production of high quality organic propagation material. The main emphasis in the pro-gram is on the model crops cabbage, onion, wheat and potato. Individual projects within the program include epidemiological studies of seed borne dis-eases to develop disease prevention strategies, meth-ods to improve resistance of seeds and seedlings towards pathogens and methods to control silver scurf in seed potatoes, development of multi-spectral analysis and sorting techniques and methods for analysis and improvement of seed vigour. Active involvement of producers and users of the seeds or seed potatoes ensures that the results will be imple-mented in practice. The program also aims at strengthening the international collaboration, amongst others through involvement in international research projects.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7373/1/Odense_Groot_et_al.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Groot, S.P.C.; Jalink, H.; Hospers-Brands, M.; Köhl, J.; Veerman, A.; Wenneker, M.; van der Wolf, J.M. and van den Bulk, R.W    (2006) Improvement of the quality of propagation material for organic farming system.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7373/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>