<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of an Environmental Management System for Organic Farms and its Introduction into Practice</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huelsbergen, Kurt-Juergen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuestermann, Bjoern</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Increasing demands for documentation of farm activities as well as environment and quality assurance call for environment adapted management systems, also in organic farming. &#xD;
The model software REPRO is a tool for farm management and consultation. It is distinguished by a systemic depiction of farming systems and can be used in agricultural practice. &#xD;
The access to farm related data and site information is the basis for statements about matter cycles (C, N, P, K), humus budget, energy efficiency, erosion, soil structure and harmful soil compaction. Its application in rather differently structured farms under organic management discloses distinctly the relationships between the design of farming systems and their environmental effects. The possibility of scenario calculations allows the validation of optimisation strategies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4375/4/4375-Huelsbergen_Kuestermann_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huelsbergen, Kurt-Juergen and Kuestermann, Bjoern    (2005) Development of an Environmental Management System for Organic Farms and its Introduction into Practice.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4375/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>