<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Response of organically and conventionally produced potatoes&#xD;
to a controlled attack of a pathogen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dasko, L'ubomír</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Drímal, Jozef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klimekova, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Urgeová, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic agricultural products have increasing share of the food market in Europe. The questions related to benefits of organic versus conventionally produced agricultural crops  are of increasing meaning. In our paper we have focused on assessment of the reaction of the immunity system of potato tubers from both agricultural systems on an external controlled attack of Phytophthora infestans, a pathogenic microorganism. The reaction of organic and conventional potato tubers was expressed via determination of chlorogenic acid. The content of chlorogenic acid in organic potato tubers increased 1.3 times after an attack, compared to potato tubers without a microbial attack. In conventional potato tubers, the increase was 4 times higher in the same way of comparison. The observed increase in conventional tubers is an evident exaggerated protection reaction to the attack of a natural potato pathogen. It is evident that there is a difference between the reaction of the immunity system of organic versus conventional potato tubers ï¿½ phytoallergy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-06-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21234/4/21234.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dasko, L'ubomír; Drímal, Jozef; Klimekova, Marta and Urgeová, Eva   (2012) Response of organically and conventionally produced potatoes to a controlled attack of a pathogen.   Journal of Food and Nutrition Research, 51 (2), pp. 89-95.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21234/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>