<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Deliverable BIO-INCROP WP1.2, WP2. Activities in Innsbruck, Austria.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Franke-Whittle, Ingrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>WP1.2 Elucidation of soil microbial components involved in soil-borne fungal diseases of organic fruit tree orchards in Europe.&#xD;
The Austrian partner of University of Innsbruck performed a further study on the microbial communities present in replant and nonreplant soils collected in apple orchards of  Italy, Germany and Austria. For this purpose, a peepsequencing approach was employed.&#xD;
&#xD;
WP2-Searching for innovative agronomic options to induce soil suppressiveness in organic fruit tree orchards.&#xD;
Different composts and organic amendments were applied to soils in order to attempt to increase microbial diversity and biomass as an approach to reducing the symptoms of ARD.  Physical-chemical parameters as well as the microbial biomass and basal respiration of composts used in amendment applied by the partners of experimental Centres in Germany, Switzerland, Italy and Austria, and those of soils after amendment and plant growth in a pot experiment were evaluated. The results will contribute towards a publication which will combine the results as well as the results from the other partners regarding plant growth.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26654/1/Franke-Whittle%20COII_BIOINCROP_WP1_WP2_June_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Franke-Whittle, Ingrid          (2014) Deliverable BIO-INCROP WP1.2, WP2. Activities in Innsbruck, Austria.    University of Innsbruck.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26654/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>