<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrate leaching and N2-fixation in grasslands of different composition, age and management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vinther, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cut grassland systems usually have high N efficiency and consequently low nitrate leaching, whereas the introduction of grazing animals increases the loss potential dramatically (Jarvis, 2000). It has been demonstrated that nitrate leaching from unfertilised grass-clover swards is lower than from mineral-N fertilised swards grazed by cattle. The possible explanation for this is that the N2 fixation by pasture legumes is regulated by a natural feedback mechanism driven by soil inorganic N levels. The feedback mechanism acts as a limit to N inputs from legumes and consequently regulates the potential for N losses (Ledgard, 2001).  In this paper we report 5 years (1997-2002) of nitrate leaching from four cropping sequences with different grassland frequency and management for both unfertilised grass-clover and fertilised monoculture grass. Furthermore, one year of N2 fixation in 1, 2 and 8-year-old grass-clover pastures is reported.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IGER - Institute of Grassland and Environmental Research, North Wyke, Okehampton, Devon, EX20 2SB, UK</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1822/1/Eriksen.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J. and Vinther, F.P.    (2003) Nitrate leaching and N2-fixation in grasslands of different composition, age and management.   In:     Abstracts for the 12th N workshop "Controlling N Flows and Losses", IGER - Institute of Grassland and Environmental Research, North Wyke, Okehampton, Devon, EX20 2SB, UK.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1822/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>