<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Crop protection in organic agriculture - a simple matter?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Litterick, Audrey M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Atkinson, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Crop protection strategies in organic agriculture and horticulture aim to prevent pest, disease and weed problems through optimisation of the cropping system as a whole. Choice of crops and varieties within the rotation and use of appropriate husbandry practices are critical to the success of the system and direct curative action against pests and diseases is rarely necessary. Research is urgently needed to determine strategies for control of key pests and diseases in organic systems if UK organic agriculture is to expand to meet increasing consumer demand. This paper describes current prevention and control strategies for pests, diseases and weeds in UK organic agriculture and identifies problems that are currently limiting expansion of the industry.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8393/1/litterick_crop_protection.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Litterick, Audrey M; Watson, Christine A and Atkinson, David    (2002) Crop protection in organic agriculture - a simple matter?   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 203-206.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8393/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>