<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Guidelines for physical weed control research: flame weeding, weed harrowing and intra-row cultivation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vanhala, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kurstjens, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ascard, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bertram, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cloutier, D.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mead, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raffaelli, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A prerequisite for good research is the use of appropriate methodology. In order to aggregate sound research methodology, this paper presents some tentative guidelines for physical weed control research in general, and flame weeding, weed harrowing and intra-row cultivation in particular. Issues include the adjustment and use of mechanical weeders and other equipment, the recording of impact factors that affect weeding performance, methods to assess effectiveness, the layout of treatment plots, and the conceptual models underlying the experimental designs (e.g. factorial comparison, dose response).&#xD;
First of all, the research aims need to be clearly defined, an appropriate experimental design produced and statistical methods chosen accordingly. Suggestions on how to do this are given. For assessments, quantitative measures would be ideal, but as they require more resources, visual classification may in some cases be more feasible. The timing of assessment affects the results and their interpretation.&#xD;
When describing the weeds and crops, one should list the crops and the most abundantly present weed species involved, giving their density and growth stages at the time of treatment. The location of the experimental field, soil type, soil moisture and amount of fertilization should be given, as well as weather conditions at the time of treatment.&#xD;
The researcher should describe the weed control equipment and adjustments accurately, preferably according to the prevailing practice within the discipline. Things to record are e.g. gas pressure, burner properties, burner cover dimensions and LPG consumption in flame weeding; speed, angle of tines, number of passes and direction in weed harrowing.&#xD;
The authors hope this paper will increase comparability among experiments, help less experienced scientists to prevent mistakes and essential omissions, and foster the advance of knowledge on non-chemical weed management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2445/1/Guidelines.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vanhala, P.; Kurstjens, D.; Ascard, J.; Bertram, A.; Cloutier, D.C.; Mead, A.; Raffaelli, M. and Rasmussen, Jesper    (2004) Guidelines for physical weed control research: flame weeding, weed harrowing and intra-row cultivation.   In:     Proceedings 6th EWRS Workshop on Physical and Cultural Weed Control, 194-225, pp. 194-225.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2445/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>