<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Segmenting the market for goat kid meat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heid, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic dairy goat farming is gaining importance in Germany and organic goat milk products become increasingly popular among consumers. At the same time, marketing of the goat kids, which are a by-product of dairy goat farming, is difficult. Consumer awareness and acceptance of kid meat is relatively low as it is not a traditional meat product consumed in Germany. Additionally, a lack in marketing structures besides direct marketing and high production costs contribute to a difficult market situation for organic dairy goat farms. There are similar problems in other European countries. &#xD;
One approach to explore marketing opportunities is to increase consumers’ awareness and acceptance of organic kid meat. A consumer survey was conducted in grocery stores in Germany. Three consumer segments were identified applying factor and cluster analysis. The three segments differ in their attitudes towards food and their eating habits. The most relevant attributes of organic kid meat should be selected and communicated to the particular consumer segment.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23790/1/23790_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heid, Astrid and Hamm, Ulrich    (2014) Segmenting the market for goat kid meat.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 379-382.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23790/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>