<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Qualität des Weidefutters in der ökologischen Milchviehhaltung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Isselstein, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brennecke, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klages, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morgenstern, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morgenstern, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tonn, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volling, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Grazing of dairy cows is mandatory in organic farming. However, as in conventional farming there is a tendency to increase milk yield per cows by employing other feeding strategies than grazing. On-farm research was initiated on organic dairy farms in Lower Saxony to investigate the current practice of grassland utilization and dairy husbandry and to explore the potential of grazing for milk production. The results show that with an increased focus on grazing of dairy cows there is considerable room for more milk being produced from grazed grass. An in-depth analysis of the spatio-temporal pattern of the quality of the herbage on offer revealed steadily high net energy and protein concentrations almost irrespective of the sward botanical composition and the season of sampling. Research is needed to improve grazing management strategies in organic farming to make better use of the high potential of grazed grasslands and thereby increase the sustainability of milk production.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21575/1/21575_Isselstein.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Isselstein, J.; Brennecke, F.; Klages, A.; Morgenstern, L.; Morgenstern, M.; Tonn, B. and Volling, O.    (2013) Qualität des Weidefutters in der ökologischen Milchviehhaltung.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21575/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>