<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A multi-country case study of the process of conversion to organic farming in the EU</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Holt, Dr Georgina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grey, Mr Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Mr Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tranter, Mr Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper reports on a series of case studies of the process of conversion to organic farming in five EU countries. The objectives of the case studies were: to identify factors affecting the decisions of conventional farmers considering conversion to organic farming; to identify problems that farmers thought they would face; and to consider and detail the financial impact of conversion on a range of farm businesses. National comparisons of the practice of conversion to organic farming reveals a wide diversity of support systems. Although these are in part necessitated by the diversity of enterprises suitable to different geographical locations, variation also results from different political agendas. Variation is also seen in farmer attitudes to organic farming. However, there are clearly concerns across countries in the financial benefits of, inputs changes for, and technical barriers to organic farming. Thus, in order to understand movements in, and out of, organic farming more fully, it is necessary to take a closer look at each of the countries here compared and to understand conversion within the national context.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9493/1/OrganicEprints_comp_article.htm</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Holt, Dr Georgina; Grey, Mr Peter; Nielsen, Mr Robert and Tranter, Mr Richard    (2003) A multi-country case study of the process of conversion to organic farming in the EU.    Working paper, Centre for Agricultural Strategy, The University of Reading.   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9493/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>