<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming in Europe - Growth, Policy Support and Future Potential</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Dr Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is increasingly recognised, by consumers, farmers, environmentalists and policy-makers, as one of a number of possible models for environmental, social and financial sustainability in agriculture. Recent years have seen very rapid growth in the sector. In 1985, certified and policy-supported organic production accounted for just 100,000 ha on 6,300 holdings in the EU, or less than 0.1% of the total utilisable agricultural area (UAA). By the end of 1998, this had increased to more than 2.8 million ha on 113,000 holdings, nearly 2.1% of total UAA, a 30-fold increase in 13 years (Foster  and Lampkin, 1999).&#xD;
&#xD;
This paper discusses factors influencing the growth of organic farming in the EU, including supporting policy measures, and the potential for widespread conversion.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Access Conferences International, London</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11018/1/geneva_00.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lampkin, Dr Nicolas    (2000) Organic Farming in Europe - Growth, Policy Support and Future Potential.   In:     Proceedings of Organic Foods 2000 Conference, Access Conferences International, London.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11018/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>