<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proteinuntersuchungen in Einzelsamen von Lupinen zur züchterischen Erhöhung des Eiweißgehaltes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jansen, Gisela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuhlmann, Josy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Besides other legumes lupins belong to the local protein crops usuable as feeding stuff in ecologic farming. Therefore an important breeding aim is to provide lupins with high and stable protein content. A non-destructive analysis using near infrared transmittance spectroscopy was developed for determination of protein in single seeds of lupins. Calibration and validation equations were calculated on the basis of 300 single seeds of 3 blue lupins (‘Azuro’, ‘Bolivio’, ‘Boregine’) growing at 3 ecological locations. The estimation of protein content was possible in a range of 15-44% protein with a coefficient of determination (r²) of 0,907 and a standard error of prediction (SEP) of 1,86%. The equation was applied to evaluate the protein content of single seeds in single plants of lupins. So the prediction of protein content is possible at early breeding stage and the investigated seeds can further used for the sowings.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9084/1/9084_Jansen_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jansen, Gisela and Kuhlmann, Josy    (2007) Proteinuntersuchungen in Einzelsamen von Lupinen zur züchterischen Erhöhung des Eiweißgehaltes.  [Protein investigations in single seeds of lupins with the breeding aim to increase the protein content.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9084/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>