<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Finnish trends in phosphorus balances and soil test phosphorus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Uusitalo, Risto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turtola, Eila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grönroos, Juha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kivistö, Juhani</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäntylahti, Väinö</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turtola, Ari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lemola, Riitta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salo, Tapio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil test phosphorus (P) concentration has a major influence on the dissolved P concentration in runoff from agricultural soils. Thus, trends in soil test P partly determine the development of pollution potential of agricultural activities. We reviewed the changes of soil test P and P balances in Finnish agriculture, and assessed the current setting of P loss potential after two Agri-Environmental Programs. Phosphorus balance of the Finnish agriculture has decreased from +35 kg ha–1 of the 1980’s to about +8 kg P ha–1 today. As a consequence, the 50-yr upward trend in soil test P concentrations has probably levelled out in the late 1990’s, as suggested by sampling of about 1600 fields and by a modelling exercise. For the majority of our agricultural soils, soil test P concentrations are currently at a level at which annual P fertilization is unlikely to give measurable yield responses. Soils that benefit from annual P applications are more often found in farms specialized in cereal production, whereas farms specialized in non-cereal plant production and animal production have higher soil test P concentrations. An imbalance in P cycling between plant (feed) and animal production is obvious, and regional imbalances are a result of concentration of animal farms in some parts of the country. A major concern in future will be the fate of manure P in those regions where animal production intensity is further increasing.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17083/1/uusitalo.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Uusitalo, Risto; Turtola, Eila; Grönroos, Juha; Kivistö, Juhani; Mäntylahti, Väinö; Turtola, Ari; Lemola, Riitta and Salo, Tapio   (2007) Finnish trends in phosphorus balances and soil test phosphorus.   Agricultural and Food Science, 16 (4), pp. 301-316.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17083/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>