<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Novel Strategies for Climate Mitigation, Sustainability and Healthy Eating in Public Foodscapes. Proceedings of a seminar held at Aalborg University, Copenhagen Institute of Technology, Denmark,November 25th-26th, 2009.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The FoodPrint09 conference, on novel strategies for climate mitigation, sustainability and healthy eating in public foodscapes, held in Copenhagen in the end of November 2009 underlined the need to take climate impact of public food into consideration when developing strategies for sustainable consumption and healthy eating in public food systems. &#xD;
&#xD;
Traditional food choice strategies address the responsibility of the individual. The iPOPY research project takes a different approach - a collective one. iPOPY research focus on how professional decision makers, public planners and politicians can impact climate through the strategies chosen in large scale food environments and how organic food supply can be integrated. The conference focused on settings where large number of individuals gathers and especially places where young people can be reached - places such as schools, festivals, and sport events. &#xD;
&#xD;
The conference dealt with important topics on why public food services should consider environmental issues as a part of their menu planning, and how to achieve this objective. Different foodscapes was explored on the conference and the conference dealt with strategies and approaches that involve a potential for significant long-term shaping of food habits through branding and learning. Hence, such settings may act as an important way to educate consumers of tomorrow to both healthy and sustainable food patterns.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Farming Systems</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>He, Chen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkola, Minna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nymoen, Lena Lie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-01-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16798/1/FoodPrint%2709_Proceedings_2nd_ed_FINAL.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg; He, Chen; Mikkola, Minna; Nielsen, Thorkild and Nymoen, Lena Lie (Eds.)    (2010) Novel Strategies for Climate Mitigation, Sustainability and Healthy Eating in Public Foodscapes. Proceedings of a seminar held at Aalborg University, Copenhagen Institute of Technology, Denmark,November 25th-26th, 2009.   ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Farming Systems, Tjele, Denmark, CORE Organic Project Series Report.  Proceedings of iPOPY-Foodprint conference 2009, Copenhagen Institute of Technology, Denmark,, November 25th-26th, 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16798/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>