<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>BIOENERGETIC LANDSCAPES REDUCE STRESS AND RESTORE HEALTH &#xD;
USING ELECTROMAGNETIC PROPERTIES OF PLANTS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nieri, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Singhania, Pawan Kumar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It is well known from Ayurveda (the traditional Indian System of medicine) that all plant species have therapeutic properties used as alimentary medicines. Nevertheless few know that it is possible to choose and use the peculiar electromagnetic properties of plants for our benefit. A long study on the biological influence of electromagnetism of our Biosphere on living beings revealed that, each plant has its own characteristic influence on each organ of the human body, and that, it is possible to create particular interactions among plants and the natural and artificial magnetism of the place, measuring afterwards the positive effects on human body. While designing a Bioenergetic Landscape Garden, it involves using Lecher Antennae to identify and measure the specific energies (their intensity and frequency) of the environment and the plants and use those with the most favourable properties for the body, by planting them in particular positions of the garden. This can greatly increase the area covered by their beneficial electromagnetic properties, using the best biological qualities of each species, amplified and spread in the environment by particular waves of the natural electromagnetism. It is possible to design and construct a Green Space and realise a Bioenergetic Landscape for the Hotels, SPA and Wellness Centers, Health and Disabled Facilities, Nursing Homes and Rest Centers, Schools, public and private gardens, terraces, roof gardens and the creation of “bioenergetic” pathways in woods, forests and Historical Parks with authentic natural therapeutic characteristics. On the basis of preliminary assessment and tests before on the ground, it will be possible to landscape the green space underlining the potentiality of the area, obtaining the best biological benefits from the plants used, while at the same time retaining all their aesthetic features. This innovative technique could also be used in creating Bioenergetic Farms to produce food with strong and harmonised bioenergetic properties for the benefit of its consumers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23477/1/23477_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nieri, Marco and Singhania, Pawan Kumar    (2014) BIOENERGETIC LANDSCAPES REDUCE STRESS AND RESTORE HEALTH USING ELECTROMAGNETIC PROPERTIES OF PLANTS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 701-704.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23477/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>