<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CARACTERÍSTICAS Y COMPARATIVA DE LOS PRODUCTORES DE ALIMENTOS ECOLÓGICOS EN EL SURESTE DE EUROPA: EL CASO DE LA REGIÓN DE MURCIA, ESPAÑA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martínez-Carrasco Pleite, Federico</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwentesius Rindermann, Rita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomez Cruz, Manuel Angel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Region of Murcia (Spain) has one of the main areas&#xD;
of organic fruit and vegetable production in Europe, with&#xD;
extensions for some products of between 10 and 20 % of the&#xD;
country’s organic agriculture surface. This work contains&#xD;
a survey carried out on 106 farmers, along with a typology&#xD;
of organic cultivations. First, an analysis was performed by&#xD;
conglomerates on the variables of each company, distinguishing small and large ones; later, using logistic regression models, an analysis was carried out on the characteristics that define the groups of farmers, the first one being the least professional but most environmentally aware farmers. The typology found of these farmers suggests the interest for more differentiated&#xD;
development policies for organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19162/1/Organic_producers_in_Murcia.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Martínez-Carrasco Pleite, Federico; Schwentesius Rindermann, Rita and Gomez Cruz, Manuel Angel   (2009) CARACTERÍSTICAS Y COMPARATIVA DE LOS PRODUCTORES DE ALIMENTOS ECOLÓGICOS EN EL SURESTE DE EUROPA: EL CASO DE LA REGIÓN DE MURCIA, ESPAÑA.  [CHARACTERISTICS AND COMPARATIVE OF ORGANIC FOOD PRODUCERS IN SOUTHEASTERN EUROPE: THE CASE OF THE MURCIA REGION, SPAIN.]  Agrociencia, 43 (6), pp. 649-657.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19162/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>