<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>NDICEA as a user friendly model tool for crop rotation planning in organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koopmans, Chris J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Burgt, Geert-Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For organic farming systems, the challenge is to become more specific in practices to maintain high standards in sustainability. Soil processes need to be clearly understood if rotations and manure applications are to become more precise.  Simulation models like the NDICEA model help in the design and maintenance of these farming systems. These models play a key-role in the design of organic precision farming. &#xD;
The NDICEA model has been calibrated for a number of long-term crop rotation experiments. Recently, the model was validated using research data from more than 35 organic farms all over the country. The model is used to calculate soil-specific mineralization rates in precision applications. In a new easy-to-use application, it was developed to design crop rotations and evaluate performance of crop rotations. This application is used to evaluate the sustainability of farming systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4400/4/4400-Koopmans_Burgt_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koopmans, Chris J. and van der Burgt, Geert-Jan    (2005) NDICEA as a user friendly model tool for crop rotation planning in organic farming.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4400/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>