<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wie lässt sich Drahtwurmfraß an Kartoffeln im Ökologischen Landbau reduzieren?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schepl, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paffrath, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Wireworms are very important animal pests in ecological farming. Some strategies were tested to regulate wireworm damage in potato farming. Forecrops such as an-nual legumes reduce the damage by wireworms under 10%. Catch crops such as Trifolium resupinatum have a positive impact on the quality of food potatoes. Under-sown crops after the last ridging had no reducing effects. Some potato varieties are more susceptible for wireworm damage. The cultivar ‛Nicola’ had the lowest wireworm damage with about 13%. Wireworm damage arised linear with later harvest dates. Pheromone traps are a good method for controlling beetles flight. Metarhizium ani-sopliae was tested as a biological control agent for wireworms. There was no effect on the wireworms’ population.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9376/1/9376_Schepl_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schepl, Ute and Paffrath, Andreas    (2007) Wie lässt sich Drahtwurmfraß an Kartoffeln im Ökologischen Landbau reduzieren?  [How to reduce wireworm damage in ecological potato farming?]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9376/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>