<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmyard manure, plant based organic fertilisers, inorganic fertiliser - which sustains soil organic matter best?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oltmanns, Meike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Legume biomass or pulse meal may be considered as alternatives to farmyard manure (FYM) in organic farms with small scale animal husbandry or in stockless organic farms. From 1996 a field trial was established on a poor sandy soil to compare plant based organic fertilisers, FYM and inorganic fertilisers, each applied at 100 kg ha-1 N. Additionally, FYM was tested at a higher rate of 170 kg ha-1 N. Average soil organic carbon content in topsoil (Corg) of the last crop rotation period (2002-05) is compared to that in 1996. Corg remained at the same level of 0.78 % only with FYM, while plant based and inorganic fertiliser decreased carbon contents to 0.74 and 0.72 % Corg, respectively. The higher FYM rate increased Corg up to 0.84 %. Based on these results, for soil organic matter maintenance, plant based organic fertilisers can not be recommended generally.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Assoc. Applied Biologists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9853/1/aab-cor06corgE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Raupp, Joachim and Oltmanns, Meike    (2006) Farmyard manure, plant based organic fertilisers, inorganic fertiliser - which sustains soil organic matter best?   In:     Aspects of Applied Biology, Assoc. Applied Biologists, 79, pp. 273-276.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9853/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>