<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ertrag und Wurzelkolonisation mit arbuskulären Mykorrhiza-&#xD;
Pilzen von organisch oder mineralisch gedüngtem Weizen auf&#xD;
trockenem, sandigen Boden</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oltmanns, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jarosch, A.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neumann, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigated wheat yield and arbuscular mycorrhiza (AM) fungal root colonization&#xD;
and spore formation in response to fertilization, either with high or low amounts of&#xD;
mineral fertilizer or cattle manure since 27 years. At low rates there was no difference&#xD;
in yield between minerally and organically fertilized plants. High rates of mineral&#xD;
fertilizers reduced yields. Reasons can be that either the high nitrogen availability was&#xD;
less effectively used for grain development of minerally fertilized plants, or the mineral&#xD;
fertilization rendered the plants more sensitive towards drought stress. The extent of&#xD;
AM fungal root colonization appeared to depend on the plant P nutritional status rather&#xD;
than the type of fertilizer applied. The lower fertilization showed higher rates of AM&#xD;
root colonization. The number of AM spores, however, was higher in organically&#xD;
compared with minerally fertilized soil, indicating that organic fertilization increased&#xD;
reproduction of these beneficial microbes under dry soil conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14400/1/Raupp_14400.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Raupp, J.; Oltmanns, M.; Jarosch, A.-M. and Neumann, E.    (2009) Ertrag und Wurzelkolonisation mit arbuskulären Mykorrhiza- Pilzen von organisch oder mineralisch gedüngtem Weizen auf trockenem, sandigen Boden.  [Yield and arbuscular mycorrhiza fungal root colonization of organically or minerally fertilized wheat grown on a dry, sandy soil.]      Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14400/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>