<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An investigation into the relationship between preceding break crops and weed populations in barley crops in organic ley/arable rotations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Litterick, Audrey M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Robson, Melissa C</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. The relationship between weed populations and cereal crops following nine organic break crops was investigated in field trials in Warwickshire, Aberdeenshire and Ceredigion in 2001. Weed biodiversity was high on all sites and varied between sites in terms of species present. Severity of weed infestation differed significantly between sites and between cereals following different break crops. The impact of break crop species on the incidence and severity of the weed burden in the following cereal is discussed in relation to the field trials at the three sites.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8408/1/litterick_Break_crops_weeds_barley.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Litterick, Audrey M; Watson, Christine A and Robson, Melissa C    (2002) An investigation into the relationship between preceding break crops and weed populations in barley crops in organic ley/arable rotations.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 227-228.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8408/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>