<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nanotechnology: The Next Challenge for Organics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lyons, Kristen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nanotechnology is the fast growing science of the ultra small; it is creating engineered particles in the size range 1 to 100 nanometres. At this size, materials exhibit novel behaviours. Nanotechnology is a rapidly expanding multibillion dollar industry, with research being heavily promoted by governments, and especially the US. Nanoscale materials are already incorporated into more than 580 consumer products, including food, packaging, cosmetics, clothing and paint. Nanotechnology has been cited as the foundation of a new “advanced agriculture”. This technology is advancing without nano-specific regulation and without labelling while, at the same time, public confidence in government regulatory agencies, and in the safety of the food supply, is declining. There is an opportunity, perhaps an imperative, for the organic community to take the initiative to develop standards to exclude engineered nanoparticles from organic products, just as GMOs have been excluded previously.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hill, Stuart</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13569/1/13569.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John and Lyons, Kristen   (2008) Nanotechnology: The Next Challenge for Organics.   Journal of Organic Systems, 3 (1), pp. 3-22.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13569/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>