<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökologische Bewirtschaftung erfordert die Steuerung von innerbetrieblichen Nährstoffflüssen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Self-organised ecosystems are characterised by a high efficiency in the use of limited nutrient resources whereas the productivity is generally low. To utilise the potentials of agro-ecosystems with respect to a high nutrient efficiency, there is a need to steer the nutrient flow and provide good starting and adaptation conditions for living organisms. &#xD;
While organic standards provide no operational guidelines on how to improve nutrient management, a concept was developed to improve N-efficiency on the farm level. N-import into the farm and N-flow through subordinate sub-systems (‘livestock’, ‘dung storage/ distribution’, ‘arable land/pasture’, and ‘feed storage/distribution’) were assessed on 9 organic and 7 conventional dairy farms, based on farm specific data and by making use of equations from the literature to estimate relevant figures. &#xD;
N-efficiency varied considerably between sub-systems within and between farms, however showing no significant difference between the production methods. The results indicate a large but farm specific potential for improvements, contradicting any attempts of generalised statements and recommendations. Instead of minimum standards, a high level of N-efficiency that is beyond the average of conventional farms should be established as a leading aim in organic agriculture to justify claims.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21474/1/21474_Sundrum.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Albert    (2013) Ökologische Bewirtschaftung erfordert die Steuerung von innerbetrieblichen Nährstoffflüssen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21474/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>