<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss des Anbausystems auf Ertrag und Gesundheit von&#xD;
Winterweizen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krebs, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanetti, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jenny, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, H.-R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zihlmann, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tschachtli, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a long-term trial in central Switzerland, yield and health of winter wheat was&#xD;
examined under organic, extensive and intensive management.&#xD;
In the organic cropping system, soil was ploughed and fertilised with cattle dung. In&#xD;
the extensive system, soil was cultivated ploughless and dung was supplemented by&#xD;
mineral fertiliser. Herbicides were used, but no growth regulators or fungicides. In the&#xD;
intensive system, soil was ploughed and manure was based on cattle dung and&#xD;
mineral fertiliser with 20 % more nitrogen than in the extensive system. For plant&#xD;
protection, herbicides, growth regulators and fungicides were used.&#xD;
In the period from 2004 to 2007, average winter wheat yields of the intensive and the&#xD;
extensive crop management system exceeded those of the organic production by 21.3&#xD;
% and 5.5 % respectively. This was probably due to the higher level of fertilisation and&#xD;
plant protection.&#xD;
In 2007, a year with frequent rain during the summer, the infestation of grains with&#xD;
Microdochium nivale and Fusarium graminearum was lowest in the organic wheat. In&#xD;
consequence, its germination capacity was higher and the deoxynivalenol content was&#xD;
lower compared with the other systems. The increased grain infestation with F.&#xD;
graminearum and the higher deoxynivalenol content of wheat grains in the extensive&#xD;
system can be explained by the ploughless tillage, with straw from the previous maize&#xD;
crop remaining on the soil surface.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9544/1/Krebs_9544.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krebs, H.; Zanetti, S.; Jenny, E.; Forrer, H.-R.; Zihlmann, U. and Tschachtli, R.    (2009) Einfluss des Anbausystems auf Ertrag und Gesundheit von Winterweizen.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9544/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>