<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Marktforschung: Ermittlung von zusätzlichen Nachfragepotentialen zur Erhöhung des Absatzes von Biomilch in der Schweiz</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a supply surplus of Swiss organic dairy products (10 - 20 % of of the organic milk produced). The project aimed to identify reasons which hamper a better market penetration of products like organic yoghurt, cheese, butter or curd. These product groups achieve smaller market shares under 5%, compared with product groups with higher organic market shares such as milk, vegetables, fruits or eggs.&#xD;
&#xD;
Farmers in Switzerland have serious problems in marketing bigger parts of their organic dairy production. This has led to pressure on producer prices. &#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims including target group:&#xD;
The market research project therefore aimed in a first stage to identify main market barriers for a better penetration of organic dairy products. Based on the identified problems recommendations will be elaborated how to stimulate a better market development at different levels (retailers, processors, BIO SUISSE).&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
- Desktop research&#xD;
- Focus group interviews with regular and occasional consumers of organic dairy products&#xD;
- Exploring market research at retailer level&#xD;
- Written and oral survey with dairy processors in Switzerland&#xD;
- Yoghurt Tasting with consumers&#xD;
- Preference test of organic milk with consumers&#xD;
- Store checks of retailers and butcheries&#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
Several market barriers were identified which hamper a better market penetration of organic dairy products. &#xD;
1. Quality problems: Organic dairy products often don’t match the quality requirements of consumers (mainly fruits yoghurt taste, colour and texture, package material of milk and cheese).&#xD;
2. Missing consumer perceptions of big differences between organic and conventional milk production in Switzerland. &#xD;
3. Missing retailer involvement: The biggest Swiss supermarket chain developed a competing conventional dairy brand which cut market shares of the organic assortment.&#xD;
4. Missing processor initiatives: The biggest processors often just respond on retailer demand but do not develop actively new and attractive organic product lines as offer for retailers. This development is in contrast to the conventional assortment development and related to the organic retailer trademark policies of Swiss retail chains which don’t accept organic producer brands next to the own trademark.&#xD;
5. The export potential of Swiss organic cheese and other dairy specialities isn’t used sufficiently.&#xD;
Recommendations start on the identified barriers. The product quality in many cases should clearly improved to match consumer expectations. Retailers should accepts organic producers brands next to their own trademarks in order to stimulate processors to develop more product innovation and own organic brands based on organic milk. Further more export activities should be stimulated and coordinated by BIO SUISSE.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6275/1/richter-etal-2004-biomilch.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Organic dairy market research 2004 (Marktforschung Biomilch 2004): Marktforschung: Ermittlung von zusätzlichen Nachfragepotentialen zur Erhöhung des Absatzes von Biomilch in der Schweiz.  [Market research on additional demand potentials for organic dairy products in Switzerland.]   Runs 2004 - 2004.      Project Leader(s): Richter, Toralf and Schmid, Otto, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6275/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>