<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Research Needs in Organic Vegetable Production Systems in Tropical Countries With a Focus on Asia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Juroszek, Dr Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tsai, Miss Hsing-Hua</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Well-managed organic vegetable production systems (OVPS) can provide food security and healthy diets for humans, while being less harmful to the environment and more efficient in natural resource use. However, most OVPS research is carried out in developed countries, mainly under temperate or subtropical climatic conditions. Institutionalized research in organic farming in most tropical countries appears to be relatively new, and it is not a significant focus for the International Agricultural Research Centers. Tropical farmers in Asia producing vegetables organically, whether by design or default, must overcome significant challenges organic growers in temperate climates seldom face, including a lack of suitable varieties, heavy rainfall and the year-round presence of pests. According to our online literature survey, tomato is the vegetable most commonly researched in organic farming, followed by lettuce, carrot and cucumber; we found little research on crops important to tropical Asia, such as eggplant, chili pepper, different cucurbits such as gourds, and locally important indigenous vegetables. To improve and promote OVPS in tropical countries, institutional research is needed to identify and develop vegetable varieties, alternative crop protection and management methods better suited to the tropics.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11804/1/Juroszek_11804_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Juroszek, Dr Peter and Tsai, Miss Hsing-Hua    (2008) Research Needs in Organic Vegetable Production Systems in Tropical Countries With a Focus on Asia.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11804/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>