<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleich von Treibhausgasemissionen unterschiedlich wirtschaftender Modellbetriebe im Alpenvorland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kasper, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Harald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hülsbergen, Kurt-Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amon, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>About 8.8 % (UBA 2010) of the total greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions in Austria are caused by agricultural practices. Besides the release of climate relevant gases, C-sequestration occurs depending on the natural conditions and farming system. &#xD;
The focus of the project was to describe the GHG-emissions and sinks of the most relevant farming types, both organic and conventional, within the main production areas in Austria. Results of an intensively cultivated region in the North-West are presented. Based on the input data, six model-farms were created with the programme REPRO, whereby forage production, cash crops and refinement systems were considered. &#xD;
All systems had a positive humus balance and sequestered carbon in the soil, especially forage production systems. Due to the use of mineral fertilizers, a higher N-balance occurred in all conventional systems. Organic systems on the other hand were able to utilize nutrients to a wider extent. The GHG-potential related to area was at least 29 % higher at conventional compared to organic systems, whereby N2O-emissions, calculated according to IPCC 1997, were most relevant. Differences were reduced and results even reversed calculating the GHG-potential per product unit. When calculating the N2O-Emissions with an increased N2O emission factor of 2.5 % of N input in a scenario, the emissions increased almost proportionally.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21469/1/21469_kasper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kasper, Martina; Freyer, Bernhard; Schmid, Harald; Hülsbergen, Kurt-Jürgen; Amon, Barbara and Friedel, Jürgen K.    (2013) Vergleich von Treibhausgasemissionen unterschiedlich wirtschaftender Modellbetriebe im Alpenvorland.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21469/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>