<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimierte Anwendung von Pflanzenschutzmitteln zur Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kühne, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reelfs, Torben</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moll, Eckard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kleinhenz, Benno</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Colorado Potato Beetle is one of the most important pests of potatoes. The effect of various plant protection products based on neem (NeemAzal-T/S), pyrethrum/rape oil (Spruzit Neu) and Bacillus thuringiensis - B.t.t. (Novodor FC) against this pest has been compared in a field experiment from 2004 until 2006. The combined application of neem and B.t.t.-product have reduced the number of Colorado Potato Beetle larvae as well as the losses of plant material by feed of the beetle larvae significantly. In three years of field experiments the application of pyrethrum/rape oil has shown no significant effect to reduce the number of Colorado Potato Beetles.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9458/1/9458_K%C3%BChne_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kühne, Stefan; Reelfs, Torben; Moll, Eckard and Kleinhenz, Benno    (2007) Optimierte Anwendung von Pflanzenschutzmitteln zur Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) im Ökologischen Landbau.  [Optimised application of plant protection products to control Colorado Potato Beetle (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) in organic farming.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9458/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>