<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Messung sekundärer Pflanzeninhaltsstoffe von Brokkoliblumen aus ökologischem Anbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wolf, Stefanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fleck, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graeff-Hönninger, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zikeli, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Today, consumer awareness on the healthiness of their foodstuff increases. The main focus is on secondary metabolites and antioxidants. Broccoli (Brassica oleracea L. convar. botrytis Alef. var. italica Plenck) has many compounds beneficial for human health, like Vitamin C, Carotionoids or Anthocyanins. To investigate these compounds two techniques are used in this study which are non-destructive sensor measurements (Multiplex®) to determine the value of anthocyanins (ANTH_RG) and flavonols (FLAV) and measurements of the antioxidant potential (water- (ACW) and lipid- (ACL) soluble antioxidants) on the basis of chemoluminescence. Field trials in autumn of 2011 and spring of 2012 were conducted in a randomized block design with different broccoli genotypes, named “Limba”, “Marathon F1” and “TH-CAN-FK”. Measurements were done two times in 2011 and three times in 2012 on broccoli florets. Results indicate that the effect of the sampling date had a significant effect on FLAV, ANTH_RG, ACL and ACW values in Broccoli florets, while the effect of the genotype had only an influence on the ANTH_RG value. These effects may be due to less rainfall and pest infestations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21583/1/21583_Wolf.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wolf, Stefanie; Fleck, Michael; Graeff-Hönninger, Simone; Zikeli, Sabine and Claupein, Wilhelm    (2013) Messung sekundärer Pflanzeninhaltsstoffe von Brokkoliblumen aus ökologischem Anbau.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21583/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>