<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigations on alternative substances for control of apple scab - Results from Conidia germinating tests and experiments with plant extracts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pfeiffer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alt, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulz, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hein, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kollar, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The intention of this research project, which was supported within the "Bundesprogramm Ökologischer&#xD;
Landbau", was to find alternatives for the control of Venturia inaequalis for the organic fruitgrower.&#xD;
Beside the investigations on reducing the ascospore potential on fallen leaves, experiments&#xD;
were conducted in laboratory, greenhouses and in orchard to test direct control of scab with different&#xD;
plant extracts, concentrations and methods of extraction. Extracts from Inula viscosa, Quillaja&#xD;
saponaria-bark, citrus-species (AGROMIL) and Saponaria officinalis revealed a distinct efficacy&#xD;
against apple scab in greenhouse studies on apple seedlings. ELOT-VIS, CHITOPLANT, COMCAT,&#xD;
MOOSEXTRAKT, SILIOPLANT und FZB 24 did not show sufficient efficacy with the application schedule&#xD;
used for control of scab. Mixtures of Quillaja-saponine and sulphur reduced effectively apple scab&#xD;
incidence. In an experiment concerning rain stability Citrus-extract and Quillaja-saponine showed a&#xD;
lower efficacy against scab after a simulated rain of 5 mm. The screening of different supplements&#xD;
to Citrus-extract as surfactants and adhesives revealed GREEMAX and BIOPLUSS as promising additives.&#xD;
Both combinations showed an efficacy comparable to copperoxychloride corresponding to&#xD;
400 g elementary copper per ha.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14452/1/20_Pfeiffer_101_107.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pfeiffer, B.; Alt, S.; Schulz, C.; Hein, B. and Kollar, A.    (2004) Investigations on alternative substances for control of apple scab - Results from Conidia germinating tests and experiments with plant extracts.  [Untersuchungen zum Einsatz alternativer Stoffe zur Regulierung des Apfelschorfes - Ergebnisse aus Konidienkeimtests und Versuchen zu Pflanzenextrakten.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 101-107.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14452/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>