<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The significance of mycorrhizal fungi for crop productivity and ecosystem sustainability in organic farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van der Heijden, Dr. Marcel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rinaudo, Mrs Valeria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verbruggen, Mr. Erik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scherrer, Mr. Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bàrberi, Prof. Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giovannetti, Prof. Manuela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Mycorrhizal fungi are widespread in agricultural systems and are especially relevant for organic agriculture because they can act as natural fertilisers, enhancing plant yield. Here we explore the various roles that mycorrhizal fungi play in sustainable farming systems with special emphasis on their contribution to crop productivity and ecosystem functioning. We review the literature and provide a number of mechanisms and processes by which mycorrhizal fungi can contribute to crop productivity and ecosystem sustainability. We then present novel results, showing that mycorrhizal fungi can be used to suppress several problematic agricultural weeds. Our results highlight the significance of mycorrhizal fungi for sustainable farming systems and point to the need to develop farming systems in which the positive effect of these beneficial soil fungi is optimally being utilized.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12004/1/12004.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van der Heijden, Dr. Marcel; Rinaudo, Mrs Valeria; Verbruggen, Mr. Erik; Scherrer, Mr. Caroline; Bàrberi, Prof. Paolo and Giovannetti, Prof. Manuela    (2008) The significance of mycorrhizal fungi for crop productivity and ecosystem sustainability in organic farming systems.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12004/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>