<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Managing crop nitrogen and soil dynamics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Salon, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauggaard-Nielsen, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Despite extensive research grain legume seed protein content and yield remains low and unstable. &#xD;
Grain legume performances in the cropping system are highly dependent upon N nutrition of the crop relying on root assimilation of soil N in combination with symbiotic fixation of atmospheric dinitrogen. In order to improve the competitive ability of grain legumes for growth resources an enlargement of the crop surface area production in combination with a judicious management of both inputs and N acquisition (and allocation to the harvested organs) is needed. Competitive ability implies to take into account economical constraints and the crop production effect on the environment, reducing the amount of N remaining after the crop harvest preventing N leaching.&#xD;
The aims of the workshop were to explore possible research activities  to enhance grain legume seed filling in relation to management of crop and soil N dynamics. About 30 conference participant were present and the workshop was strengthened by several poster presentations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>AEP</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/137/1/GL34.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Salon, Christoph and Hauggaard-Nielsen, Henrik    (2001) Managing crop nitrogen and soil dynamics.   Grain legumes, 2001, 34 (4), pp. 18-19.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/137/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>