<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic feed makes the immune system more alert (Summary)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Machteld</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Most studies on organic food are dealing with differences in nutrient contents of organic versus conventional products. Much less studies have focussed on potential differences in health effects. The presented study is the first experimental study in the Netherlands in which the effects of feed derived from organic or conventional origin were studied, using animals as a model for humans. Two generations of chicken as well as the feed, especially composed out of organically or conventionally produced ingredients, were extensively studied, using several most modern techniques. Various differences in nutrient content were observed in the ingredients. Most consistent finding was a difference in protein content, resulting on average in a 10% higher protein content in the conventionally produced feeds. &#xD;
&#xD;
Results also revealed biomarkers for future research: body weight gain, responsiveness of the immune system, metabolic reactions in blood and liver and genetic regulation in the gut. With these biomarkers, clear differences between the two groups of chicken were found. For research on health effects in humans, which is the ultimate goal, it is important to have appropriate biomarkers which can measure health effects in healthy individuals.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12961/1/1947.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huber, Machteld    (2007) Organic feed makes the immune system more alert (Summary).   Louis Bolk Instituut.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12961/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>