<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökologische Sanitärlösungen in Afrika: Beitrag zu nachhaltiger Abfallentsor-gung und erhöhter Bodenfruchtbarkeit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Germer, Jörn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grenz, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sauerborn, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>While plant nutrient deficiencies are a major constraint to increasing crop yields in many rural parts of Sub-Saharan Africa, excess nutrients in organic wastes and wastewater cause environmental and hygienic problems in urban areas. We report on an ongoing research aimed at implementing principles of ecological sanitation on a university campus near Accra, Ghana. Alternative sanitation including dry urinals and separating toilets was installed in buildings. Pure urine, urine-water mix, greywater from baths and kitchens and faeces are treated and stored separately. Except for faeces, all materials are used to fertilise annual (urine) and perennial (urine-water, greywater) crops. Urine application significantly boosted maize and sorghum growth. Pathogens present in all fresh sanitary products, e.g. Escherichia coli, could be largely deactivated by six weeks of storage. A survey revealed no fundamental objections of farmers against the use of sanitary products. Scenario calculations suggest that recycling organic wastes and urine may contribute to alleviating nutrient deficiencies, particularly with regard to P and in densely settled areas. Future research should aim at developing hygienically safe, resource-efficient ways of urine application.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9429/1/9429_Germer_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Germer, Jörn; Grenz, Jan and Sauerborn, Joachim    (2007) Ökologische Sanitärlösungen in Afrika: Beitrag zu nachhaltiger Abfallentsor-gung und erhöhter Bodenfruchtbarkeit.  [Ecological sanitation in Africa: Contribution to sustainable waste disposal and improved nutrient management.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, u, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9429/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>