<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic forage seed production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Boelt, Birte</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From January 2004 only organically produced seed can be used in organic farming systems within the EU. Optimal forage production relies on the access to improved cultivars of high quality clover and grass seed for forage mixtures. Currently the supply of organic forage seed in Europe i scarce. In Denmark a production of one of the main constituents of forage mixtures, perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.) is established, however, another main constituent, white clover (Trifolium repens L.) is still in request.&#xD;
In general seed yield in organic production is decreased compared to conventional production. In perennial ryegrass the seed yield reduction is approximately 25% whereas it similarly are 80% in white clover. Until now research initiatives has not been able to increase seed yields in white clover, whereas organic grass seed production in general are performed without larger difficulties. Currently the European Commission has put forward a proposal allowing derogations to use conventional grown seed if organic varieties are not available in species that will not be listed in an annex to the regulation.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Loch, Donald S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3052/1/Organic_Forage_Seed_Production.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Boelt, Birte    (2003) Organic forage seed production.   In: Loch, Donald S. (Ed.)  Proceedings Fifth International Herbage Seed Conference, Gatton, Australia, 23-26 November 2003. Herbage Seeds in the New Millenium - New Markets, New Products, New Opportunities, pp. 43-47.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3052/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>