<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An extract of Penicillium chrysogenum elicits early defense-related responses and induces resistance in Arabidopsis thaliana independently of known signalling pathways</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thürig, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Felix, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Binder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boller, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An aqueous extract of the mycelium of Penicillium chrysogenum (further called ‘Pen’ induced early defense-related responses such as an extracellular alkalinisation in cell cultures and ethylene production in leaf slices of numerous mono- and dicotyledon plant species, including Arabidopsis thaliana, tomato, tobacco and rice. The Pen-elicitor was sensitive to protease digestion but insensitive to other enzymes, suggesting that the elicitor-active region is a protein or a peptide. Reversed phase, ion exchange and size exclusion chromatography revealed that the Penelicitor is heterogeneous. This prevented further identification of the elicitor. Pen protected A. thaliana from a broad range of pathogens, including an oomycete (Hyaloperonospora parasitica), two ascomycetes (Botrytis cinerea, Alternaria brassicicola) and a bacterium (Pseudomonas syringae pv. tomato DC3000) without having a direct antimicrobial effect. Various mutants of A. thaliana were used to test whether Pen induces resistance on one of the known signaling pathways: Pen was fully protective against B. cinerea in A. thaliana transgenes or mutants impaired in the salicylic acid (NahG, npr1), jasmonic acid (coi1-1), and ethylene (ein2-1) signalling pathway. Similarly, Pen-mediated resistance against H. parasitica was not affected in the mutants npr1, coi1-1 or ein2-1. However, its efficacy was reduced in the transgene NahG. From these data on cell cultures and on A. thaliana we conclude that Pen contains at least one unidentified elicitor, most likely a protein or a glycoprotein, inducing resistance via signal transduction pathways different from classical SA/NPR1- or JA/ethylene-dependent pathways.&#xD;
(c) 2006 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9078/1/Thuerig-etal-2006-penicillium-chrysogenum-pmpp.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thürig, Barbara; Felix, Georg; Binder, Andreas; Boller, Thomas and Tamm, Lucius   (2006) An extract of Penicillium chrysogenum elicits early defense-related responses and induces resistance in Arabidopsis thaliana independently of known signalling pathways.   Physiological and Molecular Plant Pathology, 67, pp. 180-193.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9078/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>