<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>First results with the Gas Discharge Visualisation (GDV) method (Kirlian photography) to assess the inner Quality of apples</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saikov, Aleksander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bigler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>GDV technology can provide useful information for distinguishing healthy and stressed plants and, in some cases, it can provide useful information for distinguishing different varieties and rootstocks. It can also provide information for distinguishing fruits grown using different fertilization treatments. However, in our cases with fruit of very similar standard quality, we were not able to find complementary information to distinguish organically from conventionally grown apple fruit. Currently we are carrying out two larger and refined studies on just that topic with 5 conventional/ organic comparison pairs from harvests of two years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7002/1/weibel-2005-PosterFQH_GDV.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, Franco P.; Saikov, Aleksander and Bigler, Christoph    (2005) First results with the Gas Discharge Visualisation (GDV) method (Kirlian photography) to assess the inner Quality of apples.   In:     Organic Food Quality and Health Association (FQH) (2005): Where we achieved - where we will go. Proceedings of the First Scientific FQH Conference held in Frick, Switzerland. Kassel, p. 77.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7002/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>