<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECT OF CONVENTIONAL VERSUS ORGANIC METHOD OF PRODUCTION ON THE BROILER CARCASS AND MEAT QUALITY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CASTELLINI, Prof C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MUGNAI, Dr C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DAL BOSCO, Dr A</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of the organic production system on broiler carcass and meat quality was assessed. Two hundred and fifty Ross male chickens were assigned to two different systems of production: conventional, housing in an indoor pen (0.12 m2/bird); organic, housing in an indoor pen (0.12 m2/bird) with access to a grass paddock (4 m2/bird). At 56 and 81 days of age twenty chickens per group were slaughtered to evaluate the carcass traits and the characteristics of breast and drumstick muscles (pectoralis major and peroneus longus). The organic chickens had carcasses with a higher breast and drumstick percentages and lower level of abdominal fat. The muscles had lower pHu and water holding capacity. Instead cooking loss, lightness values, shear values, Fe, polyunsaturated fatty acids of n-3 series and TBA-RS were higher. The sensory quality of the breast muscle was better. Organic production system seems to be a good alternative method, due to better welfare conditions and good quality of the carcass and meat. A negative aspect was the higher level of TBA-RS in the muscles, probably due to greater physical activity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9318/1/organic.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CASTELLINI, Prof C; MUGNAI, Dr C and DAL BOSCO, Dr A   (2002) EFFECT OF CONVENTIONAL VERSUS ORGANIC METHOD OF PRODUCTION ON THE BROILER CARCASS AND MEAT QUALITY.   Meat Science (60), pp. 219-225.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9318/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>