<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EU Ecolabel for food and feed products – feasibility study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sengstschmid, Helmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sprong, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stockenbrand, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiller, Achim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The environmental impacts of the production and processing of food, feed and drinks make up between 20% and 30% of the total environmental impacts of consumable goods in the EU. In the case of eutrophication (the accumulation of nutrients in water causing a reduction in oxygen availability) they account for as much as 58% of the total impacts.&#xD;
The EU Ecolabel is a voluntary scheme that forms part of overall EU policy to encourage more sustainable consumption and production.&#xD;
To date, the EU Ecolabel scheme has developed criteria for products in the non-food sector. The Regulation that governs the scheme (66/2010) aims to extend the EU Ecolabel into new product categories including food. However, the Regulation stipulates that before extending to the food sector, a feasibility study should be undertaken.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20232/1/Ecolabel_for_food_final_report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sengstschmid, Helmut; Sprong, Niels; Schmid, Otto; Stockenbrand, Nina; Stolz, Hanna and Spiller, Achim         (2011) EU Ecolabel for food and feed products – feasibility study.    Oakdene Hollins. UK, FiBL, CH and University Göttingen, D.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20232/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>