<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Food security of small holding farmers: comparing organic and conventional systems in India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Panneerselvam, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, John E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study compared farm production, crop yield, input cost, and income in organic and conventional farming systems in three states of India: Uttarakhand, Madhya Pradesh, and Tamil Nadu. The results showed that organic farming reduced the input cost without affecting the net margin in all three states. Total food production was found to be comparable for the two systems in two of three states. While yield of rice and wheat generally was lower under the organic systems, yield from intercropping food crops was generally higher. The number of agro-ecological methods and percentage of farms practicing different agro-ecological methods were higher under organic systems than conventional systems. These results suggest that organic farming has the potential to improve food security of small farmers by reducing indebtedness due to the lower cost of production without affecting total farm production and farm income.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Taylor&amp;Francis</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18125/1/18125.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Panneerselvam, P.; Hermansen, John E. and Halberg, Niels   (2011) Food security of small holding farmers: comparing organic and conventional systems in India.   Journal of Sustainable Agriculture, 35 (1), pp. 48-68.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18125/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>