<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ProEcoWine: Development of a Novel Plant Protection Product to Replace Copper in Organic Viticulture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bilbao, Jennifer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tseng, Eileen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuerst, Manfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Erb-Brinkmann, Maike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid-Staiger, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ördög, Vince</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Egner, Siegfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fungi like downy mildew reduce wine yield and impair wine quality. In conventional as well as organic viticulture, grape growers usually apply copper for preventing these fungal diseases. In the ProEcoWine project funded by the EC, on behalf of five companies, the Fraunhofer IGB, the University of West Hungary and Laboratoire PHENOBIO develop a novel bio-plant protection product to replace copper fungicides. To achieve this, microalgal strains with antifungal properties have been cultivated to be further processed into a plant protection product enriched with micronutrients. Strains with the most efficient control (more than 90%) over downy mildew and Botrytis have been identified and selected for validation in greenhouse and field experiments, while effective and economic cultivation methods for high density growth are being established. The optimal formulation of microalgae concentrate containing micronutrients and natural preservatives will then be determined after downstream methods required for the activation of antifungal activity are evaluated, optimizing the process for the manufacture of ProEcoWine.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24150/1/24150_final_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bilbao, Jennifer; Tseng, Eileen; Fuerst, Manfred; Erb-Brinkmann, Maike; Schmid-Staiger, Ulrike; Ördög, Vince and Egner, Siegfried    (2014) ProEcoWine: Development of a Novel Plant Protection Product to Replace Copper in Organic Viticulture.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 539-542.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24150/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>