<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung biologisch-dynamischer Präparate in Rebbergen</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
The majority of vine bio-dynamic growers report positive experiences in terms of plant production but also wine quality. However, quantitative and scientifically proved data are not available. However there is a high interest of the wine growers for appoved data on the efficiency of the bio-dynamic preparations. As in other countries bio-dynamic viticulture is rapidly growing in Switzerland. However, there is very little scientific evidence for the efficiency of the preparations. Thus, science-based recommendations for its use or optimisation cannot be given.&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims including target group:&#xD;
To show the quantitative effects of bio-dynamic preparations on parameters of plant growth, disease tolerance, soil properties and finally also on vine quality. An additional goal of the project is the management improvement of the bio-dynamic growers participating in the trials. The results may show possibilities to optimize the standard and the specific bio-dynamic management measures of the growers.&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
In 2003 the project team that includes 4 bio-dynamic growers installed an On-Farm trial on 4 different sites of bio-dynamic vine farms. At each site 4 different treatment blocks are separated: a) with preparation 500 and with prep. 501; b) with 500 alone; c) with 501 alone; d) no preparations. Several times of the year plant growth and health is assessed. Vine quality is assessed by separated microvinifcation per treatment and site. The management of the 4 vineyards is harmonized.&#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
First results do not show differences in disease incidence. There was a tendency found for more chlorophyll in leaves where prep. 501 is applied. At two sites there was a tendency for improvement of the quality of soil aggregates where 500 is applied.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Bio-dynamic preparations in vine production: Wirkung biologisch-dynamischer Präparate in Rebbergen.  [Effect of bio-dynamic preparations in vine production.]   Runs 2003 - 2008.      Project Leader(s): Levite, Dominique and Weibel, Franco, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6410/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>