<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of catch crop type and root depth on nitrogen  leaching and yield of spring barley</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sapkota, Tek Bahadur</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lægdsmand, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen Eivind</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Catch crop root growth and nitrogen (N) uptake from both shallower and deeper soil layers is important for N management in arable farming system particularly in climates where excess winter precipitation induces N leaching. We simulated the root growth and biomass yield of three common catch crops [chicory (Cichorium intybus L.), fodder radish (Raphanus sativus L.) and perennial &#xD;
ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.)] and their effect on soil mineral N in different soil layers by using the FASSET model. The simulated results of catch crops root growth and mineral N in the soil profile were validated against two years (i.e. 2006 and 2007) of observations taken in Foulum and Flakkebjerg, Denmark. Fodder radish had the deepest root system and depleted N from deeper soil layers than &#xD;
chicory and ryegrass. The effect of these three catch crops on N leaching and grain yield of spring barley was simulated for 30 years using the FASSET model. The simulations showed that the system with ryegrass catch crop &#xD;
had a smaller amount of N leaching from 1 m depth than the system with other catch crops and without catch crops. However, estimated total N leached from 2 m soil depth was the smallest in the system with fodder radish followed by the system with chicory, indicating that these catch crops are capable for taking soil N also from below 1 m depth. On average, the system with fodder radish was estimated to decrease N leaching from 2 m depth by 79% compared with the system without catch crops, resulting in an average spring barley grain yield increase of 2%. Chicory and ryegrass &#xD;
correspondingly contributed to reducing N leaching from 2 m soil depths by 71 and 67%, but with the cost of decreasing spring barley yield by 3 and 5%, respectively, when compared with the system without catch crop. Termination of catch crop use slightly increased the spring barley yield, but also increased N leaching by about 17%. Inclusion of catch crop in the system increased the total N and C content in the soil in all cases but the increase was largest with ryegrass.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18766/1/18766.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sapkota, Tek Bahadur; Askegaard, Margrethe; Lægdsmand, Mette and Olesen, Jørgen Eivind   (2011) Effects of catch crop type and root depth on nitrogen leaching and yield of spring barley.   Field Crops Research, 125, pp. 129-138.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18766/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>