<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrogen fixation and transfer in grassclover leys under organic and conventional cropping systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bühlmann, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background and aim&#xD;
Symbiotic dinitrogen (N2) fixation is the most important external N source in organic systems. Our objective was to compare symbiotic N2 fixation of clover grown in organically and conventionally cropped grass-clover leys, while taking into account nutrient supply gradients.&#xD;
Methods&#xD;
We studied leys of a 30-year-old field experiment over 2 years in order to compare organic and conventional systems at two fertilization levels. Using 15N natural abundance methods, we determined the proportion of N derived from the atmosphere (PNdfa), the amount of Ndfa (ANdfa), and the transfer of clover N to grasses for both red clover (Trifolium pratense L.) and white clover (Trifolium repens L.). &#xD;
Results&#xD;
In all treatments and both years, PNdfa was high (83 to 91 %), indicating that the N2 fixation process is not constrained, even not in the strongly nutrient deficient non-fertilized control treatment.&#xD;
Annual ANdfa in harvested clover biomass ranged from 6 to 16 gN m−2. At typical fertilizer input levels, lower sward yield in organic than those in conventional treatments had no effect on ANdfa because of organic treatments had greater clover proportions. In two-year-old leys, on average, 51 % of N taken up by grasses was transferred from clover.&#xD;
Conclusion&#xD;
Both, organically and conventionally cropped grass-clover leys profited from symbiotic N2 fixation, with high PNdfa, and important transfer of clover N to grasses, provided sufficient potassiumand phosphorus-availability to sustain clover biomass production.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23228/1/Oberson-etal-2013-PlantansSoil-onlinefirst.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oberson, A.; Frossard, E.; Bühlmann, C.; Mayer, J.; Mäder, P. and Lüscher, A.   (2013) Nitrogen fixation and transfer in grassclover leys under organic and conventional cropping systems.   Plant and Soil,   (online),  - .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23228/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>