<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Status Quo Analyse von Dauerversuchen &#xD;
zum Ökologischer Pflanzenbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cais, Kathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rehm, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rippel, Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The research project focused on a status-quo analysis of long-term field experiments for organic farming in Germany, Austria and the German speaking part of Switzerland. The study comprised long-term field experiments with an expected minimum duration of five years. The status-quo analysis categorized the long-term field experiments into four main research fields: a) system comparison, b) production engineering, c) fertilisation and d) soil fertility and further key aspects.&#xD;
All in all, 47 long-term field experiments were identified. The four main research fields chosen were investigated in 20, 24, 27 and 46 long-term field experiments, respectively. The system comparison of the main research fields identified the major research into “conventional versus organic farming” and “organic farming: ‘stocking ratio’ versus stockless” with eight resp. twelve experiments. In production engineering research focused on “soil cultivation” with 14 experiments. Soil fertility and further key aspects, yield and humus formation/humus balance were investigated in 40 resp. 35 field experiments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21193/1/21193_Urbatzka.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, Peer; Cais, Kathrin; Rehm, Anna and Rippel, Rudolf    (2013) Status Quo Analyse von Dauerversuchen zum Ökologischer Pflanzenbau.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21193/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>