<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Report on the ECO-PB Workshop on the proposed EC Organic Seed Regime 2004</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From the Introduction to the Proceedings&#xD;
&#xD;
"The European Consortium for Organic Plant Breeding (ECO-PB) is an active network supporting the production and use of organic seeds. It sees the European Union’s Organic Seed Regime as potentially a great step forward for in the development of organic seed but is concerned about the latest discussions regarding implementation per January 1st 2004.&#xD;
&#xD;
Current European Commission proposals seem to allow a great deal of room for derogation. Seed companies are indicating that this year (2003) their organic seed sales have already dropped. Growers are aware that the probable new rules will allow derogation even for those crops for which there is sufficient, appropriate organic seeds. A number of key seed companies have announced they will definitely stop their organic programmes should the criteria for derogation remain unclear and if derogation remains possible for all crops irrespective of availability, as it becomes financially unviable. That is a real threat and would be a great setback for ongoing efforts to build up a healthy organic seed sector and hence further close the organic production chain.&#xD;
&#xD;
Furthermore, we have received much feedback about national authorities which are tentative about how to&#xD;
tackle the national implementation of the new seed regulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
ECO-PB has therefore decided to organise at short notice a WORKSHOP on the ORGANIC SEED Regime 2004 to help clarify the above issues. We aim to facilitate an international discussion with key national players to exchange valuable information and concerns, and to establish common points of view on the organic seed regime in the organic sector on international level. The workshop will tie into discussions held and decisions made in the Article 14 Committee of the European Commission on April 4-6."</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ECO-PB European Consortium for Organic Plant Breeding</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lammerts van Bueren, E. T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wilbois, Klaus-Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2930/1/wilbois-2003-ecopb-workshop-report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lammerts van Bueren, E. T. and Wilbois, Klaus-Peter (Eds.)      (2003) Report on the ECO-PB Workshop on the proposed EC Organic Seed Regime 2004.     ECO-PB European Consortium for Organic Plant Breeding.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2930/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>