<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>COREPIG, final report of WP3: Development and evaluation of a HACCP based surveillance and management system</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmer repeatedly face problems with suckling piglet mortality, weaning diarrhoea, en-doparasites and farrowing/reproduction. These problems are multifactorial, they are caused by many factors whereby the key factors often differ from farm to farm. Thus, it was the aim of the 3rd work package of Corepig to develop a management tool based on the HACCP (hazard anal-ysis critical control points) principle, which can be used by farmers, advisers and veterinarians to solve health problems on organic pig farms.&#xD;
Several teams of experts for organic pig production including advisers and researchers created four risk assessment protocols, one each for suckling piglet mortality, weaning diarrhoea, endo-parasites and farrowing/reproduction problems. As the lists of possible risk factors are long and complex, the assessment protocols were incorporated into semi-automated MS Excel® files. The tools were tested on 32 farms in Austria, Denmark, France and Germany, where risks for the four problem areas could but reduced on 72% of farms. Farmers as well as advisers acknowledged the HACCP based management tools as valuable helps for organic pig produc-tion.&#xD;
The revised tools and their descriptions can be downloaded from the project homepage at http://www.coreorganic.org/research/projects/corepig/index.html (to be launched 01.09.2011).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Dippel, Sabine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Møllegaard Knage-Rasmussen, Kristian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19312/4/19312.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dippel, Sabine and Møllegaard Knage-Rasmussen, Kristian (Eds.)    (2011) COREPIG, final report of WP3: Development and evaluation of a HACCP based surveillance and management system.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19312/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>