<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of organic growing systems on sensory quality and chemical composition of tomatoes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thybo, Anette K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edelenbos, Merete</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, Lars P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Jørn Nygaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Tomato plants were grown in open beds, confined beds, or combined beds with compost based on clover grass hay, deep litter and peat. Due to only minor effects of growing systems on sensory quality and chemical composition of tomato fruits is was concluded that it is possible to produce tomato fruits in confined and combined soil bed systems without any loss in eating quality. Actually the results indicate, that a slight increase in quality of tomatoes from the confined and combined systems is obtained. The present result points to the fact that confined and combined growing systems may be new relevant commercial growing systems, in which the quality of tomatoes seems to be ensured, and in which nutrient loss and root diseases contamination can be reduced.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier Ltd.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4657/1/Tomato_growing_systems.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thybo, Anette K.; Edelenbos, Merete; Christensen, Lars P.; Sørensen, Jørn Nygaard and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian   (2006) Effect of organic growing systems on sensory quality and chemical composition of tomatoes.   Journal of Food Science and Technology, 39, pp. 835-843.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4657/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>