<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A localised development of organic farming as a response to the problem of water quality: a new challenge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vincent, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fleury, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Initiatives aiming at developing organic farming (OF) to meet water quality stakes are increasing. This article is a comparative study of four such projects. It is based on semi-structured interviews. Two logics for public action are implemented to foster the development of OF in areas facing water quality problems. The first one aims at concentrating actions in water sensitive areas. The main tool that is then mobilized is the use of localized agri-environmental measures supporting conversion to organic farming. The second logic aims at implementing actions for organic development at a geographical scale considered as relevant for developing OF and differing from water sensitive areas. The main actions that are then activated are coordination, consciousness-raising about OF for agricultural stakeholders and structuring of processing and distribution chains for organic products. Our result showed that the actor networks differ according to local contexts, project leaders, and objectives. They tended to expand and become more complex over time. This explains why such projects are difficult and slow to put in place. Nevertheless, water conservation has now become an asset for the development of OF. This entails reconsidering the theoretical development models for OF, thus enriching them with a territorial dimension.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26784/1/Vincent_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vincent, A and Fleury, Philippe   (2013) A localised development of organic farming as a response to the problem of water quality: a new challenge.  [Le développement territorialisé de l’AB pour protéger la qualité de l’eau : Un nouvel enjeu.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 497-508.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26784/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>