<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fresh and residual phosphorus uptake by ryegrass from soils with different fertilization histories</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tagmann, Hans U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langmeier, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming largely depends on animal manure as a source of phosphorus (P) and the recycling of animal manure globally is becoming increasingly important. In a pot experiment, using radioactive P labeling techniques, we studied ryegrass uptake of P applied with animal manure and water soluble mineral fertilizer to soils that had been cropped for 22 years according to organic or conventional farming practices. The soils differed in P status and microbial activity. Labeling soil-available P also allowed assessing the uptake from residual P that remained in the soils because of their different fertilization histories. On each soil, recovery of fresh manure P in four harvests of ryegrass shoots was lower than recovery of mineral P. It ranged from 24% to 35% for manure P and from 37% to 43% for mineral P. Recovery of fresh manure P was affected by soil-available P contents. It was lower at a higher available P in a conventional soil. Different levels in microbial activity among soils were of lesser importance for the recovery of fresh manure P in plants. The recovery of residual P ranged from9%to 15%. Residual P contained in organic cropped soils contributed less to P nutrition of ryegrass than the residual P contained in conventional cropped soils, probably due to their lower residual P contents being composed of stable P forms. The indirect isotope dilution technique is useful in assessing manure P uptake by plants, but attention must be given to added P interactions, i.e., the potential impact of organic amendments on P uptake from nonlabeled soil and residual P.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-04-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25683/1/Oberson%20et%20al%202010%20PlantSoil%20P%20fertilizers%20DOK%20soils.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oberson, Astrid; Tagmann, Hans U.; Langmeier, Monika; Dubois, David; Mäder, Paul and Frossard, Emmanuel   (2010) Fresh and residual phosphorus uptake by ryegrass from soils with different fertilization histories.   Plant and Soil, 334, pp. 391-407.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25683/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>