<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrate leaching in crop rotations with grass-clover as influenced by sward age, grazing, cutting and fertilizer regimes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Grazing animals have profound effects on pastoral systems including nutrient removal by grazing and redistribution through excreta. Generally, in grazed pastures the conversion of consumed N into product is low and a substantial quantity of N (&gt;70%) is recycled through the direct deposition of animal excreta. This low N utilization by grazing animals reflects the relatively high concentrations of N required for metabolic functions and optimum growth of plants compared to that needed by the grazing ruminant for amino acid and protein synthesis (Haynes and Williams, 1993). Increasing the N concentration in grass, such as by increasing the rate of N fertiliser application, can result in a substantial N surplus (i.e. N inputs – N outputs in products). For example, N surpluses of 150 to 250 kg N ha-1 yr-1 occur in highly productive dairy farm systems in the Netherlands and northern Germany (Rotz et al., 2005).  Grazing cattle return N in urine patches at rates of up to about 1000 kg N ha-1, which is far in excess of plant requirements (Haynes and Williams, 1993). Urine N is in highly mineralisable forms compared to dung N, and within 3-5 days is rapidly converted to plant-available N in soil. This can result in inorganic soil N under urine patches up to 10 times greater than under dung patches, and more than 30 times greater than areas unaffected by excreta (Afzal and Adams, 1992).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20637/4/20637.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J.; Askegaard, M. and Søegaard, K.   (2012) Nitrate leaching in crop rotations with grass-clover as influenced by sward age, grazing, cutting and fertilizer regimes.   Agriculture, Ecosystems and Environment,  , pp. 1-12.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>