<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control methods for Dermanyssus gallinae in systems for laying hens: results of an international seminar</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mul, M.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Niekerk, Thea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chirico, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kilpinen, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sparagano, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thind, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zoons, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moore, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bell, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gjevre, A.-G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chauve, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper reports the results of a seminar on poultry red mite (PRM), Dermanyssus gallinae. Eighteen researchers from eight European countries discussed life cycle issues of the mite, effects of mites on hens and egg production, and monitoring and control methods for PRM in poultry facilities. It was determined that PRM probably causes more damage than envisaged, with the cost in The Netherlands&#xD;
alone reaching 11 million euro per annum. However a great deal is still unknown about PRM (e.g. reproduction, survival methods, etc.) and that PRM monitoring is an important instrument in recognising and admitting the problem and in taking timely measures. Currently, the most promising control method combines heating the hen house in combination with chemical treatments. Future areas of development which show promise include the use of entomopathogenic fungi, vaccination and predatory mites. The final aim is to solve the problem of D. gallinae in housing systems for laying hens.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19930/1/Mul_et_al_2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mul, M.F.; van Niekerk, Thea; Chirico, J.; Maurer, Veronika; Kilpinen, O.; Sparagano, O.; Thind, B.; Zoons, J.; Moore, D.; Bell, B.; Gjevre, A.-G. and Chauve, C.   (2009) Control methods for Dermanyssus gallinae in systems for laying hens: results of an international seminar.   World's Poultry Science Journal, 65, pp. 589-600.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19930/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>