<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of software to plan conversion to organic production (OrgPlan)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tzilivakis, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Measures, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stockdale, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. OrgPlan is a computer programme aimed at farmers and advisors assisting with the planning of an organic conversion. The programme is divided into technical modules, supported by a standard enterprise database, a report builder and an advisory section. Through the farm profile builder, rotation, cropping and livestock planner, conversion scenarios over several years can be developed and are evaluated for technical and financial feasibility by calculating farm gate budgets for key resources (forage energy and key nutrients) and financial reports (cash flow budget and profit and loss account). The poster illustrates the basic functioning of the software as well as the underlying rationale for the scenario evaluation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8388/1/padel_orgplan_conversion_software.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne; Tzilivakis, John; Measures, Mark; Stockdale, Elizabeth and Watson, Christine    (2002) Development of software to plan conversion to organic production (OrgPlan).   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 169-172.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8388/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>