<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECTS OF ORGANIC FERTILIZERS ON THE SEED GERMINATION AND SEEDLING VIGOUR OF TOMATO</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alam, M. K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahim, M.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahman, M.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahiruddin, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pot experiment was conducted to evaluate the efficiency of different organic fertilizers on germination and early growth of tomato seedling. Four different types of compost like trichocompost, vermicompost, kitchen waste compost, cow dung based bioslurry and soil (control) were used as treatment.  Organic fertilizers except kitchen waste compost significantly influenced germination and other growth parameters of tomato seedling in comparison with control treatment. Trichocompost showed the better performance in all parameters which was followed vermicompost in most cases. The poor performance exhibited by kitchen waste compost might be due to the presence of heavy metal like lead and copper which inhibit the emergence of tomato seed and thereafter on different parameters of tomato seedling.  Overall, trichocompost and vermicompost could be used as potting media for growing healthy tomato seedling while kitchen waste compost may be discourage to use as potting media for vegetable seedling production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23990/1/23990_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alam, M. K.; Rahim, M.A.; Rahman, M.H. and Jahiruddin, M.    (2014) EFFECTS OF ORGANIC FERTILIZERS ON THE SEED GERMINATION AND SEEDLING VIGOUR OF TOMATO.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 49-52.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23990/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>