<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Vegetable Storage in Wales – Opportunities and Constraints</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Diepen, Pauline</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a growing interest in buying local produce, but there is insufficient produce available in Wales to meet this demand. One problem is lack of storage. Much organic vegetable produce in Wales is lost by poor storage. ADAS has undertaken this study on behalf of Organic Centre Wales under the Farming Connect Scheme, to assess opportunities for improving storage and increasing the available quantity of Welsh vegetables.&#xD;
The number of organic vegetable producers in Wales in 2006 was estimated to be 118 (Horticultural Network, 2006).&#xD;
The main crops stored in Wales are potatoes, carrots, squash, onions, cabbage and celeriac. Many factors may contribute directly or indirectly to suitability for storage, these include length of life in store and quality of the crops in store.&#xD;
Costs of storage are perceived to be high but investment in storage facilities can increase turnover and maximise marketable potential. The majority of growers in Wales use field storage due to its simplicity, but there are disadvantages to field storage.&#xD;
Alternatives to field storage include indoor and outdoor clamps and cold storage. Each method has advantages and disadvantages.&#xD;
&#xD;
Recommendations&#xD;
• A joint effort by the whole organic fruit and vegetable industry is required to increase the amount of organic produce produced within Wales.&#xD;
• Processing and Marketing grants for improvement of storage for SME and or cooperatives are required to increase the amount of local produce produced and sold in Wales.&#xD;
• Research is needed into the economic feasibility and issues involved with setting up and running storage facilities using alternative energy&#xD;
• The practicalities and costs of using biodegradables needs to be investigated&#xD;
• Best storage practices should be established</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11075/2/Organic_Vegetable_Storage.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Diepen, Pauline         (2007) Organic Vegetable Storage in Wales – Opportunities and Constraints.    Organic Centre Wales, University of Wales, Aberystwyth and ADAS Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11075/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>