<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pro-Q: Strategien zur Verbesserung der Eutergesundheit und Minimierung des Antibiotikaeinsatzes in schweizerischen Biomilchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heil, Fritz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Notz, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spranger, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Data of mastitis causing factors will be collected on 100 new farms per year in Switzerland: housing, feeding, human-animal-interaction, milking technology, milking hygiene. These data will be connected to the mastitis status of the herd based on quarter milk samples and milk recording data. During a period of at least 2 years these farms will be intensively advised by the project team and their practical veterinarians. Therapies will primarily be based on homeopathic remedies. The development of mastitis causing factors and the mastitis status of the farms is followed up at regular intervals to show possible correlations between (changing) factors and mastitis status. In addition, a network of health data should be implemented for providing information for farmers and veterinarians in preventive herd health management. The aims of the project are reduction in the use of antibiotics in udder treatment, improvement of the udder health state of the herds and, as a consequence, improvement of milk quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3876/1/3876.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Walkenhorst, Michael; Heil, Fritz; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Klocke, Peter; Notz, Christophe and Spranger, Jörg    (2005) Pro-Q: Strategien zur Verbesserung der Eutergesundheit und Minimierung des Antibiotikaeinsatzes in schweizerischen Biomilchviehbetrieben.  [Pro-Q: Strategies for improving udder health and minimizing the use of antibiotics in swiss organic dairy herds.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3876/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>