<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparing Fertilization Regims Under Three Onion Farming Systems in a Semiarid Tropical area</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Perez, Martha-Cecilia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ramirez-Guerrero, Hugo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An experiment at the University experimental station  at Cabudare, Venezuela compared six fertilization regimes in three onion (Allium cepa L.) production systems (two organic (OS), two integrated (IS) and two conventional (CS) systems), for their effects on crop growth, productivity, and soil properties. Fertilization regimes (two per system) consisted of (i) 3 Mg ha-1 sugarcane filtercake compost (fc) (OSfc), (ii) 3 Mg ha-1 chicken manure compost (chm) (OSchm), (iii) 0.6 Mg ha-1 mineral compound fertilizer (mf) (CSmf), (iv) without any fertilizer (nf) (CSnf), (v) mf + chm (ISchm), and (vi) mf + chm + fc (ISchmfc). Additionally, farming systems included nonchemical (OS), chemical (CS) and integrated pest management. Results indicated that the onion growth and productivity was higher from plots managed under integrated systems (mainly ISchm). However, when comparing the effect on soil properties, differences were not found. The organic onion production in the semiarid area was highly productive during the dry season studied</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4444/4/Perez_etal_onion_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Perez, Martha-Cecilia and Ramirez-Guerrero, Hugo    (2005) Comparing Fertilization Regims Under Three Onion Farming Systems in a Semiarid Tropical area.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4444/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>