<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Below-harvest biomass and N2 fixation in grass-clover at different cutting frequencies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vinther, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The below-harvest nitrogen accumulating in stubble, stolons and roots is an important com-ponent in the N balance and the potential N losses in grass-clover cropping systems. The effects of cutting frequency on the total dry matter, total nitrogen and N2 fixation, including contributions from below-harvest production, were studied. In a greenhouse experiment with red and white clover plants, cutting reduced the above-ground dry matter production by 56-62% and the below-ground by 68-73%, compared to uncut plants. Similarly, in a two-year field study with ryegrass-white clover, simulated grazing reduced the harvested dry matter production by 6-19% and the below-harvest, i.e., stubble, stolons and roots, by 20-35% com-pared to normally mowed grass-clover. Thus, the results from both the greenhouse and the field study indicated that below-ground or below-harvest production was more affected by cutting or simulated grazing than harvested production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Uppsala</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Frankow-Lindenberg, B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4163/1/4163.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vinther, F.P.    (2005) Below-harvest biomass and N2 fixation in grass-clover at different cutting frequencies.    In: Frankow-Lindenberg, B. (Ed.)   Adaption and Management of Forage Legumes - Strategies for improved Reliability in mixed Swards.  Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Uppsala, pp. 187-190.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4163/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>