<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumption of Organic Foods from a Life History&#xD;
Perspective:An Explorative Study among Italian consumers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Naspetti, Simona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bracchi, Luca</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Taking into consideration individuals’ cognitive reasoning, and assuming that consumption of organic food has involved a change of mind about food experiences and food habits, we have identified the concepts, stories and theories mentioned by respondents in their discourses about organic food. Regular consumers trust organic products because they believe that they are healthier and tastier than any other product. A growing stock of information supports their food choice and confidence in organic food. Occasional consumers have strong beliefs about the better taste and the higher quality of organic food in general. Non organic users sometimes perceive organic food as a new fashion, the last fad. Organic food is still confused with close ‘substitutes’, such as ‘natural’, ‘macrobiotic’ and similar products. &#xD;
Many occasional consumers believe that regular consumers are somewhat obsessed with organic food and that they look and behave strangely. Organic products are generally perceived and experienced as expensive products, when compared to conventional alternatives. To organic consumer the rewards they perceive to gain from organic food is well beyond the resources (in terms of time and money) they employ to search for the higher quality of organic products. Institutional attempts to change consumer behaviour are commonly categorized into consumer information, consumer education and consumer advice (Peter et al., 1999).In order to increase both behavioural and attitudinal loyalty, the level of consumer information and product knowledge should be increased. Besides, consumers will become more committed if their beliefs regarding the intrinsic self-relevance of organic food will increase in the future.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15188/1/Exploring_the_Development_of_Organic_Consumption_in_Italy_2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Naspetti, Simona; Zanoli, Raffaele and Bracchi, Luca         (2008) Consumption of Organic Foods from a Life History Perspective:An Explorative Study among Italian consumers.    Università Politecnica delle Marche, Dipartimento di Ingegneria e in formatica Gestionale - DIIGA.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15188/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>