<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Conversion to Organic Farming: A typical example of the diffusion of an innovation?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper reviews a wide range of studies of organic farmers published over the last 20 years using the framework of adoption/diffusion. The model that was developed by rural sociologists in the US and was the main guiding theory for the development of agricultural extension work. After a summary of the adoption/diffusion model and a short description of organic farming and its development in Europe, many similarities in personal and social characteristics of organic farmers in earlier and later studies with innovators and early adopters, particularly of environmental innovations are identified. The comparison of the characteristics of organic farming with other innovations shows differences, some of which have been used to develop some recommendations how the wider diffusion of organic farming could be supported but the limitations of the adoption model have to be considered.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3976/1/Padel_2001_adoption.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne   (2001) Conversion to Organic Farming: A typical example of the diffusion of an innovation?   Sociologia Ruralis, 40 (1), pp. 40-61.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3976/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>