<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of cultivar and soil characteristics on nutritional value in organic and conventional wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Murphy, Dr. Kevin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoagland, Dr. Lori</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reeves, Dr. Philip</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Dr. Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Evidence of greater nutritional value in organic crops is currently a subject of intense debate. Our objectives in this study were to test for grain mineral concentration in 35 winter wheat cultivars in paired organic and conventional systems, and to determine the influence of cultivar, soil characteristics and farming system on mineral concentration.  Here we report preliminary results that show that the grain mineral concentration in organic wheat was higher for copper (Cu), magnesium (Mg), manganese (Mn), phosphorus (P) and zinc (Zn) and lower in calcium (Ca), than the grain mineral concentration in conventional wheat. No difference was found between systems for iron (Fe) concentration.  Cultivar was significant in determining mineral concentration for Ca, Cu, Mg, Mn and P.  Soil mineral concentration was not responsible for grain mineral concentration, with the exception of P.  The organic wheat farming systems had higher grain mineral concentrations of Cu, Mg, Mn, P and Zn than the conventional systems, possibly due in part to increased soil organic matter and pH in the organic systems.  Growing specific cultivars capable of exploiting particular soil conditions may be necessary in order to optimize the nutritional value in organic farming systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12397/1/12397.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Murphy, Dr. Kevin; Hoagland, Dr. Lori; Reeves, Dr. Philip and Jones, Dr. Stephen    (2008) Effect of cultivar and soil characteristics on nutritional value in organic and conventional wheat.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12397/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>