<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Impact of Site and Management Factors on Humus Dynamics in Long-term Field Experiments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brock, Christopher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of management and environmental site factors on quantitative and qualitative indicators of humus dynamics was investigated in eight long-term field experiments in Germany and neighbouring countries. Humus dynamics were basically influenced by environmental site conditions, but at a given site differences between farming systems could be ascerted. Mixed farming systems with farmyard manure application as a rule had a more favourable impact on humus dynamics than stockless systems. Whether an advantageous performance of humus dynamics in organic farming as compared to conventional farming will occur or not, is dependent on the respective farm types of both systems that are related to each other.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12536/1/Brock_12536_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brock, Christopher and Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter    (2008) The Impact of Site and Management Factors on Humus Dynamics in Long-term Field Experiments.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12536/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>