<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production of compost of high quality from bovine wastes and organic olive and vineyard wastes.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>MAMEN, Nassima</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the thesis was to prepare high quality compost in two different piles from a basis of bovine animal manure charged with olive wastes or viticulture residues, in accordance with the Italian law on the fertilizers (Law n.748/1984 - art. 1c). All the raw materials have been selected from a group of organic farms in Apulia region. The plant residues have been crushed and the bovine animal manure has been prepared before preparing the mixture. Two piles of about 30 tons have been prepared with different composition. The first heap had the following composition: 60 % of bovine animal manure and 40% olive wastes, the second one 70 % of manure and 30% vineyard wastes. In order to produce quality compost chemical and physical analyses have been carried out in different stages of the compost production.  Analyses explained the difference between the two piles, the evolution of the mineral elements (including heavy metals) and the evolution occurring to the organic matter. The compost cycle (90 days) has been monitored during the two main phases (active and curing phase)  measuring temperature, pH, moisture, oxygen and C/N ratio. At the end of the cycle, the quality of compost has been evaluated by doing, both on manure and plant wastes, the following analyses : PH, Ashes, EC, Salts, Total Organic Carbon, Total nitrogen (N), C/N ratio, total Phosphorous (p), total Potassium, level of heavy metals in the two piles. Differences between the final composition of each pile and the possible applications into the soil have been taken into account.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6866/1/nassima04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>MAMEN, Nassima   (2004) Production of compost of high quality from bovine wastes and organic olive and vineyard wastes.  [Production de compost de haute qualité à partir de déchets bovins, oléicoles et viticoles biologiques.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 347. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6866/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>