<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Arbeitszeitbedarf für die Betreuung von Biogasanlagen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wagner, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Juschkat, Michaela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heitkämper, Katja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stadelmann, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartmann, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schick, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The working time requirement for different methods of biogas production forms the basis for a full cost calculation as well as for the planning of working capacities in biogas plant management. The aim of this study is to quantify the time requirement under different conditions. An ergonomic analysis was carried out for ten biogas model plants which differed in terms of gas utilisation and installed capacity as well as of substrate usage (energy feedstock and mass) and plant size. The results of the model calculations yielded a total working time requirement of between 679 and 2,140 MPh/year for the ten model plants from an electrical output of 75 kW to a gas supply of 700 m3 under normal conditions. The time required for feeding a plant increases in proportion to the mass and the number of different stackable substrates, low substrate bulk density also increases the time requirement. Daily tours of inspection include process monitoring, silo and fermenter sampling. The required time depends on the distances covered, which increase with plant size. Maintenance work also increases with plant size. Feeding and plant management jobs account for the largest share of total working time requirement.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21419/1/21419_Wagner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wagner, Andrea; Juschkat, Michaela; Heitkämper, Katja; Stadelmann, Monika; Hartmann, Stefan and Schick, Matthias    (2013) Arbeitszeitbedarf für die Betreuung von Biogasanlagen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21419/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>