<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of selection pressure exerted on Plasmopara viticola by organically based fungicides</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Matasci, C.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gobbin, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stutz, Ch.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gessler, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>Downy mildew is one of the most important grape diseases world-wide. The pathogen is a genetically highly diversified organism with a high capacity of adaptation. A monitoring of changes in population structure of P. viticola subjected to new copper replacing products or strategies, studied and developed within REPCO (Replacement of Copper Fungicides in Organic Production of Grapevine and Apple in Europe) is important for assessing selection pressure which could lead to a reduction of efficacy of these new measures. Therefore P. viticola lesions collected on untreated and treated vines were analyzed by means of microsatellite markers. No significant differences in the populations structure were determined among untreated and treated populations, indicating that the applied products didn’t exerted any selection pressure on the P. viticola populations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8212/1/Matasci.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Matasci, C.L.; Gobbin, D.; Stutz, Ch. and Gessler, C.    (2006) Analysis of selection pressure exerted on Plasmopara viticola by organically based fungicides.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8212/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>