<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Plant genetic resources in mountain oases of northern Oman</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gebauer, Dr. Jens</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luedeling, M.Sc. Eike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hammer, Prof. Dr. Karl</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buerkert, Prof. Dr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study we assessed the genetic resources of three mountain oases in the al-Hajar range using a GIS-based field survey and farmer interviews. While arid conditions prevail throughout the mountain range, the different elevations of the oases in the Jabal al Akhdar mountains provide markedly differing agro-climatic conditions. Overall, 107 different crop species were identified belonging to 39 families. Species number was highest among fruits (33 spp.), followed by vegetables (24 spp.). Intensive irrigation allows cultivation of a broad range of species at all oases. However, the number of species varied significantly among sites. Fruit species diversity and homogeneity of the distribution of individual fruit species was highest at Balad Seet and lowest at Maqta, as indicated by respective Shannon indices of 1.00 and 0.39 and evenness values of 32% and 16%. Century plant, faba bean and lentil were identified as relict crops, supporting oral reports of past cultivation and providing evidence of genetic erosion. Overall greatest species similarity was found between Balad Seet and Al Jabal al Akhdar, as indicated by a Sørensen coefficient of similarity of 67%. Overall the study shows a location-specific but surprisingly diverse mosaic of crops in Omani mountain oases that merits further studies and conservation efforts.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11900/1/Gebauer_11900_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gebauer, Dr. Jens; Luedeling, M.Sc. Eike; Hammer, Prof. Dr. Karl and Buerkert, Prof. Dr. Andreas    (2008) Plant genetic resources in mountain oases of northern Oman.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11900/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>