<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Use of Reynoutr;a sachalinens;s plant extracts, clay preparations and Brev;bacillus brev;s against fungal diseases of grape berries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmitt, Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kunz, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nandi, Sunil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seddon, Barrie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ernst, Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>R. sachalinensis plant extracts (Milsana&lt;l!», clay preparations and B. brevis were tested lor control 01 powdery and downy mildew and grey mould in organically grown grapes over three years. Milsana&lt;l!&gt; was in ali trials as effective against U. necator as sulphur, even in years with very high disease pressure. The plant extract showed also positive effects in Botrytis control. Myco-Sin&lt;l!&gt; was in ali trials as effective in controlling P. viticola as the copper containing agent FW 450. The combination 01 Milsana&lt;l!&gt;, Myco-Sin&lt;l!&gt; and B. brevis revealed the potential 01 B. brevis lor control 01 B. cinerea in grape berries, and indicated additional positive effects towards the contro I 01 U. necator. The combined use 01 these biological control agents shows strong potential lor replacement 01 copper and sulphur in organic viticulture.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14617/1/schmitt_146.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmitt, Annegret; Kunz, Stefan; Nandi, Sunil; Seddon, Barrie and Ernst, Annegret    (2002) Use of Reynoutr;a sachalinens;s plant extracts, clay preparations and Brev;bacillus brev;s against fungal diseases of grape berries.  [Verwendung von Pflanzenextrakten aus Reynoutria sachalinensis, Gesteinsmehlen und Brevibacillus brevis gegen pilzliche Krankheiten an Weintrauben.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 146-151.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14617/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>