<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ochratoxin A producing Penicillium verrucosum isolates from cereals reveal large AFLP fingerprinting variability</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frisvad, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lund, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elmholt, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Aims: To examine if molecular amplified fragment length polymorphism (AFLP) fingerprinting of the only ochratoxin A-producing species in European cereals, Penicillium verrucosum, can be used as a method in hazard analysis using critical control points (HACCP). &#xD;
Methods and Results: A total of 321 isolates of P. verrucosum were isolated from ochratoxin A contaminated cereals from Denmark (oats), UK (wheat and barley) and Sweden (wheat). Of these, 236 produced ochratoxin A as determined by thin layer chromatography; 185 ochratoxin A-producing isolates were selected for AFLP fingerprinting. A total of 138 isolates had unique AFLP patterns, whereas 52 isolates could be allocated to small groups containing from two to four isolates with similar AFLP patterns. A total of 155 clones were found among the 185 P. verrucosum isolates, thus 84 % of the isolates may represent different genets of P. verrucosum. As the few isolates that were grouped often came from the same farm, and those groups that contained AFLP-identical isolates from different countries were morphotypically different. On single farms up to 35 clones were found. The few groups of ramets from the same genet indicated that a HACCP approach based on clones may require a very large number of AFLP analysis to work in practice, we recommend basing the HACCP approach on the actual species P. verrucosum. A more detailed characterization should rather be based on the profile of species present at different control points, or analysis of the mycotoxins ochratoxin A and citrinin in the isolates. Examination of 86 isolates with HPLC and diode array detection of P. verrucosum showed that 66% produced ochratoxin A, 87% produced citrinin, 92% produced verrucin and 100% produced verrucolone.&#xD;
Conclusions: Among 184 ochratoxin A-producing Penicillium verrucosum, 155 clonal lineages were indicated by AFLP fingerprinting, indicating a high genetical diversity, yet the species P. verrucosum is phenotypically distinct and valid. &#xD;
Significance and Impact of the Study: AFLP fingerprinting of Penicillium verrucosum indicates that genetic recombination takes place in this fungus.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7392/1/7392.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Frisvad, J.C.; Lund, F. and Elmholt, S.   (2005) Ochratoxin A producing Penicillium verrucosum isolates from cereals reveal large AFLP fingerprinting variability.  [.]  Journal of Applied Microbiology, 98, pp. 684-692.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7392/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>