<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Professional transmission in organic farming: how to understand each other and learn at word</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chrétien, Fanny</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The transmission of farmers’ skills and profession is not limited to transfers of knowledge or technical references, even if these are necessary to professionalise future farmers. Professional transmission refers more broadly to complex work situations involving persons, objects (within the meanings of artefact and intentionality) and particular conditions. These situations of transmission, during working activities, are produced by the articulation between three dimensions: 1/individual forms of involvement (in working, in learning and in transmission processes), 2/exposure to difficulties and challenges in working activities and interactions requiring new solutions, and finally 3/historical and sociological specificities of practices and areas. This article proposes to defend a method that analyses various forms of professional transmission in agriculture, considering these three dimensions. The last part aims to illustrate this method through a case of an organic farm transmission in the Alsace region.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26230/1/Chretien_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chrétien, Fanny   (2013) Professional transmission in organic farming: how to understand each other and learn at word.  [La transmission professionnelle en agriculture biologique, ou comment à la fois se comprendre et apprendre.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 297-316.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26230/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>