<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison of traditional and genomic breeding programs for organic and low input dairy cattle accounting for traits relevant in different macro-climatic zones</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frevert, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yin, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simianer, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>König, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the past decade, successful selection on production traits for dairy cattle has greatly increased milk production. Recently, selection indices for female fertility were gradually and increasingly introduced into the overall breeding goals for dairy cattle (Miglior et al., 2005).&#xD;
As a by-product of fermention in ruminants, enteric methane emissions (ME) should also be controlled and mitigated due to their contribution to global warming (Forster et al., 2007) and as a cause for inefficient use of dietary energy.&#xD;
Moderate heritabilities ranging between 0.30 and 0.35 for predicted and real measurements of ME were reported for dairy cows and ewe lambs (de Haas et al., 2011; Pinares-Patiño et al., 2011), indicating that a heritable component for ME is available for implementing sustainable breeding strategies to reduce ME in dairy farms. In dairy cattle production systems, the traditional progeny testing substantially increases accuracy of selection especially for bulls.&#xD;
However, availability of high-density SNP arrays enable dairy cattle breeders to apply genomic selection in their breeding strategies. Consequently, the objective of this study was to compare selection response for a complex breeding goal comprising ME, milk yield (MY), days open (DO), clinical mastitis (CM), body condition score (BCS) and milking temperament (MT) and total discounted return for organic and low input dairy cattle (with organic Brown Swiss as an example) from progeny testing and genomic breeding program by applying ZPLAN+ (Täubert et al., 2010).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26639/1/Frevert-etal-2014-paper-lowinputbreeds-dairy-cattle.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Frevert, H.; Yin, T.; Simianer, H. and König, S.    (2014) Comparison of traditional and genomic breeding programs for organic and low input dairy cattle accounting for traits relevant in different macro-climatic zones.    Working paper.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26639/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>