<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of animal health and welfare planning on medicine use, herd health and production in European organic dairy farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gratzer, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Britt I. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejdell, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nicholas, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stöger, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whistance, L.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A reduction of medicine use (udder treatments, metabolic treatments and total number of treatments) in organic dairy herds was achieved within a time period of one year under different conditions across seven European countries. At the same time an improvement of udder health (SCS) and a stable situation in other health areas (metabolic disorders, fertility) was found, however regardless of the focus area in the AHWP. The AHWP process which was implemented on the farms may therefore be regarded a feasible approach to minimise medicine use without impairment of health, longevity and productivity under most European organic dairy farming conditions. However, further long-term studies are necessary to investigate effects of specific advice included in herd health and welfare plans.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-12-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25608/1/Ivemeyer2012inpress%20ANIPLAN.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivemeyer, Silvia; Smolders, G.; Brinkmann, J.; Gratzer, E.; Hansen, B.; Henriksen, Britt I. F.; Huber, J.; Leeb, C.; March, S.; Mejdell, C.; Nicholas, P; Roderick, S; Stöger, E.; Vaarst, M.; Whistance, L.K.; Winckler, C. and Walkenhorst, Dr. Michael   (2011) Impact of animal health and welfare planning on medicine use, herd health and production in European organic dairy farms.   Livestock Science, XXX, pp. 1-10.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25608/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>