<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SOIL QUALITY AND CROP PRODUCTIVITY AS AFFECTED BY DIFFERENT SOIL MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS IN ORGANIC AGRICULTURE "TILMAN-ORG Session"</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Willekens, Koen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vandecasteele, Bart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Vliegher, Alex</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A multi-year trial was conducted to compare soil management strategies (tillage and fertilization) with regard to their effect on crop performance and soil quality. Two soil management systems were assessed. Farm compost application was combined with reduced non-inversion tillage, whereas animal manure was incorporated by conventional tillage with a moldboard plough. With regard to soil quality, a reduced tillage practice in combination with compost application seemed to be favorable for soil quality of the surface layer in the short term. With regard to crop productivity, an effect of soil management strategy is less clear and dependent on a seasonal variation of growth circumstances.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24081/1/24081_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willekens, Koen; Vandecasteele, Bart and De Vliegher, Alex    (2014) SOIL QUALITY AND CROP PRODUCTIVITY AS AFFECTED BY DIFFERENT SOIL MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS IN ORGANIC AGRICULTURE "TILMAN-ORG Session".   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 65-68.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24081/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>