<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THINKING ALOUD ABOUT SUSTAINABLE AQUACULTURE PRODUCTS: CONSUMER PERCEPTIONS AND BARRIERS TO COMMUNICATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Korn, Antje</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Janssen, Meike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aquaculture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainable methods of aquaculture have evolved as a response to negative impacts of overfishing of the oceans and problems associated with conventional aquaculture. The German fish market is characterised by a multitude of different labels and claims for sustainable production and fishing methods. However, little is known about how consumers in Germany evaluate and interpret the different food labels and claims of sustainably produced aquaculture products. This paper presents results of think aloud protocols about consumers’ fish-buying decision making and in-depth interviews on consumer preferences for different sustainability labels and claims. Results indicate that not only product attributes, e.g. Origin, Production methods, Organic production, and the sensory Taste of the fish product were relevant for the consumers, but also Skepticism and a Lack of knowledge about procedures of aquaculture were important. When asked to evaluate the sustainability of the products, the organic labels were the most recognized and trusted sources of information. The sustainability claims presented in the in-depth interviews were mainly rejected as being too imprecise. In order to communicate the value of sustainable aquaculture products the knowledge gap between consumers and producers about the production processes needs to be closed. Consumers prefer local aquaculture production and a clear labeling of the product origin. Communication should therefore include information about the origin of the aquaculture product and, at best, the whole production chain. All information on product packages should be easily accessible to consumers. Claims about sustainability should be precise and certification schemes must be trustworthy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23819/1/23819_Korn_owc_scientific%20track_2014_SUSTAINABLE%20AQUACULTURE%20PRODUCTS_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Korn, Antje and Janssen, Meike    (2014) THINKING ALOUD ABOUT SUSTAINABLE AQUACULTURE PRODUCTS: CONSUMER PERCEPTIONS AND BARRIERS TO COMMUNICATION.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 395-398.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23819/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>