<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Plant biomass nitrogen and effects on the risk of nitrate leaching of intercrops under organic farming in Eastern Austria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Farthofer, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, J. K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pietsch, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rinnhofer, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loiskandl, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Data on the potential of intercrops to reduce soil nitrate contents, on their N accumulation and biological nitrogen fixation (BNF) are lacking for organic farming in the dry, pannonic region of Eastern Austria. The effect of legumes, non-legumes, and legumes + non-legumes used as intercrops on inorganic soil nitrogen, crop yield and biomass N, and BNF were tested in comparison to bare fallow. Non-legumes and legumes + non-legumes were more efficient than legumes in reducing inorganic soil N contents in autumn and nitrate contents in soil solution from the subsoil in winter. This reduction in inorganic soil N did not last until March of the following year due to an N mineralisation from the mulch. The legume + non-legume mixture contained a larger amount of crop N than both legumes and non-legumes. This was due to the combined effect of soil-N uptake by the non-legumes and BNF by the legumes in the mixture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5789/1/Farthofer_et_al_2004_intercrops.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Farthofer, R.; Friedel, J. K.; Pietsch, G.; Rinnhofer, T.; Loiskandl, W. and Freyer, B.    (2004) Plant biomass nitrogen and effects on the risk of nitrate leaching of intercrops under organic farming in Eastern Austria.       Paper at:   EUROSOIL 2004, Freiburg, Germany, Sept. 4th to 12th.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5789/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>