<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Transport, trading and retailing. QLIF subproject 6: Development of strategies to improve quality and safety and reduce costs along the food supply chain</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knight, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of the aims of QLIF subproject 6 was to provide a better understanding of the supply chain performance and the collaboration system of organic supply chains. A notable finding was that supply chain actors with a high collaboration index outperformed respondents with a lower collaboration in terms of overall, non-financial and financial performance. Also, there is evidence that the higher the perceived risk for quality and safety is, the higher the probability that collaborative practices were in place. Nevertheless, overall, the level of collaboration is still too low. In a second part of QLIF subproject 6, HACCP case studies and training courses have been developed with special reference to organic agriculture. A HACCP approach to food safety management can be applied throughout the food chain, from farm to fork. Although a HACCP approach is not a legal requirement in primary production in the EU, it is recognised as an effective and logical means for food safety control that is equally applicable to agriculture including organic and low-input production systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Elsgaard, Lars</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16593/1/16593.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Knight, C and Stolze, M    (2009) Transport, trading and retailing. QLIF subproject 6: Development of strategies to improve quality and safety and reduce costs along the food supply chain.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture, Newcstele and Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16593/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>