<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A discussion of norms for S supply in organic farming based on content in forage and ruminant performance in Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Sissel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bakken, Anne Kjersti</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The content of sulphur (S) in grassland on 27 Norwegian organic farms with dairy or sheep production was investigated in 2001 and 2002. The forage content of S was below the norms (2 g S kg DM-1) for both plants and animals in a large proportion of the samples. The average S content in forage at dairy farms was 1.4 g S kg DM-1 and at sheep farms 1.5 g. Even on grasslands with low plant S content (&lt;1 g S kg DM-1), S-fertilization did not increase yields and increased the plants’ S content only very slightly. No indications of S deficiency were observed on the dairy farms. For one sheep farm with a forage S content of 1.1 ± 0.1g S kg DM-1, brittle and short winter wool was reported.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ISOFAR</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11946/1/11946.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Sissel and Bakken, Anne Kjersti    (2008) A discussion of norms for S supply in organic farming based on content in forage and ruminant performance in Norway.   In: Neuhoff, Daniel (Ed.)   Proceedings of the 2nd scientific conference of the international society of organic agriculture research (ISOFAR), Livestock, socio-economic and cross disciplinary research in organic agriculture, ISOFAR, II, pp. 160-163.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11946/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>