<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Moving on – European organic farming movements between political action and self-reflection</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming movements in Europe are widely recognised as a positive force by market actors and civil society, as well as relevant actors in policy networks. At the same time, the organic movement is in a process of self-reflection, reconsidering its value basis. Taking account of both a policy network and a social movement perspective, this article seeks to understand political action of the organic sector. Making use of a cross-country comparison of European organic farming policy networks, it conceptualises the consequences of such action with regard to political influence and the identity of the organic farming movement. While different strategies are employed to influence politics, a space needs to be opened up within the movements for continuous innovation and the re-construction of a collective identity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Inderscience</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16462/1/Moschitz_IJARGE_abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun   (2009) Moving on – European organic farming movements between political action and self-reflection.   International Journal of Agricultural Resources, Governance, and Ecology.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16462/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>