<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Co-production of ethanol, biogas, protein fodder and  natural fertilizer in organic farming – evaluation of a  concept for a farm-scale biorefinery</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oleskowicz-Popiel, Piotr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kádár, Zsófia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heiske, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klein-Marcuschamer , D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simmons, Blake A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blanch, Harvey W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Jens Ejbye</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The addition of a biorefinery to an organic farm was  investigated, where ethanol was produced from germinated &#xD;
rye grains and whey, and the effluent was separated into two streams: the protein-rich solid fraction, to be used as animal feed, and the liquid fraction, which can be co-digested with clover grass silage to produce biogas. A method for ethanol production from rye was applied by utilizing inherent amylase activity from germination of the seed. Biogas potential of ethanol fermentation effluent was &#xD;
measured through anaerobic digestion trials. The effluent from the trials was assumed to serve as natural fertilizer. A technoeconomic analysis was also performed; total capital investment was estimated to be approximately 4 M USD. Setting a methane selling price according to available incentives for "green electricity" (0.72 USD/m3) led to a minimum ethanol selling price of 1.89 USD/L (project lifetime 25 yr, at a discount rate 10%).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20461/4/20461.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oleskowicz-Popiel, Piotr; Kádár, Zsófia; Heiske, Stefan; Klein-Marcuschamer , D.; Simmons, Blake A.; Blanch, Harvey W. and Schmidt, Jens Ejbye   (2012) Co-production of ethanol, biogas, protein fodder and natural fertilizer in organic farming – evaluation of a concept for a farm-scale biorefinery.   Bioresource Technology,  104,  440- 446.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20461/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>