<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Estimated N leaching losses for organic and conventional farming in Denmark</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knudsen, Marie Trydeman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Ib Sillebak</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berntsen, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petersen, Bjørn Molt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Erik Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of organic compared to conventional farming practices on N leaching loss was studied for Danish mixed dairy and arable farms using an N balance approach based on representative data. On mixed dairy farms a simple N balance method was used to estimate N surplus and N leaching loss. On arable farms the simple N balance method was unreliable due to changes in the soil N pool. Consequently, the FASSET simulation model was used to estimate N surplus, N leaching loss and the changes in the soil N pool. &#xD;
The study found a lower N leaching loss from organic than conventional mixed dairy farms, primarily due to lower N inputs. On organic arable farms the soil N pool was increasing over years but the N leaching loss was comparable to conventional arable farms. The soil N pool was primarily increased by organic farming practices and incorporation of straw. The highest increase in the soil N pool was seen on soils with a low level of soil organic matter. The level of N leaching loss was dependent on soil type, the use of catch crops and the level of soil organic matter, whereas incorporation of straw had a minor effect. N leaching was highest on sandy soils with a high level of soil organic matter and no catch crops. The study stresses the importance of using representative data of organic and conventional farming practices in comparative studies of N leaching loss.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4637/1/4637.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4637/2/4637.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Knudsen, Marie Trydeman; Kristensen, Ib Sillebak; Berntsen, Jørgen; Petersen, Bjørn Molt and Kristensen, Erik Steen   (2006) Estimated N leaching losses for organic and conventional farming in Denmark.   Journal of Agricultural Science, 144 (2), pp. 135-149.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>