<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of nitrogen utilizsation by means of the concept of primary production balance</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seuri, Pentti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Primary production balance (PPB) indicates the ratio (*) between harvested nutrients and nutrients put into crop production from outside the system (=primary nutrients). The PPB is independent of the final output (crop vs. animal products) and can be used to evaluate different systems (farms). The utilization of nitrogen(N) was evaluated by means of the PPB on nine organic farms, stockless and mixed ones, in eastern Finland.&#xD;
The mixed farms were able to reach a remarkably higher primary production balance (1.0 – 1.2) compared with the stockless ones (0.5). Values higher than 1.0 indicate recirculation of nutrients. Other components of the high PPB were legumes as nitrogen source and optimum livestock density.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), Bonn; Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cornish, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5940/1/Seuri.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seuri, Pentti and Kahiluoto, Helena    (2005) Evaluation of nitrogen utilizsation by means of the concept of primary production balance.       Paper at:   Researching sustainable systems : first scientific conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), held in cooperation with IFOAM and NASAA, Adelaide, South Australia, 21-23 September 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5940/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>