<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Food for Youth in Public Settings: Potentials and&#xD;
Challenges. Preliminary Recommendations from a European&#xD;
Study</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report contains presentations from the four explorative work packages in iPOPY. The iPOPY project –&#xD;
innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth – is one of eight transnational research programs&#xD;
initiated by the 11 European countries participating in the CORE Organic I funding body network. iPOPY aims&#xD;
at increasing the consumption of organic food among young people, especially in school meal settings but&#xD;
also elsewhere, e.g. at music festivals. We work towards this goal by studying how organic food as well as&#xD;
the organic concept in general has been introduced in public food serving settings in various countries, and&#xD;
what may be the most promising approaches. Italy, Finland, Denmark, Norway and Germany are the&#xD;
countries being studied. The iPOPY work packages explore policy issues, supply chain organization and the&#xD;
impact of certification, the users’ perceptions and participation in the food system, and the health impacts of&#xD;
organic food implementation.&#xD;
By June 2010, iPOPY will be completed. Hence, this report is linked to the last iPOPY seminar arranged&#xD;
during the BioFach Trade Fair in Nuremberg, Germany. We arranged similar seminars also in 2008 and 2009.&#xD;
These seminars presented the situation with respect to organic school meals in many different European&#xD;
countries (2008) and in more detail in iPOPY countries as well as some relevant cases (2009). Proceedings&#xD;
are available from the 2009 seminar (Nölting et al 2009), and all presentations from the 2008 seminar are&#xD;
found on the iPOPY website, www.ipopy.coreportal.org.&#xD;
In the seminar in 2010, we will draw a link from iPOPY results to the municipality of Nuremberg, which has&#xD;
ambitious aims as to becoming an Organic Model City (BioModellstadt). This includes far reaching goals for&#xD;
the share of organic and regional food served in public schools and kindergartens. Further, the project&#xD;
results will be linked to the general situation for school meals in Europe. For this presentation, no written&#xD;
paper is available, but we will present the slides on the website. From the project we present preliminary&#xD;
recommendations and conclusions from the four explorative work packages.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Strassner, Carola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16883/1/CORE_Proc_BioFach_2010_ipopy_VF.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strassner, Carola; Løes, Anne-Kristin; Nölting, Benjamin and Kristensen, Niels Heine (Eds.)    (2010) Organic Food for Youth in Public Settings: Potentials and Challenges. Preliminary Recommendations from a European Study.   ICROFS, International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems, Tjele, Denmark.  Proceedings of iPOPY session held at the BioFach Congress 2010, Nuremberg, Germany, February 20, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16883/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>