<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving animal welfare by assessing college’s farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, Gidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Health and welfare is a major topic in the Netherlands in both organic and non-organic dairy farming. This report highlights issues arising from welfare assessments conducted on Dutch farms producing milk for Ben and Jerry’s (B&amp;J) ice cream. The Netherlands is the base for the European market for B&amp;J ice-cream. Four years ago 11 farms were asked to produce milk for B&amp;J. High human and animal welfare was a pre-condition. In order to evaluate the animal welfare on those farms, cows were assessed at the end of the housing season and at the end of the grazing season. At a plenary meeting the farmers discussed the results and the possible improvements on their farms. Since the farmers had a desire to control things on their own farms, they wanted to assess their own farms and animals. In a number of sessions a checklist was developed by the group of farmers and tested. This so-called ‘caring dairy’ checklist is now used in all kinds of farmers groups, conventional and organic, with farmers assess each others cows and farms. A 5 hour workshop at a host farm at the beginning of the process includes a theoretical and practical part and at least a proposal from the host farmer with three points to improve. The following assessments of colleagues take 3 hours per farm, which also results in proposals to improve.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Vaarst, Mette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Roderick, Stephen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15918/1/15918.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smolders, Gidi    (2009) Improving animal welfare by assessing college’s farms.    In: Vaarst, Mette and Roderick, Stephen (Eds.)  CORE Organic project nr: 1903 - Aniplan. Workshop report - The process of researching animal health and welfare planning. Core Organic project Series, no. 1903-2. Aarhus Universitet - Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, Departement of Animal Health and Bioscience, pp. 28-30.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15918/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>