<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigations into the effect of pre-bloom defoliation on quality and yield of organically grown `Riesling` grapes as well as `Zweigelt` grapes grown according to integrated plant protection guidelines</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mehofer, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hanak, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmuckenschlager, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With the varieties `Riesling` and `Zweigelt` in a two year trial the effects of defoliation at&#xD;
different stages of development on the occurrence of sunburn and botrytis and on cluster&#xD;
compactness, yield, cluster weight, berry weight, must weight, acidity, pH-value and the&#xD;
concentrations of phenols and nitrogen in the must were determined. In the year 2012 with the&#xD;
variety `Riesling` damages caused by sunburn increased because of defoliation and were&#xD;
significantly highest in the treatment `early removal of 6 leaves and of 2° shoots at pre bloom&#xD;
at the development stage BBCH 57`. In the year 2013, because of the climatic conditions,&#xD;
damages caused by sunburn were significantly lower and occurred only on individual berries,&#xD;
just as with the variety `Zweigelt`. With the grape variety `Riesling` occurrence of Botrytis&#xD;
was significantly highest in the control treatment, were no leaves and shoots had been&#xD;
removed. The removal of six leaves and the 2° shoots at pre bloom (BBCH 57) had a&#xD;
significantly reducing effect on the incidence and severity of Botrytis. With the variety&#xD;
`Zweigelt` Botrytis infestation was very low and occurred only on individual berries.&#xD;
A&#xD;
reduction of cluster compactness caused by the defoliation before flowering could not be&#xD;
determined with the variety `Riesling`. Cluster compactness was classified `medium` to&#xD;
`dense`. With the variety `Zweigelt` cluster compactness was significantly reduced from&#xD;
`dense` to `medium` by the treatment `removal of six leaves and 2° shoots at pre bloom`.&#xD;
With both varieties yield and cluster weight were significantly lowest in the treatment&#xD;
`removal of six leaves and 2° shoots at pre bloom`. Year-dependent reduction of yield was 16&#xD;
% respectively 21 % with the variety `Riesling` and 28 % respectively 35 % with the variety&#xD;
`Zweigelt`. Cluster weight decreased year-dependent by 20 % respectively 15 % with&#xD;
`Riesling` and by 24 % respectively 29 % with `Zweigelt`. In both years but only with the&#xD;
grape variety `Riesling` must weight significantly decreased in the treatment `removal of six&#xD;
leaves and 2° shoots at veraison` namely from 0.8 to 1°KMW respectively from 0.4 to&#xD;
0.7°KMW. However the treatment `removal of six leaves and 2° shoots at pre bloom` did not&#xD;
influence must weight with both varieties. Only in 2012 and only with `Riesling` the content&#xD;
of phenols in the must of the treatment `removal of six leaves and 2° shoots at pre bloom` was&#xD;
significantly increased and had a value of 0.039 g/l. With both varieties the nitrogen levels in&#xD;
the must dispersed strong within the different treatments but without significant differences&#xD;
between the treatments. In the wine tasting no significant differences could be determined&#xD;
between the vines of the four treatments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Mehofer, M; Hanak, K and Schmuckenschlager, B   (2015) Investigations into the effect of pre-bloom defoliation on quality and yield of organically grown `Riesling` grapes as well as `Zweigelt` grapes grown according to integrated plant protection guidelines.   Mitteilungen Klosterneuburg , 65, pp. 10-13.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28528/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>