<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Suitability of traditional and conventional pig breeds in organic and low-input production systems in Europe: Survey results and a review of literature</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leenhouwers, J. I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Merks, J.W.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For many years, there has been debate about the suitability of traditional and conventional pig breeds in low-input and organic production systems. This review compiles reproductive and finishing performance of traditional and conventional breeds in low-input and organic production systems in Europe, based on literature studies and farm surveys until 2010. In comparison with traditional breeds, conventional breeds wean many piglets, have efficient and fast growth and lean carcasses. They thrive well in North West European climatic conditions with temperate summers and mild winters. Optimal housing may be indoors with outdoor runs, because this provides a controlled environment in which large litters are more easily managed. The lean meat of conventional breeds is suitable for the commodity organic pork market. Traditional breeds comprise a group of prolific breeds with good finishing performance (e.g. Saddlebacks, Pulawska) and breeds kept for special meat production (e.g. Ibérico, Cinta Senese). The prolific and leaner traditional breeds are suitable for commodity organic pork production, especially when crossed with conventional white boar breeds to give some extra leanness to the carcass. Special meat breeds are unsuitable for commodity organic pork production owing to their low fertility and high carcass fatness, but extra added value is obtained by their specific meat and fat quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23044/1/Leenhouwers-merks-2013-AnimalGeneticRecources-finalpublished-pp1-16.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leenhouwers, J. I. and Merks, J.W.M.   (2013) Suitability of traditional and conventional pig breeds in organic and low-input production systems in Europe: Survey results and a review of literature.   Animal Genetic Resources, online, pp. 1-16.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23044/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>