<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Attitudes towards organic foods among consumers from the Mediterranean Arabic countries living in Italy.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ahmed, Abdel Munem</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigates food habits in general and attitudes towards organic food products of consumers from the Mediterranean Arabic Countries (MACs) living in Italy. Organic food markets are still emerging in the consumers’ countries of origin. The questionnaire-based interview was administered to 211 consumers during Spring 2005. The results show that knowledge about organics is weak. Level of education has a strong influence on knowledge of organic food products. Workshops, universities and schools are the most effective sources for the real knowledge about organic agriculture. Consumption of organic foods slightly increased after immigration in Italy. Health and environmental concern are the main reasons to buy organics. High price and low availability of organic food products are the main obstacles to consumption.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7010/1/Abdelmunem05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ahmed, Abdel Munem   (2005) Attitudes towards organic foods among consumers from the Mediterranean Arabic countries living in Italy.  [L’attitude à l’égard des aliments biologiques des consommateurs originaires des pays arabes méditerranéens résidents en Italie.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 407. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7010/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>