<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Home range and dispersal of the field vole Microtus agrestis in an organic agro-ecosystem</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Thomas Secher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olsen, Kent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Tine Sussi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vedel-Smith, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During 2008-2011 field voles (Microtus agrestis) were  studied in a Danish agro-ecosystem in connection with a programme elucidating the role of organic farming as refuge for biodiversity, due to the observed biodiversity losses in conventional farmland. The aim of the study was to &#xD;
quantify home ranges and movements of voles in order to test a hypothesis that vole populations living in organic farm could colonize unoccupied areas in conventional farms. Voles were radiocollared and tracked until death or disappearance. Results showed that vole home-ranges were &#xD;
larger during onset of the breeding season than during the height of the breeding season and the non-breeding period. Males had larger home ranges than females. Voles occupying isolated small biotopes had restricted home range and only few individuals crossed fields from one small biotope to another. Although crossings do occur, the magnitude of dispersal seems restricted.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01-24</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19073/7/19073.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Thomas Secher; Olsen, Kent; Hansen, Tine Sussi and Vedel-Smith, Christina   (2012) Home range and dispersal of the field vole Microtus agrestis in an organic agro-ecosystem.   Mammalian Biology,  ,  - .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19073/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>