<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diskrepanz zwischen Verbraucheraussagen und tatsächlichem Kaufverhalten bei Öko-Produkten in der Direktvermarktung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Direct marketing represents traditionally an important method of sale for organic agri-culture. Added value remains on farm and this form of marketing serves as attribute to strengthen trust and image and to maintain proximity to the customer. Direct market-ing however is losing market shares against competing places of sale in a growing organic market. By analysing panel data and an additional survey with the panel participants it can be seen that a large share of customers think that they were buying organic products, but in reality bought conventional products. Organic farmers should therefore improve their communication with consumers. A large discrepancy between stated and actual buying frequency also advises reconsideration of consumer surveys` results under methodical aspects.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9659/1/9659_Niessen_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niessen, Jan and Hamm, Ulrich    (2007) Diskrepanz zwischen Verbraucheraussagen und tatsächlichem Kaufverhalten bei Öko-Produkten in der Direktvermarktung.  [Discrepancy between consumers` statements and their real buying behaviour with organic products using the example of stated and actual buying frequency in direct marketing.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9659/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>