<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rentabilität vegetabiler Düngemittel im ökologischen Gemüsebau am Beispiel eines süddeutschen Gemischtbetriebes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hummel, Anke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lippert, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Torsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulz, Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For a given organic farm with livestock and vegetable production in Southern Germany the economic viability of on farm produced legume seed meal as Plant Based Organic Fertiliser (PBOF) is analysed by means of a Linear Programming (LP) model  in order to asses under which conditions such a fertiliser use may be profitable. Yields, labour demand and gross margins of the different farming activities are taken from data collections and adapted based on information provided by the farmer, whose specific crop rotation, labour and stable restrictions are also implemented in the LP model. Nitrogen supplies and demands of the different farming activities are drawn from data collections and information by plant scientists. Our calculations show that legume seed meal as PBOF is profitable in case that cheap purchasable organic nitrogen fertilisers are not available. In future, further model calculations shall show whether this result also holds for other farming and site conditions than those underlying the quite specific conditions of our model farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17548/2/Hummel_17548.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hummel, Anke; Lippert, Christian; Müller, Torsten and Schulz, Rudolf    (2011) Rentabilität vegetabiler Düngemittel im ökologischen Gemüsebau am Beispiel eines süddeutschen Gemischtbetriebes.       Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17548/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>