<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecosystem Functions and Services of Biodiversity in Grasslands</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Multifunctionality with positive effects on nature and society is a central element of organic agriculture, and a high biodiversity is essential for this. Grassland has the greatest potential for providing this service, but the organic fields are large and biodiversity is low. The purpose of this project is to increase plant biodiversity in grassland and significantly improve ecosystem functions and services in the nature-farmer-consumer chain and for society, and thus also increase the market value of organic products. We will: 1) design and demonstrate productive and biodiverse grassland with squares of flowering plants, 2) improve conditions for bees and other pollinators using flowering grasslands for hay or silage, 3) increase carbon sequestration via increased plant biodiversity, and grasslands of longer duration, 3) produce high quality cheeses based on species-rich hay, 4) examine relationships between biodiversity and cheese quality, and convey the perception and the product history to the gastronomic world and to the consumer, 5) develop marketing concepts for organic products with multifunctionality and 6) describe the economic and environmental perspectives for multifunctionality in grassland at farm and regional level using systems analysis, economic modeling and life cycle assessment. In relation to Green Growth the project contributes to increased biodiversity, more connected nature and an increased organic farming area.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19606/1/EcoServe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EcoServe: Ecosystem Functions and Services of Biodiversity in Grasslands.  [Økosystem Funktioner og Services af Biodiversitet i Græsmarker.]   Runs 2011 - 2013.      Project Leader(s): Eriksen, Jøregen.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19606/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>