<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biolandwirtschaft und Tourismuswirtschaft in Graubünden – Marktgerechte Nutzung von nachhaltigen Synergiepotenzialen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuhnhenn, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simon, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This project focuses both, tourism suppliers (e.g. hotels, restaurants etc.) and organic farming in Grisons (an alpine region in Switzerland). The main objective is the optimization of the cooperation between the above mentioned branches along the inter-sectoral value-added chain in order to foster the sustainable development of the tourism industry and to generate guarantee of a continued existence for organic farms. As a result, the inter-sectoral delivery system and relations within the tourism industry and the organic farming segment will be more efficient. Additionally, new and innovative bookable offers will be designed in the innovative field of “eco-tourism”. A four phase approach is chosen to assure the target achievement. The results of the first phase are achieved already on the base of a structured expert interview. These results show that executing the cooperation of organic farming and tourism lacks in reality and offer first hints for improving the collaboration of both branches.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21209/1/21209_Simon.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kuhnhenn, Ulrike and Simon, Silvia    (2013) Biolandwirtschaft und Tourismuswirtschaft in Graubünden – Marktgerechte Nutzung von nachhaltigen Synergiepotenzialen.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21209/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>