<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>European consumers' conceptions of organic food: A review of available research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Torjusen, Hanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sangstad, Lotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O'Doherty Jensen, Katherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjærnes, Unni</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report is a publication from the project entitled 'Recommendations for Improved Procedures for Securing Consumer Oriented Food Safety and Quality of Certified Organic Foods from a Consumer Perspective' (acronym: 'Organic HACCP'), supported by the European Commission, Fifth Framework Programme, Quality of Life and Management of Living Resources, and co-ordinated by Dr. Kirsten Brandt.&#xD;
The report includes a summary and 9 chapters, which respectively regard a statement of objectives and methods (Chapter 1), critical considerations regarding current approaches to consumer studies (Chapter 2), an overview of factors related to the production, distribution and regulation of organic foods, which differentially affect patterns of consumption in European countries (Chapter 3), 4 case studies regarding the consumption of organic foods and the contextual features influencing consumption patterns in Denmark (Chapter 4), United kingdom (Chapter 5), Italy (Chapter 6) and Hungary (Chapter 7). These case studies are followed by a summary review of trends in Europe with regard to consumer characteristics, buying behaviour and consumer concerns (Chapter 8), as well as a series of recommendations with regard to future research regarding the consumption of organic foods within the European region (Chapter 9).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Oslo: National Institute for Consumer Research</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2490/1/haccprapport.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Torjusen, Hanne; Sangstad, Lotte; O'Doherty Jensen, Katherine and Kjærnes, Unni    (2004) European consumers' conceptions of organic food: A review of available research.    Professional Report, no. no. 4-2004. Oslo: National Institute for Consumer Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2490/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>