<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Response of Sunflower Yield and Phytohormonal Changes to Azotobacter,Azospirillum,Pseudomonas and Animal Manure in a Chemical Free Agroecosystem</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maziyar, Mehran</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>M.Reza, Ardakani</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamid, Madani</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mohammad , Zahedi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mohsen, Amirabadi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saeed, Mafakheri</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There are new trends in agriculture to move toward the low input systems with the lower application of chemical fertilizers. To reach this goal, different methods, such as the application of biofertilizers, may be used. So this experiment was conducted in 2010 at a research farm in Arak, Iran, in factorial in the form of a randomized complete block design with three replications and four factors: animal manure (M), Pseudomonas putida (P), Azotobacter chroococcum (A)and Azospirillum lipoferum (Z). Results indicated that manure significantly affected grain yield (P≤0.01); the highest grain yield was achieved in the interaction of manure × Azotobacter × Pseudomonas (4.556 ton/ha). Grain yield was not significantly affected by the microorganisms. Moreover, the four factors of the experiment significantly affected auxin, gibberellin and cytokinin content of plant. Overall, this experiment indicated that desirable yield can be achieved by the application of manure and biofertilizers, in a sustainable  agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22514/7/22514.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Maziyar, Mehran; M.Reza, Ardakani; Hamid, Madani; Mohammad , Zahedi; Mohsen, Amirabadi and Saeed, Mafakheri   (2011) Response of Sunflower Yield and Phytohormonal Changes to Azotobacter,Azospirillum,Pseudomonas and Animal Manure in a Chemical Free Agroecosystem.   Annals of Biological Research, 2 (6), pp. 425-430.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22514/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>