<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von lebenden Mulchen auf die Begleitflora und die Weizenerträge unter Bedingungen des Ökolandbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hiltbrunner, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liedgens, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stamp, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Streit, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Switzerland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For the success of no-tillage in organic farming, new tools have to be developed to control weeds. One possible strategy could be sowing the main crop into an earlier established living mulch of easily controllable cover crops. &#xD;
Field trials were carried out in the Swiss midlands to investigate the impact of different legume cover crops on weed populations and grain yield of directly drilled winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) in a living mulch system. In general, weed suppressing effect was best with highly productive legumes. A significant reduction of the weed density of dicotyle, monocotyle, and spring germinating species was observed. Though, effective weed suppression resulted also in strong competition with the winter wheat. In order to improve the practicability of such systems, seeding technique of the main crop and living mulch management should be investigated.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3258/1/3258.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hiltbrunner, J.; Liedgens, M.; Stamp, P. and Streit, B.    (2005) Einfluss von lebenden Mulchen auf die Begleitflora und die Weizenerträge unter Bedingungen des Ökolandbau.  [Impact of living mulches on weeds and yield of winter wheat in organic farming.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3258/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>