<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of cultivar and dipping pre-treatment on quality of minimally processed organically grown apples</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gobbi, Dr Serena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genna, Dr Angela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cerasi, Dr Michela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Dr Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Senesi, Dr Emilio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nowadays the demand for fresh or minimally processed fruits and vegetables is increasing but few have organic origin; among all fruits, fresh-cut apples are very much appreciated from the consumers. The aim of this work was to investigate the effect of an anti-oxidant treatment and the influence of cultivar on the quality of minimally processed organically grown apples during shelf-life. Cv Golden Delicious and cv Pink Lady were used, and the anti-oxidant treatment was carried out by dipping the apples in a solution of citric acid 1% and ascorbic acid 0.5%. After washing and core removing, apples were mechanically cut into 8 slices and dipped for 15 min-utes in the anti-oxidant solution. After draining, the excess water was dried with absorbing paper; then the apple slices were packaged in polythene boxes and stored at 3±1°C. Some slices were packaged without previous treatment as a control sample. Chemical and physical parameters were studied after 0, 2, 5 and 7 days of storage. Results showed that both cultivar could be used to obtain high quality fresh-cut products which can be stored at least for 7 days, and the antioxidant treatment had a positive effect in preserving apple characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7557/1/paper_organic_apple.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gobbi, Dr Serena; Genna, Dr Angela; Cerasi, Dr Michela; Kelderer, Dr Markus and Senesi, Dr Emilio    (2006) Influence of cultivar and dipping pre-treatment on quality of minimally processed organically grown apples.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7557/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>