<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Schädlingsprognose mit SOPRA als Entscheidungshilfe im&#xD;
Bioobstbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Samietz, Dr. Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graf, Dr. Benno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Höhn, Heinrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaub, Dr. Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Höpli, Hans Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The forecasting tool SOPRA has been developed with the objective to optimize timing&#xD;
of monitoring and control measures of insect pests in fruit orchards. Phenologymodels&#xD;
were developed driven by solar radiation, air temperature and soil temperature&#xD;
on hourly basis including simulation of characteristic habitat conditions for Dysaphis&#xD;
plantaginea, Hoplocampa testudinea, Cydia pomonella, Grapholita lobarzewskii,&#xD;
Cacopsylla pyri, Rhagoletis cerasi, Anthonomus pomorum and Adoxophyes orana. On&#xD;
base of local weather data, age structure of pest populations is simulated and crucial&#xD;
events for management in organic and integrated production are announced. Through&#xD;
a web-interface, the simulation results are made available to consultants and growers&#xD;
(www.sopra.info). As timing of monitoring and management are especially important in&#xD;
organic growing, SOPRA is applied as decision support system (DSS) for major insect&#xD;
pests of organic fruit orchards in Switzerland.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14434/1/Samietz_14434.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Samietz, Dr. Jörg; Graf, Dr. Benno; Höhn, Heinrich; Schaub, Dr. Lukas and Höpli, Hans Ulrich    (2009) Schädlingsprognose mit SOPRA als Entscheidungshilfe im Bioobstbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14434/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>