<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Unwrapping the Northern Sea cheese - Enacting the Sea as terroir</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ostrowski, Kasper</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper investigates how a Danish dairy has found an innovative way of making geographical claims by affiliating a regional Danish cheese with the Northern Sea. The Nordic foodscape has, alongside with an increasingly globalized agrifood sector, changed thoroughly over the last decade. Historically, strong geographical claims in relation to food or produce have been less propagated in the Nordic countries, compared to the South. But recently, enactments of quality such as ‘the local’ and the ‘place-specific’ or the ‘endogenous’ and the ‘authentic’ have gained momentum as pivotal notions within the making of markets, not least in Scandinavia. Devoid of well-established traditions for making such geographical claims – new ways of prestige enhancing and connecting produce with origin are now explored. Departing from an ANT perspective and with a regional Danish cheese as centrepiece, such an exploration is investigated in this paper. With this paper I thus hope to inform and stimulate current and future research activity within food-related ANT and rural studies alike.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-01-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22122/7/22122.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ostrowski, Kasper   (2013) Unwrapping the Northern Sea cheese - Enacting the Sea as terroir.   Journal of Rural Studies,  ,  - .    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22122/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>