<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The strategic turn of Organic Farming in Europe : a resource based approach of Organic Marketing Initiatives</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sylvander, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Le Floch-Wadel, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Couallier, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper explores the Organic farming’s development potential in Europe by analysing the enterprises capacities to reach a workable structure of the supply chains, in order to market good products at reasonable prices. This study has been carried out in the framework of the OMIaRD project, which aimed to assess the impact of the Organic Marketing Initiatives on Rural Development. The results show that, after a growing phase, most of the OMIs meet strategic problems linked to their ability to face an increasing of collected, processed and marketed volumes. This strategic turn point leads them to take decisions together with their stakeholders, so as the economical and ethical goals are not questioned by the changes to be implemented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6731/1/paper-version1-BS-15feb05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sylvander, B.; Le Floch-Wadel, A. and Couallier, C.    (2005) The strategic turn of Organic Farming in Europe : a resource based approach of Organic Marketing Initiatives.       Speech at:   International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Researching Sustainable Systems, Adelaide, Australia, September 21 – 23, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6731/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>