<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Determinants of Spatial Distribution of Organic Farming in Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bichler, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Häring, Anna Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lippert, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The share of organically managed land is spread unevenly throughout Germany and shows pronounced regional concentrations. The spatial distribution of organic farming is assumed to be influenced by several factors. Location factors of farms are regionally different and thus may influence the spatial distribution of organic farming. Agglomeration effects and therefore spatial dependence are also considered important in determining spatial distribution. &#xD;
These factors with a potential influence on the spatial distribution of organic farming can be divided into four categories: natural factors, farm-structure factors, socio-economic factors and political factors. Their possible influence on the spatial distribution of organic farming is analysed by several statistical methods: ordinary least square regression model, spatial autoregressive models, analysis of variance and Spearman correlation. Of the analysed factors, spatial contiguity has the strongest influence on the spatial distribution of organic farming (indicating relevant agglomeration effects).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ISOFAR / FIBL</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Köpcke, Ulrich</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cornish, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6322/1/Bichler_et_al_revised_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bichler, Barbara; Häring, Anna Maria; Dabbert, Stephan and Lippert, Christian    (2005) Determinants of Spatial Distribution of Organic Farming in Germany.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems, Adelaide/Australien, September 21.-23. 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6322/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>