<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dietary citrus pulp improves protein stability in lamb meat stored under aerobic conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gravador, Rufielyn S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jongberg, Sisse</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Mogens L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luciano, Giuseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priolo, Alessandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lund, Marianne N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The antioxidant effects of dried citrus pulp on proteins in lamb meat, when used as a replacement of concentrate in the feed, was studied using meat from 26 male Comisana lambs. The lambs of age 90 days had been grouped randomly to receive one of the three dietary treatments: (1) commercial concentrate with 60% barley (Control, n = 8), (2) concentrate with 35% barley and 24% citrus pulp (Cp24, n = 9), or (3) concentrate with 23% barley and 35% citrus pulp (Cp35, n = 9). Slices from the longissimus thoracis et lomborum muscle were packed aerobically and stored for up to 6 days at 4°C in the dark. The citrus pulp groups, Cp24 and Cp35, significantly decreased protein radicals and carbonyls, and preserved more thiols within six days of storage compared to the Control group. The citrus pulp groups significantly slowed down the rate of protein oxidation, indicating that dietary citrus pulp reduced oxidative changes in meat proteins.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25282/1/Gravador-etal-2014-MeatScience-p231-236.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gravador, Rufielyn S.; Jongberg, Sisse; Andersen, Mogens L.; Luciano, Giuseppe; Priolo, Alessandro and Lund, Marianne N.   (2014) Dietary citrus pulp improves protein stability in lamb meat stored under aerobic conditions.   Meat Science, 97 (2), pp. 231-236.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25282/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>