<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Perspektiverne i OrganoFinery-projektet</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fog, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Through a concept for biorefinery of green herbage to protein feed, fertilizer and energy, the project develops a new platform for organic growth. The project will deliver solutions to the following key challenges to the organic sector: Supply of organic protein feed to monogastric livestock, improved, climate-friendly, and robust crop rotations in areas with a low density of livestock, better use efficiency of the nutrients, and higher yields. These solutions are important for the sectors credibility and legitimacy. The project applies an ambitious, holistic, whole value-chain and cross disciplinary approach with the following activities: 1) Identification of the best suited material for biorefinery through cropping trials; 2)Harvest and extraction of green leaf protein through fermentation and separation; 3) Production, profiling and testing of organic protein feed on poultry, 4) Treatment of the residual biomass in a biogas plant for the production of biogas and valuable organic fertilizer, 5) Business model development for organic protein feed, fibre material for biogas and for system export, 6) Optimizing of the system for upscaling, 7) Involvement of all stakeholders.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-04-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28720/7/28720.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fog, E.    (2015) Perspektiverne i OrganoFinery-projektet.  [Prospects in the OrganoFinery Project.]          Møde i Æg- og Fjerkræbrancheudvalget, 8. april 2015.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28720/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>