<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>AMARANTHS (Amaranthus viridis) Dry matter and soil qualities: Organic Vs Inorganic Fertilizers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>ADEOLUWA, OLUGBENGA O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>AKINYEMI, OLUWASEYI</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Continuous use of mineral fertilizer in soils is associated with reduced crop and soil quality.In this report, comparative effects of poultry manure and its extract, compost and mineral fertilizers was observed. &#xD;
The study was carried out on the field in two successive plantings (first planting and residual) at the Department of Agronomy, University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria. The treatments used were poultry manure, poultry manure extract, NPK(15-15-15), and control. Fertilizer treatments applied at 100 kg N / ha were laid in a completely randomized block design with four replicates.   Observations taken percentage dry matter and some chemical properties of the post harvest soils. Analysis of   variance (ANOVA) at (P&lt;0.05) was used as statistical tool, while means were separated with least significance difference (LSD).&#xD;
The result of this research revealed that percentage dry matter accumulation of crop treated with poultry manure and poultry manure extract was better than that of mineral fertilizer NPK. Also, Poultry manure extract also improved post harvest soil nitrogen and pH than the NPK fertilizer.&#xD;
Thus, poultry manure and poultry manure extract which are organic fertilizers are recommended for raising quality green amaranth under similar soil condition</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24105/1/24105%20OWC14%20A4_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ADEOLUWA, OLUGBENGA O. and AKINYEMI, OLUWASEYI    (2014) AMARANTHS (Amaranthus viridis) Dry matter and soil qualities: Organic Vs Inorganic Fertilizers.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 879-882.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24105/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>