<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Simultaneous epidemic development of scald and net blotch on single leaf layers of a spring barley crop</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vollmer, J.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pinnschmidt, H.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Munk, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Østergård, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background and objectives&#xD;
Two pathogens growing on the same leaf compete for the same resources, i.e. space and plant nutrients. This may lead to density dependent disease development. The pathogens may also influence each other directly such that the influence of one on the other is more complex than a simple function of the area of the other pathogen. Different interaction types are, for example, competition, mutualism and exploitation. The importance of such interactions for epidemics of simultaneously occurring pathogens has received little attention. The objective of this study is to investigate the simultaneous epidemic development of Rhynchosporium secalis (causing scald) and Drechslera teres (causing net blotch) on spring barley under field conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
Materials and methods&#xD;
The field trial was performed with artificial inoculation of R. secalis and D. teres on three spring barley varieties differing in their susceptibility towards the pathogens. The pathogens were inoculated in three combinations: only one was inoculated, they were inoculated together, the second pathogen was inoculated 26 days after the first. A non-inoculated treatment was included. The trial had three replications. Nine plants were harvested from each plot five times during the season. Leaves were dried and disease severity and senescence observed. Only leaves with &lt; 50 % senescence were included in the analysis. &#xD;
Whole-plant disease severity over time was calculated as average of disease severity on leaves weighted by leaf area. Disease development per leaf layer was evaluated by fitting an exponential model to severity data over time for each leaf layer per variety, treatment and replicate. Association between scald and net blotch severity on individual leaves was analysed using Kendall’s tau.&#xD;
&#xD;
Results and discussion&#xD;
Net blotch developed on all leaf layers and reached whole-plant disease severities up to 15%. Scald did not develop on upper leaf layers and whole-plant severity was less than 2%. Disease severity curves at whole-plant level showed no effect of inoculating the other pathogen. The analysis of the growth rate of each disease per leaf layer showed a significant effect of variety and leaf layer within variety but no effect of treatment. However, we observed significant negative associations between the diseases on individual leaves for several combinations of leaf layer and variety. These results show that the individual leaf approach can provide new information and underline the importance of considering interactions between pathogens in the field.&#xD;
&#xD;
Acknowledgement&#xD;
This work was funded by the DARCOF II project BAR-OF</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5974/1/5974.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vollmer, J.H.; Pinnschmidt, H.O.; Munk, L. and Østergård, H.    (2005) Simultaneous epidemic development of scald and net blotch on single leaf layers of a spring barley crop.       Poster at:   9th international workshop on plant disease epidemiology, Landerneau, France, 11-15 April 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5974/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>