<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Psychosocial Outcomes as Motivations for Visiting Nearby Urban Green Spaces</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Home, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hunziker, Marcel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bauer, Nicole</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>High-density urban living means that urban green spaces are important nodes of contact with nature. This study examines expected outcomes that motivate people to seek green spaces in urban settings. A sample of Swiss residents were presented with Shin, Kwon, Hammitt, and Kim's (2005) psychosocial outcomes scale and asked which activities they choose to undertake in nearby natural areas. The most important motivations for visiting nearby green spaces were related to restoration, with social bonding as a desirable side benefit. There were few observable differences between urban and rural residents and level of education attained. Older people are motivated to visit nearby green spaces by the wish to seek social contact while younger people are motivated by the wish to seek escape and to reflect. This study contributes to the understanding of the psychosocial outcomes that residents expect from engaging in an activity in an urban green space.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28898/1/home-etal-2012-LeisureSciences-34-p350-365.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Home, Robert; Hunziker, Marcel and Bauer, Nicole   (2012) Psychosocial Outcomes as Motivations for Visiting Nearby Urban Green Spaces.   Leisure Sciences, 34, pp. 350-365.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28898/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>