<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Measuring Sustainable Development:&#xD;
A Brief Discussion - and a view to Agricultural Policies on Certified Organics in a Globalizing Context.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Egelyng, Dr. Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Economic (GNP) growth has long remained the main-stream measure of national progress. However, com-plex, composite and multi-dimensional development indicators, such as green national accounts and sus-tainability indices, have gained importance. The paper take it´s point of departure in a brief review of these changing measures of development, and present one preliminary conclusion on how far alternative meas-ures has succeded. Further – the paper explores how complex indicators in the field of agriculture have perhaps spilled back into international agricultural policy changes, where conditions existed for challeng-ing the role of (economic or production) growth as the only measure and policy objective. Implicitly therefore a perspective is added speculating that agriculture may be a field where development re-search has further potential to play a role in moving new development measures up government policy agendas.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11307/1/Paper_III_-_Henrik_Egelyng.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Egelyng, Dr. Henrik    (2006) Measuring Sustainable Development: A Brief Discussion - and a view to Agricultural Policies on Certified Organics in a Globalizing Context.       Paper at:   2006 FAU Conference “Breaking New Ground: Development Research 2005-2015 and beyond., Copenhagen Business School (CBS)., May 10-11th 2006..     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>