<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Arbeitszeitbedarf in der ökologischen Schweinehaltung – ein&#xD;
Vergleich von zwei Stallsystemen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Riegel, Dipl.-Ing. agr. (FH) Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schick, PD Dr. habil. Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klöble, Dr. Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fritzsche, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Up-to-date information on the working-time requirement in pig husbandry and in ecological&#xD;
pig husbandry in particular which reflects the changed basic conditions in&#xD;
agricultural practice is extremely rare in the literature. In the Agroscope Reckenholz-&#xD;
Tänikon ART project Working-Time Requirement in Pig Husbandry according to the&#xD;
EU Eco-Regulation carried out within the framework of the “Calculation Documents”&#xD;
work programme of the Association for Technology and Structures in Agriculture&#xD;
(KTBL), current key figures were provided.&#xD;
Housing systems and work processes used in pig husbandry vary substantially. For&#xD;
this reason, two examples commonly used in practice are compared in this article:&#xD;
outdoor climate housing with two-space pens, and a Pig Port 3. Dung removal and&#xD;
litter spreading in the pen and run of the two-space pens is performed with the aid of a&#xD;
mobile unit, whilst manual processes are used in some cases in the Pig Port 3. Feeding&#xD;
is automatic, and roughage is made available in the outdoor run.&#xD;
For a livestock population of 520 fattening places in the two-space pens and 500&#xD;
fattening places in the Pig Port, an annual working-time requirement of 2.6 and 2.8&#xD;
MPh per fattening place, respectively, is to be reckoned on.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14094/1/Riegel_14094.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Riegel, Dipl.-Ing. agr. (FH) Marion; Schick, PD Dr. habil. Matthias; Klöble, Dr. Ulrike and Fritzsche, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Stephan    (2009) Arbeitszeitbedarf in der ökologischen Schweinehaltung – ein Vergleich von zwei Stallsystemen.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14094/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>