<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Coordination and synergy – increasing the width and depth of research in organic farming (SYNERGY)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming (DARCOF) is a "centre without walls", which is to say that the researchers remain in their own research environment but collaborate across institutes. The overall remit is to coordinate Danish R&amp;D for organic farming, with a view to achieving optimum benefit from the allocated resources.&#xD;
The specific objectives of the SYNERGY project are to secure the continued interdisciplinary development of Danish research in organic farming and to explore the many possibilities of synergy in DARCOF II.&#xD;
&#xD;
In relation to these objectives, the assignments of SYNERGY are to:&#xD;
• Co-ordinate, evaluate and manage DARCOF II as a whole&#xD;
• Analyse, discuss and synthesis knowledge across research projects and disciplines&#xD;
• Develop research methodology and investigate values associated with organic farming&#xD;
• Contribute to the education of research scientists involved in the DARCOF II&#xD;
• Communicate the research findings to the organic farming community and society in general&#xD;
• Contribute to international co-operation and communication&#xD;
&#xD;
In this way the project intends to secure the completion of the overall objectives of the programme; namely to contribute to increased production, and closer relationships between organic and inherent qualities in organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/533/1/ans.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/533/2/stat.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/533/3/stat02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Coordination and synergy – increasing the width and depth of research in organic farming (SYNERGY).    Runs 2000 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Kristensen, Erik Steen, Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming (DARCOF).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/533/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>