<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zu verschiedenen Bewirtschaftungssystemen im Weinbau unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der biologisch-dynamischen Wirtschaftsweise und des Präparateeinsatzes – Ergebnisse aus der Umstellungsphase 2006-2009</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meissner, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Johanna Renate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kauer, Randolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stoll, Manfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schultz, Hans-Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>World wide many wine farms are converting into organic or biodynamic viticulture. The main reasons are better wine quality and healthier wine with the long-term aim of sustainability in viticulture. &#xD;
In 2005 a long-term study started in Geisenheim. The objective of the research program is to investigate, compare and optimise the techniques of integrated, organic and particularly biodynamic wine production in terms of resource protection and food quality. &#xD;
The goals of this study are to look at the effects on the biological and microbial activity in the soil, the vegetative and generative growth of the vine, microbiology, the grape and wine quality and the sustainability of the three viticultural systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21547/1/21547_meissner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meissner, Georg; Döring, Johanna Renate; Kauer, Randolf; Stoll, Manfred and Schultz, Hans-Rainer    (2013) Untersuchungen zu verschiedenen Bewirtschaftungssystemen im Weinbau unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der biologisch-dynamischen Wirtschaftsweise und des Präparateeinsatzes – Ergebnisse aus der Umstellungsphase 2006-2009.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21547/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>