<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Environmental assessment of organic soybean (Glycine max.) imported from China to Denmark: a case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knudsen, Marie Trydeman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yu Hui, Qiao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yan, Luo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Growing global trade with organic products has increased the demand for environmental impact assessments during both production and transport. Environmental hotspots of organic soybeans produced in China and imported to Denmark were identified in a case study using a life cycle assessment&#xD;
approach. Furthermore, environmental impacts of organic and conventional soybeans at farm gate were compared in the case study. The total global warming potential (GWP) per ton organic soybeans imported to Denmark revealed that 51% came from transportation and 35% from the farm level.&#xD;
Comparing organic and conventional soybean at farm gate showed that GWP, non-renewable energy use, acidification and eutrophication was lower per ton organic soybeans, whereas land use was slightly higher.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17327/1/17327.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Knudsen, Marie Trydeman; Yu Hui, Qiao; Yan, Luo and Halberg, Niels   (2010) Environmental assessment of organic soybean (Glycine max.) imported from China to Denmark: a case study.   Journal of Cleaner Production, 18 (14), pp. 1431-1439.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17327/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>