<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Basic results in biological control of the European Cherry Fruit Fly Rhagoletis cerasi L. (Diptera: Tephritidae) with entomopathogenic nematodes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Köppler, Kirsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peters, Arne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogt, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2002 and 2003, within the ‚Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau’, initial experiments to control&#xD;
the European cherry fruit fly Rhagoletis cerasi were carried out under laboratory, semi-field and&#xD;
field conditions with several entomopathogenic nematode species and strains. In the laboratory the&#xD;
efficacy of nematodes against R. cerasi larvae, pupae and adults was examined. To characterize&#xD;
the controlling potential, different nematode dosages, exposure temperatures and substrates were&#xD;
tested in cell wells, petri dishes and plastic boxes. In the semi-field experiments plastic fruit boxes,&#xD;
filled with soil, were used. In the field tests R. cerasi-larvae and nematodes were released in defined&#xD;
areas in a cherry orchard of the institute. For evaluation of the experiments, the infestation rates&#xD;
and efficiencies (ABBOTT) were determined. Steinernema carpocapsae and S. feltiae achieved the&#xD;
highest efficacies. In laboratory, infestation rates in cell wells up to 91 % and efficencies up to 96 %,&#xD;
in petri dishes up to 96 %, respectively 98 %, and in plastic boxes 88 %, respectively 89 %, were&#xD;
attained. The experimental substrates like quartz sand or soil type and the tested temperatures did&#xD;
not result in consistent significant differences in laboratoy tests. A dosage below 25 nematodes per&#xD;
cm2 resulted in insufficient infestation rates. In the semi-field experiments a maximum infestation&#xD;
rate of 86 % (efficiency 78 %) and in a first field test an efficiency of 88 % was obtained. R. cerasipupae&#xD;
were not infested. These results indicate a high controlling potential of entomopathogenic&#xD;
nematodes against R cerasi, especially of the steinernematid species S. carpocapsae and S.&#xD;
feltiae. Further experiments under realistic conditions in the field are forcibly necessary before putting&#xD;
this control method into practice.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14033/1/9_Vogt_48_54.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Köppler, Kirsten; Peters, Arne and Vogt, Heidrun    (2004) Basic results in biological control of the European Cherry Fruit Fly Rhagoletis cerasi L. (Diptera: Tephritidae) with entomopathogenic nematodes.  [Erste Ergebnisse zur biologischen Bekämpfung der Kirschfruchtfliege Rhagoletis cerasi (Diptera: Tephritidae) mit entomopathogenen Nematoden.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 48-54.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14033/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>