<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Uønskete stoffer i husdyrgjødsel. &#xD;
Konvensjonell husdyrgjødsel brukt i økologisk drift - er det problematisk?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Serikstad, Grete Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McKinnon, Kirsty</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eggen, Trine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within certain restrictions, conventional animal manure can be used in organic farming when the farm’s own resources do not cover the demand for plant nutrients.&#xD;
This review came forward as a request from The Norwegian Food Safety Authority (NFSA) and The Advisory Committee for Organic Farming Regulations to gain more knowledge concerning potential contamination of manure by unwanted elements, such as residues of veterinary medicines, pesticides or high levels of heavy metals.&#xD;
Both a literature research on the topic and contact with relevant research and advisory institutions in Europe, show that there is a need to investigate the topic further. There is a lack of relevant analyses of animal manure. Methods for analysing need to be developed; and more research is needed on the uptake of harmful elements in plants.&#xD;
We recommend that a Nordic seminar is held to discuss and coordinate future research on the topic. We also suggest that The NFSA take an active part in the process due to probable changes in current regulations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioforsk</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012-12-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26726/1/BIOFORSK%20RAPPORT%20om%20u%C3%B8nska%20stofferOppdatering102012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Serikstad, Grete Lene; McKinnon, Kirsty and Eggen, Trine         (2012) Uønskete stoffer i husdyrgjødsel. Konvensjonell husdyrgjødsel brukt i økologisk drift - er det problematisk?   Bioforsk Rapport, no. Nr 28/2012. Bioforsk , Tingvoll.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26726/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>