<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Wirkungen von Maßnahmen der Verkaufsförderung bei Öko-Lebensmitteln im Handel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wild, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents and comments basis data for point of sale marketing on organic products. The research on promotions to date has been directed only toward conventional products. Therefore, the main issue of this contribution is to offer an overview of sales promotion instruments as well as evaluating different kinds of sales promotion and improving their effectiveness for organic products. This research addresses the optimal design of a series of promotions, which especially approach non-costumers and occasional customers of organic products. This study is based on a quantitative empirical method which allows comparing sales promotion effectiveness in food retailing and natural food retailing. Besides that, this report provides producers as well as retailers an appropriate performance rating of their organic product sales promotion.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3254/1/3254.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wild, Sandra    (2005) Die Wirkungen von Maßnahmen der Verkaufsförderung bei Öko-Lebensmitteln im Handel.  [Assessing the effectiveness of sales promotion on organic products.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3254/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>