<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Increasing organic food consumption through public procurement&#xD;
Findings and recommendations - With a special focus on school meals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nymoen, Lena</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This product is a leaflet (available in English and Italian)summarizing recommendations from the iPOPY research project. The project studied how increased consumption of organic food may be achieved by strategies and instruments linked to public food-serving outlets for young people. iPOPY analysed the following key aspects of public organic food procurement (POP) for youth in Italy, Denmark, Finland, Norway and to some extent in Germany: Policy issues, supply chain organization and the role of certification, users’ perceptions and participation in the food system, and the health impacts of organic food implementation. The interdisciplinary research focussed on organic school meals as the most important channel of public&#xD;
food provision for youth.&#xD;
This leaflet, addressing actors at the interface between science and practice, presents the main findings of the project and provides recommendations to specific actors, such as policy makers as well as practitioners and stake holders from the catering sector, administrations and schools or other food serving arenas.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioforsk Organic Food and Farming</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17382/1/iPOPY_recommendations_layout_final_August19.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17382/4/iPOPY_recommendations_layout_final_1005_italiano.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nölting, Benjamin and Nymoen, Lena    (2010) Increasing organic food consumption through public procurement Findings and recommendations - With a special focus on school meals.  [Forme innovative di Approvvigionamento Pubblico dei prodotti Biologici per i giovani. innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth iPOPY.]  Bioforsk Organic Food and Farming, Tingvoll, Norway.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17382/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>