<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Monetäre Auswirkungen angepassten Reifeninnendrucks im Ackerbau unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Erbsen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wolf, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Detlev</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Harald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wild, Melanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Demmel, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A goal in ecological agriculture is to avoid and reduce soil compaction. One possibility is the use of a tire inflation system (TIS). Additionally, sowing equipment with broader working width can be used. Both technologies save working time and fuel. Furthermore, yield could increase due to less soil compaction, especially for peas as field trials show. Data from the field trials and from original farms were used to calculate the profitability for the soil protection technologies. The fuel savings are enough to cover the variable and fix costs of the TIS. The pea surplus is an extra revenue. If working time reduction is additionally valued than in total the farms can gain above 19,-€/ha arable land using a TIS. The most farms have not enough traction power for broader sowers. If it exists the gain is about 26 €/ha arable land. The gain is mostly enough for the amortization of the TIS. For sowers with broader working width the amortization is only given if there is not a combined cultivation machine or it is at least a cheap one.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21407/1/21407_Wolf.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wolf, Daniel; Möller, Detlev; Schmidt, Harald; Wild, Melanie and Demmel, Markus    (2013) Monetäre Auswirkungen angepassten Reifeninnendrucks im Ackerbau unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Erbsen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21407/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>