<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Factors Influencing the Extent of Practice of Organic Farming Technologies: A Case Study of Tangail District in Bangladesh</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sarker, Md. Asaduzzaman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Itohara, Yoshihito</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study was attempted to explore the major factors influencing the extent of practice of organic farming technologies (called OFTs from here) by the Bangladeshi farmers. The empirical data for the study were collected from the organic farmers of the selected villages of Tangail district in Bangladesh. The results of the study identified four factors like development of knowledge and awareness regarding environmental issues, creation of health awareness, and simplicity of the OFTs and availability of basic production factors as the major influential factors which can increase the extent of practice of OFTs by the farmers. Taking these factors into account the policy makers can formulate a strategy to increase the extent of practice of various OFTs by the farmers for the successful expansion of organic farming in Bangladesh.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Science Publications</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Gavini, Professor  Nara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Blum, Vice Chairman &amp; Scientific Officer Kenneth</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bajbouj, Senior Psychiatrist Malek</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Amin, Associate professor Amr</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15607/1/15607.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sarker, Md. Asaduzzaman and Itohara, Yoshihito   (2008) Factors Influencing the Extent of Practice of Organic Farming Technologies: A Case Study of Tangail District in Bangladesh.   American Journal of Agricultural and Biological Sciences, 3 (3), pp. 584-590.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15607/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>