<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss des Gemengepartners Leindotter (Camelina sativa L.) auf Beikrautbesatz, Schädlingsbefall und Ertrag in Körnererbsen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ackermann, Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saucke, Dr. Helmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of mixed cropping semi-leafless peas with linseed dodder (Camelina sativa (L.) Crtz.) on weed development and pest incidence was investigated in small plot experiments in Northern Hessen, Germany, over two years. Mixed cropping peas together with linseed dodder had a significant suppressive effect on weed-coverage, in average 62 % efficacy in 2003 and 54 % in 2004, compared to mono cropped peas. The infestation level of pea aphid (Acyrthosiphon pisum) and the damage incidence of pea moth (Cydia nigricana) in harvested peas, was neither significantly reduced nor enhanced. In both years mixed cropping peas gained a relative surplus in yield compared to peas grown as a sole crop. The results demonstrate the advantageous complementary use of environmental resources in grain peas by the companion crop C. sativa and its antagonistic effect towards weed development.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3788/1/3788.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ackermann, Kerstin and Saucke, Dr. Helmut    (2005) Einfluss des Gemengepartners Leindotter (Camelina sativa L.) auf Beikrautbesatz, Schädlingsbefall und Ertrag in Körnererbsen.  [Effect of the companion crop linseed dodder (Camelina sativa L.) on weed development, pest incidence and yield in grain peas.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3788/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>