<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aufbau eines antibiotikaminimierten Eutergesundheitskonzeptes&#xD;
in Schweizerischen Biobetrieben nach Betriebssanierung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Notz, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spranger, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Individual health status depends on the individual constitution and the living conditions including all their positive and negative factors. The research areas of constitution and herd health management should produce a better understanding of the connections between constitution, living conditions and health. Results should help to create preventive strategies to guarantee high livestock health status, and not only on organic farms. Nevertheless illness is not completely avoidable. Thus the research areas of homeopathic basic research, mistletoe, and homeopathic mastitis treatment need to identify the potential and limits of complementary therapy methods. The aim of FiBL animal health research is to address all levels of animal health and to create a holistic herd health concept. The first steps taken on this path have been successful.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universität für Bodenkultur, Wien - Institut für Ökologischen Landbau</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2568/1/spranger-2003-antibiotikaminimiertes-eutergesundheitskonzept.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Notz, Christophe; Spranger, Jörg and Klocke, Peter    (2003) Aufbau eines antibiotikaminimierten Eutergesundheitskonzeptes in Schweizerischen Biobetrieben nach Betriebssanierung.       Paper at:   7. Wissenschaftstagung zum ökologischen Landbau: Ökologischer Landbau der Zukunft, Wien, 24.-26. Februar 2003.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2568/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>