<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Codling moth granulovirus: Variations in the susceptibility of local codling moth populations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fritsch, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Undorf-Spahn, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, Jutta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, Claus P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Jürg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study is part of a BMELV (German Federal Ministry for, Food, Agriculture and Consumer Protection)&#xD;
project for prevention of codling moth damage by long-term population control in large areas. Specimens&#xD;
from local codling moth populations were collected in fall 2003 from three different orchards in the South of&#xD;
Germany; two of them having been treated with granulovirus of codling moth (CpGV Madex 2 and/or Granupom)&#xD;
over many years (Lake Constance II and South Baden) and one since two years (Lake Constance I). In&#xD;
autumn 2004, specimens from populations in four other orchards with serious CM problems were collected to&#xD;
investigate whether more populations were involved in that region. Furthermore, the population Lake Constance&#xD;
I and South Baden were tested again. During the season, the location South Baden was almost&#xD;
weekly treated with 100 ml/ha of Madex 2 to test whether the level of susceptibility would change after such&#xD;
heavy treatments.&#xD;
The susceptibility of the offsprings of the overwintering generation to CpGV was investigated in the spring of&#xD;
the following year in bioassays on artificial diet and compared to a laboratory strain of the codling moth. The&#xD;
results indicated significant differences in sensitivity to the virus between the local codling moth populations.&#xD;
The LC50-values showed that in 2004, South Baden and Lake Constance II were more than thousand fold&#xD;
less susceptible than the populations Lake Constance I and the laboratory strain. The results from the bioassays&#xD;
in 2005 confirmed the low susceptibility of South Baden and of the new locations in Saarland and from&#xD;
an orchard 100 km away from South Baden. The population Lake Constance I, on the other hand, maintained&#xD;
its high sensitivity to the virus. The slope of the dose-mortality-regression lines of the unsusceptible&#xD;
populations was significantly lower than those of the susceptible ones, including that of the laboratory strain.&#xD;
This indicates a high inhomogeneity in the individual response of the unsusceptible larvae against the virus.&#xD;
Actually, the problem of reduced sensitivity to the virus seems to be limited to a few orchards in Germany, the&#xD;
majority of orchards being not affected.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13752/1/ecofruit_12th_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fritsch, Eva; Undorf-Spahn, Karin; Kienzle, Jutta; Zebitz, Claus P.W. and Huber, Jürg    (2006) Codling moth granulovirus: Variations in the susceptibility of local codling moth populations.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 7-13.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13752/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>