<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zielgruppen für Bioangebote in der Gemeinschaftsverpflegung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lüth, Maren</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiller, Prof. Dr. Achim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Enneking, Prof. Dr. Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Communal feeding institutions are a trade channel for organic food of rising importance. But up to now an elaborated ecologically oriented marketing concept in this sector is missing. The aim of this study is to develop a marketing strategy for organic food in communal feeding which addresses specific target groups. For this purpose consumption motives of 406 students in the refectories of Göttingen and Kassel were analyzed by a Brand Choice Experiment. The main result was that organic products should preferably be combined with high quality. To address an extended target group a positioning strategy combining ecological with health and hedonistic arguments is recommended. A multi segment strategy with different menu lines, appropriate for the respective target groups should be aspired.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3748/1/3748.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lüth, Maren; Spiller, Prof. Dr. Achim and Enneking, Prof. Dr. Ulrich    (2005) Zielgruppen für Bioangebote in der Gemeinschaftsverpflegung.  [Target groups for organic products in communal feeding.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3748/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>