<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Disease control in organic cherry production with new products and early plastic cover of the trees</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häseli, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel,  Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of 3 new natural fungicides to control Monilia (Monilia laxa) of sweet cherry as well as the&#xD;
effects of plastic cover during flowering period were tested in different trials on 4 organic farms in&#xD;
Switzerland during three years. Under low to medium disease pressure Serenade (Bacillus subtilis),&#xD;
Trilogy (Azadirachtin-free Neemoil) and lime sulphur reduced Monilia incidence by 30 to 60 %&#xD;
relative to control. With high disease pressure, however, non of these products had a relevant&#xD;
controlling effect.&#xD;
Covering the trees during flowering period resulted in a &gt;90 % reduction of the 3 diseases Monilia&#xD;
laxa, Clasterosporium carpophilum and Blumeriella japii. Additionally, the proportion of burst fruit&#xD;
and the loss by bloom frost was strongly reduced under plastic cover .&#xD;
The weak effect of all natural fungicides tested against Monilia laxa brings us to the conclusion that&#xD;
we will focus research on indirect measures such as plastic cover during flowering period and more&#xD;
intensive variety testing under 100 % organic production conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14458/1/24_Haeseli_122_130.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häseli, Andreas and Weibel, Franco    (2004) Disease control in organic cherry production with new products and early plastic cover of the trees.  [Krankheitsregulierung im biologischen Kirschenanbau mit neuen Produkten und einer frühzeitigen, vor der Blüte installierten Überdachung.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 122-130.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14458/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>