<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>2004 Cereals reveal an intriguing surprise: the performance of cereals on organic farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hinchsliffe, Kay</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The great variability in the performance of cereals on organic farms that we have highlighted from past research trials has been confirmed in a new and more widely based trial. Participation from 20 producers gives the results a robust character and has enabled us to spot something we had not previously noted. EFRC researchers Prof Martin Wolfe AND Kay Hinchsliffe set out the results.  &#xD;
Introduction&#xD;
EFRC is currently working on a Defra-funded project designed to use participatory research and development methodology, and is conducted on sites across the country with the participation of 20 farmers, seed producers and more than 10 researchers (EFRC, NIAB, Middlesex University, University of Kingston &amp; HDRA). The idea is to integrate the contributions of different stakeholders into developing a robust system for identifying, testing, multiplying and marketing cereal varieties, lines, mixtures, and populations best suited to organic production in different parts of the country .&#xD;
Three high quality winter wheat varieties, Hereward, Solstice and Xi 19 and their mixture, were selected for the trial based on their performance in previous years’ replicated variety trials. Participating farmers drilled each variety in strips (total area of 1/10 ha) surrounded by their own winter wheat crop. This article summarises data from the first year of field trials (2003-4); since this is the first year they should be treated with caution.  The trial is being repeated and has already been planted by essentially the same group of participating farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4186/1/4186.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wolfe, Martin and Hinchsliffe, Kay    (2005) 2004 Cereals reveal an intriguing surprise: the performance of cereals on organic farms.   Elm Farm Research Centre Bulletin, 2005 (76), pp. 5-8.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4186/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>