<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Flächenleistung und Arbeitserledigungskosten im Dammkultursystem im Ver-gleich zu einem optimierten Pflugsystem im ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rolfsmeyer, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Detlev</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cultivation methods in organic farming are controversial discussed as the traditional ploughing system faces a variety of disadvantages, especially with regard to soil con-servation. To address these problems a mound cultivation system has been devel-oped. This paper presents a case study (on-farm-research) combined with expert interviews and economic modelling results. The aims of the study are to identify the most important cost driver, to calculate the cost of mound cultivation with regard to energy consumption and labour costs and to formulate conditions where this system is economically viable. Experience from on-farm-research and modelling show that the system is in particular suitable for large farms where the field labour organisation is a challenge. Mound cultivation means less time needs, less energy consumption, better soil conservation (erosion), and better conditions for catch crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9683/1/9683_Rolfsmeyer_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rolfsmeyer, Daniel and Möller, Detlev    (2007) Flächenleistung und Arbeitserledigungskosten im Dammkultursystem im Ver-gleich zu einem optimierten Pflugsystem im ökologischen Landbau.  [Time use and production costs of mound cultivation compared to an optimized plowing system in organic farming.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9683/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>