<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biopesticides for the control of storage insect pests</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Problem &#xD;
&#xD;
Cereals are an important component of the UK diet and of livestock feedstuffs but during storage are at risk of infestation by insects which damage quality and value. Chemical pesticides have been used to control infestations but are being phased out due to concerns about perceived safety, resistance and environmental impact. Biological control offers an alternative to the use of conventional chemical agents.&#xD;
 &#xD;
   &#xD;
Project Aims &#xD;
&#xD;
The primary aim of this project is to provide the basis for a whole new class of biological pesticides for use in the storage of a wide range of commodities including cereals and oilseeds. &#xD;
 &#xD;
   &#xD;
Approach &#xD;
&#xD;
Devise novel methodology which enables a model putative biopesticide to function under simulated conditions representing storage. Develop innovative methods to maximise delivery of the agent to a range of pests under appropriate conditions. Clarify the risks that need to be considered for registration. Confirm acceptability and practicality by addressing concerns about use, validating efficacy on realistic surfaces and in a trial premises, and calculating cost.&#xD;
 &#xD;
Benefits to the industry &#xD;
&#xD;
This project will benefit the UK durables industry by &#xD;
a) providing sufficient evidence that a model biopesticide will provide a real alternative to the use of conventional pesticides for the protection of stored cereals&#xD;
b) ultimately allowing conventional pesticides to be restricted to emergency use only&#xD;
c) helping organic farmers to protect the quality of their product by storage in compliance with organic standards&#xD;
d) laying the foundations for the development of other biopesticides.  The project will benefit the pest control industry by enabling contractual obligations for freedom from pests to be achieved without exposing operatives to harmful chemicals.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Biopesticides for the control of storage insect pests.    Runs 2005 - 2009.      Project Leader(s): Chambers, Dr John, Central Science Laboratory.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6769/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>