<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Response of soil microbial biomass and community structures to conventional and organic farming systems under identical crop rotations</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Esperschütz, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schloter, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study the influence of different farming systems on microbial community structure was analyzed using soil samples from the DOK long-term field experiment in Switzerland, which comprises organic (BIODYN and BIOORG) and conventional (CONFYM and CONMIN) farming systems as well as an unfertilized control (NOFERT). We examined microbial communities in winter wheat plots at two different points in the crop rotation (after potatoes and after maize). Employing extended polar lipid analysis up to 244 different phospholipid fatty acids (PLFA) and phospholipid ether lipids (PLEL) were detected. Higher concentrations of PLFA and PLEL in BIODYN and BIOORG indicated a significant influence of organic agriculture on microbial biomass. Farmyard manure (FYM) application consistently revealed the strongest, and the preceding crop the weakest, influence on domain-specific biomass, diversity indices and microbial community structures. Esterlinked PLFA from slowly growing bacteria (k-strategists) showed the strongest responses to long-term organic fertilization. Although the highest fungal biomass was found in the two organic systems of the DOK field trial, their contribution to the differentiation of community structures according to the management regime was relatively low. Prokaryotic communities responded most strongly to either conventional or organic farming management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13315/1/Esperschuetz-FEMSME-2007.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Esperschütz, Jürgen; Gattinger, Andreas; Mäder, Paul; Schloter, Michael and Fließbach, Andreas   (2007) Response of soil microbial biomass and community structures to conventional and organic farming systems under identical crop rotations.   FEMS Microbiology Ecology, 61 (1), pp. 26-37.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13315/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>