<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Plant-availability of catch crop S following spring incorporation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Catch crops might reduce sulphate leaching and thereby increase the overall S use efficiency in crop rotations. At 2 experimental sites in Denmark (a sandy loam and a coarse sand) S uptake of catch crop species was measured. Furthermore net release of S following incorporation of this material  (S contents 0.13-1.03%, C:S ratios of 40-329 and lignin content of 1-10.8%) was investigated in a pot experiment with spring barley in sandy soil. The catch crops showed huge differences in their ability to sequester S. The best catch crops (legumes on sandy loam), sequestered 10-12 kg S ha-1 and the poorest catch crops (ryegrass and sorrel on coarse sand), sequestered less than 3 kg S ha-1. The S mineralisation rates were highest for crucifers (57-85% of total S added) and lowest for legumes (up to 46% of total S added). Differences can partly be explained by the C:S ratio, whereas no significant relationship was found with the lignin content of the incorporated catch crops. The catch crops may constitute a solution that can help avoiding S deficiency and increase synchrony between plant demand and available soil S in a crop rotation. However, the release of S will not fulfil the need of S demanding crops and even for cereals the mineralisation will most often only make a contribution. In the case of legume catch crops it is advisable to use a supplemental S source.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3173/1/3173.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J.; Thorup-Kristensen, K. and Askegaard, M.   (2004) Plant-availability of catch crop S following spring incorporation.   Journal of Plant Nutrition and Soil Science, 167, pp. 609-615.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3173/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>