<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Varieties for organic production and marketing (cont. of OF0110)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study will aim to establish whether crop varieties require dedicated organic trials or whether advice on their performance under organic conditions can be extrapolated from conventional trial data. A number of varieties from different vegetable types will be selected for their expected suitability for production under organic conditions. Selected varieties will be used in trials examining parameters such as speed of emergence and establishment, total and marketable yields, quality attributes, pest resistance and incidence of disease. The establishment of reliable data with these crops will allow additional advice to be provided to organic growers on the most appropriate variety and husbandry techniques to obtain maximum marketable yield of good quality produce. Additional data on extending the supply period from home grown produce would benefit producers and should reduce imports. Results of the study will be disseminated through annual reports circulated via the NIAB Vegetable Associate Scheme, in horticultural and organic literature and at an open day.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Varieties for organic production and marketing (cont. of OF0110).    Runs 1996 - 1997.      Project Leader(s): Unspecified, , National Institute of Agricultural Botany.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7942/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>