<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Digestibility in selected rainbow trout families and modelling of growth from the specific intake of &#xD;
digestible protein</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jokumsen, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The experiments aimed to clarify variations in digestibility of dietary nutrients in rainbow trout. Furthermore, the objective was to study how differences in digestibility might be related to growth and feed utilisation at various growth rates.  When comparing the results from the experiments it appeared that particularly protein digestibility was closely related to specific growth rate and feed conversion ratio at high growth rates. As a tool to visualise the relationship between protein digestibility and growth of rainbow trout a growth model was developed based on the specific intake of digestible protein, and general assumptions on protein content and protein retention efficiency in rainbow trout. The model indicated that increased protein digestibility only partly explained growth increase and that additional factors were important for growth increment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18750/1/18750.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Richard and Jokumsen, Alfred    (2008) Digestibility in selected rainbow trout families and modelling of growth from the specific intake of digestible protein.   Aquaculture International, 17 (2), pp. 187-197.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18750/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>