<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Instant infusion pasteurisation of bovine milk. II. Effects on indigenous milk enzymes activity and whey protein denaturation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hammershøj, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hougaard, A.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vestergaard, J.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poulsen, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ipsen, R.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Direct heat treatment of two milk types, skimmed and non-standardised, was performed by instant steam infusion and compared with indirect heating. Infusion conditions were temperatures of 72-120°C combined with holding times of 100-700 ms, and indirect heat conditions were 72°C/15s and 85°C/30 s. The activity of indigenous enzymes; alkaline phosphatase, lactoperoxidase, xanthine oxidase and -glutamyl transpeptidase was evaluated. Mainly the infusion temperature was determinant for inactivation. Whey protein denaturation represented by -lactoglobulin increased significantly with infusion temperature. The non-standardised milk had a higher denaturation rate than skimmed milk. The effect of instant infusion on pH and milk fat globule size in relation to whey protein denaturation and association is discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Wiley-Blackwell</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-12-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16581/1/16581.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hammershøj, M.; Hougaard, A.B.; Vestergaard, J.S.; Poulsen, O. and Ipsen, R.H.   (2009) Instant infusion pasteurisation of bovine milk. II. Effects on indigenous milk enzymes activity and whey protein denaturation.   International Journal of Dairy Technology.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16581/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>