<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil organism in organic and conventional cropping systems.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bettiol, Wagner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ghini, Raquel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Galvão, José Abrahão Haddad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ligo, Marcos Antônio Vieira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mineiro, Jeferson Luiz de Carvalho</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Despite the recent interest in organic agriculture, little research has been carried out in this area. Thus, the objective of this study was to compare, in a dystrophic Ultisol, the effects of organic and conventional agricultures on soil organism populations, for the tomato (Lycopersicum esculentum) and corn (Zea mays) crops. In general, it was found that fungus, bacterium and actinomycet populations counted by the number of colonies in the media, were similar for the two cropping systems. CO2 evolution during the cropping season was higher, up to the double for the organic agriculture system as compared to the conventional. The number of earthworms was about ten times higher in the organic system. There was no difference in the decomposition rate of organic matter of the two systems. In general, the number of microartropods was always higher in the organic plots in relation to the conventional ones, reflectining on the Shannon index diversity. The higher insect population belonged to the Collembola order, and in the case of mites, to the superfamily Oribatuloidea. Individuals of the groups Aranae, Chilopoda, Dyplopoda, Pauropoda, Protura and Symphyla were occasionally collected in similar number in both cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22415/1/Bettiol_Soil.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bettiol, Wagner ; Ghini, Raquel ; Galvão, José Abrahão Haddad ; Ligo, Marcos Antônio Vieira  and Mineiro, Jeferson Luiz de Carvalho    (2002) Soil organism in organic and conventional cropping systems.  [Organismos do solo em sistemas de cultivo orgânico e convencional.]  Scientia Agricola, 59 (3), pp. 565-572.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22415/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>