<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainability Aspects of Automatic Milking Systems (AMS) in Organic Dairy Production in Denmark and the Netherlands.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oudshoorn, Frank W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de  Boer, Imke J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Renes, Reint Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Use of new technology can contribute to sustainable development, but a careful assessment should be made. Using a theoretical framework, the economical, ecological and societal consequences for sustainability are assessed and translated.  Selected sustainability indicators are validated though literature and evaluated by a participatory method; the focus group interview.  There are no reports or references to research on organic dairy farms with AMS. By cross examining references on AMS use with organic principles and sustainability aspects, it can be foreseen that economy, eutrophication of grassland, and milk quality can be threats to sustainability.  Advisors and farmers represent the stakeholders in production. There were differences in perceptions among Dutch and Danish advisors, as well as between advisors and farmers. Economy is more often mentioned among Dutch advisors, but grazing and milk quality clearly concerned all participants in the focus groups. Participants often referred to consumers and animal welfare.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4438/3/Oudshoorn_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oudshoorn, Frank W.; de Boer, Imke J.M. and Renes, Reint Jan    (2005) Sustainability Aspects of Automatic Milking Systems (AMS) in Organic Dairy Production in Denmark and the Netherlands.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4438/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>