<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Des bilans de phosphore majoritairement négatifs pour les systèmes de grandes cultures biologiques sans élevage en Midi-Pyrénées.&#xD;
Quels impacts sur le phosphore biodisponible des sols et l’état de nutrition des cultures ?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>COLOMB, Bruno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jouany, Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prieur , Loic</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil phosphorus (P) fertility management in organic cropping systems is a debated issue in the general context of decreasing resources in a near future. A survey showed that in Midi-Pyrenees a majority of stockless organic cropping systems present overdrawn P balances. We investigated the impacts of P balances on the soil plant available P and nutrition status on the long-term field experiment of La Hourre (CREAB, Auch, France), which is representative of rainfed systems set on clayey calcareous soils. The changes in soil plant available P were monitored between 2002 and 2012 using P Olsen soil test. The results specified the declining rate of P availability in time and according to the amplitude of the negative balance. The levels of soil available P did not still lead to degradation of the crop P nutrition status; in this context, N inputs are low, so consequently crop P needs remain limited. However the problems associated with long term management of soil P fertility remain. Beyond the desirable scientific perspectives, we propose a first analysis of the factors on which it would be relevant to act in order to allow the farmers to improve their practices.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26231/1/Colomb_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>COLOMB, Bruno; Jouany, Claire and Prieur , Loic   (2013) Des bilans de phosphore majoritairement négatifs pour les systèmes de grandes cultures biologiques sans élevage en Midi-Pyrénées. Quels impacts sur le phosphore biodisponible des sols et l’état de nutrition des cultures ?  [Most of stockless organic farming systems in the Midi-Pyrenees region display negative field P budget. What are the impact on soil P fertility and plant P status?]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 73-82.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26231/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>