<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Direkte und indirekte Verfahren zur Bestimmung der Mehlqualität von Öko-Weizensorten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Linnemann, Ludger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Direct and indirect methods for determining the technological flour quality of modern wheat varieties with high gluten quality have been assessed. Direct methods like the commonly used Rapid-Mix-Test (RMT) and an optimized baking test were compared to the indirect parameters gluten and crude protein. The results for the optimized baking test in 2007 showed more than 30 % higher loaf volume (713 ml/100 g flour) compared with the RMT (544 ml/100 g flour). In this selection of varieties, the determination of wet gluten between two laboratories showed no consistency in the results. In addition to that, very good flour quality (&gt;660 ml/100 g flour) started on a relatively low crude protein level of flours &gt; 9,0 %, but low correlations were obtained for crude protein (%) and gluten (%) for the loaf volume. The results underline that the loaf volumes depend on the specific gluten qualities for varieties and the kind of dough processing. The optimised baking test is therefore crucial in assessing the potential of bread making quality for wheat varieties, to ensure good bread wheat performance in organic farming. Because of the present results, the current demands on the quality of flours must be revised.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21572/1/21572_Linnemann.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Linnemann, Ludger    (2013) Direkte und indirekte Verfahren zur Bestimmung der Mehlqualität von Öko-Weizensorten.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21572/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>