<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genotypbedingte Veränderungen der Proteinqualität bei der Gärfutterbereitung von Rotklee</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krawutschke, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weiher, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gierus, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thaysen, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ensilage of red clover results in lower concentrations of non-protein nitrogen compared to other forage legumes. It is assumed that the polyphenol oxidase (PPO) activity in red clover is related to this effect. Therefore, a laboratory ensiling trial was carried out to quantify the changes in crude protein (CP) fractions during the ensiling process using the Cornell Net Carbohydrate and Protein System. At four cutting dates, fresh, wilted and ensiled herbage of three red clover genotypes and white clover grown in two systems (with and without mechanical stress) was sampled. The specific PPO activity was measured photometrically in fresh leaves of the plants. Concentrations of fraction A increased from 130-197 g/kg CP to 372-544 g/kg CP during the fermentation process leading to a drop in true protein, primarily fraction B1. The most important source of variance was the ensiling stage, except for fraction C. Despite of differences in protein fractions between genotypes, these variations can not be explained by the specific PPO activity.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17345/3/Krawutschke_17345.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krawutschke, Manuel; Weiher, Nina; Gierus, Martin; Thaysen, Johannes and Taube, Friedhelm    (2011) Genotypbedingte Veränderungen der Proteinqualität bei der Gärfutterbereitung von Rotklee.  [Genotypic impacts on changes in protein quality during the ensilage of red clover.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17345/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>