<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>pro-Q: Auswirkungen eines Bestandesbetreuungsprojektes auf&#xD;
Eutergesundheit, Antibiotikaeinsatz, Nutzungsdauer und Milchleistung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Notz, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maeschli, Ariane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Staehli, Pamela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 2003, the Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) is realizing a herd&#xD;
health management programme (“pro-Q” project) focussing on udder health and the&#xD;
use of homeopathic based treatment and prevention. Aims of the project are: (1) to&#xD;
reduce antibiotic mastitis treatments, (2) to optimize udder health and (3) to improve&#xD;
longevity, measured as averaged herd lactation number. The farms get expert advice&#xD;
on prevention and treatment at herd- and animal-level. After 2 years, treatment recordings&#xD;
of the 78 investigated farms showed that antibiotic mastitis therapies were&#xD;
reduced from 37 to 26 treatments per 100 cows and year (equals a reduction of 28%).&#xD;
The mean herd lactation number increased significantly by 0.2 lactations from 3.3 to&#xD;
3.5 lactations per cow. Udder health remained constant over all farms during 2 years:&#xD;
theoretical bulk milk cell counts averaged constantly at approximately 180'000&#xD;
cells/ml.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14476/1/Notz_14476.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Notz, Christophe; Klocke, Peter; Walkenhorst, Michael; Maeschli, Ariane; Staehli, Pamela and Ivemeyer, Silvia    (2009) pro-Q: Auswirkungen eines Bestandesbetreuungsprojektes auf Eutergesundheit, Antibiotikaeinsatz, Nutzungsdauer und Milchleistung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14476/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>