<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Symbiotische N2 Fixierung und N–Bilanz von Soja unter Be-rücksichtigung der N-Rhizodeposition im DOK Versuch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hammelehle, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Torsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Symbiotic N2 fixation (Nfix) and N-balance was determined from organic and conven-tional grown soybean in the DOK experiment (Switzerland). Nfix was calculated i) based solely on soybean aboveground N (AGN) and ii) additionally taking into account belowground N (BGN), comprising N in physical roots and N rhizodeposition. Nfix was averagely two times higher considering AGN and BGN, ranging from 22 g N m-2 (conventional manure) to 37 g N m-2 (conventional mineral). N balances were positive in all treatments, but with 2 – 7 g N m-2 based on AGN solely comparatively small. These values were exceeded fourfold when considering BGN ranging from 13 g N m-2 (conventional manure) to 21 g N m-2 (organic and conventional mineral).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21426/1/21426_hammelehle.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hammelehle, Andreas; Müller, Torsten; Oberson, Astrid; Mäder, Paul and Mayer, Jochen    (2013) Symbiotische N2 Fixierung und N–Bilanz von Soja unter Be-rücksichtigung der N-Rhizodeposition im DOK Versuch.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21426/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>