<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zum Einfluss von Standort und Sorte auf Ertrag, Sortierung und Qualität von ökologisch erzeugten Kartoffeln für die Verarbeitung zu Chips</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Dipl.Ing. agr Thorsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Dipl.Ing. agr Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, Prof. Dr. Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Dr. Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Dr. Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Dr. Norbert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Previous experiments (2000-2001) suggested a strong impact of the site on which organic potatoes are cultivated on the quality of tubers for processing to crisps. In 2003 and 2004, six varieties were selected to be examined consequently on three different sites. Total and graded yield was affected by variety and site. Dry matter content of all varieties was on each site above the required level of 235 %. Reducing sugar content of tubers after harvest was very low and crisps quality very high, only after a storage period varieties could be differentiated. Cautious recommendations of varieties for organic crisp production are given in the paper.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3831/1/3831.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Haase, Dipl.Ing. agr Thorsten; Krause, Dipl.Ing. agr Tanja; Heß, Prof. Dr. Jürgen; Böhm, Dr. Herwart; Loges, Dr. Ralf and Haase, Dr. Norbert    (2005) Zum Einfluss von Standort und Sorte auf Ertrag, Sortierung und Qualität von ökologisch erzeugten Kartoffeln für die Verarbeitung zu Chips.  [Effect of site and variety on yield and quality of organic potatoes for processing to crisps.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3831/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>