<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PICKFIBER</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>PICKFIBER is an international platform of experts on the development, testing and data managing of novel food components based on organic food fibers with specific properties to fight obesity and associated conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Estonian University of Life Science is leading WP1 - Compendium of organic vs conventional food.  To produce a scientific review report about organic and conventional food quality studies and effects on human health for the scientific advisors of the European Safety Food Authority and innovative agro-food companies.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Report „QUALITY OF ORGANIC vs CONVENTIONAL FOOD AND EFFECTS ON HEALTH” will contain six chapters: &#xD;
1.Quality concept of food&#xD;
2.Harmful components in food&#xD;
3.Nutritional value of the organic vs conventional plant products&#xD;
4.Nutritional value of organic vs conventional animal products&#xD;
5.Animal experiments&#xD;
6.The impact of organic food on human health&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
The report analyses beside nutritional quality of food, also the health effects of pesticide residues, nitrates, mycotoxins and artificial additives and gives overview of animal and human experiments. &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Authors: Darja Matt, Ewa Rembialkowska, Anne Luik, Elen Peetsmann, Sirli Pehme&#xD;
&#xD;
Report will be available at the end of October 2011.&#xD;
&#xD;
PICKFIBER is the subproject of Innovation for Welfare project (co-financed by the ERDF and made possible by the INTERREG IVC programme).</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    PICKFIBER.    Runs 2010 - 2011.      Project Leader(s): Matt, Darja, Estonian University of Life Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19311/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>