<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zur Genotyp-Umwelt-Interaktion von Fleischqualitätsmerkmalen bei unterschiedlichen Genotypen in ökologischer und konventioneller Schweinemast</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Horst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baulain, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brade, Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köhler, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weißmann, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Seven different pig breeds were kept under conventional and under organic feeding and housing conditions on two performance testing stations to analyse genotype-environment interactions for meat quality traits. Genetically controlled physical pork quality traits like pH- and EC-values are unaffected by both housing and feeding systems and no genotype-environment interaction could be found. In contrast, chemical meat characteristics like intramuscular fat content and fatty acid pattern are strongly influenced by genotype and feeding and a significant genotype-environment interaction. But no considerable reranking could be observed. The differences are caused by the differences in energy and amino acid supply between environments and variable lean meat synthesis capacity of the various genotypes. The significance is mainly generated by varying differences between environments within genotypes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17515/3/Brandt_17515.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brandt, Horst; Werner, Daniela; Baulain, Ulrich; Brade, Wilfried; Köhler, Peter and Weißmann, Friedrich    (2011) Zur Genotyp-Umwelt-Interaktion von Fleischqualitätsmerkmalen bei unterschiedlichen Genotypen in ökologischer und konventioneller Schweinemast.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17515/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>