<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Individualisten zwischen Tradition und Selbstverwirklichung:&#xD;
Öko-Pioniere im sozialen Wandel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schick, Alissa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Helmle, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Alternative way of live, self-determination and autonomy were key words characterising&#xD;
organic oriented farmers in the past. It seems that such values were part of organic&#xD;
pioneers’ personal identity at a time when organic farming was not well accepted in&#xD;
politics and society. However, what can we learn from these pioneers’ experiences&#xD;
and their particular ways of interpreting social life, overcoming critical life phases and&#xD;
farm development? Based on the theories of social change and social movements 13&#xD;
semi-structured interviews with farmers practising organic-farming over a period of&#xD;
approximately 30 years were conducted. The autobiographical reports reveal that the&#xD;
willingness to create something new, perseverance and stress tolerance are among&#xD;
the characteristics, which stimulated and orientated the pioneers’ behaviour. These&#xD;
characteristics are still required within the current “bio-boom” because of the need for&#xD;
continued development in this sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14366/1/Schick_14366.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schick, Alissa and Helmle, Simone    (2009) Individualisten zwischen Tradition und Selbstverwirklichung: Öko-Pioniere im sozialen Wandel.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14366/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>