<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performance of roquette crop fertilized with cattle and green manure using two planting densities.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pimentel, Márcio Sampaio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Togun, Adeniyi Olumuyiwa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guerra, José Guilherme Marinho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De-Polli, Helvécio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This research was conducted to study the direct fertilization combining 0 and 160 kg N ha-1 of cattle manure and green manure as branches of pigeon pea (Cajanus cajan L.) and their residual effects on two population densities of roquette (Eruca sativa Miller) crop, in Seropédica, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Yield, number of leaves plant-1, leaf area index, shoot fresh weight, stems dry matter, roots dry matter, leaves dry matter, total dry matter and plant height were measured. The experiment was a randomized block design set as a factorial 2 x 2 x 2, and three replications: 0 and 160 kg N ha-1 of cattle manure, 0 and 160 kg N ha-1 of branches of pigeon pea and 500,000 and 1,000,000 plants ha-1. The results indicate that the population density of 500,000 plants ha-1 showed, in general, better results in terms of yield per plant. However, 1,000,000 plants ha-1 had significantly higher yield per hectare. It was observed that there was no significant difference between the use of cattle manure and branches of pigeon pea on the yield of roquette under directly fertilization and residual effect of fertilization. The replacement of cattle manure by branches of pigeon pea associated with 1,000,000 plants ha-1 showed less loss of roquette yield under the residual effect of fertilization.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24535/1/Pimentel_Performance.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pimentel, Márcio Sampaio; Togun, Adeniyi Olumuyiwa; Guerra, José Guilherme Marinho and De-Polli, Helvécio   (2010) Performance of roquette crop fertilized with cattle and green manure using two planting densities.  [Desempenho da cultura de rúcula submetida a adubação verde e esterco bovino utilizando duas densidades de plantio.]  Revista Brasileira de Agroecologia, 5 (2), pp. 139-148.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24535/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>