<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heritage plants in historic gardens - case Jokioinen Manor Park, Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hartikainen, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Antonius, Kristiina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Veteläinen, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Owners of the manors have multiplied the biodiversity of horticultural plants in&#xD;
Finland by importing the seeds and seedlings abroad to their gardens over the&#xD;
last three hundred years. For many reasons in manor gardens are only some of&#xD;
these heritage plants left, like roses, perennials and ornamentals shrubs. We have&#xD;
developed a method for gathering knowledge of original plants in historic gardens&#xD;
and for rediscovering and repatriating them as heritage plants back to the&#xD;
gardens. This method includes an inventory of the existing cultural flora, search&#xD;
for the lost vegetation (so called run-a-away-plants) and gathering the cultural&#xD;
knowledge of the plants. In our case study we rediscovered several original plant&#xD;
strains originating from Jokioinen manor in Southern Finland. In this paper we will&#xD;
also demonstrate some ideas on how to bring out the cultural history of plants to&#xD;
visitors in historical gardens.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19712/1/parks.docx</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hartikainen, Merja; Antonius, Kristiina and Veteläinen, Merja    (2011) Heritage plants in historic gardens - case Jokioinen Manor Park, Finland.       Paper at:   Biodiversity in agriculture - lessons learned and future directions, NJF seminar 436, Ulvik in Hardanger, Norway, 24-26 May 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19712/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>