<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>RAPD markers for the characterization of the olive fruit fly parasitoid Opius concolor (Spzel.) used in biological control programs.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>ALBAKRI, Mamoun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The endoparasitoid Opius concolor (Spzel.) has been used as a biological control agent in the biological control programs of the olive fruit fly, which consists of massive releases of parasitoid in fields where indigenous wild types are present. Field differentiation between the released and the indigenous parasitoids, and the estimation of the proportion of released individuals in the overall field population are a prerequisite to estimate the efficiency of the biological control programs. Because wild and released parasitoids are morphologically indistinguishable, a DNA molecular technique, based on Polymerase chain reaction (PCR), the Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA (RAPD-PCR) was used to differentiate between five different populations of this parasitoid, two populations from Jordan, two populations from South Italy and reared strain population. The polymorphism generated by RAPD-PCR method showed that it is highly possible to differentiate between strains of Opius concolor from distinct geographical areas of different countries (Jordan, Italy), between strains of distinct geographical areas of the same country and between wild indigenous and reared strains.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6867/1/MamounAlbakri04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ALBAKRI, Mamoun   (2004) RAPD markers for the characterization of the olive fruit fly parasitoid Opius concolor (Spzel.) used in biological control programs.  [Marqueurs RAPD pour la caractérisation de l’Opius concolor (Spzel.) le parasitoïde de la mouche de l’olivier utilisé dans les programmes de lutte biologique.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 348. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6867/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>