<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die gute alte Fruchtfolge als Bekämpfungsmethode gegen den&#xD;
Maiswurzelbohrer (Diabrotica virgifera virgifera LeConte)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bertossa, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaub, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Colombi, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Diabrotica virgifera virgifera (Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae), the western corn rootworm&#xD;
(WCR), is an immigrant from North America and one of the top ten global agricultural&#xD;
pest species. Within the last 15 years, WCR invaded Europe at 3 focal points, and has&#xD;
been steadily extending its domain soon threatening commercial maize production.&#xD;
After the first detection in Switzerland in 2000 near Lugano, careful observations by&#xD;
pheromone trap monitoring of this quarantine organism have been realized.&#xD;
Experiences with WCR whose populations dynamics are incompletely understood,&#xD;
have also been studied by installing a continuous maize field comparing population&#xD;
dynamics with rotated maize fields in the immediate surroundings. Our experiences&#xD;
with WCR populations in the Swiss territory are here briefly summarized:&#xD;
1. Mandatory crop rotation in the canton Ticino slowed spread of WCR significantly.&#xD;
WCR infestations north of the main Alpine mountain chain were rare and eradicated&#xD;
by crop rotation. 2. In a continuous maize cropping system population of WCR can&#xD;
reach economic damage level, but can also be confined by unknown factors 3.&#xD;
Switzerland with its rigorous crop rotation program may serve as an example of farsighted&#xD;
WCR management preserving environment and saving money.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14414/1/Bertossa_14414.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bertossa, M.; Schaub, L. and Colombi, L.    (2009) Die gute alte Fruchtfolge als Bekämpfungsmethode gegen den Maiswurzelbohrer (Diabrotica virgifera virgifera LeConte).       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14414/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>