<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EcoOrchard. Innovative design and management to boost functional biodiversity of organic orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic tree fruit quality and yield are often reduced (10 - &gt;80%) because of insect and pest damage. No effective control measures exist for many of these pests. This increases economic risk and can reduce growers’ motivation to develop organic production. At the same time, there is a large potential for organic apple production as consumers become increasingly interested in organic food. The aim of the project is to reduce pest damage and pesticide use by increasing on farm functional (agro)-biodiversity (FAB). The two main expected outcomes of ECOORCHARD are to a) identify common assessment methods and compare these to new approaches to increase FAB and b) recommend a method suitable for monitoring FAB on farms and in scientific trials.  Methods will be developed in close collaboration with growers, which will increase successful on-farm implementation. The project investigations will take place in nine different countries in Europe and the outcome will be relevant for growers in the whole EU region</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28698/2/28698.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EcoOrchard: EcoOrchard. Innovative design and management to boost functional biodiversity of organic orchards.    Runs 2015 - 2017.      Project Leader(s): Sigsgaard, Assoc Prof Lene, University of Copenhagen.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28698/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>