<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of "Boni-Protect" - a yeast preparation for use in the control of postharvest diseases of apples</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weiss, Armin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mögel, Gudrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kunz, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Postharvest pathogens cause major losses in apple production. Gloeosporium album (Pezicula alba) and Gloeosporium perennans (Pezicula malicorticis) are the main pathogens in organic fruit growing. There are several microorganisms with an antagonistic efficency against these fungi. Out of these organisms two yeast isolates have been chosen to develop the plant strengthener Boni-Protect. Boni-Protect reduced the symp-tom development of P. malicorticis, B. cinerea and P. expansum after artificial inoculation of apple wounds. In several field trials preharvest applications of Boni-Protect led to reduced disease development during stor-age.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8838/1/ecofruit_12th_20.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weiss, Armin; Mögel, Gudrun and Kunz, Stefan    (2006) Development of "Boni-Protect" - a yeast preparation for use in the control of postharvest diseases of apples.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Weinsberg, Germany, pp. 113-117.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8838/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>