<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Environmental impacts of a lunch plate - challenges in interpreting the LCA results</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kurppa, Sirpa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grönroos, Juha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hyvärinen, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katajajuuri, Juha-Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kauppinen, Tommi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäkelä, Johanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nissinen, Ari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nousiainen, Jouni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saarinen, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Usva, Kirsi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Viinisalo, Mirja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Virtanen, Yrjö</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The challenges of the project were to reveal and interpret complex and contrasting environmental issues associated with food by consumers, in order to build up more comprehensive understanding on LCA results as measures of sustainability.&#xD;
&#xD;
This approach was to linked to the specific example of lunch plates. Expertise from various scientific fields was used to identify the key environmental issues; food chain stakeholders to provide appropriate environmental data for LCA, consumer researchers to link that with the food consumption framework, and teaching experts to introduce pedagogic aspects into the lunch plate presentation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Finland Futures Research Centre, Turku School of Economics</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16409/1/consumer5.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kurppa, Sirpa; Grönroos, Juha; Hyvärinen, Helena; Katajajuuri, Juha-Matti; Kauppinen, Tommi; Mäkelä, Johanna; Nissinen, Ari; Nousiainen, Jouni; Saarinen, Merja; Usva, Kirsi; Viinisalo, Mirja and Virtanen, Yrjö    (2009) Environmental impacts of a lunch plate - challenges in interpreting the LCA results.   In:     FFRC eBOOK, Finland Futures Research Centre, Turku School of Economics, pp. 185-193.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16409/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>