<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The nematicidal and the fertilizing effect of argan, castro and neem cake on cucurbits (cucumber and melon) grown under greenhouse in Agadir region (South of Morocco).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>AZIM, Khalid</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work is to evaluate the impact of oil cake amendments (argan, neem, castor cake and ground castor) on control of Meloidogyne spp., soil fertility, and the growth and yield of cucumber grown under greenhouse in south-western Morocco. The results show that oil cakes induce a reduction in gall formation, soil nematodes density, root rot infestation, and an improvement of plant height and yield as compared to the control. Argan cake improved yield by 112% compared to the control. Generally, argan cake gave better results compared to the other treatments. In pots experiment on melon, maximum suppression (100%) of root knots and soil larvae population were found with argan, castor cake and ground argan shoot; while neem cake was less effective. Argan cake resulted in 24% increase in fresh weight compared to the infested control, while ground argan shoot enormously decreased both height and weight.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7012/1/Azimkhalid05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>AZIM, Khalid   (2005) The nematicidal and the fertilizing effect of argan, castro and neem cake on cucurbits (cucumber and melon) grown under greenhouse in Agadir region (South of Morocco).  [L’effet nématicide et fertilisant des tourteaux d’argan, ricin et neem sur les cucurbitacées (concombre et melon) cultivées sous serre dans la région d’Agadir (sud du Maroc).]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 406. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7012/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>