<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performance of Organic Grain Cropping Systems in Long-Term Experiments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Teasdale, John R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cavigelli, Michel A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming and conventional no-tillage farming systems share many of the same benefits from protecting and improving soils.  A review of recent results from two long-term systems experiments in the mid-Atlantic region of the U.S.A. demonstrates that organic cropping systems with organic amendments can increase soil carbon, nitrogen, and yield potential more than conventional no-tillage, despite the use of tillage in organic systems.  However, reduced-tillage organic systems present challenges for weed control, particularly with simple rotations typical of conventional grain cropping systems.  Organic systems that employ more complex rotations including a hay crop have demonstrated greater potential for improved weed control, increased nitrogen availability, and increased yields.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11539/1/Teasdale_11539_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Teasdale, John R. and Cavigelli, Michel A.    (2008) Performance of Organic Grain Cropping Systems in Long-Term Experiments.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11539/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>