<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Empfehlungen zum Einsatz des klassisch-homöopathischen Behandlungsverfahrens bei der Therapie der akuten katarrhalischen Mastitis des Rindes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sobiraj, Axel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The EU-Regulation (No. 2092/91) postulates that homeopathic and phytotherapeutic remedies shall be used in preference to allopathic products chemically synthesised, provided that their therapeutic effect is proven. However, in the literature only few scientific data are available. The objective of a clinical control trial was to examine the effectiveness of the classical homeopathic treatment in the case of bovine clinical mastitis in comparison to the chemotherapeutic treatment and to a control group given a placebo. In the trial only cases of mild or moderate acute clinical mastitis caused by environmental associated pathogens and cases with negative bacteriological result in the milk sample were enclosed. A number of 147 quarters affected with acute clinical mastitis were treated. 56 days after beginning of the treatment, 30.8% of the cows with positive bacteriological status at day 0 given homeopathic treatment were cured in contrast to 4.3% in the placebo-group. The chemotherapeutic treatment resulted in 24.1% cured cases. The differences in healing between the homeopathic and the placebo group were significant (p&lt;0.05), while the difference between the homeopathic and chemotherapeutic therapy regime was not. The results indicate that there is a therapeutic effect of homeopathic treatment in case of mild or moderate clinical mastitis, but the proof of effectiveness is closely related to the inclusion criteria and to the comprehensive procedure of diagnosis.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9542/1/9542_Werner_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Werner, Christina; Sundrum, Albert and Sobiraj, Axel    (2007) Empfehlungen zum Einsatz des klassisch-homöopathischen Behandlungsverfahrens bei der Therapie der akuten katarrhalischen Mastitis des Rindes.  [Recommendations for using the homeopathic treatment strategy in the case of bovine clinical mastitis.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9542/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>