<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studies on the attractional effect of root exudates on hyphal growth of an arbuscular mycorrhizal fungus in a soil compartment-membrane system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vierheilig, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alt-Hug, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Engel-Streitwolf, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiemken, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effects of tomato and bean rhizospheres on hyphal spreading of the arbuscular mycorrhizal (AM) fungus Glomus mosseae were studied using a soil compartment system in combination with hydrophobic polytetrafluorethylene (PTFE) membranes. Both the nylon screen and the PTFE membrane were freely permeable to hyphae but not to roots. Furthermore, the hydrophobic PTFE membrane seemed to be a barrier to the flux of soil solutions containing root exudates. The results show that water soluble exudates of tomato and bean roots greatly stimulate hyphal growth in the soil compartment system used. Moreover, water soluble root exudates of bean exert a clear attractional effect on AM hyphal growth.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>1998</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26774/1/Vierheilig_et_al_1998_PS_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vierheilig, H.; Alt-Hug, M.; Engel-Streitwolf, R.; Mäder, P. and Wiemken, A.   (1998) Studies on the attractional effect of root exudates on hyphal growth of an arbuscular mycorrhizal fungus in a soil compartment-membrane system.   Plant and Soil, 203, pp. 137-144.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26774/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>