<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mobile and stationary systems for pigs – nutrient excretion, distribution on outdoor areas and environmental impact</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Salomon, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benfalk, Christel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindahl, Cecilia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindgren, Kristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objectives of this study were to quantify fluxes and balances of N, P, K, Cu and Zn in two organic fattening pig outdoor systems, to quantify the load of nutrients in different sub-areas through behavioural studies of defecation and urination and to make an environmental risk assessment. The study forms part of a larger project with the aim of identifying a joint strategy. The outdoor area balance was calculated for N, P, K, Cu and Zn. Total calculated amounts of N, P, K, Cu and Zn in manure were distributed between outdoor sub-areas according to ratios determined in behavioural studies of defecation and urination and by manure mapping. Some proposals for improving the nutrient management and decreasing the negative environmental impact in different outdoor systems are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4463/4/Salomon_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Salomon, Eva; Benfalk, Christel; Lindahl, Cecilia and Lindgren, Kristina    (2005) Mobile and stationary systems for pigs – nutrient excretion, distribution on outdoor areas and environmental impact.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4463/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>