<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Applications de soufre en automne: une nouvelle manière de lutter contre l`ériophyide à galles du poirier.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Linder, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Autumn applications of sulphur – a new approach to control the pear leaf blister mite Eriophyes pyri.&#xD;
Abstract: The pear leaf blister mite can cause severe damage to pear leaves and young fruits in some regions. Due to hidden living inside leaf blisters, the mites are largely protected against the impact of plant protecting agents. Until now, treatments with mineral oil or rape oil in early spring, during the time when the mites leave their hibernation sites under the bud scales to invade the young leaves and blossoms, are the only possibility to control these mites in Swiss organic fruit growing. The aim of this study was to examine the effects of sulphur, mineral oil and Surround®WP applied after harvest during the time, when the mites leave their blisters and migrate to their hibernation sites. The different treatments were applied shortly after harvest to benefit from the mild temperatures in September. Counting the number of mites after dissection of the buds in laboratory in autumn and spring showed a good efficacy for all treatments. But the visual control in spring during bloom could not verify these results for all treatments. Only the sulphur-treated trees were virtually free of blisters in spring. With a corrected efficacy (Abbott’s formula) of 95% (one application in autumn) or 100% (three applications), respectively, even a cleaning-up of heavily infested orchards is possible.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Revue suisse de viticulture arboriculture horticulture</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6139/1/daniel-2004_04SchwefelPockenmilbeRSVAH.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia; Wyss, Eric and Linder, Christian   (2004) Applications de soufre en automne: une nouvelle manière de lutter contre l`ériophyide à galles du poirier.  [Autumn applications of sulphur – a new approach to control the pear leaf blister mite Eriophyes pyri.]  Revue suisse de viticulture arboriculture horticulture, pp. 199-203.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6139/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>