<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil carbon sequestration of organic crop and livestock systems and potential for accreditation by carbon markets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>M체ller, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H채ni, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oehen, Bernadette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During a two-day RTOACC workshop hosted by the Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), participants discussed the potential for organic agriculture in carbon markets and the need to develop strategies for the role of organic agriculture in climate policy. To move in this direction requires quantifying and raising recognition of the mitigation potential of organic agriculture. Thus the participants also looked at available data and began a process of identifying data gaps. In doing so, they presented the related ongoing work of their organizations and drew conclusions for the further orientation and actions of the RTOACC.&#xD;
The following synthesizes the discussions, reports and outcomes of the workshop.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21773/1/Gattinger-etal-2012-Kapitel2-ausRTOACCbericht-p10-31.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gattinger, Andreas; M체ller, Adrian; H채ni, Matthias; Oehen, Bernadette; Stolze, Matthias and Niggli, Urs    (2011) Soil carbon sequestration of organic crop and livestock systems and potential for accreditation by carbon markets.    In:     Organic agriculture and climate change mitigation - A report of the Round Table on Organic Agriculture and Climate Change .  Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), Natural Resources Management and Environment Department, Rome, Italy, chapter 2, pp. 10-31.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21773/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>