<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Occurrence and importance of plant-parasitic nematodes in organic farming in Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hallmann, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frankenberg, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paffrath, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Harald</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In an attempt to evaluate the occurrence and economic importance of plant-parasitic nematodes in organic farming in Germany, a survey was conducted with the main emphasis on vegetable and cereal production systems. For vegetables, the survey included quantification and identification of plant-parasitic nematodes in soil samples and a questionnaire for growers querying production factors and damage levels. For cereals, the survey focused on quantification and identification of plant-parasitic nematodes in soil and plant samples. Overall, Pratylenchus and Tylenchorhynchus were the most prominent nematode genera under both production systems with an incidence of over 90% of the samples. Meloidogyne was detected in 51% of the samples in both systems. Other nematode genera showed differences between the two production systems. In production systems with a high frequency of vegetables, Paratylenchus was detected in 56% of the samples and Heterodera in 15%, whereas in rotations with a high cropping frequency of cereals, incidences of plant-parasitic nematodes were 56% for Heterodera, 47% for Trichodorus and 45% for Paratylenchus. Yield losses could exceed 50% on carrots, onions and cereals and were most pronounced on sandy soils. In many cases, nematode problems started 5 to 10 years after conversion to organic farming. The survey indicated that plant-parasitic nematodes are widely spread in organic farming in Germany and can cause severe damage which may result in complete loss of the crop.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Koninklijke Brill NV, Leiden, 2007</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15252/1/hallmann-etal-2007-Nematology_Vol9_6__869-879.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hallmann, Johannes; Frankenberg, Andrea; Paffrath, Andreas and Schmidt, Harald   (2007) Occurrence and importance of plant-parasitic nematodes in organic farming in Germany.   Nematology, Vol. 9 (6), pp. 869-879.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15252/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>