<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The European Market for Organic Food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Toralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Most of the information and statistics presented in this chapter were compiled as part of a survey among national experts of national or international organic markets. Many of these figures are based on estimates, and the methods of data collection vary from country to country as no uniform data collection system for organic market data is yet in place. In addition, national organic sales figures may vary between years depending on the information sources.&#xD;
Descriptions of market trends in this chapter are the result of market observations by Toralf Richter (Bio Plus AG, Switzerland) and Susanne Padel (University of Wales). The authors would welcome any comments that may help to improve the quality of data and information about the organic market in Europe in future. Some content of this chapter was already published in the Soil Association ‘Organic Market Report 2006’3.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements IFOAM, Bonn, Germany &amp; Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yussefi, Minou</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13170/1/richter-padel-2007-world-of-organic-chapter15.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Richter, Toralf and Padel, Susanne    (2007) The European Market for Organic Food.    In: Willer, Helga and Yussefi, Minou (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2007.  International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements IFOAM, Bonn, Germany &amp; Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland, chapter 15 Europe, pp. 143-154.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13170/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>