<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil mechanical behaviour of sandy loams in a temperate climate: case studies on long-term effects of fertilization and crop rotation.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Munkholm, Lars J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjønning, Per</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petersen, Carsten T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two case studies on Danish sandy loams investigated long-term effects of fertilization and crop rotation. Case Study 1 compared a diversely cropped organically farmed soil (DFG(1)) with a conventionally farmed soil predominantly growing annual crops (DFA), both receiving animal manure.  In Case Study 2, a diversely cropped organically managed soil DFG(2)) receiving animal manure was compared with an almost exclusively cereal cropped conventionally farmed soil receiving no animal manure (CCC). A multi-level experimental strategy was followed to compare integrating field methods with specialized laboratory methods. Ease of tillage was described in the field and characterized using a drop shatter field test and by measuring aggregate tensile strength. Fitness as a seedbed was characterised visually in the field and from the drop shatter test. Impedance to seedling emergence and root penetration was evaluated by measuring bulk soil shear strength. For Case Study 1, soil tilth was better for the DFA soil than for the DFG(1) soil (i.e. lower soil strength and higher ease of fragmentation and friability index for DFA). However, a crumbly structure and a moderate bulk density suggested that the DFG(1) soil was also a favourable medium for plant growth. For Case Study 2, the CCC soil had a lower organic matter content, higher bulk density, higher soil strength, and lower ease of fragmentation in comparison with the DFG(2) soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/61/1/Soil_mechanical.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Munkholm, Lars J.; Schjønning, Per and Petersen, Carsten T.   (2001) Soil mechanical behaviour of sandy loams in a temperate climate: case studies on long-term effects of fertilization and crop rotation.   Soil Use and Management, 17, pp. 269-277.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/61/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>