<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of organic farming in distant rural Māori communities in New Zealand through &#xD;
successful participatory approaches</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kerckhoffs, Dr. L.H.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A research partnership was initiated between scientists of Crop and Food Research and rural Māori communities in the Tairawhiti region of New Zealand to help these communities with the transition from extensive agriculture to intensive organic horticulture. Within the project, growers are working together with agricultural scientists, extension specialists and social scientists using participatory approaches, what has proved to be a powerful tool for increasing the relevance and effectiveness of research for these communities. Progress towards original goals has been slower than expected, but mutual trust and developed relationships between the scientists and the community were recognised as the key factor in the project, and both groups were able to learn new and valuable skills. Many hands-on tools and techniques that made a real difference within the context of local organic vegetable cropping were developed and successfully employed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12062/1/12062.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kerckhoffs, Dr. L.H.J.    (2008) Development of organic farming in distant rural Māori communities in New Zealand through successful participatory approaches.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12062/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>