<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sainfoin seeds as protein source for weaned piglets - a new utilization of a long-known forage legume</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baldinger, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hagm端ller, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spanlang, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matzner, Marlene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia) has been used as a forage legume for centuries and is also popular for use as green manure in some Austrian regions, but so far the protein-rich seeds have not been utilized as a feedstuff. As part of the EU Core Organic ll research project ICOPP (Improved contribution of local feed to support 100% organic feed supply to pigs and poultry), sainfoin seeds have recently been tested as a protein source for weaned piglets. The protein-rich components of the control diet were peas and soybean cake, which were substituted by sainfoin seeds in the experimental diets H (10% sainfoin seeds), D 10 and D 16 (10 and 16% dehulled sainfoin seeds, respectively; as fed basis). Neither feed intake and body weight gain nor feed conversion ratio differed between treatments. This leads to the conclusion that sainfoin seeds can be used as a protein source for piglets just as well as peas and soybean cake.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Th端nen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-09-14</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22328/7/22328.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baldinger, Lisa; Hagm端ller, Werner; Spanlang, Ulrike; Matzner, Marlene and Zollitsch, Werner    (2012) Sainfoin seeds as protein source for weaned piglets - a new utilization of a long-known forage legume.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, Johann Heinrich von Th端nen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries, Hamburg, Trenthorst, Germany, pp. 371-374.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22328/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>