<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Eating quality of filet and round from grazing Holstein bulls and Limousine x Holstein bulls and heifers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Therkildsen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vestergaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Production of organic beef from young cattle is not very developed in Denmark, in spite of a well-established  organic dairy production with male off-spring. These calves are sold to conventional production, because of low performance in organic production systems. The purpose of this study was to test a concept for production of organic  beef based on crossbred animals from dairy cows sired with a beef breed. The experiment included a comparison between spring-born pure-bred Holstein bulls (HB), crossbred Limousin x Holstein bulls (CB) and heifers (CH), 15 of each group. After weaning the calves were raised outdoor on pasture the 1st summer and indoor on a low energy grass-haylage ration over winter followed by pasture the 2nd summer and slaughter at a fixed age of 16.9 mo. CB showed an improved daily gain, EUROP conformation, but not fatness compared with HB, which was inferior compared with the CH. A sensory evaluation showed more intense aroma and taste characteristics of the loin from HB compared with the other groups, whereas the tenderness of the loin and round from both HB and CB were inferior compared with CH, and is expected to be too low to fulfil consumer expectations of tender beef.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Therkildsen, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vestergaard, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-08-17</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27304/7/27304.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Therkildsen, M. and Vestergaard, M. (Eds.)    (2014) Eating quality of filet and round from grazing Holstein bulls and Limousine x Holstein bulls and heifers.    . Proceedings of Proceedings of the 60th International Congress of Meat Science and Technology, Punta del Este, Uruguay, 17-22 August 2014.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27304/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>