<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Conference pears; work on system changes to enable better scab&#xD;
control in organic orchards in the Netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jansonius, Pieter Jans</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Scab control in Conference pears is the bottleneck in organic growing. A group of growers,&#xD;
advisers and researchers in the Netherlands is working on new approaches to organic&#xD;
pear growing. Central to this approach is a reliable and good scab control. Changes in the&#xD;
system of cultivation are sought which will enable this scab control with less fungicide.&#xD;
This has become even more urgent since copper was banned as a fungicide in the&#xD;
Netherlands. First results from trials on vigour control show that there is potency for&#xD;
system changes that will enable a better scab control in organic growing. Scab incidence&#xD;
was reduced in three trials with 34, 58 and 82% respectively. The project, in which also&#xD;
other cultivation measures are being tested, will be continued.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13634/1/029-034.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jansonius, Pieter Jans    (2008) Conference pears; work on system changes to enable better scab control in organic orchards in the Netherlands.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 29-34.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13634/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>