<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of using water extracts of compost and organic materials on soil fertility and plant nutrition</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>HAMDY EL NAGGAR, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this work is to obtain a number of complete soluble compost extracts rich in macronutrients which can be used for fertigation safely through modern irrigation systems and to evaluate their effects on soil fertility and potato (c.v. Sieglinde) growth under organic farming system. Three materials were treated with water to obtain the following dilution ratios: Farm Compost 1:5 (FC5); Farm Compost 1:20 (FC20); Farm Compost + Guano 0.75: 0.25: 5 (FCG); Guano 0.25:5 (G) and Commercial Compost 1: 10 (CC). The release of the nutrients (N, P, K, Ca, Mg) from the aforementioned treatments was monitored as a function of time. The effect of dilution, C/N ratio of the amendments, and Guano additions to compost were determined. During 10 days of extraction, the release of nutrients proceeds gradually, starting one hour later and reaching its maximum 8 days after extraction. Also EC and pH values of the solutions increased from the beginning of the extraction up to 3 days.Results revealed a general increase in macronutrients (N, P and K) in potato plant leaves, stems and roots, as well as in the growth parameters. The treatment FCG shows the highest tuber yields (49.78 ton/ha) for potato plant with respect to the control (16.44 ton/ha) whereas treatments FCG and G also promote an increase in tuber nitrates content (198, 243 mg kg-1 F.W., respectively). Analysis of soil organic matter and soil available nutrients was not significantly affected by the various treatments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6469/1/AhmedElNaggar02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>HAMDY EL NAGGAR, Ahmed   (2002) Effect of using water extracts of compost and organic materials on soil fertility and plant nutrition.  [Effets de l’utilisation d’extraits liquides de compost et de substances organiques sur la fertilité du sol et la nutrition des plantes.]  Thesis, Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 274. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6469/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>