<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cultivation and analysis of anthocyanins containing-, blue potatoes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trautz, Prof. Dr. Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koops, Dipl. Ing. (FH) Bianka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herrmann, Prof. Dr. M.-E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Anthocyanins, as secondary plant substance in different agricultural crops such as potatoes and cereals have positive effects on health due to their antioxidant capacity. Therefore food industry, nutritional medicine and consumers have an increasing interest in these crops. The objectives of the interdisciplinary research project (AGIP) starting in march  2006 are ascertainment and assessment of the impact of different agricultural production processes and production intensities. Furthermore, the impact of different ways of food preparation concerning anthocyanin content and antioxidative capacity in selected cultivated plants will be tested. Main focus will be on potatoes due to the fact that potatoes as a staple food are consumed in large quantities. Therefore potatoes can be an important quantitative source for anthocyanins.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7169/1/biaKL_potatoes21.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trautz, Prof. Dr. Dieter; Koops, Dipl. Ing. (FH) Bianka and Herrmann, Prof. Dr. M.-E.    (2006) Cultivation and analysis of anthocyanins containing-, blue potatoes.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7169/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>