<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Brutplatzqualität unterschiedlich ökologisch bewirtschafteter&#xD;
Ackerfrüchte für die Feldlerche (Alauda arvensis)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Neumann, Dr. Helge</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Dr. Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Habitat quality of different arable crops for skylarks (Alauda arvensis) was analysed in&#xD;
a three year field study on 12 organic farms in northern Germany. Grass clover,&#xD;
spiked spring cereals (barley/spelt/wheat), winter wheat as well as grain legumes&#xD;
(including mixtures) hold constant abundances of skylarks during the whole breeding&#xD;
period. In spring oats, winter spelt and winter cereals with awn (barley/rye), however,&#xD;
skylark densities decreased during the breeding time, which might be explained by&#xD;
comparatively taller and/or denser vegetation structure of theses crops during&#xD;
June/July. Crops showed no significant differences in maximum abundances of&#xD;
skylarks. Concerning possible effects on breeding success, harrowing and/or hoeing&#xD;
of cereals and grain legumes should be completed as early as possible in spring to&#xD;
prevent breeding losses. Compared to cereals and grain legumes, the management of&#xD;
grass clover crops probably resulted in higher breeding losses due to a high intensity&#xD;
of mowing. While the cutting regime of grass clover used as green manure crops can&#xD;
be adapted to breeding phenology of skylarks, modification of cutting systems of&#xD;
forage crops should cause negative effects on quality of forage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14369/1/Neumann_14369.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Neumann, Dr. Helge; Loges, Dr. Ralf and Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm    (2009) Brutplatzqualität unterschiedlich ökologisch bewirtschafteter Ackerfrüchte für die Feldlerche (Alauda arvensis).       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14369/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>