<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The competitiveness of different herbs in grass/clover pastures.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mogensen, Lisbeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On Danish dairy farms, herbs are often sown together with grass/clover, but the amount of herbs in the sward is often limited. The competitiveness of different herbs is therefore examined over three years (2007-2009) in grazed grass/clover pastures on five organic dairy farms and further on a research station. The seed mixture was composed of perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne), white clover (Trifolium repens), red clover (Trifolium pratense), chicory (Cichorium intybus), long-leaved plantain (Plantago lanceolata), caraway (Carum carvi), birds foot trefoil (Lotus coniculatus), salad burnet (Poterium sanguisorba), sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia) and chervil (Anthriscus cerefolium). The botanical composition varied between the experimental sites, but in general, the proportion of the single herb decreased over time. Chicory and plantain had the highest competitiveness and therefore the highest proportion of dry matter. Caraway, lotus and burnet had a considerable lower competitiveness. Sainfoin and chervil disappeared rapidly after establishment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16133/2/16133.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Søegaard, Karen; Mogensen, Lisbeth and Eriksen, Jørgen    (2009) The competitiveness of different herbs in grass/clover pastures.   In:     NJF Seminar 422. Fostering healthy food systems through prganic agriculture - Focus on Nordic-Baltic region, p. 29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16133/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>