<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mastitisfaktoren: Einfluss von Lärm und Vibrationen auf die Eutergesundheit von Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This project is connected with the pro-Q-project (Promotion of udder health and quality of organic produced milk in Switzerland).&#xD;
The project aim is to get knowledge about correlations between noise and vibration in milking parlours and udder health.&#xD;
Udder health parameters are somatic cell count (SCC) and microbiology of quarter foremilk samples, SCC of test day results (cow whole milk samples). These parameters will be compared with the data from the measurements of noise and vibration in milking parlours on 32 pro-Q farms.  &#xD;
&#xD;
Involved organisations, project partners:&#xD;
Dusan Nosal, FAT, Tänikon, Switzerland; Daniel Schwager, SHL, Zollikofen Switzerland&#xD;
Erwin Bilgery, BITEC-Engineering, Switzerland&#xD;
Literature:&#xD;
Schwager, Daniel (2004): Einfluss von Lärm und Vibrationen auf die Eutergesundheit von Milchkühen, Diplomarbeit, Schweizerische Hochschule für Landwirtschaft, Zollikofen&#xD;
http://www.fat.admin.ch/pdf/FAT_Bericht_625_D.pdf&#xD;
Responsible institution:&#xD;
Dusan Nosal, FAT Tänikon, Agroscope, Switzerland&#xD;
Results:&#xD;
Some first results are published in the diploma thesis of D. Schwager, further data are collected.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Mastitisfaktoren: Einfluss von Lärm und Vibrationen auf die Eutergesundheit von Milchkühen.  [Mastitis factors: Influence of noise and vibrations on the udder health of dairy cows.]   Runs 2004 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Heil, Fritz and Walkenhorst, Michael, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6223/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>