<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of seed mixture composition and management on competitiveness of herbs in temporary grasslands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mortensen, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In multispecies grasslands the proportion of different herb species may vary considerably due to low competitiveness of some herbs. To examine the possibility for increasing the competitiveness an experiment with three factors were set up: 1) amount of herb seed in a perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne), white clover (Trifolium repens) mixture, 2) slurry application and 3) cutting frequency. The experiment was carried out over two years. The herbs mix contained salad burnet (Sanguisorba minor), fenugreek (Trogonella foenum-gruecum), chicory (Chicorium intybus), caraway (Carum carvi), birdsfoot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus), chervil (Anthriscus cerefolium), plantain (Plantago lanceolata), Lucerne (Medicago sativa) and melilot (Melilotus officinalis). The proportion of herb seeds was 5, 25, 50 or 100 %. The herb species were most competitive in the first harvest year. In the second year the proportion of all herb species were very low in the mixtures, where white clover and perennial ryegrass were represented. The proportion of many herbs were higher at a 7-cut than at a 4-cut management, and application of cattle slurry also affected the competitiveness. In general chicory, caraway and plantain were the strongest competitors, salad burnet and birdsfoot trefoil were intermediate, and melilot, fenugreek and chervil were very weak competitors.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22042/7/22042.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mortensen, T.; Søegaard, K. and Eriksen, J.    (2012) Effect of seed mixture composition and management on competitiveness of herbs in temporary grasslands.   In:     Grassland Science in Europe, 17, pp. 76-78.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22042/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>