<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of shading on root and shoot development of melon (Cucubrita pepo) transplants in conventional and organic float system nurseries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bilalis, Ass. Prof. Dimitris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kanatas, MSC Panagiotis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konstantas, MSC Aristidis</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Float system is a common technique of tobacco and vegetables transplant production. We evaluated the shade effect on the roots and shoots development for two float systems surgeries (CV:conventional and ORG:organic) on melon transplants. The shade had differently influenced the development of the roots and shoots of the two float systems surgeries. Roots fresh weight and surface was significant higher under shade for organic transplants and significant lower under shade for conventional transplants. Hence, shoots fresh weight and surface was significant higher under shade for organic as well as conventional transplants. Because of the described differences in roots development, the transplants which were produced in the organic float system nursery had better quality under shade in contrast to those produced in conventional float system nursery which had better quality under light. The quality of transplants is related to their behaviour during the transplanting process, their resistance to the transplanting stress and their survival in the field.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12246/1/Bilalis_12246_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bilalis, Ass. Prof. Dimitris; Kanatas, MSC Panagiotis and Konstantas, MSC Aristidis    (2008) Effects of shading on root and shoot development of melon (Cucubrita pepo) transplants in conventional and organic float system nurseries.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12246/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>