<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Heard health management in organic pig production using a quality assurance system based on Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bonde, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sorensen, J.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Health and welfare problems in organic pig production may differ form problems in conventinal pig herds as a result of differences in management. Control of animal health problems in organic herds is affected by the restrictions in medicine use and prophylactic medication as well as by the risk of wildlife contact and difficulties in cleaning and and disinfectin imposed by the access to outdoor areas. To monitor risk factors for diseases and to control these risk factors as a means to prevent diseases, we suggest the implementation of health management based on Hazard Analysis Critical Control Point (the HACCP concept). The development of a HACCP system requires the quantification of risk factors by means of epidemiological studies of alternatively by an expert panel.This paper describes a procedure for developing a HACCP system for welfare problems in organic sow herds. A panel of farm advisers assessed the impact of different risk factors on problems in organic pig production and suggested possible control points. Further work concentrates on evaluating the control points and drawing up action plans to include in the system. The advantage of HACCP in herd health management is the preventative approach focusing on risk factors. Additionally, the continuous documentation of observations and corrective actions integrated in the concept is important when evaluating the herd health management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5202/1/5202.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bonde, M. and Sorensen, J.T.   (2004) Heard health management in organic pig production using a quality assurance system based on Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points.   NJAS Wageningen Journal of Life Sciences. Rodent control strategies in organic farming., 52 (2), pp. 133-143.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5202/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>