<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results of 5 years of thinning trials with lime sulphur in South Tyrol</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Thinning trials with lime sulphur were carried out for 5 years on different sites in South Tyrol. The sprays were applied during blossom to various varieties. During these trials different amounts of active ingredients, water volumes and numbers of treatments were used. Beside the thinning effect the influence on yield (kg/tree) and Fruit quality (average size of the Fruits, fruit-russetting, fruit-deformations) and the return bloom of the treated trees were evaluated. In several cases the use of lime sulphur gave satisfactory results (thinning effect &gt;20%). The results showed a correlation with the amount of active ingredient, water volume, and number of treatments. In most of cases it was possible to increase the average Fruit size. The influence on fruit-russetting was in most cases non significant, the fruit deformations increased slightly. Return bloom improved if the thinning effect was sufficient.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14610/1/kelderer_112.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Lardschneider, Ewald and Casera, Claudio    (2002) Results of 5 years of thinning trials with lime sulphur in South Tyrol.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing and Viticulture. Proceedings to the Conference from 4th to 7th Feb. 2002 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 112-117.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14610/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>