<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic pig production in free range systems</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>TABLE OF CONTENTS&#xD;
.&#xD;
Preface&#xD;
A. Sundrum and F. Weissmann&#xD;
.&#xD;
Integration of organic pig production into land use&#xD;
J. E. Hermansen&#xD;
.&#xD;
Behaviour, performance and carcass quality of three genotypes of growing-finishing pigs in outdoor pig production in Austria: A pilot study&#xD;
Simone Laister and S. Konrad&#xD;
.&#xD;
Performance, carcass and meat quality of different pig genotypes in an extensive outdoor fattening system on grass clover in organic farming&#xD;
F. Weissmann, G. Biedermann and A. Klitzing&#xD;
.&#xD;
Fattening pigs in an outdoor system as a part of the crop rotation within organic farming: Growth performance and carcass yield &#xD;
Antje Farke and A. Sundrum&#xD;
.&#xD;
Integration of organic pig production within crop rotation: Implications on nutrient losses&#xD;
M. Quintern&#xD;
.&#xD;
Outdoor pig farming in the Netherlands&#xD;
H. van der Mheen and H. Vermeer&#xD;
.&#xD;
Documentation of animal health in organic pig herds: A case study&#xD;
Marianne Bonde, N. P. Baadsgaard and J. T. Sørensen</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bundesforschungsanstalt für Landwirtschaft, FAL (Federal Agricultural Research Centre)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sundrum, Albert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Weissmann, Friedrich</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4893/1/Outdoorpigs_FAL-Agr-Res_Spec-Iss-281.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Albert and Weissmann, Friedrich (Eds.)    (2005) Organic pig production in free range systems.   Bundesforschungsanstalt für Landwirtschaft, FAL (Federal Agricultural Research Centre),  Landbauforschung Völkenrode (FAL Agricultural Research): Sonderheft (Special Issue), no. 281.  Proceedings of Outdoor systems with fattening pigs – status quo and future developments in Western European countries, Trenthorst, 18. December 2003.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4893/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>