<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss des Ertragspotentials des Standorts und des Anbausystems  auf den Züchtungserfolg bei Weizen in Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baresel, J P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reents, Dr H J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmermann, Dr G</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Baking quality is a major problem of wheat production in organic farming in Germany. The main reason is low protein content, but also different gluten characteristics. The aim of our investigations was to verify, whether selection of varieties with special adaptation to organic farming (or OF systems with particular low input) is advantageous. 66 Genotypes of winter wheat (registered German varieties, breeding lines, older varieties and varieties bred for organic farming) were compared in 5 environments over two years. Yield, protein content and quality parameters were assessed. Aptitude to LI- or HI- conditions was determined using intravarietal linear regression. While selection for special adaptation proved to be superior for yield and protein yield, this could not be confirmed for gluten characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3699/1/3699.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baresel, J P; Reents, Dr H J and Zimmermann, Dr G    (2005) Einfluss des Ertragspotentials des Standorts und des Anbausystems auf den Züchtungserfolg bei Weizen in Deutschland.  [Influence of Environment on Breeding Success for Wheat in Germany.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3699/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>