<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic farming policy networks in Europe: context, actors and variation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Despite most having developed under the umbrella of the Common Agricultural Policy (CAP), national-level organic farming policy networks in Europe vary. The aim of this paper is to explore the reasons for this variation. Quantitative network analyses were carried out in five 'old' and five 'new' EU member states and in Switzerland. To examine the patterns of influence on these eleven policy networks, the cases are compared in two stages. First, we examine the factors co-varying with the size and density of the networks and then we apply a most similar system - most different outcome research design. We identify the political environment as the main factor affecting size and density of organic farming policy networks in Europe. The distribution of power between organic farming organizations and agricultural ministries is influenced by state involvement and by the resources available to organic farming policy actors.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16460/1/MoschitzStolze_Food_Policy_2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun and Stolze, Matthias   (2009) Organic farming policy networks in Europe: context, actors and variation.   Food Policy, 34 (3), pp. 258-264.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16460/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>