<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainability evaluation of long term organic farm systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vazzana, Prof Concetta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raso, Dr Enrico</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Migliorini, Dr Paola</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper deals with the evaluation of sustainability at farm level in a long term experimental farm organically managed since 1992 in Tuscany. The aim was to develop and implement a multi-objective organic agriculture, to establish new concepts of farming as result of long term research analysis and to provide a practical and easy understanding on what is necessary to change or improve in farming management. Soil fertility and biodiversity indicators are taken into consideration in the period 1992-2006: the weak points and the improvement obtained by the farm management are underlined. The values of indicators changed rapidly towards the desired ones in the first 6 years period. After 13 years, in 2005-2006, the situation appear almost stable, P balance is still a problem, some little discrepancies for C/N ratio and KAR indicate the need to re-examine some of the production methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12364/1/MOLTE_indicators_def.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vazzana, Prof Concetta; Raso, Dr Enrico and Migliorini, Dr Paola    (2008) Sustainability evaluation of long term organic farm systems.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12364/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>