<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Persistence of Two Campylobacter jejuni Strains in&#xD;
Soil and on Spinach Plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jäderlund, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sessitsch, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arthurson, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There are indications that the more frequent use of untreated organic residues for fertilization results in increased risk of contamination with human pathogens. Here, we evaluate the ability of two different strains of Campylobacter jejuni to persist in manure and soil as well as spread to spinach plants. It was revealed that different strategies for inoculation of C. jejuni contribute to the persistence of the bacterium in soil, roots, and shoots. Upon inoculation of the bacteria into manure prior to soil application,the amount of C. jejuni subsequently recovered in soil was higher than that from treatments involving the addition of C. jejuni cells to the soil after plant emergence. Irrespective of the bacterial inoculation dose and strategy employed, the C. jejuni content in soil remained relatively constant, whereas the majority of C. jejuni cells applied to spinach leaves could be recovered during the whole evaluation period of 21 days.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Jäderlund, L.; Sessitsch, A. and Arthurson, V.   (2011) Persistence of Two Campylobacter jejuni Strains in Soil and on Spinach Plants.   Applied and Environmental Soil Science, 2011, 7 pages.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20369/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>