<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Perspectives and paradoxes in the Latvian organic sector in the context of EU acccession</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aistara, Ms. Guntra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Baltic states</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Latvian Organic Agriculture Association (LBLA) marked its ten year anniversary this year, one year after joining the European Union (EU). In these ten years, the number of certified or transition period organic farms has grown from 38 to almost 3000, with two thirds of that growth occurring since EU accession.  During the same period, however, the amount of certified organic produce reaching the consumer has increased only marginally, as many obstacles remain for farmers to develop and gain market access. This paper analyzes the effects of EU accession from the farmers' perspective, and reveals that the implementation of EU regulations in the Latvian post-socialist context often has unintended consequences due to the complex interaction of EU and Latvian administrative processes, differences in farmers' experiences and expectations, and the dilapidated state of existing rural infrastructure. These findings raise crucial questions about how current EU policies and support structures will assist or hinder farmers in new member states in establishing a niche in European organic agriculture and contributing to sustainable rural development.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7695/1/Denmark_conf_short_paper_FINAL.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aistara, Ms. Guntra    (2006) Perspectives and paradoxes in the Latvian organic sector in the context of EU acccession.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7695/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>