<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SLOW AND STEADY WINS THE ORGANIC RACE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vikram, Amit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gupta, Meenu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kohli, U.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic production is carried out under an extensive regulatory setup because organic products are sold as value-added products with certified organic labelling in developed countries. Production is strictly monitored at every step in production chain. Organic production apart from being eco-friendly offers higher net returns per unit area compared to conventional agriculture. Organic production uses traditional tillage systems, crop rotations, crop residues, animal manures, legumes, green manures, off-farm organic wastes, mineral bearing rocks, and biological pest and weed control to maintain soil productivity. Thus, an organic farm should be a self contained system of production with minimal dependence on external inputs. Those farms having dairy as one of the active components will have to convert to organic livestock management so that manures supplied are as per requirements for organic production. The dairy products can also be certified organic to fetch higher prices. Organic farming is a highly labour intensive enterprise. Some of the major organic accreditation agencies are IFOAM (International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements), FiBL, Demeter and many more. APEDA has also developed national standards for organic production. Indian farmers face many challenges in adoption of certified organic production. Some of the important organic production requirements as per national standards for organic production have been developed by APEDA.Genetically engineered cultivars or plant materials are not permitted in organic production. Some of the important organic production requirements as per national standards for organic production have been developed by APEDA. Some of the important organic production requirements as per national standards for organic production have been developed by APEDA.Before products from a farm/project can be certified as organic, inspection shall be carried out during the conversion period. To ensure a clear separation between organic and conventional production, the certification programme (agency) shall inspect, where appropriate, the whole production system. Organic production is one area of agriculture which can convert India’s ‘Green Revolution’ into ‘Evergreen Revolution’.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>The Tribune Trust, Chandigarh, India</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6058/1/6058.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vikram, Amit; Gupta, Meenu and Kohli, U.K.    (2004) SLOW AND STEADY WINS THE ORGANIC RACE.   The Tribune, May 2004, 124 (145), p. 16.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6058/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>