<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auf dem Weg zu flugbrandresistenten Gerstensorten für den Ökolandbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Popova, T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Todorova, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper represents a part of the continuing breeding program for resistance to true loose smut in barley in Bulgaria. It is also a continuation of the paper presented on the 8th European Symposium on organic farming in Kassel 2005. Research on seed-borne diseases started in Bulgaria on barley in the 1960´s at the Institute for barley Re-search in Karnobat. Breeding research especially for a later use in organic farming in Bulgaria started 1998 with the present international project managed by Dr. Todorova. 56 dihaploid lines were derived from F1-hybrids of two barley crosses between resis-tant and susceptible Bulgarian and foreign cultivars bearing the resistant genes Run12 and Run13. The DH progenies were tested in 5 generations for loose smut resistance on the field and in the lab with the embryotest. 10 resistant DH-progenies with gene Run12 and 16 resistant DH-progenies with Run13 were selected.  In the last years agronomically characterisation of the future cultivars is going on. 7 dihaploid lines with appropriate agronomic traits are selected for future cultivar developing with true loose smut resistance for organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9881/1/9881_Popova_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Popova, T and Todorova, R.    (2007) Auf dem Weg zu flugbrandresistenten Gerstensorten für den Ökolandbau.  [Towards true Loose smut (Ustilago nuda) resistant Barley for Organic Farming.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9881/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>