<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil type, management history, and soil amendments influence the development of soil-borne (Rhizoctonia solani, Pythium ultimum) and air-borne (Phytophthora infestans, Hyaloperonospora parasitica) diseases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thürig, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laustela, Matias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mahlberg, Nicole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nietlispach, Bruno</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weber, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of soil type, long-term soil management, and short-term fertility input strategies on the suppressiveness of soils against soil-borne (Ocimum basilicum – Rhizoctonia solani, Lepidium sativum – Pythium ultimum) as well as air-borne (Lycopersicon esculentum – Phytophthora infestans, Arabidopsis thaliana – Hyaloperonospora parasitica) diseases was studied. Soils from field trials established in five European sites with contrasting pedo-climatic conditions were examined. Sites included (i) a long-term management field trial comparing organic and conventional farming systems (DOK-trial, Therwil, Switzerland) (ii) a short-term fertility input field trial comparing mineral and organic matter fertilisation regimes (Bonn (BON), Germany) (iii) two short-term fertility input field trials (Stockbridge (STC) and Tadcaster (TAD), UK) comparing the impact of farmyard manure, composted farmyard manure, and chicken manure pellet amendements and (iv) soil from a site used as a reference (Reckenholz (REC), Switzerland). Soil type affected disease suppressiveness of the four pathosystems signficantly, indicating that soils can not only affect the development of soil-borne, but also the resistance of plants to air-borne diseases at relevant levels. Suppressiveness to soil- and air-borne diseases was shown to be affected by soil type, but also by long-term management as well as short-term fertility inputs.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer + Business Media</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17865/1/Tamm-etal-2010-eur-j-plant-pathol.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tamm, Lucius; Thürig, Barbara; Bruns, Christian; Fuchs, Jacques G.; Köpke, Ulrich; Laustela, Matias; Leifert, Carlo; Mahlberg, Nicole; Nietlispach, Bruno; Schmidt, Christoph; Weber, Felix and Fließbach, Andreas   (2010) Soil type, management history, and soil amendments influence the development of soil-borne (Rhizoctonia solani, Pythium ultimum) and air-borne (Phytophthora infestans, Hyaloperonospora parasitica) diseases.   European Journal of Plant Pathology, 127 (4), pp. 465-481.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17865/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>