<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic beef farming in the Czech Republic: structure, development and economic performance</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hrabalova, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper analyzes the development and the prospects of organic farming in the Czech Republic with particular emphasis on organic beef farming. Background information on organic farming in the Czech Republic regarding the structure of land use, legislation and support payments as well as a short description of the market for organic beef are provided. An analysis of the economic performance and of the impact of payments on the economic situation of organic beef farms follows. Grazing livestock farms, mostly cow-calf systems, are the most widespread farm type in the Czech Republic. Five typical farm models were set up with the aim of giving an overview of the diversity of organic beef production systems. The results indicate that organic beef farming is in most cases economically viable. Nevertheless, organic farming payments, as well as other payments, account for a high share of economic success, so that it can be stated that organic grazing livestock farms are highly dependent on support payments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8830/1/Organicprints_abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hrabalova, Andrea and Zander, Katrin   (2006) Organic beef farming in the Czech Republic: structure, development and economic performance.   Agricultural Economics, 52 (2), pp. 89-100.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8830/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>