<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The content of bioactive compounds in rat experimental diets based on organic, low-input and conventional plant materials</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rembialkowska, Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hallmann, Ewelina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rusaczonek, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bennett, Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Kirsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lueck, Lorna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Rat feed based on raw plant materials was produced according to the nutritional recommendations for rat feeding trials. Rat feeds produced from crops grown under 4 different production systems were used: (a) organic, (b) conventional, (c) low input 1 (organic plant protection was used in combination with mineral fertilizers) and (d) low input 2 (conventional pest management and only organic fertilizers were used). The results showed that rat feeds prepared from the organically produced plants contained more total polyphenols and the nutritionally desirable, bioactive compound lutein. The main objective of analyzing bioactive compounds in the rat feed is to determine whether the differences in composition of feed materials from different production systems could explain any measured differences in impact on the health status of rats.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9912/1/rembialkowska-etal-2007-rats.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rembialkowska, Ewa; Hallmann, Ewelina; Rusaczonek, Anna; Bennett, Richard; Brandt, Kirsten; Lueck, Lorna and Leifert, Carlo    (2007) The content of bioactive compounds in rat experimental diets based on organic, low-input and conventional plant materials.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9912/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>