<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Limitations in the implementation of preventive measures and the need of a system-oriented approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dietze, Klaas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A high level of animal health is demanded by an increasing number of consumers and expected to be realised especially in organic farming. In a study on 20 organic sow herds, conducted to assess the effects of the implementation of animal health plans, the status quo of animal health of sows and piglets and possible constraints which limit the possibilities of appropriate diagnosis, treatment and preventive measures were assessed.&#xD;
The on-farm assessment brought up a high variability among the farms with regard to standard livestock data and the occurrence of weak-points in hygienic, nutritional and animal health management. Recommendations were elaborated together with the veterinarian and the advisory service. However, in the first year after being given the advice, only a few measures have been implemented.&#xD;
Where both the complexity and the individuality of farm systems need to be taken into account, it is reasonable to grasp the farm as an ecosystem and to define animal health as an emergent property of the farm system. Within a system approach, animal health precaution plans can be developed as a suitable frame for feedback mechanisms. The use of feedback mechanisms, however, requires a clear guideline concerning the expected output of the system. Consequently, there is a need for a change in the paradigm from a standard-oriented to an output-oriented approach.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-07-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19327/1/ISAHCongress_2009_System_approach.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Albert; Dietze, Klaas and Werner, Christina    (2009) Limitations in the implementation of preventive measures and the need of a system-oriented approach.   In:     Proceedings of the XIV ISAH-Congress 2009 (International Society of Animal Hygiene), 19th to 23rd July, Vechta, Germany, pp. 57-60.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19327/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>