<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Yield stability of single and two-clover grass-clover swards at grazing, cutting and different fertilizer regimes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Increasing plant diversity in grasslands may improve productivity and yield stability. This study investigates in a field experiment, yield and quality of two-species swards of ryegrass/white clover and three-species swards of ryegrass/white and red clover at five different managements representing cutting, grazing, combinations of cutting and grazing and different fertilizer treatments in 1 to 4-yr-old swards. Generally, the three-species mixture produced higher yields than the two-species mixture when swards were young and lower yields when swards were 3 and 4 years old. Fertilizer responses were similar in both mixtures and also rather independent of sward age. The overall mean annual yield increase by slurry application was 1.34 t DM corresponding to approximately 11 kg DM per kg NH4-N. In the three-species mixture there was a shift from red clover dominating in the first two years, to white clover dominating in years 3 and 4. The crude protein content of harvested plant material was not significantly affected by species mixture and variation in crude protein was mainly explained by cutting time.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20636/7/20636.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J.; Askegaard, M. and Søegaard, K.   (2012) Yield stability of single and two-clover grass-clover swards at grazing, cutting and different fertilizer regimes.   Grass and Forage Science,  , pp. 1-12.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20636/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>