<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production of organic cucumbers under different fertilization and soil mulching</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Babik, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Babik, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaniszewski, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Hybrid cucumbers were cultivated on the red clover/grass ploughed in the autumn (control). Aditionally in the spring compost (25 t.ha-1) and the liquid manure (20 m3.ha-1)were applied. Enrichment of the soil with the composition of effective microorganisms (EM - 5l.ha-1) or 3-times foliar spray of 0.2% sea-algae extract was also applied in the experiment. The soil surface was mulched with the straw, red clover/grass and black polypropylene (PP-50 g.m2) or left coverless (control). The earliness and structure of the yield, the content of mineral nutrients in the soil and in the plant and the biological value of fresh and dill pickled cucumbers were determined. The fertilization with the liquid manure significantly increased the content of N-NO3 in the soil in the first period of plants growth, more than in the case of compost. The use of EM had no effect on available nitrogent content in the soil. The content of N-NO3, during vegetation period, in the soil mulched with clover was higher than in control as well as in soil covered with straw or polypropylene fleece. The additional use of organic fertilizers or the soil enrichement with EM asa well as foliar spraying with the sea-algae extracts, in cucumbers cultivated on ploughed 2-years red clover/grass, did not increase early and marketable yield of cucumber. The fertilization with the liquid manure and straw mulching had unfavorable effect on the yield and crop quality, increasing the share of misshaped fruits and occurence of hollow seed cavity. Compost fertilization, foliar spraying of sea-algae extract and red clover mulch secured the best quality of dill pickled cucumbers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Society for Horticultural  Science (ISHS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rallo, Luis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>De la Rosa, Raul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Monteiro, Antonio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>De Oliveira, Pedro Bras</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17441/1/posterIB2.jpg</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Babik, I.; Babik, J. and Kaniszewski, S.    (2010) Production of organic cucumbers under different fertilization and soil mulching.   In: Rallo, Luis; De la Rosa, Raul; Monteiro, Antonio and De Oliveira, Pedro Bras (Eds.)  Abstracts. Volume II (Symposia), International Society for Horticultural Science (ISHS), Lisboa, pp. 656-657.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17441/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>