<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studying learning and innovation networks – a conceptual and methodological framework</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Home, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper outlines the main concepts and methodology that the SOLINSA project uses in its study of learning and innovation networks. This project aims to identify barriers to the development of Learning and Innovation Networks for sustainable agriculture (LINSA). In such networks, social learning processes take place, and knowledge about sustainable agriculture is co-produced by connecting between the different frames and social worlds of the stakeholders with the help of boundary objects. Studying such processes at the interface between different knowledge spheres of research, policy and practice requires a specific methodology. A transdisciplinary reflective learning methodology addresses the complex question of understanding learning and innovation. The paper highlights the challenges of this approach that involves stakeholders already in the phase of defining the research objectives and strategies. Results from a first round of application of the conceptual and methodological framework will be presented and discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22255/1/Moschitz%20-%20WG9%20-%20Studying%20learning%20and%20innovation%20networks.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun and Home, Robert    (2012) Studying learning and innovation networks – a conceptual and methodological framework.       Paper at:   Agriculture in an urbanizing society. International Conference on Multifunctional Agriculture and Urban-Rural Relations, Wageningen, 1-4 April 2012.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22255/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>