<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effects of compost and compost extract on soil properties and lettuce growth.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CAVOSKI, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The work was conducted at the experimental field of the Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Italy in 2004. The aim was to study the effects of compost and compost extract on soil properties and lettuce growth. The chemical, biological and phytotoxic tests of compost extract proved its high  selected soil properties (pH, EC, Organic matter, available nutrients, cations and anions contents) markedly with depth and time, the most prominent changes showed by compost extract application. The applications of compost and compost extract significantly increased lettuce growth, yield, yield components and storage, all were highly significantly influenced by compost. The relation between chlorophyll-meter readings and nitrogen concentration showed highly significant linear regression and provided evidence that the chlorophyll-meter could be used to determine side dressing N requirements. The benefits of the compost and compost extract without chemical fertilizer demonstrated the validity and possibility of sustainable agronomic performance of lettuce using available recycled organic materials.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6871/1/IvanaCavoski04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CAVOSKI, Ivana   (2004) The effects of compost and compost extract on soil properties and lettuce growth.  [Les effets du compost et des extraits de compost sur les propriétés du sol et sur la croissance de la laitue.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 352. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6871/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>