<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Usefulness of some winter wheat varieties for cultivation in organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stalenga, Jarosław</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jończyk, Krzysztof</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Evaluation of the usefulness of six common winter wheat varieties (Kobra, Roma, Korweta, Sukces, Zyta, Mewa)  and one variety (Schwabenkorn) of spelt winter wheat (Triticum spelta) for cultivation in organic farming was the aim of the research. The research was based on a special field experiment established in 1994 on a grey-brown podzolic soil in which different crop production systems (organic, integrated and conventional) are compared. The research was conducted between 2002 and 2004 on the field of winter wheat in the organic system. The following parameters were taken into account in the research: Leaf Area Index, nitrogen nutrient status and grain yield. Average grain yields of winter wheat independently of the year and variety amounted to 4.36 t/ha. The largest yields were observed for Mewa and Kobra variety. Schwabenkorn variety of spelt wheat was characterised by the highest values of Leaf Area Index. According to 3 different tests Mewa variety was in the best nitrogen nutrient status and it seems to be the most useful one for organic farming. Efficiency of nitrogen utilization is an interesting test of usefulness of cereals varieties for organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4327/4/Stalenga_Jonczykl_usefulness_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stalenga, Jarosław and Jończyk, Krzysztof    (2005) Usefulness of some winter wheat varieties for cultivation in organic farming.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4327/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>