<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Research and development strategy 2012 in Organic farming and food "Growth, credibility and resilient systems"</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This new overarching research and development strategy has been prepared by the programme committee at ICROFS in 2012. It describes the areas where a research effort would benefit the industry and also its importance to society. Research and development strategy 2012 is the result of a long hearing process, where stakeholders within and associated with the organic sector were given the opportunity to present their views on existing development potentials and barriers and where research and development activities will be able to make a difference. It has led to hoth new ideas and greater visions, which the sector believes are essential to ensure leaps in knowledge and development. The process has also uncovered very specific barriers and problems that require a solution to ensure the viability and credibility of the organic sector. It is ICROFS intention, that the strategy should form the starting point for forthcoming funding for research and development in organic food production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mathiesen, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, L.S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22537/1/22537.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mathiesen, C. and Sørensen, L.S. (Eds.)    (2012) Research and development strategy 2012 in Organic farming and food "Growth, credibility and resilient systems".    International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), Tjele, Denmark.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22537/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>