<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecosystem services in smallholder coffee farming systems: a case study in Uganda using chemical soil indicators</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pohl, Walther</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mentler, Axel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Okalany, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Probst, Lorenz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zechmeister-Boltenstern, Sophie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Farmers in coffee producing countries may not be aware of the economic, social and ecological benefits available through organic agriculture. At a local, regional and global scale, smallholder coffee farmers can discover that organic production methods are linked to provisioning, regulating, cultural and supporting ecosystem services. It is assumed that organic agriculture has a significant influence on soil parameters, and by association, on ecosystem services. Differences between farming systems in soil chemical properties reveal advantages for coffee farmers and shows the ecosystem services derived through organic agriculture at a local level.&#xD;
Benefits discovered in organic coffee systems are higher inputs of organic matter, higher biodiversity of soil microorganisms, less soil erosion, and the potential for higher aggregate stability and superior nutrient circulation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23767/1/23767%20Paper%20OWC14_Walther%20Pohl_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pohl, Walther; Mentler, Axel; Okalany, Emmanuel; Probst, Lorenz and Zechmeister-Boltenstern, Sophie    (2014) Ecosystem services in smallholder coffee farming systems: a case study in Uganda using chemical soil indicators.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germay, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1119-1122.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23767/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>