<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards more ecoefficient food production: MFA approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Risku-Norja, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäenpää, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koikkalainen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rikkonen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vanhala, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The key for the sustainable development is dematerialisation and ecoefficiency. Applied to&#xD;
agriculture ecoefficiency means production of nutritionally better food by using less inputs&#xD;
and by reducing the environmental burden. In restricting the material throughput it is essential&#xD;
to identify the most voluminous material flows and to direct the measures to them. Improving&#xD;
ecoefficiency of the food production requires that the benefits and the inputs are quantified in&#xD;
an unambiguous way and that the inputs are estimated for the whole production chain. A&#xD;
comprehensive view of the whole system is necessary.&#xD;
The food system comprises four mutually linked loops: 1) the plant production 2) the&#xD;
livestock husbandry, 3) the food processing industry and 4) the human consumption. In the&#xD;
present paper MFA approach has been used to describe the system. A general framework for&#xD;
estimating and balancing the materials flow is outlined. The focus is on agriculture,&#xD;
specifically on the materials flow created by the biological metabolism of the animal&#xD;
husbandry.&#xD;
The holistic MFA approach provides means to evaluate environmental and economic&#xD;
consequences of the production. For the decision-makers the MFA approach is a tool to guide&#xD;
the development and to assess the progress towards increasing ecoefficiency within the food&#xD;
system. The results can be used in developing new sustainability indicators. Some of the&#xD;
possibilities are shortly discussed.&#xD;
The study is the first step in developing MFA methods to analyse and to monitor the materials&#xD;
flow of the Finnish food systems. It is a part of the project “The Materials Flow and&#xD;
Ecoefficiency of Agriculture and the Sustainable Compatibility of the Food Production”&#xD;
carried out in collaboration between the MTT - Agrifood Research Finland and the Thule&#xD;
Institute at the University of Oulu. The results are used also in compiling the Finnish physical&#xD;
input-output tables. The study, thus, contributes to the overall development of the materials&#xD;
flow accounting statistics.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17586/1/riskunorja.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Risku-Norja, H.; Mäenpää, I.; Koikkalainen, K.; Rikkonen, P. and Vanhala, P.    (2002) Towards more ecoefficient food production: MFA approach.       Paper at:   Farming and rural systems research and extension - local identities and globalisation : 4th European IFSA symposium, Florence, Italy.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17586/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>