<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ist die FAMACHA©-Eye-Colour-Karte zur klinischen Diagnose von Haemonchus&#xD;
contortus – Befall bei Schafen und Ziegen in Norddeutschland geeignet?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koopmann, Regine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In sheep and goats the most pathogenous worm is the bloodsucking Barber’s pole worm Haemonchus contortus. Studies in South Africa confirmed the FAMACHA-Test to be a useful tool for identifying anaemic animals. Apart from the reduction of anthelmintic drugs, the targeted, selective treatment of single animals may delay the development of anthelmintic-resistant worms. Three field studies, carried out in Northern Germany in consecutive years, showed that at a comparatively low infestation of H.contortus, the FAMACHA©-Eye-Colour-Test had not enough power for detecting all animals with the highest worm egg output (KOOPMANN et al. 2006). If the repeated examination during the pasture period by the FAMACHA©-Eye-Colour-Score is possible, it could find the very pale animals in need to be treated.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9402/1/9402_Koopmann_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koopmann, Regine    (2007) Ist die FAMACHA©-Eye-Colour-Karte zur klinischen Diagnose von Haemonchus contortus – Befall bei Schafen und Ziegen in Norddeutschland geeignet?  [Is the FAMACHA©-Eye-Colour-Chart a useful tool for the detection of Haemonchus contortus – infestation of sheep and goats in Northern Germany?]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9402/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>