<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bio-Schulverpflegung in Italien, Finnland, Dänemark und Norwegen – Was kann Deutschland lernen?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The policies and practice of school meal provision in Germany are currently in a dynamic&#xD;
transition led on by the introduction of a fulltime school system. One of the&#xD;
many issues being highlighted is its potential to increase the use of organic produce.&#xD;
The research project “innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth” (iPOPY;&#xD;
www.ipopy.coreportal.org) analyses the entire system. Results of the first comparison&#xD;
between Italy, Finland, Denmark, and Norway are presented here, as a background to&#xD;
discuss the German situation. Using a common guideline developed in iPOPY the&#xD;
types of school meal provision can be categorised as (a) warm lunch (IT, FI) or (b) fruit&#xD;
and milk subscription schemes to supplement a packed lunch (DK, NO). Italy emerges&#xD;
as the pioneer of organic school meal provision. Certification of organic catering is&#xD;
mandatory in Germany whereas the other countries have slightly diverging or no&#xD;
apparent regulation. Notwithstanding the wide array of influencing factors, some decisive&#xD;
elements fostering organic school food can be identified such as (a) active local&#xD;
stakeholders and (b) quality requirements.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14420/1/N%C3%B6lting_14420.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nölting, Benjamin; Strassner, Carola; Løes, Anne-Kristin and Nielsen, Thorkild    (2009) Bio-Schulverpflegung in Italien, Finnland, Dänemark und Norwegen – Was kann Deutschland lernen?       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14420/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>