<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of cleaning /disinfection strategies on helminth infections in finishing pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vermeer, Herman M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borgsteede, Fred H.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaasenbeek, Cor P.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blanken, Klaas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ascaris suum is the most prevalent helminth on organic pig farms (Carstensen et al., 2002)&#xD;
and is transmitted mainly via the faeces. The use of anthelmintics does not fit in the organic&#xD;
principles and preventive measures are promoted. This project focused on assessing the efficacy&#xD;
of a cleaning protocol for the dunging area of pens on Ascaris s. transmission to pigs. In&#xD;
4 batches with 8 identical pens for 15 pigs each (n=480 pigs) 6 pigs per pen were orally infected&#xD;
with Ascaris s. The other pigs can be earliest infected at 10 weeks and half of the pens&#xD;
were thoroughly cleaned at that time. Affected livers and egg counts in the manure had to&#xD;
show if this cleaning protocol keeps the non infected animals free of Ascaris s. The results&#xD;
show no effect of the cleaning protocol on the non infected pigs. These pigs had 57% damaged&#xD;
livers in both treatment and 50% had positive egg counts in the manure. The conclusion&#xD;
is that pen hygiene does not contribute to a reduction of Ascaris s. infections.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15674/1/4-1-2-2_RIAH_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vermeer, Herman M.; Borgsteede, Fred H.M.; Gaasenbeek, Cor P.H. and Blanken, Klaas         (2008) Effect of cleaning /disinfection strategies on helminth infections in finishing pigs.   QLIF final report, no. WP 4.1.2.2.. .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15674/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>