<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ansatzpunkte der „Wissenschaftlichen Weiterbildung“ für neue Bildungsformate im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Specht, Judith</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Häring, Anna Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Scientific continuing education means, that universities do not offer only regular fulltime bachelor or master programs, but create as well offerings for extra-occupational studies or scientific certificates. These courses are characterized by a new understanding of the relation of practical and theoretical knowledge, they emphasize on what a learner needs to know after completing a course instead of theory-driven standard contents and address professional practitioners with an interest in additional knowledge. These elements of scientific continuing education are in context of organic farming of further relevance, as they tackle the well-known and discussed relation of theoretical and practical knowledge. &#xD;
This paper is about the need of continuing education in ecologic agriculture (e.g. relevant issues or course design) and discusses the question, if this widened approach of scientific education can contribute to strengthen the ecologic agricultural system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-09-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27254/1/27254_specht.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Specht, Judith and Häring, Anna Maria    (2014) Ansatzpunkte der „Wissenschaftlichen Weiterbildung“ für neue Bildungsformate im Ökologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   13. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde, 17. - 20. März 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27254/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>