<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Acting against common bunt: exploration of various control methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fontaine, Laurence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Robin, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruyère, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>du CHEYRON, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Common bunt (Tilletia caries, Tilletia foetida) is a fungal disease with a large ability to spread. Consequences may be rejection of grains for sale or even a large decrease of yield. Different trials were carried out in organic farming in a research project (funded by the French Ministry of Agriculture between 2008 and 2011) to achieve a better control of common bunt. Results confirm that the resistance of wheat cultivars is a factor to consider. Despite most varieties currently cultivated in organic farming are sensitive to common bunt, some cultivars appeared to be resistant to the races tested. Concerning seed treatment, no product is available for organic farming and 100% efficient; but several solutions have been identified. Only one product is currently authorized for common bunt control on cereals (cerall), it has a significant but sometimes irregular efficiency. Products with acetic acid (white vinegar) or with a base of mustard flour (Tillecur) have similar results. Copper products at low level (reduced to about 500g Cu/t) give a very good level of protection. Before using those solutions, prevention is essential to mobilise, through diversified crop rotations, field observation, seed choice, regular analysis of farm seed, cleaning of machinery…</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26256/1/Fontaine_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fontaine, Laurence; Robin, N.; Bruyère, J. and du CHEYRON, P.   (2013) Acting against common bunt: exploration of various control methods.  [Agir rapidement pour contenir la carie commune : exploration de diverses méthodes de contrôle.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 35-46.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26256/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>