<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>„Hauptsache, es schmeckt“ - der Einfluss von Jugendlichen auf&#xD;
den Öko-Lebensmittelkonsum in Familien</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gilles, M.Sc. Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Prof. Dr. Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Riefer, Dipl.-Soziologin Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This contribution presents results of a qualitative study investigating juveniles’ influence&#xD;
in family decision-making with regard to organic food. According to recent research&#xD;
it can be assumed that expenditures for organic food in families with children decline&#xD;
as children grow older. For organic food marketing this raises the questions if, why&#xD;
and how juveniles influence family decision-making and what organic products are&#xD;
prefered or rejected? Semi-structured interviews were conducted with juveniles aged&#xD;
13 to 18 years. The data was analysed using qualitative content analysis. Most juveniles&#xD;
proved to be open-minded towards organic food and they supported its consumption&#xD;
at home. Juveniles’ main criticism encompassed the taste of some organic product&#xD;
groups such as sweets, crisps, spreads and pizzas. If juveniles are not satisfied&#xD;
with the taste of an organic product they use different strategies to influence family&#xD;
purchase decisions. The main aim of these strategies is often to buy a conventional&#xD;
product. Therefore, organic suppliers should invest more money into researching&#xD;
juveniles’ specific taste preferences and should develop products which meet the&#xD;
expectations of juveniles better with respect to taste, but also regarding product appearance&#xD;
and packaging. Via advertising, product images should be optimised to&#xD;
comply with the actual lifestyle of the target group. Ethical aspects should also be&#xD;
included into communication strategies, as juveniles have a special sense for social&#xD;
justice and animal welfare.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14019/1/Gilles_14019.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gilles, M.Sc. Ute; Hamm, Prof. Dr. Ulrich and Riefer, Dipl.-Soziologin Angelika    (2009) „Hauptsache, es schmeckt“ - der Einfluss von Jugendlichen auf den Öko-Lebensmittelkonsum in Familien.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14019/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>