<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cadmium content of Finnish linseed and estimated consumer intake</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kymäläinen, Hanna-Riitta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sjöberg, Anna-Maija</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to screen the cadmium (Cd) contents of seed and seed crush of Finnish linseed and to evaluate the acceptable daily dose. The Cd content of Finnish linseed is of interest, since some properties of linseed as the content of fatty acids are different in northern growth locations compared with other growing areas. Seed samples (N = 85) were collected from the experimental farm of Helsinki University and from commercial fields in different locations in southern Finland and Ostrobothnia. In addition, 15 samples of linseed crush were examined. The cadmium contents of the linseed samples, determined with atomic absorption spectroscopy, varied between 0.27 and 1.3 mg kg-1 (dry weight) (mean 0.61 mg kg-1). The Cd contents of the crush samples were between 0.47 and 1.5 mg kg-1 (mean 0.85 mg kg-1). There were differences between the Cd contents of the three examined varieties and years at the experimental farm. Increase in nitrogen fertilization somewhat increased the Cd uptake of linseed. The permitted intake of linseed depends on body weight and on the Cd content of the product and is in most cases higher than the dietary recommendation (24–30 g daily dose of linseed).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17087/1/</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kymäläinen, Hanna-Riitta and Sjöberg, Anna-Maija   (2006) Cadmium content of Finnish linseed and estimated consumer intake.   Agricultural and Food Science, 15 (1), pp. 3-11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17087/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>