<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of Processing on Bioactive Substances Content and Antioxidant Properties of Apple Purée from Organic and Conventional Production in Poland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rembiałkowska, Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hallmann, Ewelina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rusaczonek, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic food market is developing dynamically in many European countries and therefore studies concerning the nutritive value of organically produced foods are becoming increasingly important. It was found appropriate to conduct studies on selected bioactive substances and antioxidant properties of apple preserves prepared from organic vs. conventional apples. Three apple cultivars, Lobo, Boskoop and Cortland, were grown in organic and conventional orchards in the Mazovia region in Poland. Dry matter, total phenols, vitamin C, total flavones and antioxidant activity were determined in fresh and pasteurized apple purée. The apple purée prepared from the organic apples contained significantly more total phenols, vitamin C, total flavones and showed a higher antioxidant capacity than the preserves prepared from conventional apples. Processing had a negative effect on both antioxidant capacity and bioactive substances. After pasteurization, the content of vitamin C, total phenols and flavones and antioxidant properties have decreased in the apple purée from both agricultural systems (organic and conventional).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9943/1/rembialkowska-etal-2007-apple_pomace.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rembiałkowska, Ewa; Hallmann, Ewelina and Rusaczonek, Anna    (2007) Influence of Processing on Bioactive Substances Content and Antioxidant Properties of Apple Purée from Organic and Conventional Production in Poland.       Poster at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, May 31-June 3 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9943/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>