<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studies on the antioxidative activity of red pigments in Italian-type dry-cured ham</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adamsen, Christina E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Mette L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Møller, Jens K.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skibsted, Leif H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Aqueous phosphate buffer extracts and acetone/water extracts of pigments from Parma ham were assessed as antioxidants by (1) electron spin resonance spectroscopy using a spin probing technique to evaluate their efficiencies as scavengers of free radicals, and (2) by electrochemical measurement of oxygen depletion rate in an aqueous methyl linoleate emulsion to evaluate their efficiencies as chain-breaking antioxidant, and using both methods, compared with the effect of apomyoglobin and nitrosylmyoglobin. Aqueous phosphate extracts and acetone/water extracts of Parma ham pigment both scavenged a semi-stable nitroxide radical (Fremy's salt), and both extracts reduced the rate of oxygen consumption for lipid peroxidation (initiated by metmyoglobin) very efficiently. For apomyoglobin no antioxidative capacity was observed, and the heme moiety of the pigment(s) of Parma ham were concluded to have antioxidative properties. The more lipophilic pigment, as extracted by acetone/water, had the most significant effect, and its ability to inhibit lipid oxidation was further tested in a model food system based on cooked pork. The lipid oxidation was increasingly inhibited by increasing additions from 0.12 ppm to 0.24 ppm Parma ham pigment, and the pigment protected a-tocopherol against degradation in a concentration dependent manner.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Klostermeyer, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3259/1/2170201.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Adamsen, Christina E.; Hansen, Mette L.; Møller, Jens K.S. and Skibsted, Leif H.   (2003) Studies on the antioxidative activity of red pigments in Italian-type dry-cured ham.   European Food Research and Technology, 217 (3), pp. 201-206.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3259/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>