<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of grass–clover forage and whole-wheat feeding on the sensory quality of eggs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Horsted, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hammershøj, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Allesen-Holm, B.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>BACKGROUND: A sensory panel evaluated the sensory profile  of eggs from hens from three experimental systems: (1) an indoor system × normal layer diet (InL), (2) a grass–clover forage system × normal layer diet (GrL), and (3) a grass–clover forage system × whole wheat and oyster shells (GrW).&#xD;
&#xD;
RESULTS: The taste of the albumen was significantly more ‘watery’ and the yolks a darker yellow/orange in the eggs from the GrL and GrW groups. The yolk was darkest from the GrW group. The yolks from the InL and GrW groups had a significantly more ‘fresh’, less ‘animal’, ‘cardboard’, and ‘intense’ aroma than the GrL group. The taste of the yolks from the InL and GrW groups was significantlymore ‘fresh’ and less ‘cardboard’-like compared to the GrL group. The yolks tasted significantly less ‘sulfurous’ in the GrW group than in the GrL group.&#xD;
&#xD;
CONCLUSION: The combination of a high feed intake from a grass–clover pasture and the type of feed allocated is an important factor in relation to the sensory quality of eggs. Thus, a less favourable sensory profile of eggs was found from hens on a grass–clover pasture and fed a normal layer diet.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18215/4/18215.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Horsted, K.; Hammershøj, M. and Allesen-Holm, B.H.   (2010) Effect of grass–clover forage and whole-wheat feeding on the sensory quality of eggs.   J Sci Food Agric, 90, pp. 343-348.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18215/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>