<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Why it failed? A case study in Turkish organic stock-raising</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oba, Beyza</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Few years ago a farmer who usually sells his products in the organic bazaar of İstanbul, Feriköy had to face a business challenge; should he raise organic animals as well? When he shared his ideas with his regular customers they were interested and even excited with the idea. Government was providing financial support for this industry and for the customers, idea was interesting because they would have access to the dairy products which at that time were not easily found in the regular shops. The idea was good but it did not work; for some time customers (although very few) gave support; they provided partial resources for buying the animals, later for food but in the long run having fresh organic milk, cheese and yogurt turned out to be an expensive adventure for them. The farmer, for some time carried the business by his own means and the support provided by the government authorities but gradually he had to give up as well.&#xD;
So this paper by focusing on other failure cases as well tries to provide a deeper understanding for developing organic stock-raising industry in Turkey so that small producers can take part in the market.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24272/3/24272.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oba, Beyza    (2014) Why it failed? A case study in Turkish organic stock-raising.           IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24272/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>