<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Was kann der biologische Landbau zur nachhaltigen Entwicklung im Süden beitragen? – Langfristige Systemvergleiche in den Tropen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zundel, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The demand of producer organisations, development agencies, national authorities, and international donors for secured data regarding the agronomic, ecological and economic performance of organic agriculture in low-income countries of the tropics is high. Yet, no systematic comparisons between organic and conventional farming systems have been conducted which allow long-term statements in these areas. The Research Institute of Organic Farming (FiBL), together with its partners, wants to establish long-term farming system comparisons in various agro-ecological and agro-economic contexts to study the various parameters which are essential for sustainable development. At present, three sites are being established: (a) in a sub-humid area in Kenya where farming is subsistence-oriented; (b) in a semi-arid area in India where cotton is produced for the export market; and (c) in a humid area in Bolivia where perennial fruits are produced for the local and the export market. This network of system comparisons in the tropics will support the development of organic farming and sustainable agriculture on a technical, economic and political level.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9387/1/9387_Zundel_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zundel, Christine; Kilcher, Lukas and Mäder, Paul    (2007) Was kann der biologische Landbau zur nachhaltigen Entwicklung im Süden beitragen? – Langfristige Systemvergleiche in den Tropen.  [What can organic agriculture contribute to sustainable development? – Long-term farming system comparisons in the tropics.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9387/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>