<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of Rapid or slow release nitrogen supply and cover crop/weed management on crop yield, pest incidence and fruit quality in intensive organic apple production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lindhard Pedersen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Apple is the commercially most important top fruit crop grown in the European Union. &#xD;
In spring 2001 one-year-old trees of the apple variety ‘Ingrid Marie’ were established in an organic production system with 3.0 m between the tree rows. Each plot consisted of three semi-plots at planting distances 0.6m (5555 trees ha-1), 0.9 m (3333 trees ha –1) and 1.2 m (2777 trees ha-1). Tree growth, soil moisture, soil-, leaf- and branch analysis, diseases, fruit production, outer and inner fruit quality were measured.&#xD;
The healthiest trees with the best coloured fruits were produced on trees grown in weed. But the yield was so low that production was not economical. A high production combined with trees less infected with fruit tree canker and with a satisfactory colouring was produced on trees grown in intensive production system of 5555 trees per ha with no nitrogen supply.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9916/1/Lindhard-2007-NitrogenApple.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lindhard Pedersen, H.    (2007) Effect of Rapid or slow release nitrogen supply and cover crop/weed management on crop yield, pest incidence and fruit quality in intensive organic apple production.       Poster at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9916/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>