<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Meemesilase ja biofungitsiidi Prestop Mix kasutamine aedmaasika hahkhallituse tõrjes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Muljar, Riin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mänd, Marika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study was conducted in 2010 in five experimental areas of Tartu County. Honey bee hives were placed at the edge of strawberry fields at first bloom; each hive had a special dispenser attached containing the biofungicide Prestop Mix, which is a preparation of the parasitic fungus Gliocladium catenulatum. As the bees exited the hive through the dispenser, they were dusted with the Prestop Mix preparation and carried it to the strawberry field. Two treatments were established: 1) a bee-excluded untreated check (covered with exclusion cages), and 2) a bee-delivered Prestop Mix treatment. We compared the bee-disseminated treatment with the untreated check by counting the healthy and Botrytis-infected berries; we also compared strawberry varieties. Our results show that treating the strawberry plants with the bee-dispersed Prestop Mix reduced the proportion of infected berries over 10% compared to the check. We also found that the efficiency of the treatment depended somewhat on the strawberry variety: the variety ‘Sonata’ compared to ‘Polka’ was slightly more efficient.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28646/1/Muljar%20ja%20M%C3%A4nd%202011c.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Muljar, Riin and Mänd, Marika    (2011) Meemesilase ja biofungitsiidi Prestop Mix kasutamine aedmaasika hahkhallituse tõrjes.  [Using honeybees and the biofungicide Prestop Mix in gray mould control in strawberry.]  In:     Kogumik Agronoomia 2010/2011, pp. 183-186.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28646/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>