<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulierung der Weißen Fliege im Kohlanbau durch den&#xD;
kombinierten Einsatz von Kulturschutznetzen und Nützlingen –&#xD;
Erste Ergebnisse des BÖL-Projekts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schultz, Britta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wedemeyer, Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saucke, Helmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leopold, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmermann, Olaf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The cabbage whitefly, Aleyrodes proletella, has gradually developed into a key pest,&#xD;
affecting the quality of organic Brassica vegetables. Netting may provide partial control&#xD;
of the cabbage whitefly. In the ongoing project mechanical control methods using the&#xD;
barrier effect of netting and biological control methods with naturally occurring whitefly&#xD;
antagonists, namely the predatory ladybeetle Clitostethus arcuatus and the larval&#xD;
parasitoid Encarsia tricolor, are combined and their efficiency tested in small-scale&#xD;
field experiments. During the first year, adverse weather conditions affected the study.&#xD;
However, first results indicate, that even under relatively low host densities the&#xD;
parasitation by E. tricolor was enhanced after their release inside the nets, in&#xD;
comparison to corresponding controls with nets only. C. arcuatus adults were&#xD;
recovered up to 60 days after their release, although progeny was not observed&#xD;
throughout the vegetation period. Application of netting reduced whitefly larvae and&#xD;
puparia by more than 70%.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14448/1/Schultz_14448.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schultz, Britta ; Wedemeyer, Rainer; Saucke, Helmut ; Leopold, Jörg and Zimmermann, Olaf    (2009) Regulierung der Weißen Fliege im Kohlanbau durch den kombinierten Einsatz von Kulturschutznetzen und Nützlingen – Erste Ergebnisse des BÖL-Projekts.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14448/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>