<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Certification in the iPOPY Countries and Germany – Current Status and Future Challenges</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roehl, Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper is part of the proceedings of an iPOPY seminar. Organic production has to be certified and labeled along the supply chain in order to maintain trust in organic premium products. Since January 1st 2009, organic certification in Europe is subject to the new Council Regulation (EC) No 834/2007 of 28 June 2007. This regulation specifically excludes so-called mass catering operations. It is up to EU member states to apply national rules or private standards insofar as these comply with community law. The paper presents the state of the art and upcoming changes of organic certification of out-of-home catering in Germany with regard to Norway, Finland, Denmark, and Italy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), DK-Tjele</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Noelting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15542/1/iPOPY_Proceedings_BioFach_2009_StrassnerRoehl.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strassner, Carola and Roehl, Rainer    (2009) Organic Certification in the iPOPY Countries and Germany – Current Status and Future Challenges.   In: Noelting, Benjamin (Ed.)  Providing organic school food for youths in Europe - Policy strategies, certification and supply chain management in Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway. Proceedings of the iPOPY seminar held at the BioFach February 20th 2009 in Nuremberg, Germany, International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), DK-Tjele, CORE Organic Series Report, pp. 18-22.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15542/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>