<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Increasing organic consumption by school meals – lessons learned in the iPOPY project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Finland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Italy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Increasingly, food consumption occurs in&#xD;
out-of-home contexts, where organic food can also&#xD;
have a role to play. Public food services may be&#xD;
utilised to increase the sustainability of providing&#xD;
nutrition. Although school meals may be well suited&#xD;
to integrating organic food and sustainable nutrition&#xD;
concepts, school food provision systems are very&#xD;
different across Europe. This paper compares school&#xD;
food provision systems and their utilisation of organic&#xD;
food in Denmark, Finland, Germany, Italy and&#xD;
Norway, discussing how various strategies and instruments&#xD;
used for organic food procurement in school&#xD;
meals may increase organic food consumption. Using&#xD;
five analytical categories—(a) type of school food&#xD;
service, (b) degree of public financing, (c) degree of&#xD;
political and administrative involvement in school&#xD;
food procurement in general, (d) degree of specific&#xD;
support for organic school food, and (e) availability of&#xD;
organic food supply adapted to school food service—&#xD;
values have been assessed for each country in order to&#xD;
summarise and visually display their differences.&#xD;
Especially, the degree of specific support for organic&#xD;
school food shows a significant relation to the actual&#xD;
use of organic food in school meals. To maximise the&#xD;
share of organic food in school meals, instruments&#xD;
should be adapted to the actual points of departure in&#xD;
each case. It is argued that strategies and instruments&#xD;
designed to promote public procurement of organic&#xD;
food increase the consumption of organic food in&#xD;
schools and that such policies will have the greatest&#xD;
impact when they are linked up with broader concepts&#xD;
such as a whole-school approach and sustainable&#xD;
nutrition.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17430/1/fulltext.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin and Nölting, Benjamin   (2011) Increasing organic consumption by school meals – lessons learned in the iPOPY project.   Organic Agriculture, 1, pp. 91-110.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17430/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>