<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Opportunities and Barriers for Niche Marketing of Lamb in European LFAs&#xD;
based on Consumer Attitudes to Product Quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ashworth, Stuart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boutonnet, Jean-Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brunori, Gianluca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Papadopoulus, Ilias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With commodity prices continuing to decrease and with policy constraint that farmers&#xD;
cannot easily increase their incomes by increasing volumes of production, they must&#xD;
find alternative ways to maintain their standard of living. This can be achieved by&#xD;
either niche marketing of agricultural products or by environmental payments, which&#xD;
are either paid by the government or the consumer.&#xD;
The results of a consumer survey carried out in Less Favoured Areas in Scotland,&#xD;
Germany, Greece, France and Italy to assess consumer attitudes of what constitutes&#xD;
the quality of lamb and the extent to which this provides an opportunity to exploit&#xD;
niche marketing, are discussed. Consumers generally have much less interest in the&#xD;
use of regional labelling, ecologically friendly production systems or the linkage of&#xD;
landscape and production systems in the buying decision. It is concluded that&#xD;
potential exists to develop niche markets for lamb and that these niches demonstrate&#xD;
significant regional differences. Equally, however, it is concluded that there are only&#xD;
limited rewards for production systems which are sympathetic to the environment. To&#xD;
achieve this goal, policy intervention is required, geared directly to environmental&#xD;
management practices. Future policy support towards farmers in LFAs is needed as a&#xD;
mix of policy instrument. Nowadays, financial support of farming in LFAs is&#xD;
necessary to grant farmers income, but structural support (e. g. in marketing products&#xD;
under reliable labelling towards consumers’ requests with trust in the "added&#xD;
values") can help to increase LFA-farmers income without increasing subsidies.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Deutscher Fachverlag GmbH</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8749/1/068_T4.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rahmann, Gerold; Ashworth, Stuart; Boutonnet, Jean-Paul; Brunori, Gianluca and Papadopoulus, Ilias   (2001) Opportunities and Barriers for Niche Marketing of Lamb in European LFAs based on Consumer Attitudes to Product Quality.  [Opportunities and Barriers for Niche Marketing of Lamb in European LFAs based on Consumer Attitudes to Product Quality.]  Agrarwirtschaft, 50 (5), pp. 293-301.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8749/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>