<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The characterisation of the Danish e-business - Aarstiderne as an alternative food network: A case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Poirier, Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heller, Elizabeth Louise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Di Martino, Enrico</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alix, Sébastien</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The object of this case study is Aarstiderne, a Danish organic food company delivering 30,000 boxes per week. The study aims to characterise this company within the context of alternative food chains, using specific environmental, economic and social criteria. During the course of the study, 19 interviews were conducted with company members, clients, suppliers, and researchers. In addition, a life cycle analysis and a price comparison for two box types were conducted. The results of the study focus on the environmental, economic, and social impacts of the company on its stakeholders throughout the food network. These results indicate how the company can be characterised in relation to other alternative food chains, with specific attention paid to how this food chain addresses some limitations of supermarket and Community Supported Agriculture food distribution models. Lastly, a comparison of the company’s own ideals to its practices is made and some suggestions for improved coherence between ideals, practices and impacts on sustainability are put forth.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Copenhagen</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006-06-13</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18187/1/18187.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Poirier, Caroline; Heller, Elizabeth Louise; Di Martino, Enrico and Alix, Sébastien   (2006) The characterisation of the Danish e-business - Aarstiderne as an alternative food network: A case study.   Thesis, The Royal Veterinary and Agricultural University (KVL) of Copenhagen.  University of Copenhagen.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18187/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>