<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breeding for improved responsiveness to arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in onion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Galvan, Guillermo A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burger, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuyper, Thom W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kik, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scholten, Olga E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF) play an important role in the uptake of nutrients and water from soil. Onions, Allium cepa L., are plants with a shallow root system. As a result, onion plants need a lot of fertiziler for their growth. Furthermore, onion plants are sensitive to drought. The aim of the current research project is to study the beneficial effect of mycorrhizal fungi on the growth and development of Allium species and to determine whether it is possible to improve onions for mycorrhizal responsiveness by means of breeding. Variation among Allium species and segregation observed in a interspecific tri-hybrid population indicate that selection and thus breeding for high responsiveness to AMF is possible.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9866/1/galvan-etal-2007-mycorrhizal_fungi_onion.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Galvan, Guillermo A.; Burger, Karin; Kuyper, Thom W.; Kik, Chris and Scholten, Olga E.    (2007) Breeding for improved responsiveness to arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi in onion.       Poster at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9866/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>