<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Landraces and Obsolete Cultivars of Minor Wheat Species in the Czech Collection of Wheat Genetic Resources</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bradova, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dotlacil, Ladislav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Proportion of landraces in the Czech collection of wheat genetic resources differentiates deeply among wheat species, 4.2 % in bread, 77.6 % in emmer and 80.0 % in einkorn wheat collection. The set of 10 selected emmer wheat landraces has been characterised by high molecular weight glutenin subunits (HMW-GSs), evaluated for 3 years in field trials and described by grain quality parameters. Emmer wheat accessions distinguished considerably in polymorphisms of HMW-GSs. Out of the total number of 10 studied emmer wheat landraces 5 accessions appeared to be homogeneous in the electrophoretic patterns of HMW-GSs and they were formed by a single glutenin line. Much higher crude protein content in comparison with check bread wheat cultivar was detected in all emmer wheat accessions. Proportion of this important component varied between 15.5 and 22.2 %. On the other hand SDS sedimentation, as an important parameter of bread making quality was very low (1.2 - 4.4 ml) and similar situation has been recorded in gluten index. Based on such results the emmer wheat landraces can be considered potentially more suitable for other purposes than for preparation of bread e.g. for different grain mixtures, purée etc.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Stehno, Zdenek; Bradova, J.; Dotlacil, Ladislav and Konvalina, Petr   (2010) Landraces and Obsolete Cultivars of Minor Wheat Species in the Czech Collection of Wheat Genetic Resources.  [Krajové a opomíjené odrůdy minoritních pšenic v české kolekci genetických zdrojů.]  Czech Journal of Genetics and Plant Breeding, 46, pp. 100-105.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21247/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>