<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tree shading: an efficient method to control alternate bearing?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conventional and integrated fruit growers, but not organic producers, have the possibility&#xD;
to use thinning agents (e.g. benzyl adenine), which allow crop regulation at a relatively late&#xD;
stage (10-16 mm fruit size). A few surveys have shown that by reducing net&#xD;
photosynthesis after blossom, June fruit drop increases. This could be an interesting new&#xD;
approach for organic apple orchards. Since 2003, different trials have been carried out at&#xD;
the Laimburg Research Station on the variety Golden Delicious rootstock M9 to devise a&#xD;
method for practical use by fruit growers. Unfortunately, there are still several constraints&#xD;
to the practical application of the shading method, not least because it does not sufficiently&#xD;
reduce alternate fruit bearing in the following year.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13737/1/310-313.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Lardschneider, Ewald and Casera, Claudio    (2008) Tree shading: an efficient method to control alternate bearing?   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 310-313.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13737/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>