<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Activity theoretical view on crop rotation planning in organic vegetable farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seppänen, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Crop rotation is an essential basis of an organic farming system. An activity theoretical&#xD;
concept of object shall be used in examining planning processes of crop rotations. Farmers'&#xD;
object construction means their creating and maintaining the social meaning and purpose of&#xD;
the material farming activity. I shall assume the farmers´ object construction in planning crop&#xD;
rotations to reflect their overall object in organic vegetable farming. First, this paper examines&#xD;
theoretically the object in organic vegetable farming by devising a framework of different&#xD;
types of object constructions. Second, two farms with organic vegetable production will be&#xD;
described, and the farmers´ objects will be shown in the light of the histories of the farms.&#xD;
This will show that the different types of objects have not evolved at random. Third, the&#xD;
dynamic movement of the object construction in the crop rotation planning processes is&#xD;
explored. The results will show that the farmers´ object, although historically understood, is&#xD;
not fixed. On the contrary, the object is in a constant move and even contradictory.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17589/1/seppanen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seppänen, Laura    (2000) Activity theoretical view on crop rotation planning in organic vegetable farming.       Paper at:   European farming and rural systems research and extension into the next millenium: Environmental, agricultural and socio-economic issues : European IFSA symposium, Volos, Greece, 3-7 April, 2000.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17589/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>