<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Leistung und langfristige Wirkung auf Humus- und Nährstoffhaushalt verschie-dener Anbausysteme des ökologischen Landbau – Ergebnisse der 1. Rotation eines Dauerfeldversuches</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Reinicke, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christen, Olaf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The increased importance of organic farming in recent years, has led to a diversifica-tion of production systems. Since 1998 different farming systems were compared in a long-term field trial at the university of Halle-Wittenberg. The systems simulated either arable or mixed farming with various tillage treatments. In the first rotation the crop yields showed a clear response to the different farming systems. The balances of organic substances were mainly affected by the amount of organic fertilisers applied, whereas the nitrogen balance was influenced by the nitrogen fixation capacity of the clover-lucerne sward.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9768/1/9768_Reinicke_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Reinicke, Frank and Christen, Olaf    (2007) Leistung und langfristige Wirkung auf Humus- und Nährstoffhaushalt verschie-dener Anbausysteme des ökologischen Landbau – Ergebnisse der 1. Rotation eines Dauerfeldversuches.  [Yields and quantification of the nutrient cycling of different production methods – Results from the first rotation of a long-term field experiment.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9768/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>