<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The role of intercropping on insects diversity in dryland field crops in a Mediterranean site</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Caballero, Berta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romero, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perez, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ventura, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chamorro, Lourdes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Goula, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sans, F.Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This work aims to evaluate the effect of crop type and density on insects’ community in the Mediterranean re-gion. In winter of 2004, four 35m x 10m blocks (replicates) were delimited and 24 equidistant 2m x 3m plots were marked. Seven crop types (barley, vetch, turnip, barley-vetch, barley-turnip, vetch-turnip and barley-vetch-turnip) at three densities were randomly established within each block. Fifteen crop shoots per plot were randomly collected in May to evaluate insect’s abundance and diversity. Our results suggest that inter-crop has a positive effect on abundance of most exam-ined groups of insects and diversity, specifically when vetch is incorporated in the mixture. Changes in abun-dance of aphids, trips and ants are also discussed connected with vetch presence.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7509/1/caballero.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Caballero, Berta; Romero, Albert; Perez, Nicolas; Ventura, Daniel; Chamorro, Lourdes; Goula, Marta and Sans, F.Xavier    (2006) The role of intercropping on insects diversity in dryland field crops in a Mediterranean site.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7509/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>