<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>National state-of-the-art report</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borec, Andreja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prišenk, Jernej</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Slovenia lies between Croatia (south), Austria (north), Hungary (east) and Italy on the west part. It has approximately 2.000.000 million inhabitants with 20.273 km2 surface area.  &#xD;
Slovenia is predominately mountain country. Slovenian mountain and hilly regions are spread out over more than 72,3% of that nation’s total area (1.467.240 hectares). The hilly and mountain regions fall under LFA (less favored) areas which represent 86,3% (1.750.920 hectares) of all nation’s total area. The 74,2% (approximately 449.000 hectares) of agricultural land in use are under LFA. Forests and the forest landscape are the most recognisable spatial elements in Slovenia, which also represent a large market opportunity and a comparable advantage for Slovenia. With forests covering 60% of its territory, Slovenia is the third most forest-rich country in Europe. Animal husbandry is the prevailing activity in Slovenian agriculture. GDP in Slovenia is 35466,0 (in Miol €) in 2012 and 36171,8 (in Miol €) in 2011. Agriculture reaches 2.1% of the GDP in the national economy, it means approximately 1396,1 (in Miol €). From final data in 2010 the agricultural holdings used 474,432 hectares of agricultural area and bred 421,553 LSU (livestock units). In 2010 almost 79% of agricultural holdings in Slovenia bred livestock.  An average agricultural holding thus used 6.4 hectares of agricultural area and bred 5.6 LSU. In the past ten years the average size of agricultural holdings in Slovenia increased by 0.8 hectares of utilized agricultural area and 0.1 LSU.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27672/3/27672.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borec, Andreja and Prišenk, Jernej         (2013) National state-of-the-art report.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27672/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>