<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Glycemic index of buckwheat bread</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rokka, Susanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Järvenpää, Eila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tahvonen, Raija</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Glycemic responses (two hour tolerance test) of buckwheat bread containing buckwheat and oat&#xD;
flour and control bread containing oat flour only were measured in clinical studies according to&#xD;
FAO/WHO recommendations noticing the recent improvements in the methods; A standard&#xD;
evening meal (supper) was be provided for each test person for the nights before tests, and test&#xD;
persons got exact orders for the exercise on the test morning. Test persons (10) fasted 8-12&#xD;
hours before each test. They ate a portion of bread or glucose containing 50 g available&#xD;
carbohydrates.&#xD;
&#xD;
The GI values of buckwheat bread and control bread will be shown in poster. The preliminary&#xD;
results of six test persons show that buckwheat bread has a slower but longer lasting glycemic&#xD;
effect than glucose. In addition, test persons commented in their questionnaires that&#xD;
the buckwheat bread kept feel of hunger away efficiently.&#xD;
&#xD;
According to the preliminary results, buckwheat bread seems to be a good choice to stabilize&#xD;
blood glucose levels after meal.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18299/1/Rokka.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rokka, Susanna; Järvenpää, Eila and Tahvonen, Raija    (2010) Glycemic index of buckwheat bread.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18299/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>