<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of green manure on root development and cotton yield under Mediterranean conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thomopoulos, MSc P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bilalis, Ass. Prof. D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konstantas, MSc A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Efthimiadou, MSc A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two experiments were conducted in Greece, during the years 2005 and 2006, in order to evaluate the effect of two legumes (vetch: Vicia sativa and faba bean: Vicia faba) on the root development and yield of the following cotton. Concerning the cotton cultivation the Organic Agriculture guidelines were followed. In both years the higher values of the root characteristics of the cotton were found in the plots where vetch had been incorporated. The seed cotton yield for vetch was 2850 and 3137 kg ha-1 in 2005 and 2006, respectively. Furthermore, in both years, a statistically important factor of correlation, between the nitrogen quantities of the soil and the seed cotton yield, had been appeared.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11556/1/Thomopoulos_11556_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thomopoulos, MSc P.; Bilalis, Ass. Prof. D.; Konstantas, MSc A. and Efthimiadou, MSc A.    (2008) The effect of green manure on root development and cotton yield under Mediterranean conditions.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11556/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>