<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interactions of summer pruning techniques and vine performance in the white cultivar Ortrugo (Vitis vinifera L.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gatti, Matteo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garavani , A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cantatore, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poni, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background and Aims: The increasing interest by the wine market in sparkling white wines challenges how the&#xD;
desired grape composition can be achieved under the pressure of global warming. The aim of the present study was&#xD;
to assess the viability of summer pruning as a tool to pilot ripening towards desired compositional patterns.&#xD;
Methods and Results: Ortrugo was subjected to basal leaf removal applied either at pre-flowering (ELR) or in&#xD;
lag-phase (LLR) and to bunch thinning (BT; removal of 50% of crop at lag-phase) in comparison with untreated&#xD;
control (C). Treatments induced large variation in bunch mass (30% less in ELR vs BT), yield per vine (37 and 21%&#xD;
less in BT and ELR vs C) and total soluble solids at harvest (BT scored 2.9°Brix higher than that of C). Conversely,&#xD;
given the same harvest date, all practices failed to maintain titratable acidity (TA) at the threshold of 6.5 g/L.&#xD;
Conclusions: The data suggest that crop regulation achieved in the high yielding Ortrugo, through either BT or ELR,&#xD;
increases sugar accumulation rate so that concurrent optimal TA level (≅6.5 g/L) can be easily achieved by slightly&#xD;
anticipating harvest date. Under conditions of thermal or light stress, or weather conducive to bunch rot, preference&#xD;
should be given to ELR.&#xD;
Significance of the Study: Suitable summer pruning techniques might be used as flexible and powerful tools to&#xD;
direct ripening towards the desired crop composition.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Gatti, Matteo; Garavani , A; Cantatore, A and Poni, Stefano   (2015) Interactions of summer pruning techniques and vine performance in the white cultivar Ortrugo (Vitis vinifera L.).   Australian Journal of Grape and Wine Research , 21 (1), pp. 80-89.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28527/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>