<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Animal welfare, ethics and organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Verhoog, Henk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lund, Vonne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this chapter we first give an overview of different interpretations of animal welfare and their relation to different lay and expert approaches to animal welfare. The importance of values to animal welfare is discussed and confronted with the role of science and the scientific ideals of value-freedom and objectivity. The interpretations of animal welfare are then compared with different frameworks from bio-ethics, which can help clarify the moral aspects of animal welfare. The values of organic farming are then discussed as a departure point for a discussion of what a relevant view of animal welfare might be like, in the context of organic farming. This reveals obvious conflicts between different values within organic farming, and some of these dilemmas are illustrated by examples from the organic practice. Finally, we indicate the relevance of such philosophical questions on values and the meaning of animal welfare for the future course of the organic movement.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CABI Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Vaarst, Mette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Roderick, Steve</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lund, Vonne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockerets, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/207/1/Chap-02_Vonne_30_apr.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Verhoog, Henk; Lund, Vonne and Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted    (2004) Animal welfare, ethics and organic farming.    In: Vaarst, Mette; Roderick, Steve; Lund, Vonne and Lockerets, William (Eds.)   Animal health and welfare in organic agriculture.  CABI Publishing, chapter 5, pp. 73-94.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/207/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>