<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Steinmehl zur Regulierung des Rapsglanzkäfers Meligethes spp.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dierauer, Hansueli</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic agriculture, treatments with rock dusts for soil amendment, disease prevention, or insect control have a long tradition. Clinoptilolite (a naturally occurring zeolite) was tested against pollen beetle Meligethes spp. in oilseed rape fields in order to find a control strategy compatible with the guidelines for organic agriculture in Switzerland. Dust and spray applications were evaluated in several large-scale field trials from 2008 to 2010. Dust applications using 300-750 kg / ha pulverized Clinoptilolite (particle size &lt;0.1 mm; product Klinofeed, company Unipoint, Switzerland) were applied using a drop-box fertilizer spreader or a Vicon pendulum spreader. For spray applications the same Clinoptilolite (product Klinospray) with a particle size of 0.017 mm was applied at rates of 30 - 50 kg / ha with a wetting agent (Heliosol, 2 l / ha; 600 l waster / ha) using a standard field crop sprayer. Under the dry and sunny weather conditions in 2009 and 2010, the treatments significantly reduced the number of pollen beetles by 50 to 80% until seven days after treatment (BBCH 51-54). Under the rainy weather conditions in 2008, no reduction of pollen beetles was observed. In all experimental years a visibly more intense flowering was observed in the treated plots. Pod setting on the main raceme was significantly increased in the treated plots.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21498/1/21498_Daniel.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia and Dierauer, Hansueli    (2013) Steinmehl zur Regulierung des Rapsglanzkäfers Meligethes spp.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21498/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>