<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecosystem service provision by establishing temporal habitats in agricultural environments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huusela-Veistola, Erja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alanen, Eeva-Liisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hyvönen, Terho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuussaari, Mikko</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Short-term rotational fallows, new set-asides and seed mixtures containing&#xD;
specific seed-bearing crops are best alternative to provide seed food for farmland&#xD;
birds (Hyvönen &amp; Huusela-Veistola 2011). The age of set-aside and vegetation&#xD;
structure are more important than seed mixture or plant species richness in&#xD;
supporting insect food for birds, and therefore set asides of various ages are&#xD;
needed (Hyvönen &amp; Huusela-Veistola 2011).&#xD;
Even a short-term fallow sown with a simple seed mixture can encourage&#xD;
populations of generalist predators (Huusela-Veistola &amp; Hyvönen 2006), but longterm&#xD;
set-asides may be even better for natural enemies (Huusela-Veistola 2008).&#xD;
Because of the various species requirements numerous habitats are needed if&#xD;
biodiversity is to be increased or maintained. At the landscape level, the&#xD;
proportion and location of non-crop temporal habitats may be important factors&#xD;
for key ecosystem services. Therefore, temporal habitats, e.g. set-asides, of&#xD;
various ages and different vegetation structures should be included in the&#xD;
agricultural landscape to encourage optimum functional biodiversity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19709/1/huusela.docx</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huusela-Veistola, Erja; Alanen, Eeva-Liisa; Hyvönen, Terho and Kuussaari, Mikko    (2011) Ecosystem service provision by establishing temporal habitats in agricultural environments.       Paper at:   Biodiversity in agriculture - lessons learned and future directions, NJF seminar 436, Ulvik in Hardanger, Norway, 24-26 May 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19709/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>