<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic conversion strategies for stockless farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huxham, Sally K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sparkes, Debbie L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilson, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. The identification of appropriate stockless organic conversion strategies will help farmers and growers in their decision to convert to organic production. The current practice of a two-year red clover/ryegrass ley conversion relies on subsidies to be economically viable. This standard conversion and six alternatives were tested on a sandy loam soil entering organic conversion. A test crop of winter wheat will be grown across the entire experimental area in the first fully organic year (2001/2002). Strategies containing a legume ley phase returned the greatest amount of nitrogen to the soil. At the end of the second year, pre-cultivation, there were no differences in soil mineral nitrogen between strategies. Gross margins were greater from those strategies with cash cropping than those without, in spite of the generally depressed yields. Preliminary analysis suggests that growing red clover for seed in year 1 followed by a red clover ley in year 2 could be the most profitable option.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8360/1/Huxham_Conversion_stockless_farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huxham, Sally K; Sparkes, Debbie L and Wilson, Paul    (2002) Organic conversion strategies for stockless farming systems.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 51-52.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8360/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>