<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rearing and releasing of Opius concolor  in organic olive orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>KOÇ, Fulya</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The olive tree finds suitable conditions for growing well in the Mediterranean basin. Besides, olives and olive oil play an increasingly important nutritional role in Mediterranean countries and are an essential part of what is widely known as “Mediterranean diet”. Unfortunately one of the most injurious pests is olive fly (Bactrocera oleae). Of African origin, this fruit fly is the key pest of olive throughout the Mediterranean Basin and the Middle East. The olive organic production is developing in order to save the environment and to obtain a safe product. One of the most difficult challenges for conformity of the organic method to Reg. CEE 2092/91 is plant protection. Various experimental tests on the biological control of the olive fruit fly have given encouraging results regarding the mass introduction of the endoparasite Opius concolor reared in laboratory conditions. Ceratitis capitata was used in the rearing program of Opius concolor in the insectarium of IAM-Bari (IT). For the releasing of Opius concolor two fields in the province of Bari (IT), which have two different climates, were tested in order to check the effect of two different climates on the populations of Opius concolor and also of B. oleae. It is concluded that the coastal area is more favorable than the inland for Opius concolor for a good parasitization. In the rearing program, the populations of the reared Opius were compared with those of the indigenous Opius in the insectarium according to parasitization and time development. Parasitation ability of reared Opius was higher than that of indigenous Opius and reared Opius lives longer under laboratory conditions. As for development over time there is no difference between reared Opius and the indigenous one.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6528/1/KocFulya02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>KOÇ, Fulya   (2002) Rearing and releasing of Opius concolor in organic olive orchards.  [Elevage et lâcher d’Opius concolor dans les oliveraies biologiques.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Tesi Master of Science, no. 280. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6528/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>