<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DOK-Versuch (Langzeituntersuchung zu biologisch-dynamischen, organisch-biologischen und konventionellen Landbausystemen)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An understanding of agro-ecosystems is key to determining effective farming systems. Here we report the 21-year study of agronomic and ecological performance of bio-dynamic, bio-organic, and conventional farming systems in Central Europe. We found crop yields to be 20 % lower in the organic systems, although input of fertiliser and energy was reduced by 34 – 53 %  and pesticide input by 97 %. Enhanced soil fertility and higher biodiversity found in organic plots may render these systems less dependent on external inputs.&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
	Soils are well buffered systems and an adaptation of the soil - plant relationship from high-input to low external input farming practices may last decades. For instance, soil nutrient stocks are frequently huge in European soils and a normalisation after conversion to organic low-input systems needs time. Also the adaptation of the soil micro-flora to altered chemical soil conditions presumably occurs only after a prolonged period of time upon conversion from high-input to low-input farming. Therefore, long-term trials are essential to assess the agronomic performance of low-input production systems and a focus should be put on studying the underlying soil processes.&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
-	to analyse the long-term agronomic performance of a Swiss wheat cultivar under organic and integrated farming systems (continued) &#xD;
-	to investigate the interrelations of soil properties and plant growth in different farming systems&#xD;
Experiments:&#xD;
-	to perform a system comparison experiment with organic and integrated farming (continued, running since 1978)&#xD;
-	to assess soil chemical, physical and biological properties&#xD;
-	to determine nitrogen and phosphorus dynamics related processes in the soil-plant –microorganisms - system&#xD;
-	to study the soil - plant interface&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
Soil microbial biomass analyses, enzyme activities, characterisation of microbial populations (Biolog, PLFA, DNA), assessment of mycorrihizal root colonisation and diversity by molecular tools, isotope tracer and dilution techniques.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    DOK: DOK-Versuch (Langzeituntersuchung zu biologisch-dynamischen, organisch-biologischen und konventionellen Landbausystemen).  [DOK Trial (long-term trial comparing bio-dynamic, organic, conventional).]   Runs 1978 - 2011.      Project Leader(s): Mäder, Paul and Fliessbach, Andreas, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14554/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>