<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutritional implications of organic conversion in large scale food service: Preliminary results from Core Organic research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>He, Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The discussion about nutritional advantages of organic consumption has traditionally focused on the properties of the food it self. Studies have shown however that change of consumption patterns towards organic food seems to&#xD;
induce changed dietary patterns. The current research was a part of the iPOPY study and was conducted to investigate if such changes can be found in school food settings. In other words does organic food schemes at school and related&#xD;
curricular activities help to create environments that are supportive for healthier eating among children? The research was carried out among school food&#xD;
coordinators in public schools in Denmark, Finland, Germany, and Italy. A questionnaire was adapted to fit the different languages and food cultures in the&#xD;
countries. The data suggest that schools with organic supply tend to develop organisational environments that a more supportive for healthy eating than their&#xD;
non organic counterparts. However the results were only significant for Denmark and Italy. In Germany results were significant in some cases whereas for Finland&#xD;
there were no differences or results were contradictory. The findings suggest the changes in school food services seems to be driven by different agendas but that&#xD;
awareness raising on nutrition and sustainability issues seems to be an important feature of many change processes. Findings also suggest that the two agendas although separated in the scientific literature is more integrated in the everyday life perspective of school practitioners.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-06-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17324/1/BEMIucdavis2010ABS%2BPPT.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg and He, Chen    (2010) Nutritional implications of organic conversion in large scale food service: Preliminary results from Core Organic research.       Speech at:   Foods for Health Workshop, arranged by Foods for Health Institute (FFHI), UC Davis and Centre for Advanced Food Studies (LMC), Denmark , Copenhagen, Denmark, Denmark June 21 – 22, 2010.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17324/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>