<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PARasites in Organic Livestock: innovative solutions to new challenges</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Parasites are ubiquitous in livestock in general and organic livestock in particular due to manage-ment factors promoting transmission (pastures/outdoor runs, plenty of bedding, restrictive use of parasiticides). The parasites cause poor animal welfare, production losses, disease, and non-uniform products. Pig helminths with hard-shelled eggs are difficult to control, as the eggs are highly resistant and may survive for years. The present project focuses on reducing the transmission of hard-shelled eggs to growing pigs by investigating 1) long-term survival of eggs on pastures (for optimising pasture rotation), 2) inactivation of eggs in bedding material (reducing transmission), and 3) a novel approach in bio-inactivation of eggs (chitin-degrading microfungi). The overall objective is, through close interaction between researchers, advisors and farmers, to develop new strategies to control parasitism in organic livestock. The strategies will ensure high levels of animal welfare (credibility), increased animal productivity (growth), and a minimum reliance on chemical drugs (robustness).</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19623/1/PAROL.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    PAROL: PARasites in Organic Livestock: innovative solutions to new challenges.  [Parasitter i økologiske produktionsdyr: innovative løsninger til nye udfordringer.]   Runs 2011 - 2013.      Project Leader(s): Thamsborg, Stig Milan.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19623/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>