<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings of the COST SUSVAR/ECO-PB Workshop on organic plant breeding strategies and the use of molecular markers</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In many countries,national projects are in progress to investigate the sustainable low-input approach.In the present COST network,these projects are coordinated by means of exchange of materials,establishing common methods for assessment and statistical analyses and by combining national experimental results.The common framework is cereal production in low-input sustainable systems with emphasis on crop diversity.The network is organised into six Working Groups,five focusing on specific research areas and one focusing on the practical application of the research results for variety testing:1)plant genetics and plant breeding,2)biostatistics,3)plant nutrition and soil microbiology,4)weed biology and plant competition,5)plant pathology and plant disease resistance biology and 6)variety testing and certification.It is essential that scientists from many disciplines work together to investigate the complex interactions between the crop and its environment,in order to be able to exploit the natural regulatory mechanisms of different agricultural systems for stabilising and increasing yield and quality.The results of this cooperation will contribute to commercial plant breeding as well as official variety testing,when participants from these areas disperse the knowledge achieved through the EU COST Action.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Louis Bolk Institute</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lammerts van Bueren, E.T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Østergård, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5107/1/5107.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lammerts van Bueren, E.T. and Østergård, H. (Eds.)    (2005) Proceedings of the COST SUSVAR/ECO-PB Workshop on organic plant breeding strategies and the use of molecular markers.   Louis Bolk Institute.  Proceedings of COST SUSVAR/ECO-PB Workshop on organic plant breeding strategies and the use of molecular markers, Driebergen, Netherlands, 17-19 January 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5107/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>