<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of alleycropping microclimate on the performance of groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) and sesame (Sesamum indicum L.) in the semi-desert region of northern Sudan</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shapo, Haider Elsafi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adam, Hussien Suliman</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An alley cropping system was established at Hudieba Research Station (17.57’N and 33.8’ E) on a loamy sand soil of the semi-desert region of northern Sudan. The objective of this study was to investigate the influence of modified microclimate in 6-m wide alleys formed by Acacia ampliceps and Acacia stenophylla on growth and yield of groundnut. and sesame. Above-ground interactions were determined by measuring air temperature, relative humidity, wind speed, solar energy and shade length and behaviour. Groundnut and sesame were evaluated for growth and yield by laying out sample plots at southern, central and northern part of the alleys and at control plots. Due to microclimatic modifications in the alleys, the yield of both crops in the alleys significantly (p=0.01) exceeded that of the sole crop. Yield reduction at the northern alley was fully compensated by high yield increase at southern and central alleys. The yield of groundnut increased by 37.7 and 19.6 % in the A.stenophylla and A.ampliceps alleys, respectively. On the other hand, the yield of sesame increased with the stenophylla-alley (+40.3%), while it decreased with ampliceps-alley (-51.5%). The results indicated that the competition for light was the major factor contributing to the increase or reduction of growth and yield of groundnut and sesame.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12199/1/12199.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Shapo, Haider Elsafi and Adam, Hussien Suliman    (2008) Influence of alleycropping microclimate on the performance of groundnut (Arachis hypogaea L.) and sesame (Sesamum indicum L.) in the semi-desert region of northern Sudan.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12199/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>