<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modern approaches for breeding high quality apples with durable resistance to scab, powdery mildew and fire blight</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kellerhals, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Patocchi, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Duffy, Brion</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frey, Jürg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>New methods to allow for more precise selection of tree and fruit characters in breeding&#xD;
programmes were developed in recent years. Marker-assisted selection (MAS) is common&#xD;
practice in the ACW apple breeding programme at Wädenswil. Genetic markers can&#xD;
reduce the number of plants and the time required for evaluation, thus new varieties&#xD;
become commercially available sooner. How can this molecular selection method&#xD;
reasonably be applied in an apple breeding programme? Application of phenotypic and&#xD;
molecular selection techniques in the ACW apple breeding programme and results are&#xD;
presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13699/1/226-231.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kellerhals, Markus; Patocchi, Andrea; Duffy, Brion and Frey, Jürg    (2008) Modern approaches for breeding high quality apples with durable resistance to scab, powdery mildew and fire blight.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 226-231.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13699/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>