<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutrient budgets on organic farms: a review of published</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stockdale, Elizabeth A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine A</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. On organic farms it is important that a balance between inputs and outputs of nutrients is achieved. This paper collates nutrient budgets collated at the farm scale for 88 farms in 9 temperate countries. The majority of budgets were compiled for dairy farms (56). All the nitrogen budgets showed an N surplus (average 83 kg N ha-1 year-1). The phosphorus (P) and potassium (K) budgets showed both surpluses and deficits (average 3.4 kg P ha-1 year-1; 13.7 kg K ha-1 year-1). For all nutrients as nutrient inputs increased the surplus increased more significantly than the nutrient outputs. Overall, the data illustrate the diversity of management systems in place on organic farms, which consequently lead to significant variability in nutrient use efficiency and potential nutrient sustainability between farms. There are opportunities for almost all organic farmers to improve the efficiency of nutrient cycling on the farm and increase short-term productivity and long-term sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8380/1/Stockdale_watson_Nutrient_budgets.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stockdale, Elizabeth A and Watson, Christine A    (2002) Nutrient budgets on organic farms: a review of published.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 129-132.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8380/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>