<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmer opinion on the process of health and welfare planning in Austria, Denmark, Germany, Norway and Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gratzer, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stöger, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, Gidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejdell, Cecilie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Britt I. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Berit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whistance, Lindsay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report serves as a deliverable from the ANIPLAN project, with the original title ‘Evaluation report on state of the art regarding animal health and welfare planning in the participating countries’ (Deliverable 5.1). We chose to focus on the farmers’ perspective in each country, and ask the farmers who had participated in our project how they perceived the process of animal health and welfare planning. We did that using a questionnaire which each participant used in an interview with the farmer, asking some specific questions with the aim to evaluate how the farmers had experienced the ANIPLAN approach. We found that this focus was important as a supplement to other outcomes from the project, such as reduction of medicines (Ivemeyer et al., 2011) and improvement of animal based parameters (Gratzer et al., 2011). Furthermore potential scenarios for implementation of this concept into practice can be developed from the farmers responses.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18407/1/18407.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leeb, Christine; Gratzer, Elisabeth; Huber, Johann; Stöger, Elisabeth; Winckler, Christoph; Brinkmann, Jan; March, Solveig; Walkenhorst, Michael; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Smolders, Gidi; Mejdell, Cecilie; Henriksen, Britt I. F.; Hansen, Berit; Whistance, Lindsay and Vaarst, Mette    (2011) Farmer opinion on the process of health and welfare planning in Austria, Denmark, Germany, Norway and Switzerland.    In:     The process of minimising medicine use through dialogue based animal health and welfare planning.  , pp. 80-88.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18407/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>