<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ansätze zur Landschaftsentwicklung durch Landwirtschaft – das Beispiel Marbachstal/ Kassel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Elsen, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a diverse landscape is no longer automatically produced by agriculture, the development of landscape may become a new challenge for organic farms, and for the integration of agriculture and nature development, too. The perception of the landscape can be the basis to create a process of landscape development instead of carrying out a single landscape plan. The example of a newly founded organic landscape and gardening farm in the Marbach Valley (Kassel) describes the first steps how to develop a dialogue between people from outside the farm (people engaged in nature conservation, local authorities), the farmer and the landscape. Two seminars were carried out as a first encounter – a social process in order to appreciate values of landscape and nature, and to integrate the goal of landscape development into organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Reents, Hans-Jürgen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/743/1/0743-elsen-t-2001-landschaftsentw.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Elsen, Thomas    (2001) Ansätze zur Landschaftsentwicklung durch Landwirtschaft – das Beispiel Marbachstal/ Kassel.  [Approaches to the development of landscape by agriculture - the example of the Marbach Valley / Kassel.]  In: Reents, Hans-Jürgen (Ed.)  6. Wissenschaftstagung zum Ökologischen Landbau "Von Leit-bildern zu Leit-linien", pp. 349-352.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/743/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>