<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Why ban sex hormones in the nursery?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Canada</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Canada leads the world with new regulations to prohibit the importation, sale and advertising of polycarbonate baby bottles that contain bisphenol A (BPA). The world production of BPA is currently 3.3 billion kilograms per year, half a kilogram per person. The estrogenic activity of BPA has been known at least since 1936. Estrogens have biological effects at parts per billion. BPA is used in food and beverage containers, including baby bottles, some drink bottles, and food container linings, in particular can linings. A recent study in the USA reported that all the adult subjects tested had bisphenol A in their urine. Canada has just declared bisphenol A to be a toxic substance. Canada has responded to the accumulating evidence that BPA leaches from polycarbonate baby bottles and behaves like an estrogen. An extra dose of female sex hormones is not the best of dietary supplements for babies, either male or female; or for teenagers, or even adults. Canada is the first country in the world to act to banish bisphenol A from the nursery.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bio-Dynamics Tasmania</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Domeney, Penny</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15074/1/15074.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2008) Why ban sex hormones in the nursery?   Journal of Bio-Dynamics Tasmania (92), pp. 12-18.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15074/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>