<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kemink subsoiling before and after planting</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bugge Henriksen, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søgaard, Carsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Kemink Exact Soil Management System is a non-inversion soil management system based on subsoiling, ridges and controlled traffic. Previous studies have documented benefits of the Kemink system used in its entirety, but the isolated effect of Kemink subsoiling has not been investigated before. To determine the isolated effect of Kemink subsoiling before and after planting two field experiments in sugar beet and barley were conducted in 1999 and 2000 under low nutrient input conditions in a conventional soil management system without recognized compaction problems. Kemink subsoiling after planting generally showed a negative effect on the growth and yield of both crops, whereas subsoiling before planting increased sugar beet yield from 8.4 to 9.5 t ha-1 and sugar beet nitrogen uptake from 48.5 to 57.4 kg ha-1. There was no effect of subsoiling before planting on the grain yield of barley. The negative effect of subsoiling after planting was more pronounced in 1999 than in 2000, and more pronounced in spring barley. The study shows that Kemink subsoiling after planting involves a significant risk of crop damage and cannot be expected to improve crop performance in conventional soil management systems in its current form, whereas Kemink subsoiling before planting may have potential as a measure to increase yield of sugar beet and possibly other row crops too, under low nutrient input conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier, Netherlands</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1568/1/1568.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bugge Henriksen, Christian; Rasmussen, Jesper and Søgaard, Carsten   (2005) Kemink subsoiling before and after planting.   Soil &amp; Tillage Research, 80, pp. 59-68.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1568/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>