<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von Düngemittel auf die Wiederfindungsraten von Parasitenlarven</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Podstatzky, Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gallnböck, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>When pasture is managed in austrian alpine regions sheep and goats were grazed more than once a year on the same inclosure. The effects of fertilizing pasture with lime on parasitic burden are seen different. Different fertilizers were tested under laboratory conditions for their effects both on infectious parasitic larvae and on egg development. The experiment was conducted with earthnematode free gras samples and with wood chips. &#xD;
With quicklime and cyanamid effects could be demonstrated in the number of larvae and on egg development. With lime only effects against parasitic larvae could be seen. The application of effective mikroorganisms resulted in reduced numbers of larvae and on egg development. In organic farming cyanamid is not allowed. Quicklime is only allowed for disinfection of stables. More examination are necessary for verifying the results of lime and effective microorganisms under practical conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21371/1/21371_Podstatzky.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Podstatzky, Leopold and Gallnböck, Markus    (2013) Einfluss von Düngemittel auf die Wiederfindungsraten von Parasitenlarven.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21371/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>