<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Audit und Benchmarking zur Optimierung der Tiergesundheit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weiler, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volling, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krömker, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Consumers of organic products expect very high food quality as well as speciesappropriate&#xD;
husbandry, high animal health and best organic feeding. Studies showed&#xD;
that in some sections in organic dairy farms animal health is not better than in conventional&#xD;
farms. Kuh-M is the first quality management system specifically for organic&#xD;
dairy farms. It is based on an internet-database where the results of the monthly milkcontrol&#xD;
and the ingredients of the bulk-milk are presented in a benchmarking. With&#xD;
these results it is possible to appreciate the status quo of the animal health like subclinical&#xD;
metabolic changes, udder health, fertility and yield. Members can use the database&#xD;
to compare their results with the pool of the other members to evaluate their&#xD;
status quo. This is supported by a yearly audit, which is performed by a dairy consultant.&#xD;
Possibilities and acceptance of Kuh-M were checked out within a diploma thesis.&#xD;
Part of this thesis was the implementation of Kuh-M in ten organic dairy farms including&#xD;
all features and one audit. After the implementation the dairy farmers were interviewed&#xD;
and their answers evaluated. The results of the interviews are showing that&#xD;
Kuh-M is a tool for supporting organic dairy farmers to optimize their animal health&#xD;
management. The system has a good acceptance among those farmers who are used&#xD;
to work with the computer.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14118/1/Weiler_14118.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weiler, Martin; Volling, Otto and Krömker, Volker    (2009) Audit und Benchmarking zur Optimierung der Tiergesundheit.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14118/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>