<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ist die Schweizer Förderung des biologischen Landbaus über Flächenbeiträge volkswirtschaftlich sinnvoll?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nic</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this paper was to calculate the cost-effectiveness of organic farming in achieving environmental policy targets compared to single-agri-environmental policies. Taking the Swiss agricultural sector as an empirical case study, both the costs and effects of organic farming and other single agri-environmental measures were calculated at sector level. Therefore, the economic sector model FARMIS was extended by three modules encompassing a) life cycle assessments for fossil energy use, biodiversity and eutrophication, b) public expenditure, including policy-related transaction costs, and c) uptake of agri-environmental policies. The calculations revealed a slightly higher abatement cost with organic farming of 14 CHF/ha for a 1 % average improvement in the environmental indicators, compared to a combination of three single agri-environmental policies (11 CHF/ha), including both extensification of arable land and meadows. In view of total public expenditure on agriculture of 2 to 3 kCHF per ha in Switzerland, these differences can be understood as marginal. Thus it is concluded that financial support for organic farms in Switzerland is economically sound in view of the provision of public goods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17542/3/Schader_17542.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schader, Christian; Sanders, Jürn; Lampkin, Nic and Stolze, Matthias    (2011) Ist die Schweizer Förderung des biologischen Landbaus über Flächenbeiträge volkswirtschaftlich sinnvoll?  [Are the Swiss direct payments for organic farms an efficient way to pursue environmental policy targets?]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17542/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>