<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sensory evaluation of juice from different organic blackcurrant cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kidmose, Ulla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, Lars P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindhard Pedersen, Hanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thybo, Anette K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To ensure a high, stable production of blackcurrant juice in Denmark, it is necessary with high-yielding blackcurrant cultivars, which are resistant against pest and diseases, and that have a high sensory quality and high health value. In this experiment, blackcurrant juice processed from berries of 12 organic cultivars was screened. A trained sensory panel using descriptive sensory profiling evaluated the sensory quality of the juice samples. In addition, the aroma profile and the content of vitamin C were determined in the juice samples. The results showed that the following sensory attributes: blackcurrant aroma, blackcurrant flavour, fruity flavour, pungent flavour, sweetness and sourness varied significantly in the 12 juice samples. In addition the aroma profile and the content of vitamin C differed between the juice samples of the 12 blackcurrant cultivars</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7688/1/paper_organicjuice2006_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kidmose, Ulla; Christensen, Lars P.; Lindhard Pedersen, Hanne and Thybo, Anette K.    (2006) Sensory evaluation of juice from different organic blackcurrant cultivars.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7688/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>