<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Three-Year Comparison of the Polyphenol Contents and Antioxidant Capacities in Organically and Conventionally Produced Apples (Malus domestica Bork. Cultivar `Golden Delicious')</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stracke, Berenike A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rüfer, Corinna E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bub, Achim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watzl, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present study was performed to evaluate the polyphenol content and antioxidant capacity of apples (cv. `Golden Delicious') grown under defined organic and conventional conditions. Apples were harvested at five comparable commercial farms over the course of three years (2004−2006). In 2005 and 2006 the antioxidant capacity was 15% higher (p &lt; 0.05) in organically produced apples than in conventionally produced fruits. In 2005 significantly higher polyphenol concentrations were found in the organically grown apples. In 2004 and 2006 no significant differences were observed (2004, 304 ± 68 μg/g organic vs 284 ± 69 μg/g conventional, p = 0.18; 2005, 302 ± 58 μg/g organic vs 253 ± 41 μg/g conventional, p = 0.002; 2006, 402 ± 100 μg/g organic vs 365 ± 58 μg/g conventional, p = 0.17). Year-to-year variations in the antioxidant capacity and the polyphenol content of up to 20% were more significant than the production method found within one year. Finally, flavanols and flavonols were major determinants of the antioxidant capacities in these apples. Overall, the production method had a smaller impact on the variation in the polyphenol content and antioxidant capacity of apples than the yearly climate.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>American Chemical Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17949/1/stracke-etal-2009-agric-food-chem.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stracke, Berenike A.; Rüfer, Corinna E.; Weibel, Franco; Bub, Achim and Watzl, Bernhard   (2009) Three-Year Comparison of the Polyphenol Contents and Antioxidant Capacities in Organically and Conventionally Produced Apples (Malus domestica Bork. Cultivar `Golden Delicious').   Journal of Agricultural and Food Chemistry, 57 (11), pp. 4598-4605.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17949/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>