<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>School food provision in Germany. A first analysis of the role of organic produce</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reimann, Silke</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>School meal provision in Germany is changing from a type of supplementary food provision towards full warm school meals. Reasons for this transition are longer school days, the expansion of the all-day school model, and an increasing interest in a healthy nutrition for children and young people. However, the organisation of school meal systems is patchy and confusing; there is an enormous range of services in various qualities. This paper describes the current situation and explores chances for sustainable school meal systems emerging out of this change. The focus is on the use of organic food in school meals.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>He, Chen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkola, Minna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nymoen, Lena Lie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-11-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17418/1/Paper_submission_-_Strassner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strassner, Carola; Nölting, Benjamin and Reimann, Silke    (2009) School food provision in Germany. A first analysis of the role of organic produce.   In: Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg; He, Chen; Mikkola, Minna; Nielsen, Thorkild and Nymoen, Lena Lie (Eds.)  CORE Organic Project Series Report, ICROFS, Tjele, Denmark, pp. 66-68.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17418/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>