<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil fertility in three cropping systems after conversion from&#xD;
conventional to organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bakken, Anne Kjersti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Breland, Tor Arvid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haraldsen, Trond K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aamlid, Trygve S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sveistrup, Tore E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Temporal changes in the scores of selected soil fertility indices were studied over six years in three different cases of organic crop rotation located in southern, eastern and central Norway. The cropping history and the initial scores of fertility indices prior to&#xD;
conversion to organic cropping differed between the sites. Crop yields, regarded as an &#xD;
overall, integrating fertility indicator, were in all rotations highly variable with few consistent temporal trends following the first year after conversion. On the site in eastern Norway, where conversion followed several years of all-arable crop rotations, earthworm number and biomass and soil physical properties improved, whereas the system was apparently degrading with regard to P and K trade balances and contents in soil. On the other two sites, the picture was less clear. On the southern site, which had a relatively fertile soil before conversion, the contents of soil organic matter and K decreased during the six-year period, but the scores of other fertility indices showed no trends. On the site in central Norway, there were positive trends for earthworm-related indices such as worm biomass and tubular biopores, and negative trends for soil porosity. The results, especially those from the eastern site, illustrate the general difficulty in drawing conclusions about overall fertility or sustainability when partial indicators show divergent trends. Consequently, the study gave no unambiguous support to the initial working hypothesis that organic farming increases inherent overall soil fertility, but rather showed that the effect varied among indicators and depended on status of the cases at conversion. It is concluded that indicators are probably better used as tools to learn about and improve system components than as absolute measures of sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mårtensson, Anna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7855/1/ANNE_KJERSTI_BAKKEN.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bakken, Anne Kjersti; Breland, Tor Arvid; Haraldsen, Trond K.; Aamlid, Trygve S. and Sveistrup, Tore E.   (2005) Soil fertility in three cropping systems after conversion from conventional to organic farming.   Acta Agriculturae Scandinavica Section B-Soil and Plant Science.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7855/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>