<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Agriculture: A Productive Means of Low-carbon and High Biodiversity Food Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Innovative management options, such as organic farming, offer promising opportunities to reconcile the objectives of feeding a rapidly growing human population with minimal adverse impacts on the environment. Because of the multiple benefits of organic farming, including the soil sequestration of carbon, the current international efforts to mitigate and adapt to climate change and its consequences provide governments with an ideal platform for fostering a shift towards more sustainable agricultural production. Among the policy tools to promote more sustainable agricultural practices, this text highlights the importance of publicly funded research and extension work.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25561/1/Niggli_2010_OrganicAgriculture_UNCTAD.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niggli, Urs     (2010) Organic Agriculture: A Productive Means of Low-carbon and High Biodiversity Food Production.    In:      Trade and Environment Review - Promoting poles of clean growth to foster the transition to a more sustainable economy.  United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD), CH-Geneva, chapter 3.II, pp. 112-118.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25561/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>