<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation des Bereichs Forschung und Entwicklung &#xD;
im Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ekert, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Häring, A. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Murphy-Bokern, Donal</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Otto, Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vieweger, Anja</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2010, the BLE commissioned an evaluation of the Federal Organic Farming Scheme (BÖL), running since 2001. This paper reports on the approach taken in the evaluation of its research component, selected findings, and recommendations. An impact model of the BÖL scheme was developed to analyse how the various measures could contribute to the scheme’s overall aims and objectives. Data from the BLE research project database were analysed to assess the distribution of resources over time by topic and by research provider. At project level, a random selection of 83 projects was reviewed by external experts, including both scientists and other stakeholders to assess their quality and relevance. An online survey of 104 project leaders and interviews with 30 sector stakeholders and 12 BLE employees were carried out and the theme identification and project selection processes were analysed to evaluate whether the programme management contribute was in line with programme goals. The overall conclusions of the evaluation were then reviewed by external experts. The evaluation concludes that financed projects resulted in a compendium of easily accessible results. The research is relevant to the sector and this is one of the greatest strengths of the programme. However, the consistently high allocation of resources to crops and soil themes is noted as a weakness. A more strategic approach to the identification of research targets and to the development of impact from research outputs with appropriate measures at both programme and project level is recommended.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21630/1/21630_ekert.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ekert, Stefan; Döring, Thomas; Häring, A. M.; Lampkin, Nicolas; Murphy-Bokern, Donal; Otto, Kristin; Padel, Susanne and Vieweger, Anja    (2013) Evaluation des Bereichs Forschung und Entwicklung im Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21630/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>