<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Accumulation and translocation of sparingly soluble manure phosphorus in different types of soils after long-term excessive inputs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Uustitalo, Risto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ylivainio, Kari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turtola, Eila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kangas, Arjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>When phosphorus (P) is applied to soils in excess of plant P demand, P accumulation takes place. By means of P fractionation, we studied the fate of P in 35 soils that had received long-term surplus P rates as fox and mink manure P (F&amp;MM-P), considered as a sparingly soluble P source. We compared these data with those from the same soils under a more typical P management, i.e., fields amended with soluble P sources superphosphate and dairy manure (SP+DM). Fractionation of manures according to the Hedley procedure suggested limited solubility of F&amp;MM-P, two-thirds of the F&amp;MM-P being soluble in acid (HCl) only. In mineral soils, surplus F&amp;MM-P accumulated for the most part as HCl-P (poorly available), whereas in organic soils accumulation occurred largely as NaOH-soluble (moderately available) and labile P. Translocation of F&amp;MM-P was evidenced by P fractionation and by agronomic P test: subsurface soil of F&amp;MM-amended fields contained more P than the same soils in fields amended with SP+DM. In the 35 soils that had received surplus F&amp;MM-P, agronomic P status was classified as “excessive” in 90% of the samples taken from the plough layer, in 75% of those from 20–40 cm depth, and in 50% of those from 40–60 cm depth. In the reference soils amended with SP+DM, “excessive” P status was recorded for 23% of the plough layer samples and 4% of the subsurface samples. These results show that manure P which appears as sparingly soluble in P fractionation may in a longer term increase the content of labile soil P and translocate in the soil profile when applied in high rates.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17085/1/uusitalo1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Uustitalo, Risto; Ylivainio, Kari; Turtola, Eila and Kangas, Arjo   (2007) Accumulation and translocation of sparingly soluble manure phosphorus in different types of soils after long-term excessive inputs.   Agricultural and Food Science, 16 (4), pp. 317-331.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17085/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>