<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ergebnisse der Einführung eines Tiergesundheitsplanes auf&#xD;
ökologisch wirtschaftenden Ferkelerzeugerbetrieben in&#xD;
Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Dr. Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dietze, Dr. Klaas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to evaluate the effectiveness of measures as part of an&#xD;
animal health plan on 17 organic sow farms in Germany. A weak-point analysis was&#xD;
performed using a modified critical control point concept for on-farm assessment and&#xD;
detailed status quo analysis. Optimisation strategies were set up in form of farmcustomized&#xD;
health plans based on the status quo assessment. Farms were attended&#xD;
continuously to ensure guidance along the animal health plan implementation.&#xD;
The results of the status quo analysis confirmed the deficits in animal health management&#xD;
from previous studies. Results showed that only 10 farms met the demands of&#xD;
the EC-Regulation with respect to housing conditions. Only 12 farms performed a&#xD;
comprehensive livestock data acquisition. Quality and intervals of cleaning and disinfection&#xD;
measures varied considerably between farms. After one year, half of the participating&#xD;
farms implemented about half of the short term measures recommended as&#xD;
part of their health plans. Animal health plans have proven to support identifying problem&#xD;
areas, to set up improvement strategies and to enforce the cooperation between&#xD;
the involved actors. However, many farms have not been able to meet the basic requirements&#xD;
necessary for improving animal health status.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14002/1/Werner_14002.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Werner, Dr. Christina; Dietze, Dr. Klaas and Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert    (2009) Ergebnisse der Einführung eines Tiergesundheitsplanes auf ökologisch wirtschaftenden Ferkelerzeugerbetrieben in Deutschland.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14002/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>