<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleich zwischen Kurzrasenweide und Schnittnutzung unter ostalpinen Klimabedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohrer, Hannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Continuous grazing is an appropriate pasture system for dairy cows in low input milk production systems like organic farming. If a dairy farm converts from indoor feeding based on preserved forages to a pasture-based system, cows will start grazing on cutting-managed meadows. In a three-year (2007-2009) field trial continuous grazing was compared to cutting management at the organic grassland and dairy farm of the AREC Raumberg-Gumpenstein. The aim of this research was to assess the influence of grazing on botanical composition as well as biomass and quality yield. In this study, changes in the botanical composition were found. Typical pasture species like Lolium perenne and Poa pratensis dominated continuous grazing plots. Work under practical conditions showed no differences concerning common losses in yield between continuous grazing and the cutting regime established. Forage of continuous grazing showed a high energy density and provided the highest crude protein yield.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17335/3/Starz_17335.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Starz, Walter; Steinwidder, Andreas; Pfister, Rupert and Rohrer, Hannes    (2011) Vergleich zwischen Kurzrasenweide und Schnittnutzung unter ostalpinen Klimabedingungen.  [Comparison of continuous grazing and cutting management under eastern Alpine climatic conditions.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17335/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>