<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biogas in organic agriculture: Effects on yields, nutrient uptake and environmental parameters of the cropping system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Kurt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stinner, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>System effects of biogas fermentation in organic cropping systems with and without livestock (dairy farming) were investigated from 2002-2005. In both systems no differences in yields and nutrient uptake were detected in the legume crops. In the livestock-system non legume crops of the slurry system had no higher yields but a higher nitrogen uptake (6 %) than the stable manure system. Slurry-fermentation had no effect on yields and nitrogen uptake. The inclusion of crop residues in the fermentation system increased the nitrogen uptake about by 10 % and reduced the nitrate leaching potential by ca. 10 %. The inclusion of external substrates lead to a further increase in nitrogen yield of 10 %, but to no significant increase in dry matter yields. Fermentation had no effects on P-availability of manures. In the stockless system fermentation of clover grass, straw and catch crops increased yields and nitrogen content of winter wheat by ca. 10 %, combined with a significant decrease in nitrate leaching potential (10 %) and in emissions of nitrous oxide (ca. 40 %).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7223/1/kurt_moeller_biogas.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Möller, Kurt; Stinner, Walter and Leithold, Günter    (2006) Biogas in organic agriculture: Effects on yields, nutrient uptake and environmental parameters of the cropping system.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7223/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>