<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>To toast or not to toast – Grass peas for weaned piglets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baldinger, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hagmüller, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Minihuber, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic pig production, supply with high-quality protein-rich feeds is tense. As part of the EU Core Organic II research project ICOPP (Improved contribution of local feed to support 100% organic feed supply to pigs and poultry), in 2012 a feeding trial with grass peas fed to weaned piglets was conducted. The grass pea (Lathyrus sativus) is a hardy grain legume that produces seeds with crude protein contents between 200 and 300 g kg-1. Unfortunately it contains the neurotoxin ODAP, which causes nerve damage in farm animals as well as humans. Since ODAP is water-soluble and susceptible to heat, hydrothermal treatment (=toasting) greatly reduces toxicity. In the feeding trial, four experimental diets were fed to a total of 144 piglets: One control diet, one diet containing 20% raw grass peas and two diets with toasted grass peas (20 and 30%, respectively). Data were analysed using proc glm (feed intake) and proc mixed (body weight) of SAS 9.1.&#xD;
Feed intake did not differ (on average 731 g day-1), but feeding 20% raw grass peas had significant negative effects on body weight gain: While the diets containing toasted grass peas resulted in body weight gain similar to the control diet (on average 395 g day-1), piglets fed raw grass peas grew much slower (292 g day-1) and consequently feed conversion ratio was significantly higher (2.28 versus 1.96 kg feed kg-1 weight gain in the control group). Therefore toasting of grass peas prior to feeding to weaned piglets is recommended.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28061/1/Poster_ASD2013_grass%20pea.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baldinger, Lisa; Hagmüller, Werner; Minihuber, Ulrike and Zollitsch, Werner    (2013) To toast or not to toast – Grass peas for weaned piglets.       Poster at:   XXI Animal Science Days, Padua, 18 - 20 September 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28061/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>