<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The antioxidant compounds in rat experimental diets based on plant materials from organic, low-input and conventional agricultural systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wiśniewska, MSc Katarzyna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rembiałkowska, prof. Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hallmann, dr Ewelina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rusaczonek, MSc Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lueck, dr Lorna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, prof. Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Results presented in this paper are part of a study that investigates the effect of four production systems on health effects in rats. This study was aimed to evaluate differences in the levels of flavonols, total polyphenols, beta-carotene and lutein which are well known antioxidants in four rat feeds.  Raw plant materials were produced according to four different agricultural systems: organic farming (without synthetic pesticides and mineral fertilizers), low-input 1 (organic plant protection was used in combination with mineral fertilizers), low input 2 (conventional pest management and organic fertilizers were used) and conventional farming (synthetic pesticides and mineral fertilizers were used). The results indicate that rat feed prepared from the organically produced plants contained more antioxidant compounds, especially total polyphenols, flavonols and lutein. Rat feed produced for feeding experiments varied significantly in a series of key phytochemicals and therefore have the potential to produce different health effects in the subsequent feeding trials.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12324/1/Wisniewska_12324_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wiśniewska, MSc Katarzyna; Rembiałkowska, prof. Ewa; Hallmann, dr Ewelina; Rusaczonek, MSc Anna; Lueck, dr Lorna and Leifert, prof. Carlo    (2008) The antioxidant compounds in rat experimental diets based on plant materials from organic, low-input and conventional agricultural systems.       Speech at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12324/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>