<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biomass production and feeding value of whole-crop cereal-legume silages</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nykänen, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jauhiainen, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rinne, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In eastern Finland, 12 mixtures of spring wheat, spring barley, spring oats and/or rye with vetches and/or peas were evaluated in field experiments from 2005 to 2007 for their dry matter(DM) production, crude protein (CP) concentration and digestibility using three different harvesting times. Spring wheat-pea and spring wheat-vetch-rye mixtures produced the highest DM yields (5,000-6,000 kg/ha) while the lowest yields were found with spring oats-vetch (4,000 kg/ha DM). The highest CP concentrations were found in vetches (200 g/kg DM) and lowest in spring cereals (90-120 g/kg DM). Organic matter digestibility was highest in peas 700-750 g/kg) and lowest in spring rye and wheat (550-610 g/kg). It is suggested that decisions concerning when to harvest legume-cereal mixtures for forage could be based on the maturity stage of the cereal, because changes in digestibility and CP concentration are slow in legumes during the potential harvesting period.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16427/1/ARnykanen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nykänen, A.; Jauhiainen, L. and Rinne, M.    (2009) Biomass production and feeding value of whole-crop cereal-legume silages.   In:     Agronomy Research, 7 (Special issue II), Agronomy Research, pp. 684-690.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16427/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>