<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrogen fertilizer value of cattle manure applied on soils originating from organic and conventional farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Langmeier, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzer, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nitrogen nutrition of plants in organic farming depends largely on animal manure. In a pot experiment the hypothesis was tested that on a long-term organically managed soil (ORG) characterized by higher soil microbial activity, a greater portion of N applied as cattle manure is mineralized and taken up by plants than on a conventionally managed soil that had received exclusively mineral fertilizers (MIN). Dry matter yields and N uptake by Italian ryegrass were higher by around 20% on ORG than MIN soil. The N utilization of 15N labeled animal manure components and mineralNdiffered little between ORG and MIN. The major part of the increasedNuptake on ORG compared with MIN was due to a significantly greater N supply from ORG soil. The increased capacity of the ORG soil to supply N to plants became more important at later cuts when N was severely limiting plant growth.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002-05-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26768/1/Langmeier_et_al_2002_A.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Langmeier, Monika; Frossard, Emmanuel; Kreuzer, Michael; Mäder, Paul; Dubois, David and Oberson, Astrid   (2002) Nitrogen fertilizer value of cattle manure applied on soils originating from organic and conventional farming systems.   Agronomie, 22, pp. 789-800.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26768/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>