<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>What we achieved - where we will go</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On the way to a new systemic research approach for organic food quality and health&#xD;
&#xD;
More than 50 researchers and supporters of the organic food sector met at the 1st scientific FQH conference from November 28th to 29th at the FQH research member institution FIBL in Frick (Switzerland).&#xD;
The two days were filled with presentations of latest research results of well-named scientists from across Europe covering topics from farm to table such as quality parameters of organic food, human health, the definition of quality and consumer expectations and legal legislation for organic food.&#xD;
The conference was embedded in two scientific discussions about the scientific future of organic quality research chaired by Hardy Vogtmann (president of the German Federal Agency for Nature Conservation) and Angelika Ploeger (FQH chairperson), respectively. As a clear baseline both discussions revealed that there is an absolute need for a new organic quality concept and for more international scientific communication prior to the development of new research programmes.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Research Association for Organic Food Quality and Health, Witzenhausen, Germany</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>International Food Quality and health Association, FQH</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6963/1/6963-FQH-2005-proceedings_1st_fqh_conference.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>International Food Quality and health Association, FQH (Ed.)    (2005) What we achieved - where we will go.   International Research Association for Organic Food Quality and Health, Witzenhausen, Germany.  Proceedings of Proceedings of the 1st scientific FQH Conference, CH-Frick, 28.11.2005 - 29.11.2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6963/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>