<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>„Bait Sprays“ - eine Alternative zur Bekämpfung der Europäischen Kirschfruchtfliege Rhagoletis cerasi ?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Köppler, Kirsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Storch, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogt, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2005 initial experiments were carried out to control Rhagoletis cerasi with bait sprays. We used GF-120 fruit fly bait which contains Spinosad and NeemAzal®-T/S mixed in a sugar-yeast hydrolysate solution. 30 ml of bait sprays were applied on single cherry trees in field cages, where we released a defined number of cherry fruit flies. One experiment with GF-120 resulted in a reduction of fruit infestation of 96 % compared with the control. In other trials with GF-120 and Neem bait the effect on the cherry fruit fly population was monitored. After 24 hours GF-120 in a 5 % and 20 % solution led to a high reduction of flies (efficacy 85 %), whereas NeemAzal®-T/S in a 5 %, 10 %, and 20 % solution only resulted in efficacies between 34 % and 42 %.  A significant effect of GF-120 was observed already after 3 hours.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8818/1/ecofruit_12th_11.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Köppler, Kirsten; Storch, Volker and Vogt, Heidrun    (2006) „Bait Sprays“ - eine Alternative zur Bekämpfung der Europäischen Kirschfruchtfliege Rhagoletis cerasi ?  [Bait sprays - an alternative to control the European cherry fruit fly Rhagoletis cerasi ?]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 61-66.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8818/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>