<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Co-Designing an organic framework: the ”REF’AB” Project in France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sautereau, Natacha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fourrié, Laetitia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Experton, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cresson, Céline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mundler, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, Stéphane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Le Tailleur, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garnier, J.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dumontier , A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willot , M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To help the development of Organic Food and Farming (OFF) systems, there is the need to consolidate conversions to OF, to support entry into organic farming, and to develop existing organic farms. Therefore a group of extensionists, researchers and educators has being working 2 years long to co-design a framework for OFF, taking into account the need to (i) embrace all forms of OFF, and at the same time to (ii) address the specificities of OFF. This project, called REF’AB (REFerentiel de l’Agriculture Biologique, 2010-2012) aims at designing the organization of set of references produced on shared methodological bases. The approach consisted in identifying key-issues of OFF systems, defining indicators, identifying relevant databases and references to feed the framework, and providing recommendations for governance to optimise the establishment and circulation of references. The outcomes of this project is that first it was not necessarily clear what a framework for OFF should be, and therefore a conference of consensus was used as a methodological&#xD;
tool to share views by multi-stakeholders. Second, we used sustainability assessment as an integrative process of the three levels (technical-economic, environmental, and social) and third, to manage to share a more transversal approach, we proposed a framework with 3 levels of key-proprieties: 1) security and efficiency, 2) durability through the protection of resources, and 3) autonomy and resilience.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27610/1/Sautereau_2012_IFSA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sautereau, Natacha; Fourrié, Laetitia; Experton, Catherine; Cresson, Céline; Mundler, P.; Bellon, Stéphane; Le Tailleur, F.; Garnier, J.F.; Dumontier , A. and Willot , M.    (2012) Co-Designing an organic framework: the ”REF’AB” Project in France.       Paper at:   10th European ISFA Symposium (International Farming System Association), Aarhus, Denmark, 1-4 July 2012.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27610/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>