<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aufbau und Qualitätssicherung für Jungpflanzen für den&#xD;
biologischen Obst- und Rebbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suter, Francisco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tschabold, Jean-Luc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lévite, Dominique</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic fruit and wine producers have to use organically produced plant material if&#xD;
available on the market. To support and enhance this difficult production sector a&#xD;
project was started in 2003 funded by the Coop Naturaplan Fonds. The improvement&#xD;
or development of better methods for fertilization, soil management, growth regulation&#xD;
and plant protection are the main objectives of this project. In our trials with apple&#xD;
trees we found that an intensification of the nitrogen fertilization including application&#xD;
of foliar fertilizers did not result in a better quality of young trees. The use of the&#xD;
bacterial bio-fertilizer BactoFil® Professional-2 without any nitrogen fertilization&#xD;
increased the tree quality under our conditions. In another experiment comparing&#xD;
cover plant and tilled soil, we obtained a better quality of the young trees where soil&#xD;
was covered with Bromus tectorum. In the grape-vine nursery trials we found that the&#xD;
main problem, the Plasmopara viticola disease, can be sufficiently controlled with the&#xD;
available organic plant protection product such as copper, sulphur and acidified clay&#xD;
powder. The quality of the organically produced vine-plantlets was equivalent with the&#xD;
conventional plants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14482/1/Suter_14482.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14482/2/Poster_Jungpflanzen_Suter_wisstagung2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Suter, Francisco; Weibel, Franco; Tschabold, Jean-Luc and Lévite, Dominique    (2009) Aufbau und Qualitätssicherung für Jungpflanzen für den biologischen Obst- und Rebbau.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14482/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>