<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture: Processes of Co-evolution, Joint Reflection and Facilitation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roep, Dirk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brunori, Gianluca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tisenkopfs, Talis</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Editorial to the Special Issue on "Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture: Processes of Co-evolution, Joint Reflection and Facilitation". &#xD;
&#xD;
There is growing recognition that the technological and organizational solutions the agricultural sector has undertaken in the past are not always compatible with the constraints and opportunities that the rural economy and society will face in the next future. This has generated an increased emphasis on transition towards new business, technological and policy models that address the challenge of sustainability. Innovation is key to transition, but the institutions that are charged with fostering innovation are often locked into old approaches and methods of intervention. The linear view of knowledge transfer as a top-down process from research to advice and practice is still predominant.&#xD;
Increasingly, this view is challenged and partly replaced by systems approaches in which agricultural producers are seen as important actors, rather than merely consumers of technologies that are generated by agricultural research and development and transferred by extension services for subsequent adoption.&#xD;
Such a systems approach has been discussed and further developed in this Journal (see e.g. the special issue 2014 (3) edited by Koutsouris and Cristovao; and Knickel et al. 2009) and in other publications, including Röling and Engel 1991; Hall et al. 2003; Sumberg and Reece 2004. The systems approach has also inspired a recent document of the EU Standing Committee of Agricultural Research (EU SCAR 2013) and many of the aspects of this approach can be found in the recent European Innovation Partnerships policy (EU Commission 2010).&#xD;
This special issue synthesizes the findings of the three year European funded research project SOLINSA ‘Agricultural Knowledge Systems in Transition: Towards a more effective and efficient support of Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture’ (GA No. 266306). The special issue assembles papers that explore new ways of learning and knowledge co-production for sustainable agriculture and rural development and critically reflect the role of research and policy for supporting sustainable innovation in rural Europe. In particular, it discusses the institutional aspects of joint learning and reflection in what has been coined as Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture or LINSA, and how joint learning and innovation in these LINSA has actually been supported and can be supported to further enhance sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28125/7/Moschitz-etal-2015-JAEE%20Editorial_Preprint_15.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28125/1/Moschitz%20et%20al_JAEE%20Editorial_Learning%20and%20Innovation%20Networks%20for%20Sustainable%20Agriculture_15.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun; Roep, Dirk; Brunori, Gianluca and Tisenkopfs, Talis   (2015) Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture: Processes of Co-evolution, Joint Reflection and Facilitation.   The Journal of Agricultural Education and Extension, 21 (1), pp. 1-11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28125/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>