<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vegetable quality in a conventional and three organic cropping systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Hanne L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kidmose, Ulla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dresbøll, Dorte Bodin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Differences in nutrient availability and methods of pest management may affect crop growth and product quality.&#xD;
The question is if conventional and organic cropping systems, which differ clearly in strategies for nutrient and pest management, influence the harvest and sensory quality of the products?&#xD;
&#xD;
Lettuce and onion were grown in a conventional and three organic vegetable cropping systems with different levels of external inputs and use of cover- and inter-crops for nutrient re-cycling and natural pest management in&#xD;
the period of 2007-2009 (VegQure project). The crop rotation consisted of 8 fields of vegetables and cereals. Onion was grown after a year of oat and iceberg lettuce after winter rye. There were 3 replicates of each&#xD;
cropping system each year. Sensory analysis of samples of iceberg lettuce was performed as quantitative descriptive &#xD;
analysis by a trained sensory panel of 10 assessors. A sensory profile of 9 attributes was evaluated on a 15-cm non-structured continuous scale. &#xD;
Harvest and sensory quality were not affected by the clear differences in nutrient and pest management between the four cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-05-18</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19587/3/19587.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristensen, Hanne L.; Kidmose, Ulla; Dresbøll, Dorte Bodin and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian    (2011) Vegetable quality in a conventional and three organic cropping systems.       Poster at:   First International Conference on Organic Food Quality and Health Research, Prague, 18-20 May 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19587/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>