<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economic analysis of organic greenhouse lettuce production in Turkey.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Engindeniz, Sait</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tuzel, Yuksel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Greenhouses and coverings</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Health issues and environmental concerns have drawn the attention to organic agriculture aiming to protect the natural balance and to produce without damaging the environment. This study aims determining economic feasibility of organic greenhouse lettuce (Lactuca sativa L.) in an on farm trial, to foster organic greenhouse vegetable production in the preservation area of Tahtali Dam, projected as the sole water resource of Izmir,Turkey’s third largest. A 384 m2 greenhouse, constructed of galvanized metal tubing anchored and covered with a polyethylene was analyzed to identify typical operation procedures,and to determine unitary construction and operation cost. Organic lettuces were produced during autumn season of 2001-2002, testing different organic fertilizer applications, including two rates of farmyard and poultry manure (30 and 50 t ha-1) with and without two organic fertilizers based on either bacteria or algae. Economical analysis was performed according to different organic fertilizer applications. Cost, yield, and price data were analyzed to determine the profitability of a typical operation. Net return obtained from organic lettuce growing ranged between us $ 0.376 and us $ 0.901 m-2, as a result of different fertilizer applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20409/1/Engindeniz_economic.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Engindeniz, Sait and Tuzel, Yuksel   (2006) Economic analysis of organic greenhouse lettuce production in Turkey.  [Análise econômica da produção orgânica de alface em estufas na Turquia.]  Scientia Agricola, 63 (3), pp. 285-290.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20409/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>