<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cropping Intensity and Organic Amendments in Transitional Farming Systems: Effects on Soil Fertility, Weeds, Diseases and Insects</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wander, Michelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eastman, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zaborski, Edmond</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eastburn, Darin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Masiunas, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Engiseth, Nicki</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ugarte, Carmen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marzano, Shinyi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rosa, Isabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Windsor Organic Research Trial (WORT) is a farming systems experiment initiated in 2003 to investigate alternative strategies for transitioning to certified organic vegetable production that compares the influence of transition schemes that differ in management intensity (cropping, tillage) and organic matter inputs on weeds; soil organic matter and nutrient availability; soil invertebrate communities; and the relationship between soil fertility, plant health and insect/disease pressure.  Soil quality was improved during transition in all systems.  Conventional soil tests were unable to document differences among systems that were reflected in biotic indicators.  The pasture-based transition system was superior.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12415/1/Wander_12415_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wander, Michelle; Eastman, Catherine; Zaborski, Edmond; Eastburn, Darin; Masiunas, John; Engiseth, Nicki; Ugarte, Carmen; Marzano, Shinyi and Rosa, Isabel    (2008) Cropping Intensity and Organic Amendments in Transitional Farming Systems: Effects on Soil Fertility, Weeds, Diseases and Insects.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12415/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>