<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung klimaangepasster Anbauverfahren im Ökolandbau mittels Methoden der Aktionsforschung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bloch, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bachinger, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Adapting organic farming to the effects of climate change requires region-specific adaptive measures. Such measures are being developed in the INKA BB project using an action research approach, which is based on a participative and transdisciplinary collaboration between scientists and farmers. The action research was implemented using SWOT analysis, a flexible tool which can be used to assess initial situations as well as to plan and evaluate. Using this method, project partners identified weaknesses in the water and nitrogen supply in Brandenburg caused by climate change, on the level of farming methods and as well as of individual organic farms. With this as a basis, on-farm and small-plot experiments were developed to test farming methods adapted to climate change. These were carried out at six farms. The experimental results were, in turn, evaluated with a SWOT analysis. This made clear that a combination of measures including reduced tillage, adapted plant varieties, catch crops and adjusted sowing dates could be an approach to adapting to climate change.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21443/1/21442_Bloch.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bloch, Ralf and Bachinger, Johann    (2013) Entwicklung klimaangepasster Anbauverfahren im Ökolandbau mittels Methoden der Aktionsforschung.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21443/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>