<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>TECHNICAL AND ECONOMIC CONSTRAINTS IN ORGANIC SUCKLER SHEEP FARMING IN FRANCE. ANALYSIS IN A GROUP OF FARMS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BENOIT, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>LAIGNEL, G</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The structures and the technical and economic results of 12 farms practising organic farming (Org) (eight upland and four lowland) were compared with those of 25 conventional farms (Conv) (14 and 11), over three years (2002-2004). The Org farms had smaller structures, fewer workers, and lower numerical productivity, especially in uplands (-16 % on average over three years) owing to lower flock intensification and sometimes because of sanitary problems. The key questions were above all economic with (i) the high cost of concentrates, the consumption of which remained high (extra cost per kg from 40 % to 60 % in 2004), and (ii) steadily decreasing average premium on meat price; only 9 % in uplands and 2 % in lowlands in 2004. Hence the gross margin per ewe was 20 % to 23 % lower on average over three years, than that on Conv farms. The impact on earnings was marked. Income is also strongly dependent on public subsidies, which are set to diminish</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7120/1/Marc_Benoit_Odense_02-2006_sheep_env.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>BENOIT, M and LAIGNEL, G    (2006) TECHNICAL AND ECONOMIC CONSTRAINTS IN ORGANIC SUCKLER SHEEP FARMING IN FRANCE. ANALYSIS IN A GROUP OF FARMS.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7120/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>