<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Techniques to improve technological and sanitary quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>David, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Celette, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abecassis, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carcea, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, J.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hellou, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeuffroy, M.-H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, I. K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agronomical ways for better quality and safety&#xD;
Choice of cultivar is an efficient way to obtain higher grain quality. Intercropping legumes (grain or forage) improves weed competition and N availability for wheat crop or succeeding crop. Green manure can be an effective alternative to farmyard manure. Fertilization with readily available nitrogen improves yield and quality when water is available. Reduced tillage affects soil fertility and wheat yield but has little effects on grain quality.&#xD;
&#xD;
Technological ways for better quality and safety&#xD;
Milling process strongly influences flour characteristics. Stone milling improves nutritive value; characteristics remain very stable independent of the milling yield. Flour characteristics from roller milling appear very susceptible to the milling yield. Increasing the milling yield in the aim of enriching nutritional quality has a detrimental effect either on safety (DON) or on bread-making quality (bread volume).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20851/1/AGTEC_general_leaflet__FVMarch12.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>David, C.; Celette, F.; Abecassis, J.; Carcea, M.; Dubois, D.; Friedel, J.K.; Hellou, G.; Jeuffroy, M.-H.; Mäder, P. and Thomsen, I. K.         (2012) Techniques to improve technological and sanitary quality.    ISARA - Institut supérieure de l'agriculture Lyon, Lyon, France.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20851/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>