<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rohphosphatmobilisierung von Sommerweizen, Weißlupine und Ackerbohne in einer Fruchtfolge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steffens, Prof. Dr. Diedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stamm, Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yan, PD Dr. Feng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Dr. Guenter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schubert, Prof. Dr. Sven</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming rock phosphate is used as a mineral P fertilizer, although the agronomic efficiency is limted. The objective of this study was to investigate in field and pot experiments the mobilization of rock phosphate by P-efficient plants (white lupin and faba bean) and the P availability for P-inefficient plants (spinach and maize) during a crop rotation in 2002/2003 and 2003/2004. The P uptake of spinach was higher in a crop rotation with white lupin and faba bean than in a crop rotation with summer wheat. In pot experiments the application of new basic slag phosphate (CaHPO4) resulted to a higher P uptake of the plants than rock phosphate.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3604/1/3604.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steffens, Prof. Dr. Diedrich; Stamm, Roland; Yan, PD Dr. Feng; Leithold, Prof. Dr. Guenter and Schubert, Prof. Dr. Sven    (2005) Rohphosphatmobilisierung von Sommerweizen, Weißlupine und Ackerbohne in einer Fruchtfolge.  [Rock phosphate mobilization by summer wheat, white lupin, and faba bean in a crop rotation.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3604/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>