<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tolerance of four spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) varieties to weed harrowing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Preben Klarskov</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holst, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andreasen, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigated the tolerance to weed harrowing of four spring barley varieties and examined the possible interactions between varietal weed suppressive ability and two nutrient levels. Tolerance was defined as the combined effect of crop resistance (ability to resist soil covering) and crop recovery (the ability to recover in terms of yield). The weed harrowing strategy was a combination of one pre- and one post-emergence weed harrowing. In terms of yield, the four varieties responded significantly differently to weed harrowing and the response depended on nutrient level. At the lower nutrient level, weed harrowing caused an increase in yield of 4.4 hkg ha-1 for a strong competitor (cv. Otira), while there was no effect on yield at the higher nutrient level. For a weaker competitor (cv. Brazil), weed harrowing caused no change in yield at the lower nutrient level, whereas yield decreased by 6.0 hkg ha-1 at the higher nutrient level. There were marked differences between the weed suppressive ability of the four varieties when not harrowed, with less pronounced but significant differences when harrowed. Weed harrowing did not change the weed suppressive ability of a variety. Varieties that are tall at post-emergence harrowing and have increased density after pre-emergence harrowing, are the ones that benefit most from weed harrowing.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Publishing, Oxford UK</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11292/1/Tolerance_of_four_spring_barley_%28Hordeum_vulgare%29_varieties_to_weed_harrowing.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hansen, Preben Klarskov; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Holst, Niels and Andreasen, Christian   (2007) Tolerance of four spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) varieties to weed harrowing.   Weed Research, 47 (3), pp. 241-251.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11292/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>