<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of docks (Rumex spp.) in organic fodder production - a true bottleneck in organic farmed branded dairy and meat products</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Control of dock species are a true bottleneck in the development of grassland based organic production in Norway. Rumex obtusifolius, Rumex crispus and Rumex longifolius are among the most important perennial weeds in grassland areas throughout the world. These docks are undesirable in grasslands because they decrease yields and reduce forage feeding value. Numerous farmers feel powerlessness regarding how to manage the Rumex problem. Some farmers continue conventionally farming instead of organic, although they generally are motivated for transferring to organic production, due to the dock problem. The main goal of the project is a high quality and stable production of regional branded dairy and meat products based on fodder from grassland with non-chemical control of docks. This is to be achieved through knowledge on important factors that influence severity of dock infestation, studies on weak growth stages of docks, evaluation of biological control of docks and a synthesis of various measures to control these weeds. The return of the efforts of the project is increased organic production of meat and dairy products.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11045/1/Project_DOCK_infestation_26april_06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Control of docks: Control of docks (Rumex spp.) in organic fodder production - a true bottleneck in organic farmed branded dairy and meat products.  [Kontroll av høymole (Rumex spp.) i økologisk forproduksjon - en flaskehals ved økologisk melke- og kjøttproduksjon.]   Runs 2006 - 2010.      Project Leader(s): Brandsæter, Lars Olav; Lunnan, Tor; Haugland, Espen; Netland, Jan; Hatcher, Paul and Koesling, Matthias, Bioforsk, Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11045/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>