<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genotyp x Umwelt Interaktionen und nachhaltige Zuchtstrategien (ÖKUH)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Is there any genotype x environment interaction, how important is it and how can it be implemented in to sustainable organic cattle breeding?&#xD;
Project aims including target group:&#xD;
Based on empiric date the preconditions to elaborate concrete breeding programs for organic cattle farmers shall be created.&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
-Estimation of genotype x environment interaction of organic and conventional farms with Swiss performance data&#xD;
-Estimation of genotype x environment interaction of organic and conventional farms with specific farms in Germany&#xD;
-Assessment of different breeding strategies for sustainable organic cattle breeding &#xD;
-Buildup of a date based information system as breeding and management assistance for organic cattle farmer&#xD;
-Setup of a communication and consulting interface for organic cattle farmer</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5934/1/fibl-projekt-tierzucht-tierhaltung-GxE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5934/2/fibl-projekt-tierzucht-tierhaltung-GxE-2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    ÖKUH: Genotyp x Umwelt Interaktionen und nachhaltige Zuchtstrategien (ÖKUH).  [Genotype x environment interaction and sustainable breeding strategies.]   Runs 2004 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Bapst, Beat, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5934/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>