<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Providing organic food for millions of Italian pupils. How do we make it?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spigarolo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarti, Valerio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Italy has successfully improved the quality of school meals over the last decade. Actors from policy and&#xD;
public administration put emphasis especially on the quality of the used products; they should whenever&#xD;
possible come from controlled and certified production. In this paper the focus is on organic products.&#xD;
This paper analyses three crucial aspects of the procurement of high quality school food: a) strengths and&#xD;
weaknesses of organic supply chains in the perspective of producers and caterers; b) call for tenders being&#xD;
used as a key instrument by municipalities, being in charge of school food procurement, in order to influence&#xD;
the quality of school food; and c) best practice cases of municipal school food systems which combine&#xD;
supply chains on the one hand and municipalities and their activities on the other hand.&#xD;
The preliminary results suggest that an integrated approach is needed for high quality school meals. Various&#xD;
stakeholders should be brought together, to discuss their demands and increase the understanding</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Strassner, Carola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-02-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17142/1/CORE_Proc_BioFach_2010_ipopy_VF_RSetal.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spigarolo, Roberto; Sarti, Valerio and Nölting, Benjamin    (2010) Providing organic food for millions of Italian pupils. How do we make it?   In: Strassner, Carola; Løes, Anne-Kristin; Nölting, Benjamin and Kristensen, Niels Heine (Eds.)  Organic Food for Youth in Public Settings: Potentials and Challenges. Preliminary Recommendations from a European Study. Proceedings of the iPOPY session held at BioFach Congress 2010. CORE Organic Project Series Report. , ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report, Tjele, Denmark, pp. 17-28.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17142/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>