<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of grapefruit seed extract as natural fungicide to control apple scab in organic apple growing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>C-pro, an experimental fungicide based on grapefruit seed extract was compared to&#xD;
copper oxychloride for the control of apple scab in a field trial. Efficacy and possible&#xD;
phytotoxic effects where accessed. The C-pro formulation was analysed for possible&#xD;
chemical additives by HPTLC.&#xD;
C-pro proved tot be more effective in controlling apple scab then the standard rate of&#xD;
300 gram copper oxychloride per ha, and gave a better leaf quality and less fruit skin&#xD;
russeting then the standard program of copper oxychloride.&#xD;
However C-pro contained 6.6 % of the synthetic preservation agent benzethonium&#xD;
chloride what excludes C-pro from use in organic agriculture.&#xD;
There is a growing interest in grapefruit seed extract products as well as in other&#xD;
plant extracts as potential crop protection materials. To prevent disappointments and&#xD;
waist of resources it is necessary to analyse these materials on possible chemical&#xD;
additives before taking them into efficacy trials.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14540/1/38_Trapman_202_207.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trapman, Marc    (2004) Evaluation of grapefruit seed extract as natural fungicide to control apple scab in organic apple growing.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 202-207.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14540/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>