<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Using minimum tillage to improve the efficiency of ecosystem service delivery on organic farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Crowley, Oliver</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Measures, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming practices aim to maximise the delivery of ecosystem services in the agricultural landscape. However, in order to maintain optimal crop productivity the mouldboard plough is often used to control weeds and this can have negative effects on a range of soil parameters, thereby jeopardizing delivery of these services. Reduced tillage (RT) can be beneficial to soils and could improve both the efficiency of production and the delivery of ecosystem services on organic farms. However, abandoning the plough on organic farms is challenging due to impaired weed control. Here we report on a two year trial where an RT system with the Ecodyn, with duck feet shares operating at a depth of 7.6 cm in combination with seed drilling, was compared with mouldboard ploughing. Spring oat and spring barley establishment was improved under RT. Weed cover and biomass was greater under RT, but there was no difference in cereal grain yields in either year. The RT system used 71% less fuel and tillage operations took 72% less time that the plough system.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>McCracken, K</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20721/1/Crowley_et_al_2012_Reduced_tillage_and_ecosystem_service_delivery_on_organic_farms.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Crowley, Oliver; Döring, Thomas F. and Measures, Mark    (2012) Using minimum tillage to improve the efficiency of ecosystem service delivery on organic farms.   In: McCracken, K (Ed.)  Agriculture and the Environment IX, Valuing Ecosystems: Policy, Economic and Management Interactions, pp. 169-174.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20721/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>