<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Production Base for Organic Temperate Fruit, Berries and Grapes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Granatstein, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirby, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>World</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fresh fruit consumption is being promoted for health reasons in North America, Europe and other regions. Consumers are responding, as evidenced by the 20 percent increase in per capita fruit consumption in the past 30 years. US consumers have increased fruit consumption by 23 percent, but they still consume half the amount recommended by the dietary guidelines of the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA). Fruit production often requires significant intervention with pesticides to control pests and diseases. Thus, health conscious consumers increasingly see organic fruit as a logical package. Fruit and vegetable sales account for about 40 percent of the retail sales of organic foods in the US (93 percent of this is fresh produce), with fruit estimated to represent about half of this. In Europe, organic fruit sales represent about five percent of all fruit sales, but the market penetration differs considerably by the specific fruit. Apples, pears, grapes (including grapes for wine, raisins and table grapes), strawberries and peaches are among the top temperate fruits consumed in the US and Europe. These fruits can also be grown in those regions and thus supply a significant share of the organic market.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FiBL, IFOAM and ITC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17930/1/granatstein-etal-2009-world-of-organic-agriculture.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Granatstein, David; Kirby, Elisabeth and Willer, Helga    (2009) The Production Base for Organic Temperate Fruit, Berries and Grapes.    In: Willer, Helga and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2009.  FiBL, IFOAM and ITC, Frick, Bonn and Geneva, chapter 6, pp. 108-111.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17930/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>