<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of plant growth promoting bacteria (PGPB) on yield, growth and nutrient&#xD;
contents of organically grown strawberry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Esitken, Ahmet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yildiz, Hilal E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ercisli, Sezai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Donmez, M.Figen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turan, Metin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gunes, Adem</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effects of plant growth promoting bacteria (PGPB) on the fruit yield, growth and nutrient element&#xD;
content of strawberry cv. Fern were investigated under organic growing conditions between 2006 and&#xD;
2008. The experimental plot was a completely randomized design with 3 replicates. Three PGPB strains&#xD;
(Pseudomonas BA-8, Bacillus OSU-142 and Bacillus M-3) were used alone or in combination as biofertilizer&#xD;
agent in the experiment. Data through 3 years showed that the use of PGPB significantly&#xD;
increased fruit yield, plant growth and leaf P and Zn contents. Root inoculation of M3 and floral and foliar&#xD;
spraying of OSU-142 and BA-8 bacteria stimulated plant growth resulting in significant yield increases.&#xD;
M3 + BA-8, BA-8 + OSU-142, M3, M3 + OSU-142 and BA-8 applications increased cumulative yield by&#xD;
33.2%, 18.4%, 18.2%, 15.3% and 10.5%, respectively. Number of fruits per plant significantly increased by&#xD;
the applications of M3 + BA-8 (91.73) and M3 (81.58) compared with the control (68.66). In addition, P&#xD;
and Zn contents of strawberry leaves with bacterial inoculation significantly increased under organic&#xD;
growing conditions. Available P contents in soil were increased from 0.35 kg P2O5/da at the beginning of&#xD;
the study to 2.00, 1.97 and 1.82 kg P2O5/da by M3 + OSU-142, M3 + BA-8 and M3 + BA-8 + OSU-142&#xD;
applications, respectively. Overall, the results of this study suggest that root inoculation of Bacillus M3&#xD;
alone or in combination with spraying Bacillus OSU-142 or Pseudomonas BA-8 have the potential to&#xD;
increase the yield, growth and nutrition content of strawberry plant under organic growing conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-12-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18589/1/%C3%A7ilekscie...pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Esitken, Ahmet; Yildiz, Hilal E.; Ercisli, Sezai; Donmez, M.Figen; Turan, Metin and Gunes, Adem   (2009) Effects of plant growth promoting bacteria (PGPB) on yield, growth and nutrient contents of organically grown strawberry.   Scientia Horticulturae, 124 (2010), pp. 62-66.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18589/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>