<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategic options for sensory quality communication for organic products to different target groups and research needs – results from ECROPOLIS project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the EU funded research project Ecropolis (www.ecropolis.eu) sensory properties and sensory profiles from organic products as well as consumer expectations were collected and analysed in six European countries (CH, DE, FR, IT; NL, PL).Recommendations were made for organic associations, producers, processors, retailers and wholesalers, in particular through the interactive on-line data base OSIS (http://osis.ecropolis.eu). There are mainly two areas, where strategic options can be developed: a) the product development and b) the sensory quality communication strategies. Communication measures can emphasise the most preferred sensory attributes in order to better attract specific consumer segments. In those countries, where organic labelling has not a positive influence or even a negative image for certain products, attributes other than organic should be communicated. In a differentiation strategy more emphasis should be given on the communication of sensory differences and specific characteristics (example of yoghurt). Research needs in this area are outlined.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23750/1/23750%20IFOAM-OWC2014_Schmid_sensory-marketing_full-text_9Febrary2014_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, Otto    (2014) Strategic options for sensory quality communication for organic products to different target groups and research needs – results from ECROPOLIS project.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1023-1026.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23750/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>