<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analytical overview of the Chinese organic sector with the focus on rural development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gargili Kuehl, Asli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yonggong, Liu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>China</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Rural development in China has been a huge success: from hunger to self-sufficiency to food donor in only a few decades. This fast growth of agricultural production, however, came at a cost – which consequently stresses the natural resources, pollutes environment and increases income inequality between poor and rich. Now, Chinese authorities seek other ways than conventional agriculture to continue high productivity, but without causing degradation of natural resources and environment to fulfil the needs for safe nutrition of a growing society. &#xD;
Ecological or organic agriculture is suggested to be a modern and promising alternative that has a sound record of adapting food safety and natural harmony.  Within this context, the main questions of this research are: what kind of development patterns did the organic sector show in China and what are the main problems in the Chinese organic food chain?&#xD;
In this paper, the development of organic agriculture and its institutional framework in China are analysed. Problems are identified from analysis of in-depth interviews with relevant stakeholders throughout the whole organic food chain. Results and conclusions are presented and recommendations made.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23781/1/23781_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gargili Kuehl, Asli and Yonggong, Liu    (2014) Analytical overview of the Chinese organic sector with the focus on rural development.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 141-144.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23781/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>