<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Promotion of Eco-Tourism Using the Practice of Wikipedia: The Case-Study of Environmental and Cultural Paths in Zakynthos</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halvatzaras, Dimitrios</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kabassi, Katerina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The development of sustainable eco tourism and cultural tourism could have positive effects in many socioeconomic factors of a country. A way of promoting eco-tourism is by using the knowledge and the experiences of different people for presenting the natural and cultural resources. This can be achieved using the practice of Wikipedia, in which anyone can submit information on a subject, in our case the environment, and an administrator reviews what will be published. In this work, we focus on the submission of cartographical data concerning the paths and routes that present environmental and cultural interest. These data have been collected and processed using GIS, Remote Sensing and GPS technologies. For each path a description of the type of the path, the terrain involved, experience needed, estimated time required and a classification of the paths according to the difficulty is attempted. In this paper, we present in detail the collection of data and their submission in the platform.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic , Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousri</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19965/1/04_Martinis_FULL%5B1%5D.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Martinis, Aristotelis; Halvatzaras, Dimitrios and Kabassi, Katerina    (2011) Promotion of Eco-Tourism Using the Practice of Wikipedia: The Case-Study of Environmental and Cultural Paths in Zakynthos.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic , Drazen; Hashem, Yousri and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstracts. International Conference on Organic Agriculture and Agro-Eco Tourism, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19965/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>