<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>School catering supply chains: study on 5 cases</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spigarolo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarti, Valerio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bocchi, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giorgi, Giulio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study presents accurate data on the school catering systems of five different municipalities which decided to invest on service quality and sustainable development. The aim is to provide a compendium to be considered by other local authorities and then used as an educational tool for drafting new templates for tender specifications.&#xD;
Regional laws as drivers for promoting organic consumption in school canteens and waste reduction through self service systems are two examples of interesting models for sustainable school food catering. This work does not present a unique best practice model but constellations of reference models for each different situation: in such way each municipality can consult the most fit case study and search the best solution according to specific variables.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-09-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17623/1/iPOPY_WP3_SupplyChain5Cases_EN.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spigarolo, Roberto; Sarti, Valerio; Bocchi, Stefano and Giorgi, Giulio         (2010) School catering supply chains: study on 5 cases.    International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), Tjele, Denmark.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17623/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>