<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Best Practice Case Study of the Participatory Market Chain Approach (PMCA) application as part of the SDC funded project “Sustainable Agriculture Support to Albania” 2009 to 2011</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mitrovic, Marija Sijan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Albania</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The SASA Project (Sustainable Agriculture Support to Albania) relates to a development project that came to an end in 2011. Funded by the Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC) and the Swiss State Secretariat for Economic Affairs (SECO), the SASA project aimed to boost overall economic and rural development through the creation of important income for the rural population while ensuring sustainable production practices and market development for agricultural quality products from Albania. This document presents the project’s main results relating mainly to its last phase (2009 – 2011), which was based on the application of the Participatory Market Chain Approach (PMCA), a participatory intervention methodology to trigger market-led commercial, technical, and institutional innovations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20677/1/Best_Practice_Case_Study_SASA_PMCA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mitrovic, Marija Sijan         (2012) Best Practice Case Study of the Participatory Market Chain Approach (PMCA) application as part of the SDC funded project “Sustainable Agriculture Support to Albania” 2009 to 2011.    Swiss Agency for Development and Cooperation (SDC) and the Swiss State Secretariat for Economic Affairs (SECO).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20677/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>