<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessment of the susceptibility to pests and diseases of 36 apple cultivars in four low-input organic orchards in France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Parveaud, Claude-Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomez, Christelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Libourel, Gilles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romet, Lionel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Warlop, Francois</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simon, Sylvaine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brun, Laurent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pouzoulet, Didier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Delebecq, Alain</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tournant, Ludovic</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oste, Sandrine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laurens, François</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of the keystones of the organic orchard is the cultivar choice as one element of pest and disease control. However, few exhaustive data sets concerning the cultivar susceptibility to pests and diseases are available for growers. In order to identify cultivars adapted to organic production methods, the susceptibility to scab, aphids and powdery mildew and the agronomic properties of 36 cultivars were assessed in four French sites under different pedo-climatic conditions. Different levels of susceptibility to scab were observed for 23 scab Vf-resistant and 13 other cultivars. In the North of France where Vf resistance is overcome, the Vf cultivars displayed different levels of scab severity. A high variability in the susceptibility to aphids was observed whereas susceptibility to powdery mildew varied less. The analysis of susceptibility properties, yield and fruit quality, fruit storability and tree behaviour permitted to identify a set of interesting cultivars according to the site.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-05-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17132/1/Ecofruit_Extended_abstract_Parveaud_et_al_2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Parveaud, Claude-Eric; Gomez, Christelle; Libourel, Gilles; Romet, Lionel; Warlop, Francois; Simon, Sylvaine; Brun, Laurent; Pouzoulet, Didier; Delebecq, Alain; Tournant, Ludovic; Oste, Sandrine and Laurens, François    (2010) Assessment of the susceptibility to pests and diseases of 36 apple cultivars in four low-input organic orchards in France.  [Evaluation de la sensibilité variétale auw bioagresseurs de 36 variétés de pommiers dans quatre vergers semi-extensifs conduits en agriculture biologique en France.]      Speech at:   14th International Conference on Organic Fruit Growing, ECOFRUIT, Universität Hohenheim, Germany, February 22 to 24, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17132/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>