<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nachhaltige Schweinezucht mittels angepasster BLUP Zuchtwertschätzung am Beispiel des Schwäbisch-Hällischen Schweins</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bühler, Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nowadays the loss of species is still a problem. Sustaining the genetic potential, especially of old domestic breeds, is an urgent matter. Possibilities for protection of domestic species are discussed and evaluated. The research is based on the rare pig breed “Schwäbisch Hällisches Schwein” (SH). In three steps, a BLUP breeding method developed to sustain the SH in its uniqueness, enabling breeders to use the positive attributes of this pig in the meat market. Breeding, according to this model, maintains and selects positive attributes of the breed in accordance with the demand of the premium meat market, the conditions of organic or low- input farming on market opportunities. These positive attributes also create an added value for farmers. The breed can be sustained, because the farmers can refinance their work by earnings from the meat market. The model is applicable for other endangered pig breeds and also other species. The research shows a new way of protecting rare breeds, almost completely independent from governmental support.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9843/1/9843_B%C3%BChler_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bühler, Rudolf and Zimmer, Christoph    (2007) Nachhaltige Schweinezucht mittels angepasster BLUP Zuchtwertschätzung am Beispiel des Schwäbisch-Hällischen Schweins.  [Sustainable pig breeding using a tailored BLUP-method – An example of the Schwaebisch Haellisches Schwein.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9843/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>