<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Politikgestaltung – Institutionen des Biosektors und ihr Einfluss auf die Politik</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming has become a policy instrument of agriculture. Thus, the sector is required more and more to get politically active. This paper presents results from an analysis of organic farming institutions from 1997-2003 in eleven European countries and shows first results of a network analysis conducted to examine networks of organic farming policy. Institutions of the organic farming sector in new EU member states are still developing and their relation with mainstream farming institutions is characterised by competition whereas in EU15 countries and Switzerland this relation is more one of creative conflict. Countries with a high share of organic farming show signs of consolidation of their institutions. Policy networks of organic farming are bigger in size and denser in these countries compared to the small networks in new member states. However, organic farming organisations, as well as the state play an important role in all networks and thus for organic farming policy making. We conclude that successful organic farming development needs a dynamic and unified organic farming sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3483/1/3483.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun and Stolze, Matthias    (2005) Politikgestaltung – Institutionen des Biosektors und ihr Einfluss auf die Politik.  [Making politics – institutions involved in organic farming policy.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3483/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>