<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>On Farm Validation of Organic Farming Technology in Elephant foot yam (Amorphophallus paeoniifolius (Dennst.) Nicolson)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suja, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Susan John, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ravindran, C.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prathapan, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundaresan, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently alternative agricultural systems, like organic farming, that are less chemical intensive, less exploitative and that can conserve the environment are gaining popularity. Tuber crops, especially aroids, like elephant foot yam, respond well to organic manures and offer scope for organic production. However, lack of package of practices recommendations hinders the promotion of this viable alternative farming practice. Hence, the organic farming technology for elephant foot yam developed at CTCRI was validated through on farm trials under State Horticulture Mission funded programme. Demonstration trials were conducted during 2008-2009 in 10 farmers’ sites to cover an area of 5 ha in Kollam and Pathanamthitta districts of Kerala to compare the yield, quality, economics and soil fertility under the organic management practices with the existing farmers’ practice and conventional practice (present package of practices recommendations) in elephant foot yam. Organic farming resulted in higher corm yield (34.60 t ha-1) and additional income (Rs. 43,651 ha-1) over conventional farming. Organically produced corms had significantly higher dry matter and Mg contents and significantly lower oxalate content. The chemical properties of the soil, especially K, were also seen favoured under organic farming. The organic farming technology standardized for elephant foot yam includes the application of farmyard manure (FYM) @ 36 t ha-1, green manuring with cowpea to generate 20-25 t ha-1 of green matter in 45-60 days, neem cake @ 1 t ha-1 and ash @ 3 t ha-1.FYM and neem cake are to be applied in pits at the time of planting. Ash may be applied at the time of incorporation of green manure at 45-60 days after planting.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27884/7/27884.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Suja, G.; Susan John, K.; Ravindran, C.S.; Prathapan, K. and Sundaresan, S.   (2010) On Farm Validation of Organic Farming Technology in Elephant foot yam (Amorphophallus paeoniifolius (Dennst.) Nicolson).   Journal of Root Crops, 36 (1), pp. 59-64.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27884/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>