<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Survey of the Demands of End Users in Europe for Organic Market Data</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Home, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Losták, Michal</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Few European countries produce complete coverage of important market data, standardization is missing, and data are seldom comparable within one country over time and between countries. Furthermore, detailed information on specific commodities is missing. Many different data collection methods are currently used and the variety of agencies collecting data in the various European countries mean that gaining a European level overview of the quality of existing data is difficult. As part of the EU research project “OrganicDataNetwork”, a survey was carried out in 2012 to identify the needs and demands of end users of organic market data, and to find areas of information asymmetry. A further goal of the survey was to undertake an appraisal of the quality of the existing available data that is used. This contribution presents some of the highlights of the results, which will be published in full during 2013.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lernoud, Julia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23193/1/home-etal-2013-fibl-ifoam-report-2013-p232-233.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Home, Robert; Stolze, Matthias and Losták, Michal    (2013) Survey of the Demands of End Users in Europe for Organic Market Data.    In: Willer, Helga; Lernoud, Julia and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2013.  FiBL-IFOAM Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), Frick and Bonn, pp. 232-233.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23193/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>