<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Swedish challenge – interdisciplinarity, collaboration and integration for research and development in organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Geber, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivarsson, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Källander, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is an example of the integration of non-monetary valued goals (as for example environmental concerns and animal welfare) in a market driven production. The main tool is the use of certification of the production. In this perspective organic farming becomes an interesting model for the entire food system. Current fast structural changes in Swedish agricultural primary production with decreasing numbers of farmers and an increasing size of farms on the one hand and increasing market competition and decreasing food prices on the other hand are well known realities.  Reports on the decreasing capacity of the global ecosystems to generate non-monetary valued life supporting ecosystem services also emphasize the role of agriculture to fulfil these functions (Millennium Assessment, 2005). Multifunctional agriculture, making use of ecosystem services for biomass production, collective utilities and new workplaces, is highlighted. &#xD;
In order to play an important role on these issues, the sustainable development of organic farming requires research covering a wide scope of aspects, from environmental issues in the farm and food production system to questions about ethics, precaution and feedback at different levels. Knowledge from different disciplines, areas and perspectives need to be integrated. Scarce resources for research and development, along with the historical development of organic farming (to a substantial part based on experiential learning and knowledge) highlight the importance of relevance and validity in organic research.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4227/1/geber-etal-2005-sweden-revised.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Geber, U.; Ivarsson, K. and Källander, I.    (2005) The Swedish challenge – interdisciplinarity, collaboration and integration for research and development in organic farming.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4227/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>