<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An assessment of apple varieties for their suitability in organic production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fitzgerald, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cross, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berrie, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cubison, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Twenty seven varieties of apple were assessed for their susceptibility to apple scab,&#xD;
mildew and rosy apple aphid in a replicated experiment at East Malling Research. The&#xD;
varieties most affected by mildew were Goldrush, DL11, Liberty, Bohemia and Pinova.&#xD;
Ceeval, Discovery, Edward VII, Howgate Wonder, Rajka, Rebella and Topaz had the&#xD;
lowest incidences of mildew. The highest incidence of scab occurred on Pilot and Pinova,&#xD;
but infestation was low throughout the assessment period. In 2006 when aphid populations&#xD;
were high, Liberty, Goldrush and Delorina had no aphid infestations, and low infestations&#xD;
were seen on Edward VII, Resi and Santana.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13682/1/213-215.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fitzgerald, J.; Cross, J.; Berrie, A. and Cubison, S.    (2008) An assessment of apple varieties for their suitability in organic production systems.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 213-215.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13682/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>