<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality of carrots as affected by pre- and postharvest factors and processing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seljåsen, Randi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Hanne L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lauridsen, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Gabriela S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Birlouez-Aragone, Inès</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this review is to provide an update on factors contributing to quality of carrots, with special focus on the role of pre- and postharvest factors and processing. The genetic factor shows the highest impact on quality variables in carrots, causing a 7–11-fold difference between varieties in content of terpenes, β-carotene, magnesium, iron and phenolics as well as a 1–4-fold difference in falcarindiol, bitter taste and sweet taste. Climate-related factors may cause a difference of up to 20-fold for terpenes, 82% for total sugars and 30–40% for β-carotene, sweet taste and bitter taste. Organic farming in comparison with conventional farming has shown 70% higher levels for magnesium and 10% for iron. Low nitrogen fertilisation level may cause up to 100% increase in terpene content, minor increase in dry matter (+4 to +6%) and magnesium (+8%) and reduction in β-carotene content (−8 to −11%). Retail storage at room temperature causes the highest reduction in β-carotene (−70%) and ascorbic acid (−70%). Heat processing by boiling reduces shear force (−300 to −1000%) and crispiness (−67%) as well as content of phenolics (−150%), terpenes (−85%) and total carotenes (−20%) and increases the risk of furan accumulation. Sensory and chemical quality parameters of carrots are determined mainly by genetic and climate-related factors and to a minor extent by cultivation method. Retail temperature and storage atmosphere as well as heating procedure in processing have the highest impact in quality reduction. © 2013 Society of Chemical Industry</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25315/1/Quality%20of%20carrots%20as%20affected%20by%20pre-%20and%20postharvest%20factors%20and%20processing.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seljåsen, Randi; Kristensen, Hanne L.; Lauridsen, Charlotte; Wyss, Gabriela S.; Kretzschmar, Ursula; Birlouez-Aragone, Inès and Kahl, Johannes   (2013) Quality of carrots as affected by pre- and postharvest factors and processing.   Journal of the Science of Food and Agriculture (J Sci Food Agric), 93 (11), pp. 2611-2626.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25315/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>