<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Der Beitrag der österreichischen Biobauern zur Erhaltung der &#xD;
alten, seltenen Nutztierrassen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fischerleitner, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berger, Beate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Atteneder, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Austrian gene conservation programme for rare breeds from 2001 to 2006 re-sulted in increasing numbers of participating farms as well as increasing numbers of animals. On the whole the programme was readily accepted and successfully realized by the farmers. The percentage of participating organic farms lies with 41% signifi-cantly above the average as only 10% of all farms are organic farms. Further the number of breeding animals in the gene conservation programme proves the en-gagement of the farmers. On organic farms 11,804 animals (44%) are in use against 15,126 animals (56%) on conventional farms in 2006. However with 6.4 animals/farm the average number of animals per organic farm is a little higher than on commercial farms (5.6 animals/farm). 9% of Austrian livestock against 44% of the rare breeds are kept on organic farms. From 2001 to 2006 there was an increase of rare breed ani-mals inorganic far ms from 28 to 44%.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9000/1/9000_Fischerleitner_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fischerleitner, Franz; Berger, Beate and Atteneder, Veronika    (2007) Der Beitrag der österreichischen Biobauern zur Erhaltung der alten, seltenen Nutztierrassen.  [The contribution of Austrian organic farmers to the conservation of rare tradi-tional breeds.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9000/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>