<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Sustainable Food and Agricultural Movement in Munich, Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schafer, Melissa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The sustainable food and agriculture movement in Munich, Germany is one of the strongest in all of Germany. Germany as a whole is the leading consumer of organic food in Europe and is one of the founders of the organic agriculture philosophy and practice. But in the case of Munich, where does this activism come from in particular? Why is Munich so strong in this movement? This paper discusses the methodology of mapping the actors involved in the sustainable food and agriculture movements following the actor-network theory (ANT). Sustainable food and agriculture is considered to be food produced follow-ing organic standards, as well as food produced regionally, but not necessarily organic. The goal is to map the relationships between the actors involved in the sustainable food movement which include consumer and environmental organizations, consumers, political institutions and organizations, farmer and organic organizations, retailers, farmers (both direct and non-direct marketing), religious organizations, researchers and restaurateurs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7528/1/Schafer_Munich_organic_movement.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7528/2/7528_Shafer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schafer, Melissa    (2006) The Sustainable Food and Agricultural Movement in Munich, Germany.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7528/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>