<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of an organic and a conventional cropping system on soil fertility</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Boldrini, Dr Arianna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benincasa, Dr Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gigliotti, Prof Giovanni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Businelli, Prof Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guiducci, Prof Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An experiment was started in 1998 in Central Italy to evaluate changes in soil fertility and the risk of N loss in an organic (ORG) and a conventional low input (CONV) cropping system. At the end of a 6-year rotation, ORG caused a higher plant biomass incorporation into the soil and thus a higher soil soluble organic carbon. The N surplus in ORG was 32% higher than in CONV, while no differences were recorded on N content in the top soil, so that ORG implicated a higher N loss from that soil layer. In ORG we recorded a higher phosphatase activity but a lower available soil P (due to application of rock phosphate in sub-alkaline soil) and a lower exchangeable K.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12381/1/Boldrini_12381_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Boldrini, Dr Arianna; Benincasa, Dr Paolo; Gigliotti, Prof Giovanni; Businelli, Prof Daniela and Guiducci, Prof Marcello    (2008) Effects of an organic and a conventional cropping system on soil fertility.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12381/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>