<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative effects of organic manure sources and rates on performance of groundnut varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mukhtar, Aishatu Abubakar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Odion, Ehiabhi Cyril</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ahmed, Adamu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Babaji, Bashir Ahmad</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aminu, Maryam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arunah, Uthman Lucky</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An experiment was conducted at the Teaching and Research farm of the Institute for Agricultural Research, Ahmadu Bello University Zaria. The aim was to study effects of different organic manure sources on performance of groundnut varieties.  Treatment consisted of three organic manure source, (Poultry manure, (PM) cow dung (CD) and household waste (HW) each at two levels (1 ton and 2 tons), two varieties of groundnut SAMNUT 21 (V1) and SAMNUT 23 (V2) and a control.  The treatments were factorially combined and assigned in a randomized complete block design and replicated three times. Growth data such as plant height, canopy spread and biomass weight and; yield data including, pod yield per plant, seed yield per plant, 100 seed weight were collected.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23107/1/23107%20Comparative%20effects%20of%20organic%20manure%20sources%20and%20rates_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mukhtar, Aishatu Abubakar; Odion, Ehiabhi Cyril; Ahmed, Adamu; Babaji, Bashir Ahmad; Aminu, Maryam and Arunah, Uthman Lucky    (2014) Comparative effects of organic manure sources and rates on performance of groundnut varieties.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 843-846.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23107/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>