<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainable rural development with emphasis on agriculture and food security within the climate change setting : SARD-climate final report</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sumelius, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bäckman, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rötter, Reimund</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainable Agricultural and Rural Development (SARD) is considered an essential step toward achieving the first Millenium Development Goal (MDG) of eradicating extreme hunger and poverty. In order to achieve this important goal, first it is important to find ways of increasing the incomes of the rural poor, who mostly depend on upon agriculture for their livelihoods. This means improving development, cooperation, trade and agricultural policy to improve agriculture's contribution to economic development and poverty reduction. Current projects estimate that 1.02 billion people will go hungry in 2009 alone; an indication that if efforts are not directed at reversing this trend it would most likely continue.&#xD;
&#xD;
The research on climate change effect on productivity and rural development is scarce. The high uncertainty of climate change effects and the implications on agriculture is based on extrapolations and scenarios. Our knowledge on local environmental issues and agriculture is insufficient and local agricultural research data do mostly not exist.&#xD;
&#xD;
The agricultural sector requires investments and incentives that can guarantee sustainable development.&#xD;
&#xD;
Farmers need credit possibilities in order to buy input, to make investments and to finance adaptation measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
Fair Trade certification offers one way to guarantee minimum prices for farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Helsinki</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17115/1/DP40.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sumelius, John; Bäckman, Stefan; Kahiluoto, Helena and Rötter, Reimund         (2009) Sustainable rural development with emphasis on agriculture and food security within the climate change setting : SARD-climate final report.    University of Helsinki.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17115/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>