<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rahmenbedingungen für den Einsatz biologischer Lebensmittel in Großküchen - Die Erfahrungen in Österreich</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gleirscher, DI Norbert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During the last few years the use of organic food in public canteens in Austria has increased, which nowadays effects a relatively large marketing potential. Reasons for the rapid development on the one hand are the increasing public awareness of environmental, social and health issues, which causes a consolidated demand for the use of organic food by the particular customers. On the political side, the recent discussions on sustainable public procurement strategies can support the establishment of organic food in public canteens by setting the particular legal and financial framework. The aim of this paper is to point out some general conditions for the successful use of organic food in public canteens.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3404/1/3404.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gleirscher, DI Norbert    (2005) Rahmenbedingungen für den Einsatz biologischer Lebensmittel in Großküchen - Die Erfahrungen in Österreich.  [Gereral conditions for the implementation of organic food in public canteens - The experience in Austria.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3404/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>