<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings of the 2012 Canadian Organic Science Conference</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Canadian Organic Science Conference and Organic Science Cluster Strategic Meetings featured leading scientists presenting and discussing current advances in the field of organic and sustainable agricultural practices in Canada and beyond.  Information is of interest to both organic and conventional researchers, with research presented in a diverse range of fields, including: soil fertility, quality and health; horticultural and specialty crops; cereal-based cropping systems; livestock productivity, health and welfare; greenhouse production and season extension; food, sustainability and organic systems; social science and organic agriculture; and extension of organic research.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Agriculture Centre of Canada</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>MacKenzie, Joanna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Savard, Margaret</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-02-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20797/1/COSC_Proceedings_Final_Web_Optimized_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>MacKenzie, Joanna and Savard, Margaret (Eds.)    (2012) Proceedings of the 2012 Canadian Organic Science Conference.   Organic Agriculture Centre of Canada, Truro, Nova Scotia, Canada, pp. 1-143.  Proceedings of Canadian Organic Science Conference and Organic Science Cluster Strategic Meetings, Winnipeg, Manitoba, Canada, February 21-23, 2012.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20797/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>