<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>One size fits all? – Differences in school food cultures identified in iPOPY research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roos, Gun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The goal of this presentation is to explore integration of organic food into schools from the perspective of school food cultures. First, the concept of school food culture is defined. The presentation is based on data and findings from the ongoing iPOPY- “innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth” project, which focuses on how increased consumption of organic food may be achieved through procuring organic food in public food service for young people. Researchers in the iPOPY project have collected available information on organic school meals and have also visited school canteens. Differences and similarities in school food cultures in Nordic countries (Denmark, Finland and Norway) and Italy are discussed. School food cultures reflect local food culture and different school meals systems. School meals can be included in educational services, schools can offer commercial food services or children can bring their lunch from home. Finland and Italy recognize school meals as a part of people’s right to education and serve warm lunch meals, whereas children in Denmark and Norway usually bring their lunch from home and there is a tradition with bread meals for lunch. This presentation shows that school meals and school food cultures are different in iPOPY countries and illustrates that it is not possible to give one recommendation that fits all for how to integrate organic food into schools.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>He, Chen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Mikkola, Minna</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nymoen, Lena Lie</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-11-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17420/4/Paper_submission_-_Gun_Roos_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17420/7/GunRoos_iPOPY_Copenhagen_25112009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Roos, Gun and  ,     (2009) One size fits all? – Differences in school food cultures identified in iPOPY research.   In: Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg; He, Chen; Mikkola, Minna; Nielsen, Thorkild and Nymoen, Lena Lie (Eds.)  CORE Organic Project Series Report, ICROFS, Tjele, Denmark, pp. 54-56.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17420/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>