<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erdbeerblütenstecher (Anthonomus rubi Herbst): &#xD;
Netzabdeckung als Kontrollmöglichkeit in einjährigen Erdbeer-beständen in der späten Sorte Malwina</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steen, Christiane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dillmann, Klaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ortlieb, Reinhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The strawberry blossom weevil is one of the key pests in organic strawberry production, since Anthonomus rubi is able to reduce the yield up to 60 % in dependence of the cultivar and the temperature development over springtime. The damage is caused by the weevil female by cutting the flower stem after laying one egg into the flower bud. As a control possibility for strawberry fields in their first year after planting, net covering has been tested to prevent the weevil from entering since A. rubi usually hibernates in nearby forest areas. Five net types with different mesh sizes and weights were tested and an uncovered control in the late blooming cultivar Malwina. In regard to the criteria “destroyed flower buds” all five net variants showed significant lower rates than the control. In regard to the criteria “yield class-1-fruits” none of the net variants showed significantly higher yield amounts than the control. Furthermore the net type “Rantai K” showed significantly less class-1-fruits compared to the control and the other net types. In regard to the criteria “yield class-2-fruits” all five net types, except the net type “FaBio 03”, showed significantly higher yield amounts than the control. But class-2-fruits are much more labour intensive and the market price is much lower compared to the class-1-fruits. These results showed that covering with net can not be recommended to the grower at this point.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21327/1/21327_steen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steen, Christiane; Dillmann, Klaus and Ortlieb, Reinhard    (2013) Erdbeerblütenstecher (Anthonomus rubi Herbst): Netzabdeckung als Kontrollmöglichkeit in einjährigen Erdbeer-beständen in der späten Sorte Malwina.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21327/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>