<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving baking quality, nutritional value and safety of organic winter wheat / Améliorer la qualité technologique, nutritionnelle et sanitaire du blé biologique, Principaux leviers agronomiques et technologiques</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>David, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abecassis, Joël</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carcea, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Celette, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hiltbrunner, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messmer, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Narducci, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peigne, Joséphine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, I. K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic bread wheat market has been diversified over time through the emergence of different sale channels. Processors require organic bread wheat of higher quality and safety in order to meet the consumers’ demand. The overall objective of the AGTEC-Org project was to identify agronomical and technological ways to improve the performance of organic wheat and flour. The findings would &#xD;
contribute to enhanced baking quality and nutritional value of organic flour, as well as prevention of mycotoxin contamination. The project involved 9 research centers or universities from 5 European countries for a total budget of about 1.5 million €. More than 400 experimental treatments were analyzed from 23 agronomic trials and 4 lab-experiments on food technology. Choice of cultivar is an efficient way to obtain higher grain quality. Intercropping legumes (grain or forage) improves weed control and N availability for wheat crop or succeeding crop. Green manure can be an effective alternative to farmyard manure. Fertilization with organic fertilizers improves yield and quality when &#xD;
water is available. Reduced tillage affects soil fertility and wheat yield but has little effects on grain quality. &#xD;
Milling process strongly influences flour characteristics. Stone milling improves the nutritive value and flour characteristics remain very stable independently of the milling yield. However, stone milling slightly raises DON levels. Characteristics of flour produced by means of roller milling appear very dependent on milling yield, instead. Increasing milling yield with the aim of enriching nutritional quality has a detrimental effect on either safety (DON) or bread-making quality (bread volume). Debranning before milling has a very positive impact on flour safety by reducing its DON content by 50 %.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26013/1/David_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>David, Christophe; Abecassis, Joël; Carcea, M.; Celette, Florian; Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle; Friedel, J.; Hiltbrunner, J.; Mäder, Paul; Messmer, Monika; Narducci, V.; Peigne, Joséphine and Thomsen, I. K.   (2013) Improving baking quality, nutritional value and safety of organic winter wheat / Améliorer la qualité technologique, nutritionnelle et sanitaire du blé biologique, Principaux leviers agronomiques et technologiques.   Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 1-13.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26013/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>