<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Les Indomptables: an ethnography of niche novelty production in Walloon agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Delobel, Vincent JMM</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>My ancestors from both sides have been farming for ages. Peasants have continuously held this as ancestral as salutary art of nourishing “débrouillardise” (lit. problem-solving creativity) for ages; they have fed others in the plain as in the mountain, under dictatorship as under “democracy”. However, farmer newspapers today say we may disappear soon; ‘eternal’ peasant population rushes to the bottom.&#xD;
Are we really going to disappear? How and why did we get to this situation? What is going on in farms today? What are farmers’ plans and projects? What futures do these projects lead to? This is in short the structure of this MSc thesis. This alarming observation motivated me to go and see in farms, not only at home but also to colleagues’ in order to better see, understand phenomena going on in the reality of farms, and to reflect deeper on underlying issues. Thus, I phoned a few cousins and other colleagues and told them I was interested in their “inventivité” (inventiveness), their own way of doing things; I asked them to go and work with them in their own farm, in their daily activities -whatever it would be- to understand why and how they are looking to change their routines, i.e. for novelties.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25218/1/Les%20Indomptables%20%28EN%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Delobel, Vincent JMM   (2014) Les Indomptables: an ethnography of niche novelty production in Walloon agriculture.    Masters thesis, Wageningen University, Rural Development Sociology chairgroup.  .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25218/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>