<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dairy farms: constraints and recommendations for enhancing health, welfare and food saftey (Workshop results)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Results &#xD;
&#xD;
- It is necessary to improve the information to the public (who are the taxpayer and pay the subsidies) about organic farming as a system, that improves animal health and welfare.&#xD;
- Consumers must get accurate information about the organic products they buy.&#xD;
- Producers should be informed about organic farming before they convert (so they know what to expect): they should be told about the regluations and pointed to the available information about organic farming.&#xD;
- Veterinarians should be informed (part of the teaching curriculum in vet schools) about the holistic system, the importance of preventive health management on organic farms and about alternative treatments.&#xD;
- In communication to the policy makers (the government), organic farming should be presented as a different farming system and not as a conventional system with some alteration.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martini, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Padel, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2710/1/walkenhorst-2003-working-group-report-dairy-farms.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smolders, G.; Walkenhorst, Michael and Padel, S.    (2003) Dairy farms: constraints and recommendations for enhancing health, welfare and food saftey (Workshop results).    In: Hovi, M.; Martini, A. and Padel, S. (Eds.)   Socio-economic aspects of animal health and food safety in organic farming systems. Proceedings of the 1st SAFO Workshop. 5.-7. September 2003, Florence, Italy.  SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project, pp. 91-93.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2710/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>