<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Samenfeste Sorten oder Hybriden - Anbauvergleich von Möhren unter den Verhältnissen des Ökologischen Landbaus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fleck, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sikora, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gränzdörffer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohmund, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fölsch, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Fragstein, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A field trial with carrots was carried out in 1998 at two sites in Hesse (North: loamy soil in Neu-Eichenberg; East: sandy soil in Queck) to compare 6 open pollinating and 6 F1 hybrids under an Organic Farming regime. Characteristics of cultivation, harvest, quality, and longevity were measured. Of the parameters of cultivation and harvest the hybrids showed a more intensive foliage growth, higher marketable yields (plus 29 and 25%), and more homogeneous taproots than the open pollinating cultivars. Picture forming methods clearly separated the samples into the two groups of breeding methods. The open pollinating cultivars were characterized by higher degrees of form intensity and ripeness and a stable vitality. The hybrids of the sandy site had a better keeping quality after 6½ months storage, only the open pollinating cultivar ‘Rodelika’ had a very high ranking similar to the hybrids ‘Kardame F1’ and ‘Bolero F1’.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Reents, Hans Jürgen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1163/1/1163-fleck-et-al-2001-samen-m%C3%B6hren-wien.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fleck, M.; Sikora, F.; Gränzdörffer, M.; Rohmund, C.; Fölsch, E.; von Fragstein, P. and Heß, J.    (2001) Samenfeste Sorten oder Hybriden - Anbauvergleich von Möhren unter den Verhältnissen des Ökologischen Landbaus.  [Open pollinating varieties and hybrids - comparison of carrot growing under organic farming conditions.]  In: Reents, Hans Jürgen (Ed.)  Beiträge zur 6. Wissenschaftstagung zum Ökologischen Landbau: Von Leit-Bildern zu Leit-Linien, Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin, pp. 253-256.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1163/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>