<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Motives and barriers to development of organic olive production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iliopoulou, D</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Douma, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giourga, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Environmental and health problems caused by conventional agriculture lead many farmers to organic agriculture, a system that has been rapidly developed worldwide. However, the adoption of organic farming is not an easy decision and it carries with it several barriers. Different interrelated factors are usually at play, rather than one decisive single motive, concerning financial, environmental, health issues and personal beliefs and values. &#xD;
This study aims to indentify the factors that encourage olive growers to adopt organic practices and the reasons that discourage them to continue. Moreover, it aims to answer the question whether the farmers would continue to grow in organic way, even if the compensatory payments will be reduced? The research is conducted in Lesvos Island, in Greece and a structured questionnaire was distributed to 69 olive growers. &#xD;
Results illustrate that financial factors are especially important incentives for conversion. On the other hand, institutional aspects are the most important problems that organic farmers face during production process. Finally, 53.6% of interviewed farmers express their intention of reversion from organic agriculture, due to variable problems. Results could help to better understand motives and barriers that lie behind farmers’ choices, in order to support the potential for the development of organic olive production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic, Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19833/1/02_Iliopoulou_FULL.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Iliopoulou, D; Douma, K and Giourga, C    (2011) Motives and barriers to development of organic olive production.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic, Drazen; Hashem, Yousry and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstract. International Conference on ORGANIC AGRICULTURE and AGRO-ECO TOURISM in the Mediterranean, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19833/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>