<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>NEW WAYS OF INCREASING BIODIVERSITY ON ORGANIC FARMS AND THEIR EFFECT ON PROFITABLILITY – the Nature Conservation Farm Brodowin –</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stein-Bachinger, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schobert, Heike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frielinghaus, Helmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Although organic farming systems have many positive biotic aspects, the protection of target species characteristic of open landscape is not guaranteed. Specific knowledge and financial incentives are necessary in order to integrate nature conservation goals successfully into agricultural practice. The main objectives of the interdisciplinary ‘Nature Conservation Farm Brodowin’ project are: the investi-gation of the interactions between large-scale organic farming and nature conservation; the identifica-tion of points of conflict; and the working out of solutions that pay sufficient attention to economic aspects. Legume-grass forage is important for typical species of farmland wildlife. Alternative meth-ods of fodder production which better meet nature conservation demands are evaluated economically. Initial calculations of the compensation payments required to offset the losses of a higher first cut range between 120 and 180 Euro/ha. A delayed second cut would cost on average twice as much. The losses and additional operational expenses incurred by retaining 10 % unmown strips are approxi-mately 90 to 140 Euro/ha. The use of special silage harvesting techniques can also help to improve the living conditions of farmland birds without resulting in disadvantages for the farmer.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4484/4/Stein-Bachinger_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stein-Bachinger, Karin; Zander, Peter; Schobert, Heike and Frielinghaus, Helmut    (2005) NEW WAYS OF INCREASING BIODIVERSITY ON ORGANIC FARMS AND THEIR EFFECT ON PROFITABLILITY – the Nature Conservation Farm Brodowin –.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4484/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>