<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Trichoderma applications on vines grown in organic nursery</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Di Marco, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Osti, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A two-year trial was conducted to evaluate the effects of applications of commercial formulations of the fungus Trichoderma on graftlings of grapevine (Vitis vinifera L.) in a commercial nursery where plants were grown under organic management. Treatments were carried out at callusing, rooting and callusing+rooting. Effects on the host-plant morpho-physiological characteristics were observed and depended on the type and timing of Trichoderma application. Treatment at rooting was the most effective whilst application at callusing and combination of treatments gave controversial results. The most noticeable effect of application of Trichoderma was an increase of quantitative-qualitative characteristics of the root system, with a consistent development of root hairs. Compared to untreated plants the percentage of certifiable plants treated at rooting was higher.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12134/1/Di_Marco_12134_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Di Marco, S. and Osti, F.    (2008) Effects of Trichoderma applications on vines grown in organic nursery.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12134/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>