<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends 2013</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Asia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>North America</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>World</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The 14th edition of The World of Organic Agriculture documents recent developments in global organic agriculture. It includes contributions from representatives of the organic sector from throughout the world and provides comprehensive organic farming statistics that cover surface area under organic management, specific information about land use in organic systems, numbers of farms and other operator types  as well as selected market data.&#xD;
&#xD;
The book also contains information on the global market for organic food, the latest developments in organic certification, information on standards and regulations as well as insights into current and emerging trends for organic agriculture in Africa, Asia, Europe, Latin America, North America and Oceania.&#xD;
In addition, the volume contains a number of country reports: Albania, Australia, Canada, Hungary, Kosovo, Montenegro, Serbia, Pacific Islands, and the United States.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lernoud, Julia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25188/1/1606-organic-world-2013.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25188/7/FiBL_IFOAM_World_of_Organic_Agriculture_2013_UA_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25188/21/CC2013_chap2_Monde.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25188/27/fibl-ifoam-2013-world-of-organic-chinese.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga; Lernoud, Julia and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)      (2013) The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends 2013.   14 edition. The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements, Frick and Bonn.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25188/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>