<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung der Biokristallisation für die Unterscheidung von Proben mittels computerunterstützter Texturanalyse und visueller Bildauswertung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, Dr. Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Machteld</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Busscher, Dr. Nicolaas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretschmer, Sebastian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Dr. Jens-Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mergardt, Gaby</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paulsen, Marianne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Doesburg, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meier-Ploeger, Prof.Dr. Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Because of the growing market in organic produce screening methods are needed which allow the characterization of the food. Since many years the so called biocrystallization technique has been used to characterize products derived from different farming systems yet the method was not validated. The results of our investigations in the last three years show that the method can fulfill the requirements for the validation process due to international standards. The sample preparation and the crystallization procedures could be standardised and documented. For the crystallization factors of influence were described and controlled. In addition to the traditionally used visual evaluation a new computerized image texture analysis program was succesfully applied. Furthermore visual evaluation was standardized due to international norms used in sensory analysis. With a panel of trained people, crystal patterns from fresh and freeze dried carrot samples can be differentiated as statistically significant. This is a siginificant step forward because this allows the development of a structure analysis programme and will contribute to connect the different approaches within the researches in this field.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3775/1/3775.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kahl, Dr. Johannes; Huber, Machteld; Busscher, Dr. Nicolaas; Kretschmer, Sebastian; Andersen, Dr. Jens-Otto; Mergardt, Gaby; Paulsen, Marianne; Doesburg, Paul and Meier-Ploeger, Prof.Dr. Angelika    (2005) Entwicklung der Biokristallisation für die Unterscheidung von Proben mittels computerunterstützter Texturanalyse und visueller Bildauswertung.  [Development of the bio crystallization method using computerized texture analysis and visual evaluation methods.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3775/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>