<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zielgruppen für den Bio-Markt – Ergebnisse einer Studie des Instituts für sozial-ökologische Forschung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stieß, Immanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Target Groups in the Market of Organic Food&#xD;
Since consumption of organic food no longer is a matter of idealistic eco-activists, a better understanding of consumer preferences becomes urgent. An empirical study of the Institute for Social-Ecological Research (ISOE) identified five target groups with the help of a social-ecological life style analysis: (1) Totally Convinced Consumers; (2) The Successful and Demanding Consumers; (3) 50+ Health Oriented Consumers; (4) The Cautious and Sceptical Consumers and (5) The Young and Undecided Consumers. The identification of target groups focuses particularly on lifestyles and attitudes, but also takes social situation, phase of life and household organization into account. The survey focuses exclusively on organic food consumers (which make up 54 % in a representative sample). They are the basis for investigating their attitudes, motives, preferences as well as buying habits, preferred organic product groups and shopping preferences related to organic food, which are shown in the study first for all buyers and then separately for each target group.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3507/1/3507.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stieß, Immanuel    (2005) Zielgruppen für den Bio-Markt – Ergebnisse einer Studie des Instituts für sozial-ökologische Forschung.  [Target Groups in the Market of Organic Foods.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3507/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>