<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Run management for organic layers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amsler, Zivile</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koller, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perler, Erika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zeltner, Esther</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Layer runs are often bare and loaded with nutrients and with infectious stages of helminths. Various management strategies are recommended in order to better distribute the hens in the run, thereby preventing local accumulation of droppings and related problems. However, little is known about the impact of those strategies.&#xD;
A series of on farm experiments has been performed in order to test the effects of flock size and of artificial structures on the dispersal of the hens in the run. Further studies evaluated the effects of mowing and run size as well as rotational use of runs on turf quality, nutrient load in the soil and on the infection of the hens with internal parasites.&#xD;
As a summary, introducing structures or applying a rotational management scheme improves run use and facilitates mowing, thus improving turf quality in the run in front of the henhouse. However, the expected reduction of helminth infections and nutrient accumulation has not been observed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21732/1/maurer-etal-2012-lbf_sh_362-p153-155.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Maurer, Veronika; Amsler, Zivile; Heckendorn, Felix; Koller, Martin; Perler, Erika and Zeltner, Esther    (2012) Run management for organic layers.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries, Braunschweig, Germany, Landbauforschung Sonderheft 362, pp. 153-155.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21732/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>