<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Advice and knowledge transfer services for organic producers in Wales</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Little, Tony</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The report records the outputs and achievements of advice and knowledge transfer activities in Wales for organic farmers and those considering conversion between 2001 and 2007. It explores how these activities have contributed to the delivery of the Organic Action Plans for Wales. &#xD;
It has the aim to inform the future development of advisory and knowledge transfer activities in Wales over the course of the next Rural Development Plan (2007 – 2013)&#xD;
The review is principally concerned with two main services:&#xD;
• The Organic Conversion Information Service (OCIS) comprising of the OCW helpline, an information pack and advisory visits, and &#xD;
• Farming Connect advisory services and knowledge transfer activities. &#xD;
In this context, ‘Advisory Services’ include the Farm Business Development Plan, Technical advice and the Environmental Opportunities Review. &#xD;
‘Knowledge transfer’ refers to the demonstration and development farms network, the discussion groups, the programme of training, conferences and seminars and the development projects. &#xD;
The report also makes recommendations to the Welsh Assembly Government on the future direction of these services. ‘Short term implementation’ relates to current contracts (up to March 2008). Medium term recommendations relate to new arrangements that might be implemented in future (from April 2008), for example as part of the new RDP.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10791/1/Advice_Review_Wales.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Little, Tony         (2007) Advice and knowledge transfer services for organic producers in Wales.    University of Wales, Aberystwyth, Organic Centre Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10791/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>