<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>- Surplus Value of Organic Food and Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aertsens, Joris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mondelaers, Koen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Huylenbroeck, Guido</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This document presents a multidisciplinary research project concerning a possible surplus value for Or-ganic Food and Farming (OFF).  The project has started January 1st 2006 and ends November 30th 2007.  By weighing results collected through a review of the literature it will be scientifically assessed  whether or not OFF outperform conventional food and farming from a point of view of environment friendli-ness, nutritional value and safety.  Net benefits for society will then be calculated indicating whether the present support given to OFF is at the optimal level.  The scientific evidence will be compared with the perception of 400 Flemish consumers.  Based on po-tential gaps between evidence and perception, com-bined with consumer characteristics, interesting sug-gestions for communication and promotion strategies concerning OFF will emerge.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8264/1/AERTSENS_document_for_poster_Odense.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aertsens, Joris; Mondelaers, Koen and Van Huylenbroeck, Guido    (2006)  - Surplus Value of Organic Food and Farming.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8264/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>