<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biological Control of Woolly Apple Aphid (Eriosoma lanigerum HAUSM.) with Aphelinus mali HALD.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hetebrügge, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fieger-Metag, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bathon, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The release of Aphelinus mali HALD. from artificial rearing for the control of Woolly Apple Aphid (Eriosoma&#xD;
lanigerum HAUSM.) was tested in field trials. The release of adults proved to be more suitable than the release&#xD;
of cards with parasitized mummies as practised in the first trial. Setting free adult A. mali at the beginning of&#xD;
June reduced the aphid population, though its efficiency was not high enough to prevent damage of the trees&#xD;
totally. The practical applications of A. mali in early spring (after blossom) were not effective because climatic&#xD;
conditions were not suitable enough. The fertility of A. mali depends on temperature and light intensity.&#xD;
The application of Micula (rape oil) and T-S forte reduced the growth of the aphid population effectively.&#xD;
These substances may be used in a combined strategy to improve the successful subsequent release of A.&#xD;
mali. Possible phytotoxic effects, however, must be considered in this context.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13764/1/ecofruit_12th_6.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hetebrügge, K.; Fieger-Metag, N.; Kienzle, J.; Bathon, H.; Zebitz, C.P.W. and Zimmer, J.    (2006) Biological Control of Woolly Apple Aphid (Eriosoma lanigerum HAUSM.) with Aphelinus mali HALD.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 36-42.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13764/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>