<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Success of a participatory research and extension programme in the Dutch organic dairy goat sector</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eekeren, Nick van</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Govaerts, Wim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2004, most organic dairy goat farms had financial problems due to a gap between the milk price paid and the cost price on farm. In 2005, a research project “BIOGEIT” was started. In 2007, the research project was combined with an extension programme. A framework was set up with 3 shells. The first shell consisted of two farmer research groups in which goat keepers worked in close cooperation with researchers on a specific theme. One research group has worked constantly on cost price optimisation and milk price. One of the activities in the farmers research group on cost price was monitoring the cost price and milk price over the years. Its objective was threefold: determining priorities for cost price optimisation, using the cost price for milk price negotiations and monitoring the project results. The cost price inclusive labour costs evolved from 58.92 euro/100 l in 2004 to 65.24 /100 l in 2009. The milk price (7% fat and protein; exclusive tax) evolved from 51 euro/100 l in 2004 to approximately 70 euro/100 l in 2012. From the year 2009 onwards, the cost price is covered by the milk price.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21609/1/2640.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eekeren, Nick van and Govaerts, Wim    (2012) Success of a participatory research and extension programme in the Dutch organic dairy goat sector.       Paper at:   Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, 2nd OAHC, Hamburg/Trenthorst, Germany, Sep 12-14, 2012.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21609/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>