<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecological modernisation in the public catering sector. Danish experiences with use of organic food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper is part of the proceedings of an iPOPY seminar. The authors reflect on whether and how organic food in schools and kindergartens can be described as a part of an ecological modernization strategy in Denmark. They discuss how it has merged with more economically and technically approach in public catering policy. They discuss how it has merged with more economically and technically approaches in public catering policy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Noelting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15541/1/15541.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nielsen, Thorkild; Kristensen, Niels Heine and Mikkelsen, Bent E.    (2009) Ecological modernisation in the public catering sector. Danish experiences with use of organic food.   In: Noelting, Benjamin (Ed.)  Providing organic school food for youths in Europe - Policy strategies, certification and supply chain management in Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway. Proceedings of the iPOPY seminar held at the BioFach February 20th 2009 in Nuremberg, Germany, International Centre for Research in Organic Food Systems (ICROFS), CORE Organic Series Report, pp. 14-17.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15541/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>