<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions in organic and conventional farming systems in the Netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bos, J.F.F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Haan, J.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sukkel, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schils, R.L.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Results are presented of a model study comparing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions in organic and conventional farming systems in the Netherlands. Calculations have been performed for model farms, designed on the basis of current organic and conventional farming practices. Energy use and greenhouse gas emissions per hectare on organic farms are lower than on conventional farms, particularly in dairy farming. Energy use and greenhouse gas emissions per Mg of milk in organic dairy farming is about 80 and 90%, respectively of that in conventional dairy farming. Energy use and greenhouse gas emission per Mg product in organic crop production is 5-40 and 7-17%, respectively higher than in conventional systems. The wide ranges found in crop production reflect large differences among individual crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9961/1/Bos-etal-2007-EnergyGreenhouse.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bos, J.F.F.P.; de Haan, J.J.; Sukkel, W. and Schils, R.L.M.    (2007) Comparing energy use and greenhouse gas emissions in organic and conventional farming systems in the Netherlands.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9961/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>