<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Status Quo der Ökologischen Rinderhaltung in Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hörning, PD Dr. habil. Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simantke, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Christel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aubel, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Erhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersson, Prof. Dr. Robby</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A survey was carried out to get key features of the organic cattle production in Germany. Questionnaires were evaluated from 750 farms with dairy or beef-suckler cows. Furthermore, 101 farms were visited to get more detailed information in the fields of housing, feeding, breeding, health, economy. Dairy farms were more specialized than beef farms. 30 dairy cows respective 15 beef cows were kept on average per farm. Most dairy farmers hold the typical regional breeds. About 10 % kept old, endangered breeds. One third of dairy farmers had still stanchion barns, but less than 10 % of beef farmers. Main health problems on dairy farms were mastitis, claw or fertility disorders. Milk production averaged on 6.150 kg per cow and year. In many dairy farms, improvements are possible with regard to animal welfare, animal health or productivity. About one fifth of the milk and one third of the beef produced still had to be sold conventionally. Beef producers are dependent on subsidies.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3682/1/3682.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hörning, PD Dr. habil. Bernhard; Simantke, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Christel; Aubel, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Erhard and Andersson, Prof. Dr. Robby    (2005) Status Quo der Ökologischen Rinderhaltung in Deutschland.  [Status quo of organic cattle production in Germany.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3682/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>