<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Successful use of honeybees for grey mould (Botrytis cinerea) biocontrol on strawberries in Turkey</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eken, Cafer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tuncer, Serdar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kadıoğlu, Zakine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genc, Tuba</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Entomovector Technology is a novel application strategy using bees for the delivery of microbial control agents. This technology is an environmentally friendly control strategy against plant pathogens and pests that makes use of pollinators to vector powder formulations of plant protection products from the hive to the flowers and leaves of pest-infested crops and improves crop pollination resulting in increased yield and crop quality. In practice, a dispenser is attached to the hive and loaded with a powder formulation of the desired biological control agent. Biological control in organic agricultural systems is more friendly to the environment and more sustainable than the other farming systems. The study was performed to determine the efficacy of entomovector technology in suppression of grey mold (Botrytis cinerea) was tested in field conditions using Prestop Mix biopreparation (Clonostachys rosea f. catenulata J1446). The experiments were conducted on experimental fields of Erzincan Horticultural Research Station in Erzincan, Turkey in 2014. The experimental design was completely randomized with 4 repetitions. The frigo plants of ‘Aromas’ strawberry cultivars were used. Each plot (no cage and cage) consisted of 70 strawberry plants planted in an area of 3.30 m × 4 m. The number of diseased fruit of each plot was recorded. The number of diseased fruit was averagely 139 in the treatment of Clonostachys rosea f. catenulate J1446 treatment disseminated with Apis mellifera. On the other hand, the untreated plots were calculated 432 in the diseased fruit number. There were significant differences number of diseased fruit between treatments.BICOPOLL is the first application of the use of honey bees in entomovector technology in Turkey. Results have shown that Clonostachys rosea f. catenulate J1446 can be effectively delivered by honey bees for prevention of Botrytis cinerea infection in strawberry. This method has important significance in organic farming, biocontrol is an environmentally friendly approach to control the development of grey mold. The project BICOPOLL was founded by transnational CORE Organic II Funding Body within the FP7 ERA-Network.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Eken, Cafer; Tuncer, Serdar; Kadıoğlu, Zakine and Genc, Tuba    (2013) Successful use of honeybees for grey mould (Botrytis cinerea) biocontrol on strawberries in Turkey.       Paper at:   XVIII. International Plant Protection Congress , Berlin, Germany, 24-27 August 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28607/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>