<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diversity in measures against infection with avian influenza in organic poultry by different European countries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bestman, Msc M.W.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper describes how different European countries prescribe measures for farmers to reduce the risk of infection with avian influenza in poultry. These measures are for example the obliged indoor confinement during so-called risk periods ort the allowance to vaccinate against this virus infection. These measures have consequences for the organic poultry sector. It seems there is a large diversity between the different European countries concerning what prescriptions there are and especially the definitions of risk areas and risk periods seem to vary. The consequence in the Netherlands, for example, is that in 2007, approximately 95% of the organic laying hens were confined during nearly 5 months, while there was no single case of avian influenza within the Dutch borders. In most other European countries, only small numbers of farms in single risk areas had to keep their animals inside. This is not only a threat to animal welfare, it also does not fit in the ‘organic way’ of keeping animals and it is impossible to communicate this to the consumer who simply expects the animals to be outside.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12621/1/Paper_Isofar_2008_Bestman.dot</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bestman, Msc M.W.P.    (2008) Diversity in measures against infection with avian influenza in organic poultry by different European countries.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12621/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>