<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The process of researching animal health and welfare planning</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whistance, Lindsay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, Stephen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, Gidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>’Minimising medicine use in organic dairy herds through animal health and welfare planning’, ANIPLAN, is a CORE-Organic project which was initiated in June 2007. The main aim of the project is to investigate active and well planned animal health and welfare promotion and disease prevention as a means of minimising medicine use in organic dairy herds. This aim will be met through the development of animal health and welfare planning principles for organic dairy farms under diverse conditions based on an evaluation of current experiences. This also includes application of animal health and welfare assessment across Europe. In order to bring this into practice the project also aims at developing guidelines for communication about animal health and welfare promotion in different settings, for example, as part of existing animal health advisory services or farmer groups such as the Danish Stable School system and the Dutch network programme. The project is divided into the following five work packages, four of which comprise research activities with the other focused on coordination and knowledge transfer, through meetings, workshops and publications. &#xD;
&#xD;
The content of this set of workshop proceedings reflects the fact that the workshop in Fokhol in Norway was held at a relatively early stage with regard to certain joint activities and methodological development. Training in animal welfare assessment had taken place for the first time in the project a couple of months previous to this workshop, and the results in terms of inter-observer reliability are presented by the organisers of this training workshop, Solveig March, Lisi Gratzer and Jan Brinkmann and their supervisor Christoph Winckler. This forms a good background for a reliable data collection in all countries. A presentation from a newly employed Ph.D. student linked to the ANIPLAN project, Lindsay Kay Whistance, gives insight into the study of defecation behaviour in dairy cattle. Although not directly part of the ANIPLAN studies, the presentation is particularly relevant to the considerations regarding animal welfare in housed and outdoor systems. Gidi Smolders from the Netherlands presented a paper about a Dutch farmer group initiative with a strong element of farmer ownership. Mette Vaarst contributes with a paper on farmer learning and empowerment in groups, with a background of Danish experiences with the so-called ‘Stable Schools’. Two papers by Roderick and Vaarst reflect the workshop discussions about research methodologies and the various contexts and conditions for farmer group work. These two papers demonstrate the complexity of the research requirements when conducting a trans-national and cross-disciplinary research project with many stakeholders.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Vaarst, Mette</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Roderick, Stephen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15692/1/15692.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>March, Solveig; Brinkmann, Jan; Winckler, Christoph; Whistance, Lindsay; Roderick, Stephen; Vaarst, Mette and Smolders, Gidi     (editor): Vaarst, Mette and Roderick, Stephen (Eds.)    (2009) The process of researching animal health and welfare planning.   CORE Organic Project Series. Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, Department og Animal Health, Welfare and Nutrition.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15692/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>