<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming in Wales 2003 - 2004</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Sue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Green, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hitchings, Roger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jedwell, Andrew</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kennard, Bob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Little, Tony</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McCalman, Heather</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pearson, Neil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Powell, Jane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rowlands, Gareth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiller, Gary</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Huw</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wacher, Carolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weller, Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic Centre Wales (OCW) was originally formed to act as an information source for producers enquiring into organic farming; in our second phase, in response to changes in the sector, we have an increased remit on policy issues. It has been a busy time, seeing the production of a second Organic Action Plan, the implementation of the CAP reform and development work on agri-environment reforms. The year also saw the start of organic maintenance payments for farmers.&#xD;
&#xD;
This Annual Report contains accounts of the progress that has been made on many fronts during the last 12 months, particularly in market knowledge due to the research for the recently published report, 'Organic Food: understanding the consumer and increasing sales'. This information, together with continuing product development work, will enable Welsh organic producers to be proactive in building a solid consumer base.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10816/1/annrepeng04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10816/2/annrep04cym.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fowler, Sue; Green, Michael; Hitchings, Roger; Jedwell, Andrew; Kennard, Bob; Little, Tony; McCalman, Heather; Pearson, Neil; Powell, Jane; Rowlands, Gareth; Spiller, Gary; Thomas, Huw; Wacher, Carolyn and Weller, Richard         (2004) Organic Farming in Wales 2003 - 2004.    Organic Centre Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10816/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>