<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 2. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LowInputBreeds Consortium,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This edition of the LowInputBreeds Newsletter provides brief state-of-the-arts reports on two themes within the project: the concept of flower breeding in pigs and the state and alternative breeding approaches in laying hens. There are also brief progress reports for the four subprojects which focus on the major livestock production systems. We would also like to draw your attention to the LowInputBreeds workshop ‘Economic, Environmental and Food Quality Assessment of LowInput Production Schemes – Consumer Standards and Demands’ to take place on May 26, 2010, in Brussels.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24642/1/LowInputBreeds-Newsletter-no-2-2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LowInputBreeds Consortium,     (2010) Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 2. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24642/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>