<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of automated tools based on electronic identification for the improvement of organic livestock production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>MATON, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MONTAGNAC, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>VIUDES, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BOUCQUET, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BOCQUIER, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Technical constraints of livestock production in organic farming systems are numerous and require more attention than in conventional systems. The implementation of individual electronic identification that is planned in Europe offers the possibility of developing automated devices that may be well adapted to the practices of organic breeders. We developed an automated mounting detector, carried by a male, which makes it possible to detect any female in oestrus. Hence, this device is the unique solution for inseminating females when they are fertile, thus ensuring links with selection programmes. The second&#xD;
device developed is a dynamic sorting door based on respect for animal behaviour, preventing stress by allowing animals not to be unnecessarily confined. When associated with an electronic weighing device, it offers the possibility of adapting health treatments to the appropriate animals, in agreement with organic breeding specifications. Finally, electronic identification combined with GPS offers the breeder the possibility of simplifying the certification of animals in areas converted to organic farming. We believe that these technologies may greatly reduce the workload of breeders while improving animal welfare.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15466/1/11-Maton.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>MATON, C. ; MONTAGNAC, D. ; VIUDES, G. ; BOUCQUET, P.  and BOCQUIER, F.    (2009) Development of automated tools based on electronic identification for the improvement of organic livestock production systems.  [Les applications de l’identification électronique des petits ruminants au service de l’élevage biologique.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 67-71.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15466/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>