<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Significant decrease in yield under future climate conditions: Stabilityand production of 138 spring barley accessions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ingvordsen, Cathrine Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Backes, Gunter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lyngkjær, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peltonen-Sainio, Pirjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Jens D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jalli, Marja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahoor, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Morten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Tesi N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stockmarr, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Rikke Bagger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>tThe response in production parameters to projected future levels of temperature, atmospheric carbondioxide ([CO2]), and ozone ([O3]) was investigated in 138 spring barley accessions. The comprehensive setof landraces, cultivars, and breeder-lines, were during their entire life cycle exposed to a two-factor treat-ment of combined elevated temperature (+5°C day/night) and [CO2] (700 ppm), as well as single-factortreatments of elevated temperature (+5°C day/night), [CO2] (700 ppm), and [O3] (100–150 ppb). Thecontrol treatment was equivalent to present average South Scandinavian climate (temperature: 19/12◦C(day/night), [CO2]: 385 ppm). Overall grain yield was found to decrease 29% in the two-factor treatmentwith concurrent elevation of [CO2] and temperature, and this response could not be predicted from theresults of treatments with elevated [CO2] and temperature as single factors, where grain yield increased16% and decreased 56%, respectively. Elevated [O3] was found to decrease grain yield by 15%. Substantialvariation in response to the applied climate treatments was found between the accessions. The resultsrevealed landraces, cultivars, and breeder-lines with phenotypes applicable for breeding towards stableand high yield under future climate conditions. Further, we suggest identifying resources for breedingunder multifactor climate conditions, as single-factor treatments did not accurately forecast the response,when factors were combined.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28030/7/28030.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ingvordsen, Cathrine Heinz ; Backes, Gunter; Lyngkjær, M.; Peltonen-Sainio, Pirjo; Jensen, Jens D.; Jalli, Marja; Jahoor, Ahmed; Rasmussen, Morten; Mikkelsen, Tesi N.; Stockmarr, A. and Jørgensen, Rikke Bagger   (2015) Significant decrease in yield under future climate conditions: Stabilityand production of 138 spring barley accessions.   European Journal of Agronomy, 63, pp. 105-113.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28030/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>