<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Forage feeding value of continuous grazed sward on organic permanent grassland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohrer, Hannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Continuous grazing provides low-cost forage with a high feeding value for milk and beef production and is a suitable pasture system in organic farming. To assess the forage feeding value of continuously grazed sward, a 3-field trial was carried out under harsh east Alpine conditions (680 m altitude, 7°C average temperature, 1000 mm annual precipitation). Forage contents of net energy (6.3-7.0 MJ NEL kg-1 DM) and crude protein (202-236 g kg-1 DM) varied on a high level during the vegetation period. Moreover, amounts of crude fibre (176-243 g kg-1 DM) and neutral detergent fibre (373-475 g kg-1 DM) were within the recommended range for ruminates. In conclusion, continuous grazing as a possible organic grassland use under harsh climate conditions can be recommended.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organising Committee of the 16th Symposium of the EGF 2011 and Agricultural Research and Education Centre (AREC) Raumberg-Gumpenstein 8952 Irdning, Austria</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19342/1/Forage_feeding_value_of_continuous_grazed_sward_on_organic_permanent_grassland.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19342/4/Forage_feeding_value.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Starz, Walter; Steinwidder, Andreas; Pfister, Rupert and Rohrer, Hannes    (2011) Forage feeding value of continuous grazed sward on organic permanent grassland.   In:     Grassland Farming and Land Management Systems in Mountainous Regions. Proceedings of the 16th Symposium of the European Grassland Federation, Organising Committee of the 16th Symposium of the EGF 2011 and Agricultural Research and Education Centre (AREC) Raumberg-Gumpenstein 8952 Irdning, Austria, Grassland Science in Europe, no. 16, pp. 356-358.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19342/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>