<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Verkaufsförderung und Zielgruppen für Öko-Ziegenlammfleisch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heid, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>While organic goat milk products are becoming increasingly popular in Germany, marketing of kid meat is difficult as it is an unfamiliar product for consumers and there are hardly any marketing structures besides direct marketing. In order to introduce organic kid meat to consumers, we conducted sales promotions offering product samples. An accompanying consumer survey provided data on potential customer groups for organic kid meat. Participants’ sensory evaluations of the sampled meat were very positive as well as their perceptions of other product attributes. Stated likeliness to buy kid meat was high. Significant differences between potential buyers and non-buyers could be identified regarding their age and consumption of organic food. Also reasons for buying organic meat differed between the groups. Offering product samples can improve consumers’ perceptions of kid meat and may increase willingness to buy. Specific characteristics of potential buyers offer opportunities for targeted communication efforts which should emphasize animal welfare, taste and health aspects of organic kid meat.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21282/1/21282_Heid.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heid, Astrid and Hamm, Ulrich    (2013) Verkaufsförderung und Zielgruppen für Öko-Ziegenlammfleisch.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21282/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>