<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Workshop on quality and nutrition value of organic milk and meat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, Håvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sakowski, Tomasz</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The workshop was arranged at the Institute of Genetics and Animal Breeding PAS in Jastrzębiec (IGAB), Poland, 19.-20. November 2009. The aim of the workshop was to encourage cooperation between Norwegian and Polish scientists specialized in organic animal breeding and organic milk and meat production. The organic market in Europe is growing annually from 2 to 15% depending on a country. Establishing scientific contacts with Norwegian researchers will positively influence the development of Polish organic scientific sector, which will transfer further the obtained knowledge and experience direct to the farmers. The workshop enabled Norwegian scientists to establish contacts with scientists from Poland and from other Central-European countries. The agenda of the meeting took into account the discussion on challenges and scientific ideas together with German, Austrian and Czech scientists. The workshop allowed presentation of contemporary organic breeding and production strategies for optimizing production methods in achieving high quality of organic milk and meat with high nutritive value for consumer. The presentations are available at the website: http://www.ighz.edu.pl/?p0=4&amp;p1=32&amp;p2=134&amp;p3=135&#xD;
During the second day of the workshop, the participants worked together and made outlines of future cooperation based on the presentations given on the first day. &#xD;
&#xD;
The workshop was funded by the Polish-Norweagian Research Fund (PNRF 284–A II– 2/08)</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-11-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17307/1/Minutes_PNRF_20.11.2009_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinshamn, Håvard and Sakowski, Tomasz    (2009) Workshop on quality and nutrition value of organic milk and meat.   Polish Academy of Scieneces, Institute of Genetics and Animal Breeding .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>