<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The use of genetically modified organisms from the perspective of organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kuchtová, Perla</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming uses methods of saving the environment and its components through restrictions or bans on the use of substances and procedures burdening and polluting the environment and increasing the risk of contamination of the food chain. Organic farming cares about welfare of farm animals. The principle of this alternative to industrial agriculture implies an effort to choose ethical approeches rather than economic terms, to respect the intrinsic value of nature (both animate and inanimate), save it and ignore it as a source of raw materials to meet the growing demands of man only. By definition, organic farming diverges from philosophy of patented living organisms, in the form of transgenic crops whose dissemination would further contribute to the loss of biodiversity and increased risks, including food security and access to food for vulnerable groups of people in society.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Česká společnost experimentální biologie rostlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-01-13</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21850/1/bulletin.PDF.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kuchtová, Perla    (2009) The use of genetically modified organisms from the perspective of organic farming.  [Využívání geneticky modifikovaných organismů z pohledu ekologického zemědělství.]  In:     Bulletin České společnosti experimentální biologie rostlin a Fyziologické sekce Slovenské botanické společnosti, Česká společnost experimentální biologie rostlin, Jinonická 80, Praha 5, 2009 (1), no. MK ČR E 13255, pp. 14-25.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21850/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>