<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wheat trials networks for determining characters for organic breeding</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rolland, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Al Rifai, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bataillon, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fontaine, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gardet, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oury, F. X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objectives of the French national institute of agronomy (INRA) cereals programme are to evaluate genetic material from breeding programmes for low input systems (high disease and lodging resistance, low seeding rate, good response to low level of nutrients, standard quality) including organic conditions.&#xD;
The aim of the study is to define important agronomic characteristics of cultivar adapted to organic farming. Despite some relation with agronomical performances in low input system, weeds competitiveness, productivity and baking quality are specific in organic farming. Productivity and baking quality are linked to nutrient acquisition ability: nitrogen uptake and nitrogen-use-efficiency. The selection of new lines based on weed competition and N efficiency is necessary. Thus, we define an index selection method.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12819/1/Rolland_12819_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rolland, B.; Al Rifai, M.; Bataillon, P.; Fontaine, L.; Gardet, O. and Oury, F. X.    (2008) Wheat trials networks for determining characters for organic breeding.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12819/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>