<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Oekobilanz-Vergleich von intensivem und extensivem Rindfleischproduktionsverfahren: Fallstudie anhand zweier Fallbeispiele</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Chassot, Dr. André</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Philipp, Anita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaillard, Dr. Gérard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The environmental impact of two contrasting beef production systems was determined by life cycle assessment (LCA). An extensive fattening system of Limousine x Simmental crossbred steers based on grass (EXT) was compared to an intensive fattening system of Simmental bulls (INT). The environmental impacts of EXT were similar or lower than those of INT. The largest differences were found in toxic effects on aquatic and terrestrial ecosystems. The amount and type of fertilizers used to produce the feed were the main source of difference between the systems. For all other environmental impacts however, there were no marked differences. It is concluded that the extensive use of grasslands for beef production has the potential to reduce the environmental impacts per kg of carcass.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3353/1/3353.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Chassot, Dr. André; Philipp, Anita and Gaillard, Dr. Gérard    (2005) Oekobilanz-Vergleich von intensivem und extensivem Rindfleischproduktionsverfahren: Fallstudie anhand zweier Fallbeispiele.  [Life cycle assessment (LCA) of two beef production systems.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3353/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>