<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How does consumer behaviour change? Examples from energy conservation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heiskanen, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnson, Mikael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saastamoinen, Mika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vadovics, Edina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A global consumer society is rapidly overshooting ecological limits, there is a dire need to find new ways to change consumer behaviour. Yet history knows few succesful examples of reducing consumption. However, since the 1970s, there is a long legacy of work on energy conservation, which we use to identify three key factors that influence consumer behaviour: consumer awareness, contextual factors and community. Drawing on evidence from a European research project called CHANGING BEHAVIOUR, we discuss where previous efforts to change energy behaviour have succeeded in making a difference. We highlight ways in which sociotechnical systems shaping consumption can be changed and emerging ways in which consumers can join forces to achieve greater power and reach. This analysis has implications for attempts to build a more sustainable consumer society, including, but not limited to, the need to reduce primary energy consumption and greenhouse gas emissions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16425/1/consumer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heiskanen, Eva; Johnson, Mikael; Saastamoinen, Mika and Vadovics, Edina    (2009) How does consumer behaviour change? Examples from energy conservation.   In:     FFRC eBOOK (7/2009), FFRC eBOOK, pp. 287-294.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16425/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>