<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The importance of amino-N for humus formation studied by comparing amino-N input to the soil and soil total nitrogen content in long-term experiments</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schuler, Christiana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raupp, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>George, Eckhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Humus formation is thought to depend directly on carbon input. Referring to earlier studies we tested the role of amino-bound nitrogen (amino-N) input to the soil using data of 10 long-term experiments with different fertilization and crop rotation treatments. In 8 out of the 10 experiments there was a significant positive correlation between the amino-N input and soil total N content. This correlation was much stronger than the one of total N input and soil N content, indicating that amino-N was more important for soil N accumulation than total N input. Amino-N from farmyard manure seems to be more effective in this respect than amino-N from other organic fertilizers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11910/1/Schuler_11910_ed%5B1%5D.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schuler, Christiana; Raupp, Joachim and George, Eckhard    (2008) The importance of amino-N for humus formation studied by comparing amino-N input to the soil and soil total nitrogen content in long-term experiments.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11910/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>