<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economic simulation of organic farms guided by farmers - A participatory approach to agricultural policy research?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häring, A. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this paper is to introduce, based on own practical experiences, an approach to agricultural policy research that is based on intensive interaction with groups of farmers, and to discuss to which extent participation is realised in this process. This approach consists of panels of farmers, scientists and agricultural advisors. In group meetings development strategies of typical organic farms and the farms reaction to changes in the policy environment are discussed on a regular base. Farmers are consulted on their opinion and define potential farm development strategies in a cooperative manner, whereas the scientist analyses data. The potentials of this cooperative approach of consultation are discussed in the light of research objectives and the benefits and input requirements of participants.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FAO, Rome</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2364/1/Kein-Dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häring, A. M.    (2000) Economic simulation of organic farms guided by farmers - A participatory approach to agricultural policy research?   In:     Proceedings of the 2nd SREN Workshop on “Research Methodologies in Organic Farming - On-farm &amp; Participatory Research”, FAO, Rome, REU Technical Series, no. 63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2364/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>