<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studies of the availability of soil phosphorus (P) and potassium (K) in organic farming systems, and of plant adaptations to low P- and K-availability</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming systems, the purchase of nutrients is firmly restricted as compared to conventional farming systems. This will often cause a negative nutrient budget on the field level, especially in cases with low animal density, where more nutrients are removed in yields than are applied in fertilisers. Studies on five organic dairy farms in Southern Norway, that were aiming at self-sufficiency,revealed that the concentrations of ammonium-acetate lactate (AL) soluble phosphorus (P) had decreased with time. The farms had been organically managed since 1986 or earlier. It was found that the higher the initial P-AL concentration,the greater was the decrease that occurred, calculated per year. Out of 156 topsoil samples,only 6 had low P-AL values (&lt; 25 mg P kg-1 soil) at the second soil sampling. Nevertheless, in the long run, a supply of P will be required in organic farming systems. For potassium (K), no corresponding decrease in K-AL was found, but for this nutrient a considerable proportion of the cultivated land had low concentrations (&lt; 65 mg K kg-1 soil) on all farms. The concentrations of acidsoluble K were also low to medium. With soil that does not have a high ability to replace K taken up by plants, a supply of K will be required in organic farming systems. Hence, the development of nutrient supplies that may fulfil the standards of organic farming is very important. Furthermore, organic farmers must strive even harder than their conventional colleagues to reduce nutrient losses caused by for example erosion or during animal manure storage and spreading.&#xD;
&#xD;
A basic principle in organic farming is the cycling of nutrients within the farming system. With low animal density, plant material may be used as&#xD;
manure (green manure or mulching). The fate of P, K and nitrogen (N) was studied when chopped plant material was used as a mulch in vegetable growing. Application of 9-10 tonnes plant dry matter (DM) ha-1 increased vegetable yields by 26% in the year of application, and grain yields were increased by 0.6 tonne ha-1 in the subsequent year. However, when the nutrient uptake in non-mulched plants was subtracted, only 15-20% of the N, P and K applied in mulch was recovered by the vegetable crops.&#xD;
&#xD;
Much of the N was probably lost by leaching or gaseous losses, whereas most of the surplus P and K were recovered in soil. The mulch-method is suited for relatively small farms with low animal density where there is no capacity to use all the farmland for vegetables. About 2/3 of the land should be used for mulch production, and 1/3 devoted to vegetables. A systematic crop rotation must be used to avoid an uneven distribution of&#xD;
nutrients within the farm. &#xD;
&#xD;
Studies in low-P growing media have shown that plants may react to low P supply by adaptations such as increased root-shoot ratio, relatively longer and thinner roots or longer root hairs. Plants have a remarkable ability to adapt tochanges in environmental conditions, such as a variable nutrient supply. In order to assess whether such daptations might be useful for organic farming systems, this topic was studied by growing accessions of spring wheat and barley released during the period 1900-2000, in the field at both optimum and limited nutrient supply, as well as in the laboratory in low-P utrient solution, where root traits were recorded. Nutrient uptake and grain yields varied significantly, but the relations between nutrient uptake and root traits were weak. Modern accessions produced higher yields than older ones, mostly because they had a higher harvest index and were more resistant to fungal disease.In cereal breeding, root traits should be recorded and the root length is important. As no significant differences in SRL were found among barley or wheat accessions in our study, I suggest that root characterisation may be simplified by estimating root length from the root weight and an appropriate value for the specific root length (SRL, m root g-1 root DM). Measuring SRL is very tedious.&#xD;
&#xD;
Most studies that have shown large effects in root or root hair growth, as a consequence of low P supply, have either not confirmed the obtained results under a controlled nvironment in the field, or the plants were not grown to maturity. Commonly, the P oncentration in such studies has been below a level that is relevant for practical farming. Such low levels would most probably have led to crop failure in the field. My studies indicate that root morphological adaptations to low P concentrations in soil are of theoretical interest, as they demonstrate the ability of plants to survive in contrasting environments. However, for the conditions found in agricultural soil within the Nordic countries, such adaptations probably have little significance.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Department of Soil and Water Sciences, Agricultural  University of Norway, P.O.Box 5028, N-1432 Ås</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/1/PhD_thesis_AnneKristin_Loes_2003.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/2/Paper_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/3/Paper_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/4/Paper_3.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/5/Paper_4.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7424/6/Paper_5.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin   (2003) Studies of the availability of soil phosphorus (P) and potassium (K) in organic farming systems, and of plant adaptations to low P- and K-availability.  [Undersøkelser av tilgjengeligheten av P og K i jorda i økologiske dyrkingssystemer, og av planters tilpasning til lav tilgjengelighet av disse næringsstoffene.]  Thesis, Agricultural University of Norway, Department of Soil and Water Sciences. Doctor Scientiarum Thesis, no. 2003: 29. Department of Soil and Water Sciences, Agricultural University of Norway, P.O.Box 5028, N-1432 Ås.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7424/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>