<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Discrimination of conventional and organic white cabbage from a long-term field trial study using untargeted LC-MS-based metabolomics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mie, Axel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, Kristian Holst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aberg, K Magnus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forshed, Jenny</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindahl, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olsson, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knuthsen, Pia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Erik Huusfeldt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The influence of organic and conventional farming practices on the content of single nutrients in plants is disputed in the scientific literature. Here, large-scale untargeted LC-MS-based metabolomics was used to compare the composition of white cabbage from organic and conventional agriculture, measuring 1,600 compounds. Cabbage was sampled in 2 years from one conventional and two organic farming systems in a rigidly controlled long-term field trial in Denmark. Using Orthogonal Projection to Latent Structures-Discriminant Analysis (OPLS-DA), we found that the production system leaves a significant (p = 0.013) imprint in the white cabbage metabolome that is retained between production years. We externally validated this finding by predicting the production system of samples from one year using a classification model built on samples from the other year, with a correct classification in 83 % of cases. Thus, it was concluded that the investigated conventional and organic management practices have a systematic impact on the metabolome of white cabbage. This emphasizes the potential of untargeted metabolomics for authenticity testing of organic plant products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25578/1/Mie%202014%20Discrimination%20of%20conventional%20and%20organic%20white%20cabbage%20froma%20long-term%20field%20trial%20study%20using%20untargeted%20LC-MS-based%20metabolomics.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mie, Axel; Laursen, Kristian Holst; Aberg, K Magnus; Forshed, Jenny; Lindahl, Anna; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Olsson, Marie; Knuthsen, Pia; Larsen, Erik Huusfeldt and Husted, Søren   (2014) Discrimination of conventional and organic white cabbage from a long-term field trial study using untargeted LC-MS-based metabolomics.   Analytical and bioanalytical chemistry, 406, pp. 1-13.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25578/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>