<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Parameters for apple quality and an outline for a new concept of quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Machteld</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. The commonly used concept of quality in relation to food, with its  emphasis on external appearance and nutritional content is not sufficient  for organic products and their market. In response a quality concept  known as ‘vital quality’ has been developed based on the life processes  (growth and differentiation) and corresponding product attributes (vitality,  structure and coherence). The research project presented is based on the  evaluation of the quality of apples, specifically cultivated for the research  project with variation in picking date, bearing, sun exposure, bio-dynamic  preparations and ageing after storage. Quality measurements included  traditional methods used routinely to assess apple quality and also  experimental parameters which are expected to be relevant for vital  quality. The experimental parameters appeared to supplement the  traditional parameters in a consideration of quality. The concept of ‘vital  quality’ is a valuable one for the consideration of wider aspects of quality  within organic farming systems and should be further developed</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8365/1/Huber_Parameters_apple_quality.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huber, Machteld    (2002) Parameters for apple quality and an outline for a new concept of quality.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 69-74.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8365/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>