<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 5. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LowInputBreeds Consortium,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With this newsletter we are informing our readers about progress made in the subprojects of the LowInputBreeds project.&#xD;
Our thematic article in this issue by Ferry Leenstra and Veronika Maurer explains the difference of free range and organic poultry farms and farmers.&#xD;
We would particularly like to draw your attention to the 1st article on page 2 about the next LowInputBreeds symposium which takes place from May 15 to 18 2012 in Tunisia – this is an ideal opportunity to share findings from the project and we would like to encourage all partners to submit an abstract.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24645/1/LowInputBreeds-Newsletter-no-5-2011.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LowInputBreeds Consortium,     (2011) Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 5. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24645/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>