<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genotype and environment interaction on yield and quality parameters of organically grown winter wheat – Triticum aestivum L. genotypes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dashbaljir, Ichinkhorloo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Liebhard, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loeschenberger, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weinhappel, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The interaction of genotype and environment upon yield and quality parameters of eight winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) genotypes was studied under organic conditions in Austria over two growing periods, 2001/2002 and 2002/2003, respectively. Two sites that have significantly different climatic conditions, Innviertel and Marchfeld, were chosen for the field experiment. &#xD;
Study site weather and soil conditions are important yield-affecting factors. Although the yield of Marchfeld-grown genotypes were lower, they had shown higher quality parameter values. Soil moisture conditions increase the grain yield but decrease its quality. To obtain seed with higher quality, a production site with favourable climate conditions should be chosen.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4376/4/4376-Dashbaljir_etal_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dashbaljir, Ichinkhorloo; Liebhard, P.; Hartl, W.; Loeschenberger, F. and Weinhappel, M.    (2005) Genotype and environment interaction on yield and quality parameters of organically grown winter wheat – Triticum aestivum L. genotypes.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4376/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>