<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Research to support development of organic food and farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Erik Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agriculture and organic agriculture in particular are developing rapidly, due not only to technological change but also to changes in agricultural policy and public expectation. Research allows new knowledge to be developed and is thus vital for the future of organic agriculture. We can ask the question, what is the purpose of research on organic farming? Is it to increase yield and productivity, to compare it with other forms of agriculture, or to quantify its environmental and social impact, minimise the adverse effects and maximise the benefits etc? The answer is of course that research has a role to play in all of these and many other aspects of developing the organic food chain. The precise purpose of the research is usually defined by the funder, and may differ with whether the funder is from the public or private sector. In this chapter we look briefly at the development of organic research through both the public and private sector and go on to explore some of the issues that surround research on organic agriculture in terms of approaches and appropriate methodologies. We also explore the extent to which organic and conventional agriculture require different research and different approaches to research.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CSIRO Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Kristiansen, Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Taji, Acram</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reganold, John</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6280/1/Watson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Watson, Christine; Alrøe, Hugo and Kristensen, Erik Steen    (2006) Research to support development of organic food and farming.    In: Kristiansen, Paul; Taji, Acram and Reganold, John (Eds.)   Organic Agriculture - A Global Perspective.  CSIRO Publishing, chapter 15, pp. 361-383.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6280/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>