<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The future policy environment of organic farming and ist impact on the economic performance against the background of the ongoing trade liberalisation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since the early 1990, organic farming has experienced a rapid growth in Europe due to increased consumer awareness towards organic products and various policy support measures. In particular, organic farming schemes based on the agri-environmental regulation (2078/92) and the rural development regulation (1257/1999) offer financial compensation for a lower income and support for marketing and processing activities (Lampkin et al., 1999).&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic farming policies as part of the general CAP are increasingly affected by the liberalisation of agricultural markets. Trade liberalisation takes place at three different areas: first, free-trade zones are established or extended (such as the EC); second, bilateral agreements facilitate trade between countries; and third, at global level, a further reduction of trade barriers are achieved through the WO talks. As a result of the liberalisation policies, competition on the supply side increases, producer prices drop down and state impact on markets are reduced. Regarding organic farming policies, liberalisation will lead to a greater harmonisation of support measures as well as production and processing standards. In the light of the ongoing WTO talks, it is expected that agri-environmental programmes will become stronger related to desired positive effects and less trade-distortive.&#xD;
&#xD;
Due to the increased economic pressure in the organic farming sector, it will be crucial for many farmers to maximise their income through environmental services, marketing activities and improved quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Sarapatka,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3251/1/sanders-2004-lednice.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sanders, Jürn    (2004) The future policy environment of organic farming and ist impact on the economic performance against the background of the ongoing trade liberalisation.   In: Sarapatka,  (Ed.)  Proceedings, p. 62.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3251/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>