<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of organic farming in Central and Eastern European countries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hrabalova, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wollmuthova, Pavla</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The total organic area in the eight examined Central and Eastern European countries (CEECs) increased to 907,900 ha and represented 2.73% of the utilised agricultural area (UAA) in 2005. This corresponds to an annual growth rate of 23.13%. However, the area of fodder crops represented over 65% of this increase. Estonia and the Czech Republic have the highest share (over 7%) in total organic area of UAA. At the same time these countries have seen a steady decrease of in-conversion area, which limits the potential for further growth. In the organic production structure, grassland and the production of fodder have become the main organic crop areas, mainly in Slovenia, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Estonia and Latvia. In relation to organic livestock, beef production dominated with 67% in total CEECs organic livestock units, followed by dairy and sheep production with 14% and 8%, respectively, in 2005. Overall, sheep are the most popular species in nearly all CEECs when shares in total production are compared. Despite the rapid growth of organic farming (OF) in CEECs in recent years, the current arrangement of organic production can be noticed as one of many factors hindering the development of the organic food market and diversification of supplies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12045/1/Hrabalova_12045_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hrabalova, Andrea and Wollmuthova, Pavla    (2008) Development of organic farming in Central and Eastern European countries.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12045/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>