<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Risk and Risk Management in Organic and Conventional Cash Crop Farming in Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koesling, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ebbesvik, Martha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lien, Gudbrand</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flaten, Ola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valle, Paul Steinar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arntzen, Halvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study presents empirical insight into organic and conventional cash crop farmers' perceptions of risk and risk management strategies, and identifies socio-economic variables linked to these perceptions. The data originate from a questionnaire survey of farmers in Norway. The results indicate that organic farmers perceived themselves to be less risk averse than conventional farmers. For both groups, crop prices and yield variability were the two top rated sources of risk, followed by institutional risks. The two groups evaluated risk management strategies quite similarly; favoured strategies were good liquidity and to prevent and reduce crop diseases and pests. The farmers' evaluation of sources of risk and choice of risk strategies depended on various socio-economic variables. The importance of institutional risks implies that policy makers should be cautious about changing policy capriciously and they should consider strategic policy initiatives that give farmers more long-term reliability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Lund, Mogens</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6541/1/Risk_and_R_Managem_Koesling_et_al_2004.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koesling, Matthias; Ebbesvik, Martha; Lien, Gudbrand; Flaten, Ola; Valle, Paul Steinar and Arntzen, Halvard   (2004) Risk and Risk Management in Organic and Conventional Cash Crop Farming in Norway.   Acta Agriculturæ Scandinavica Section C - Food Economics, 1 (4), pp. 195-206.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6541/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>