<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau (BOEL): Zertifizierung/ Kontrolle</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Federal Organic Farming Scheme (FOFS: This scheme is a temporary funding source (2002 – 2007/2008) especially to support the whole organic farming sector (incl. research) in Germany.  In the summer of 2001, the Federal Ministry of Consumer Protection, Food and Agriculture commissioned a project team comprised of representatives from associations and science and headed by the Federal Agricultural Research Centre to develop a proposal for a package of measures to foster organic farming in Germany. A hearing of representatives from trade and industry, associations, consultancy, science and administration laid the foundation for the team's work.&#xD;
Based on this work, the Federal Minister of Consumer Protection, Food and Agriculture Renate Künast decided to incorporate the proposed measures into the Federal Organic Farming Scheme (FOFS) to translate them into practice. This scheme supplements existing support measures with the aim of improving the basic conditions necessary for expanding organic farming. At the same time, it strives to increase supply and demand on a balanced, sustainable basis.These measures tackle all levels of organic farming, from the production to the consumption of organically produced food. Plans include training and information measures. Emphasis is also being placed on research promotion, the development of new technologies and steps to translate research findings into practice. Currently the FOFS is the main pool of the BMVEL for organic research funding.&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Values, standards and certification &#xD;
Twenty-one projects are assigned to this category, consisting of projects concerned with decision support for certification agencies to comply with the GMO prohibition or decision guidance for processors and traders to minimise the risk of GMO blending into the production process. The introduction of a quality management system, as well as databank technical requirements for the development of a trace back system, are current projects considering actual needs. Information supply about organic products without GMO is realised through a handbook for practitioners. Further internet pages have been established presenting overviews about certified companies or judicial laws relevant for import and export countries. Several projects are concerned with the development of methods to verify organic products like eggs and salmon. Others are dealing with the establishment of evaluation systems for approval of technical ingredients, food additives and auxiliary substances, as well as risk management for plant protection residues.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Research Programme description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{ Programme part}       BÖL: Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau (BOEL): Zertifizierung/ Kontrolle.  [Federal Organic Farming Scheme (FOFS): Certification / Inspection.]   Runs 2002 - 2008.    Programme Leader(s): Lange, Stefan.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5972/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>