<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Symbiotic N2 fixation by soybean in organic and conventional&#xD;
cropping systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nanzer, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bosshard, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, Davie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic cropping systems nitrogen (N) often limits agricultural production. N2 fixing&#xD;
crops present an important option to improve N supply and to maintain soil fertility. We&#xD;
investigated N2 fixation of soybean in conventional and organic cropping systems. The&#xD;
study was carried out on a long term field experiment, characterized by unequal&#xD;
fertilization rates and soil microbial activity for the different systems. We assessed the&#xD;
proportion of N derived from atmosphere (Ndfa) and the total amount of N&#xD;
symbiotically fixed (Nfix) using the 15N natural abundance method. Ndfa for soybean&#xD;
was low, ranging from 24 to 54%. The lowest Ndfa was reported for the exclusively&#xD;
mineral fertilized, and the highest for the bio-organic cropping system. However, there&#xD;
were no differences between the farming systems in total amount of N symbiotically&#xD;
fixed. Irrespective of the cropping system, N withdrawal by harvest was higher than N&#xD;
input by N2 fixation, meaning that soil N stock was not preserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14124/1/Nanzer_14124.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nanzer, Simone; Frossard, Emmanuel; Bosshard, Christine; Dubois, Davie; Mäder, Paul and Oberson, Astrid    (2009) Symbiotic N2 fixation by soybean in organic and conventional cropping systems.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14124/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>