<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exchangeable potassium in soil as indicator of potassium status in an organic crop rotation on loamy sand.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic agriculture, where K may be a limited resource, reliable tools are important in the assessment of K availability in the soil in order to avoid K deficiency.  We investigated the effect of four organic farming systems on the exchangeable K in the plough layer of a six-course crop rotation from 1994 to 1997. The accumulated K balances over the four years varied between &#xD;
-49 and  +120 kg K ha-1 and the corresponding exchangeable K (0-20 cm) in autumn 1997 was 7.1 and 9.6 mg K 100 g soil-1, respectively, as an average of the crop rotation. The exchangeable K fraction responded to the K application in manure and to the crop in the rotation. In an additional experiment, no yield response to K was found, despite a low level of exchangeable K. The exchangeable K was a useful indicator of changes in the K status in the farming system with the largest positive K balance whereas this K fraction was insufficient as an indicator in the other three farming systems. The considerable variation of exchangeable K through the crop rotation makes the soil test method most suitable at the crop rotation level where fluctuations caused by crop and management are smoothed out.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/391/1/AE2002.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Askegaard, Margrethe and Eriksen, Jørgen   (2002) Exchangeable potassium in soil as indicator of potassium status in an organic crop rotation on loamy sand.   Soil Use and Management, 18, pp. 84-90.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/391/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>