<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>BioConcens: Biomass and bioenergy production agriculture – consequences for soil fertility, environment, spread of animal parasites and socio-economy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oleskowicz-Popiel, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ambus, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carter, M.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauggaard-Nielsen, H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johansen, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, U</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, A.M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, H.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, L.H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roepstorff, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skytte, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidt, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, A.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, M.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, E.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The research programme called “international research cooperation and organic integrity” was commenced for a period 2006-2010. It is coordinated by DARCOF (The Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming). The whole programme, with acronym DARCOF III, consists of 15 projects (http://www.darcof.dk/research/darcofiii/index.html). One of them is BIOCONCENS - Biomass and bioenergy production in organic farming – consequences for soil fertility, environment, spread of animal parasites and socio-economy (http://www.bioconcens.elr.dk/uk/). The production of bioenergy in organic agriculture (OA) can reduce its dependency of fossil fuels and decrease green house gasses emission; consequently it will increase sustainability of organic farms. Biorefinery concept based on co-production of biogas, bioethanol and protein fodder in organic farming will be developed within the BIOCONCENS project and the background for the project and the different work packages will be presented in this paper.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14406/1/poster_Oleskowicz-popiel.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oleskowicz-Popiel, P; Ambus, P;  Carter, M.S.; Dalgaard, T.; Hauggaard-Nielsen, H; Johansen, A; Jørgensen, U; Nielsen, A.M; Nielsen, H.B.; Nielsen, L.H; Olesen, J.E.; Roepstorff, A; Skytte, K; Schmidt, J.E.; Thomsen, A.B.; Thomsen, M.H. and Jensen, E.S.    (2008) BioConcens: Biomass and bioenergy production agriculture – consequences for soil fertility, environment, spread of animal parasites and socio-economy.       Paper at:   vth International Symposium on anaerobic digestion of solid wastes and energy crops.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14406/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>