<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic concepts for animal health and welfare</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic livestock farming involves a strong principle of high food quality and good animal health and welfare. The  emphasis of animal health promotion, disease prevention and support of the natural behaviour and the natural lives of the animals is strong. Organic livestock farming places strong emphasis on conditions that allow animals to exhibit behavioural needs. This involves the provision of a natural environment, and in particular outdoor conditions and a reliance on natural forages. This creates a clear distinction between conventional and organic herds. Such environments also allow animals to be effectively integrated into crop production. At the same time, the human care giving is very important in order to prohibit any suffering or negative effects of the systems in which the animals live. This presentation highlights these issues and give examples in terms of some of the existing challenges for animal health management on a North-Western European, as well as an EU and a global level will be shortly given and in order to discuss some of the specific areas concerning animal health and welfare promotion in organic livestock farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-10-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16372/2/16372.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vaarst, Mette    (2009) Organic concepts for animal health and welfare.       Keynote presentation at:</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16372/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>