<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prediction and detection of long-range migration of pest insects</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Markkula, Irmeli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leskinen, Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pylkkö, Pirkko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ooperi, Sini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tiilikkala, Kari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ojanen, Hannu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raiskio, Sakari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koistinen, Jarmo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In Finland most of the long-range migrations of pest insects are carried by warm air currents from south and south-east, by winds blowing from the continent. Changes in climate affect not only local populations, but also the source populations in these migrations. The possible&#xD;
changes predicted by climate change models in the areas of interest in Finland include longer growing seasons, milder winters, and slight increase in precipitation at the higher latitudes, but also increase in droughts in the southerly areas where many of the migrants are supposed to overwinter. The migratory insect pests can take full advantage of the longer growing season, and monitoring of the migration both in the fields and in the air would be important in making the control measures as effective as possible.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17284/1/Markkula.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Markkula, Irmeli; Leskinen, Matti; Pylkkö, Pirkko; Ooperi, Sini; Tiilikkala, Kari; Ojanen, Hannu; Raiskio, Sakari and Koistinen, Jarmo    (2010) Prediction and detection of long-range migration of pest insects.   In:     NJF Report vol 6, no 1, Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists, p. 58.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17284/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>