<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Österreichisches Projekt Grundlagen zur Züchtung,&#xD;
Vermehrung und Sorten-/Saatgutprüfung für den Biolandbau:&#xD;
Ergebnisübersicht</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berger, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Birschitzky, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bistrich, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bürstmayr, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diethart, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flamm, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fleck, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Girsch, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grausgruber, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gollner, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hofer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hrbek, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jakupaj, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kinastberger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lafferty, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leonhardt, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Löschenberger, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luftensteiner, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mechtler, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberforster, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petrasek, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ratzenböck, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulmeister, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schweiger, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vollmann, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weinhappel, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winkler, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zechner, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the Austrian research project “Basic principles for breeding, multiplication and&#xD;
variety testing for organic agriculture” (from 2004 until 2008) novel methods for the&#xD;
assessment of the suitability of seed and cultivars for organic farming were developed&#xD;
and evaluated by an interdisciplinary co-operation of researchers, breeders and&#xD;
variety testers. Organic farming requires specific combinations of crop plant&#xD;
characters, especially seed health and resistance against seed-borne diseases.&#xD;
Another crucial feature is the competitive ability against weeds. Early development&#xD;
was found to significantly increase the competitiveness of different crop plants.&#xD;
Genotypic variation in characters necessary for an efficient utilisation of below-ground&#xD;
resources was also investigated, e.g. interrelations between root development and&#xD;
drought stress tolerance and between mycorrhiza formation and nutrient use&#xD;
efficiency. Based on the results obtained in various cultivar trials, it can be concluded&#xD;
that genotypes suitable for organic growing conditions may be pre-selected from early&#xD;
breeding material of conventional breeding programmes. The selected breeding&#xD;
material must subsequently be rigorously tested on organically managed fields starting&#xD;
from the first yield trials at the latest. The project results were communicated to&#xD;
farmers and advisors during field days and excursions. They will be applied in the&#xD;
breeding of new cultivars.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14498/1/Hartl_14498.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hartl, W.; Berger, S.; Birschitzky, J.; Bistrich, H.; Bürstmayr, H.; Diethart, I.; Flamm, C.; Fleck, A.; Friedel, J.; Fuchs, F.; Girsch, L.; Grausgruber, H.; Gollner, M.; Hofer, M.; Hrbek, R.; Jakupaj, S.; Huber, K.; Kinastberger, A.; Lafferty, J.; Leonhardt, C.; Löschenberger, F.; Luftensteiner, H.; Mechtler, K.; Oberforster, M.; Petrasek, R.; Ratzenböck, A.; Schulmeister, K.; Schweiger, P.; Vollmann, J.; Weinhappel, M.; Winkler, J. and Zechner, E.    (2009) Österreichisches Projekt Grundlagen zur Züchtung, Vermehrung und Sorten-/Saatgutprüfung für den Biolandbau: Ergebnisübersicht.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14498/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>