<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Haltung, Gesundheit und gegenseitiges Besaugen von Kälbern&#xD;
auf biologischen Betrieben in Österreich</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Waiblinger, Ao.Univ.Prof.Dr. Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gugatschka, Mag. Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this project was to collect data about housing and health of dairy calves&#xD;
and the occurrence of cross-sucking in organic dairy farms. A questionnaire was sent&#xD;
to 300 organic dairy cow farms in Lower Austria. 99 questionnaires were returned&#xD;
(33%). On average the farms kept 15 cows, nearly half of them in tie-stalls and half&#xD;
loose-housed. 52 farms declared to keep calves group-housed from the first or the&#xD;
second week of life (lw), 14 farms kept their calves always in single pens. 23 farms&#xD;
weaned calves before lw 12, starting with lw5. Cross-sucking in calves occurred on 62&#xD;
farms, intersucking in cows on 26 farms. Cross-sucking in calves was observed on&#xD;
less farms with single housed calves compared to farms with group-housed calves,&#xD;
according to expectations. But early group housing (start at latest on second week) did&#xD;
not differ from later group housing (lw 3 – 8). Also, diseases were not associated with&#xD;
type of housing. In sum, there is need for further advancement and advice to improve&#xD;
calf housing and welfare.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14560/1/Waiblinger_14560.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Waiblinger, Ao.Univ.Prof.Dr. Susanne and Gugatschka, Mag. Marion    (2009) Haltung, Gesundheit und gegenseitiges Besaugen von Kälbern auf biologischen Betrieben in Österreich.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14560/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>