<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil tillage in organic farming: impacts of conservation tillage on soil fertility, weeds and crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peigné, Dr. Joséphine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aveline, Dr. Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cannavaccuiolo, Dr. Mario</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giteau, Ing. Jean-Luc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gautronneau, Ing. Yvan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmers are encouraged to adopt conservation tillage to preserve soil quality and fertility and prevent erosion. In the framework of a national study, we compared conservation (no tillage NT and reduced tillage RT) and conventional (mouldboard ploughing MP and shallow mouldboard ploughing SMP) tillage systems in 3 field experiments and 2 on-farm surveys. We measured the impacts of soil tillage on: (1) soil compaction: more compacted soil under NT and RT, (2) earthworm populations: more earthworms under NT, (3) weed infestation: weed level tends to be higher under NT, but it is not a general trend, and (4) crops: crop yields are lower under NT according to weed infestation. Then, independent of soil type and experimental year (2 to 5 years), it seems that soil physical fertility decreases under NT and RT. But, the first reason of a decline of crop yield under NT is the weed infestation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12290/1/peign%C3%A9_12290_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Peigné, Dr. Joséphine; Aveline, Dr. Anne; Cannavaccuiolo, Dr. Mario; Giteau, Ing. Jean-Luc and Gautronneau, Ing. Yvan    (2008) Soil tillage in organic farming: impacts of conservation tillage on soil fertility, weeds and crops.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12290/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>