<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ertragsleistung und Rutingehalte verschiedener&#xD;
Buchweizensorten unter ökologischen Anbaubedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Goeritz, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kawiani, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwarz, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kämper, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ehmsen, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Buckwheat is an ancient traditional food and medicinal plant. In this study we&#xD;
investigated grain yield and rutin content of common (Bamby, Lileja, Hruszowska) and&#xD;
tataric (Lifago) buckwheat varieties under organic farming conditions at different N&#xD;
levels. Grain yield and rutin content were not significantly affected by the factors ‘year’&#xD;
and ‘N-supply’. However, strong effects of the factor ‘variety’ could be determined. The&#xD;
tataric buckwheat Lifago showed highest grain and rutin yields compared to the&#xD;
common buckwheat varieties. Due to the rutin related bitter taste Lifago buckwheat is&#xD;
rather useful for medical application than for basic food. Converting rutin into less&#xD;
bitter active substance quercetin during processing as well as cross-breeding of&#xD;
common buckwheat x wild type buckwheat might be alternatives for basic food&#xD;
application. Since we found no effect of additional N-supply, buckwheat is well suited&#xD;
for low input farming systems like organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14436/1/Goeritz_14436.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Goeritz, M.; Kawiani, R.; Loges, R.; Schwarz, K.; Kämper, M.; Ehmsen, T. and Taube, F.    (2009) Ertragsleistung und Rutingehalte verschiedener Buchweizensorten unter ökologischen Anbaubedingungen.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14436/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>