<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>QACCP Analyse in der Verarbeitung von biologischer Säuglingsnahrung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Väisänen, Hanne M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seidel, Kathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the study was to evaluate the quality influencing processing steps based&#xD;
on the processes of carrot baby food. Once the processing conditions were identified,&#xD;
the possibilities for alternative processing techniques will be explored to improve the&#xD;
overall product and process quality. Next to the food safety (hazard) in the food processing&#xD;
the quality aspect is getting more and more important and an analyse system&#xD;
to optimise the process needs to be established (QualityAnalysisCriticalControlPoint).&#xD;
Organic carrots (Daucus carota, Maestro variety) were processed in a pilot plant trail&#xD;
according a carrot puree process typical in baby food industry. The samples differed&#xD;
regarding the treatment of the raw material prior the sterilization process. Different&#xD;
factors affecting the process like processing time and temperature were documented.&#xD;
It can be concluded that the treatment of the raw material prior the sterilization process&#xD;
can be a critical point according to the process quality. Also great variations in&#xD;
inside temperature are possible among the samples going through the sterilization&#xD;
process. Since the process time is adjusted by the coldest sample, it is important to&#xD;
follow the factors affecting the heat transfer.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14586/1/S%C3%A4rkk%C3%A4Tirkkonen_14586.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo;  Väisänen, Hanne M.; Kretzschmar, Ursula and Seidel, Kathrin    (2009) QACCP Analyse in der Verarbeitung von biologischer Säuglingsnahrung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14586/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>