<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality of organic feedstuffs grown in Trenthorst (Germany) – evaluated by Near Infrared Reflectance Spectroscopy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the present study we address the development of a rapid technique –NIRS– for the evaluation of organically produced feedstuffs in Trenthorst (Germany). The exclusive use of organically produced animal feedstuffs is fixed in the EU-VO 2092/91 for the year 2011. The differences of the contents of crude nutrients between the data of conventionally and organically analysed feedstuffs, as well as the possible differences of the contents from year to year, point out that a satisfying calculation of feed rations needs an exact knowledge of the chemical constituents of the feed components used. Therefore, well-defined material from field trials of the experimental station of the Institute of Organic Farming in Trenthorst of the years 2002-2005 was used for the determination of the contents of crude nutrients and energy in different grain legumes and cereals. All samples were analysed by classical chemical methods and also scanned by NIRS. Predictions of crude protein, crude ash, ether extract, starch, sugar and energy contents for pigs and dairy cattle showed satisfactory accuracy. The correlation coefficients for crude protein, ether extract and starch were 0.98, respectively. Standard error of prediction was below 0.1 MJ ME (pig) kg-1  DM and below 0.08 MJ NEL kg-1 DM. The prediction accuracy for crude fiber, fiber fractions and AMEN was poor. The prediction accuracy should be improved during further growing seasons.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12211/1/Aulrich_12211_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aulrich, Karen and Böhm, Herwart    (2008) Quality of organic feedstuffs grown in Trenthorst (Germany) – evaluated by Near Infrared Reflectance Spectroscopy.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12211/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>