<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Experiences of Organic Dairy Farmers with Ailing Milk Markets&#xD;
- A Sociological Study in Northern Germany -</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oppermann, Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The case refers to organic milk production and the marketing of organic milk produce.&#xD;
We describe the situation of two groups of organic dairy farmers working in&#xD;
northern Germany.&#xD;
The two groups are confronted with an extremely difficult choice. They have to&#xD;
choose whether they will continue to follow a quality oriented strategy of organic farming&#xD;
or whether they will favour mass production concepts – based on the principles for organic production of course.&#xD;
Against this background several general results can be drawn from our study. The&#xD;
process which we characterize as “transforming rural communication” is actually&#xD;
underway in rural areas. The consciousness of problems and tasks related to the development of rural areas has become stronger. &#xD;
More off, actors who want to dedicate themselves to these tasks are joining together. In Germany, significantly more regional initiatives can be found today than several years ago, whereby certain political promotion&#xD;
programs play a large role.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bundesforschungsanstalt für Landwirtschaft (FAL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8730/1/137_SAG_%C3%96ko_TRUC.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oppermann, Rainer and Rahmann, Gerold    (2005) Experiences of Organic Dairy Farmers with Ailing Milk Markets - A Sociological Study in Northern Germany -.  [Experiences of Organic Dairy Farmers with Ailing Milk Markets - A Sociological Study in Northern Germany -.]   In: Rahmann, Gerold (Ed.)   Ressortforschung für den Ökologischen Landbau 2005.  Sonderhefte der Landbauforschung Völkenrode, no. 290. Bundesforschungsanstalt für Landwirtschaft (FAL), pp. 35-55.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8730/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>