<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Luzernegrünmehl in Futtermischungen mit abgesenktem ME-Gehalt für die ökologische Hühnermast</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carrasco Alarcon, Luz Salomé</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellof, Gerhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic diets with low energy and amino acid contents were studied (Bellof, et al. 2005) with positive effects on growth and carcass performance of broilers. Alfalfa is moderately rich in protein, pigments and saponins and limited content of energy (AME). This event could benefit the design of low energy diets. Also alfalfa was able to produce healthy broiler meat (low fat and cholesterol) with a special flavour (Ponte et al., 2004). In the conventional production the results are controversial. A trial with 6 % of alfalfa diet found reduced performance of broilers (Tkácová et al., 2011), and a long raising study (56 d) found high and low carcass yield with 17 and 45 g/d of alfalfa intake respectively (Ponte et al., 2004). This fact could be attributed to the different fiber contents of the alfalfas used by the above mentioned authors (25.7 % vs. 21.8 % respectively).The aim of the trial was to study the impact of high levels of alfalfa in low energy diets on production parameters of slow-growing broilers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21527/1/21527_carassco.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Carrasco Alarcon, Luz Salomé and Bellof, Gerhard    (2013) Luzernegrünmehl in Futtermischungen mit abgesenktem ME-Gehalt für die ökologische Hühnermast.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21527/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>