<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Opportunities of organic agriculture in Albania</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leksinaj, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The perspectives of contribution to organic agriculture, aside from the market aspects, have to be seen in their broader sense.  It should be argued that the creation of the organic agriculture might contribute to the conservation of the traditional customs and practices. The possibility of using a higher premium than labour might encourage the population to deal in agriculture for much longer.&#xD;
The organic agriculture has proven that it is able to provide efficient possibilities on diversification and penetration into the market, this when reference is being made to both marginal and less developed areas. These possibilities do guarantee a satisfactory return for farmers and retains a satisfactory use of the natural resources. We recommend a series of interventions in the integrated organic system to occur over an efficient action plan at the national level that is primarily intended:&#xD;
- to satisfy and make the normative framework on the sector much easier to be implemented;&#xD;
- to promote organic agriculture at all levels;&#xD;
- to organize with other links of supply chain at the start and at the end of the production cycle, that is by improving the availability of inputs, by promoting processing and the positioning of products in the market;&#xD;
- to support the formation, research and extension&#xD;
- to develop the organic product markets through a consolidation of the exports, as well as affair share of attention to the typology of the potential customers in the food market (urban populations with high incomes, tourists that appreciate the rural wealth and the nature of the country). The presence of such policies constitutes one of the development of a connection between policies of territory conservation and agriculture in the strategic activities of the development program of agriculture, programs where the environmental policies, tourism and organic agriculture constitutes the entirety of a sustainable solution and an evaluation of food products, in the rural development and the protection of territory.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24560/1/24560.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leksinaj, E.    (2013) Opportunities of organic agriculture in Albania.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 101-102.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24560/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>