<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards sustainable food systems through innovative networks in public catering</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Risku-Norja, Helmi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainability of food systems inherently implies food security, but in search for cost savings, the&#xD;
decision‐makers tend to belittle the significance of food security, to overlook the various aspects of&#xD;
sustainability in statutory catering and to ignore the environmental, societal and cultural aspects of food. An&#xD;
extensive survey on the present status of statutory public catering shows, that although the severe natural&#xD;
circumstances present great challenges for food production in Finland, municipal public catering is still today&#xD;
largely based on domestically produced food. Thus, even in extreme circumstances national food security is&#xD;
possible. However, because food security is not seen as constituting an essential part of sustainable&#xD;
development (SD), the situation may alter in future. There is also large variation among Finnish municipalities as&#xD;
to how those involved in catering understand the concept SD, how SD has been accounted for and how it can be&#xD;
promoted in practice. In addition, there is very little direct co‐operation between researchers, extension and&#xD;
practical actors of municipal catering. The results imply that in order to encourage sustainable food&#xD;
consumption, the concept of SD should be brought clearly into the context of public catering. The municipalities&#xD;
differ as to the foci and development needs. Therefore, there are no universal solutions, but the solutions need&#xD;
to be slotted to the prevailing local circumstances and reconciled in mutual understanding among the actors.&#xD;
Innovative networks involving municipal actors, researchers and an expert as a broker provide one promising&#xD;
channel for finding the local way to improve sustainability of public catering. This study aims at reconnecting&#xD;
people to the origin of food in their own surroundings and encouraging them to actively promote sustainable&#xD;
food systems and sustainability in public catering through empowerment of the actors within innovative local&#xD;
networks. The presentation captures the results from the survey and discusses future perspectives of increasing&#xD;
sustainability within public catering in light of first experiences from the actors’ innovative networks.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>BOKU university</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17563/1/riskunorja.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Risku-Norja, Helmi and Mikkola, Minna    (2010) Towards sustainable food systems through innovative networks in public catering.       Paper at:   9th European IFSA symposium, Vienna, 4-7 July, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17563/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>