<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutritive quality of Finnish grown grain legumes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lizarazo, Clara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Santanen, Arja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stoddard, Fred</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Grain legumes have excellent nutritional quality that makes them a staple ingredient for feeding&#xD;
ruminants, pigs and poultry. Legumes are known for their high protein content, and although&#xD;
they are low in the sulphur-containing amino acids and tryptophan, they have a high content of&#xD;
lysine; thus they are an ideal supplement to cereal-based diets and food products (Duranti &amp;&#xD;
Cius 1997).&#xD;
Legumes have many beneficial effects in human diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
There is potential and sufficient farmer interest to establish grain legume crops in the&#xD;
Nordic-Baltic region through screening imported germplasm for adaptation. There are many&#xD;
potential uses of legume seeds as functional ingredients, thus further research is needed to&#xD;
design legume-supplemented food products. In addition, it is very important to publicize&#xD;
their health benefits, to assure consumer acceptance.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18310/1/Lizarazo.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lizarazo, Clara; Santanen, Arja and Stoddard, Fred    (2010) Nutritive quality of Finnish grown grain legumes.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18310/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>