<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The strategic turn of Organic Farming in Europe : from a resource&#xD;
based to an entrepreneurial approach of Organic Marketing&#xD;
Initiatives</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sylvander, Bertil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schieb-Bienfait, Nathalie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This chapter explores the Organic farming’s development potential in Europe by analysing&#xD;
the enterprises capacities to reach a workable structure of the supply chains, in order to&#xD;
market good products at reasonable prices. This study has been carried out in the framework&#xD;
of an European project (OMIaRD), which aimed to assess the impact of the Organic&#xD;
Marketing Initiatives on Rural Development. The results show that, after a growing phase,&#xD;
most of the Organic Marketing Initiatives meet a strategic turn point, linked to their ability to&#xD;
face logistic problems, linked to an increasing of collected, processed and marketed volumes.&#xD;
This strategic turn point leads them to take decisions together with their stakeholders, so as&#xD;
the economic and ethical goals are not questioned by the changes to be implemented.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Cardiff University Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Marsden, Terry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Murdoch, Jonathan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6715/1/BioChapter_Sylvander-version_3-4nov05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sylvander, Bertil and Schieb-Bienfait, Nathalie    (2005) The strategic turn of Organic Farming in Europe : from a resource based to an entrepreneurial approach of Organic Marketing Initiatives.    In: Marsden, Terry and Murdoch, Jonathan (Eds.)   Between the local and the global : confronting the complexity in the contemporary food sector.  Cardiff University Press, chapter 10.      [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6715/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>