<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic beef production by Maremmana breed: qualitative meat characteristics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mele, Prof. Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morbidini, Prof. Luciano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cozza, Dr. Francesca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pauselli, Prof. Mariano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pollicardo, Dr. Alice</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Meat quality of Maremmana young bulls and steers was evaluated during three consecutive years, according to an extension service experimental program. Cooking loss values of meat samples were lower in meat from steers, whereas shear force values were higher. Meat from steers was darker than meat from young bulls, as a consequence of a low level of Lightness and a high level of Chroma. Meat chemical composition showed a higher content of intramuscular fat in steer meat, which showed also a lower level of saturated fatty acids and a higher level of unsaturated fatty acids. Conjugated linoleic acid content in meat fat either from young bulls or from steers was similar to that found in meat from confined cattle fed preserved forages and concentrates. However steer meat showed higher CLA content than young bull meat.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12250/1/Mele_12250_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mele, Prof. Marcello; Morbidini, Prof. Luciano; Cozza, Dr. Francesca; Pauselli, Prof. Mariano and Pollicardo, Dr. Alice    (2008) Organic beef production by Maremmana breed: qualitative meat characteristics.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12250/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>