<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Crop protection and soil fertility in organic okra cultivation in Mauritius</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Facknath, Dr S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hurree, Miss B</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Okra was grown in organic and conventional systems. The organic plots included an intercrop system, using onion in alternate rows. Well-decomposed manure was used as a soil amendment, and mulching was done with cane straw. A bird net prevented damage by birds to seeds. Neem extract was applied as and when needed based on economic threshold values of important pests. Parameters studied included plant height, leaf area index, soil pH, soil NPK, and yield and quality of harvested okra fruits. Okra was grown in the conventional plots in a monocrop system, fertilised with synthetic NPK fertilisers, and sprayed with synthetic pesticides. Comparison of soil, plant and yield parameters showed that leaf area index, plant height (from week 10) and fruit yield and quality were higher in the organic system compared to the conventional system, while pest damage was equal in the two systems. Soil pH and phosphorus levels were lower in the organic plots, while available nitrogen and potassium were higher in the organic plots.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12696/1/Facknath_12696_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Facknath, Dr S and Hurree, Miss B    (2008) Crop protection and soil fertility in organic okra cultivation in Mauritius.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12696/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>