<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Leguminosen Ackerbohnen, Körnererbsen und&#xD;
Buschbohnen auf die Fruchtfolge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paffrath, Dipl.Ing.agr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming legumes play an important role in crop rotation. Especially&#xD;
instockless farming systems, grain legumes are preferred over clover-grass, which is&#xD;
not cultivated any more. The purpose of the field trial was to test the previous crop&#xD;
effect of field beans, grain peas and bush beans on the whole crop rotation. Control&#xD;
crop was spring wheat. Follower crops were potato – winter wheat – barley. The&#xD;
experiment was repeated consecutively for four years. In the first year yield of potato&#xD;
following the cultivation of all legumes was on average significantly higher (14 %)&#xD;
compared to previous crop spring wheat. No significant effect could be observed on&#xD;
winter wheat during the second year. Yield of barley following the legumes in the third&#xD;
year was significantly (22%) higher. No differences could be seen between the three&#xD;
legumes. The positive effect of legumes was obvious during the whole crop rotation.&#xD;
The nitrogen efficiency of field beans and grain peas was better than from bush beans.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14256/1/Paffrath_14256.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paffrath, Dipl.Ing.agr. Andreas    (2009) Einfluss der Leguminosen Ackerbohnen, Körnererbsen und Buschbohnen auf die Fruchtfolge.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14256/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>