<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Hohenheimer Box: &#xD;
Entwicklung einer Methode zur Vor-Ort-Massenzucht der Erzwespe Lariophagus distinguendus gegen Vorratsschädlinge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niedermayer, Steffi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steidle, Johannes L.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biological pest control is an important tool in stored products protection. To improve the biological control of the granary weevil Sitophilus granarius L. (Coleoptera: Curculionidae), a rearing box for the parasitic wasp Lariophagus distinguendus (Förster) (Hymenoptera: Pteromalidae) has been developed. The box contains breeding substrate as well as populations of hosts and parasitoids and is placed directly in the storage site. A special outlet prevents hosts from leaving the box while freshly emerged parasitoids are released continuously over several months. A repeated shipment of wasps has thereby become obsolete.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21545/1/21545_Niedermayer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niedermayer, Steffi and Steidle, Johannes L.M.    (2013) Die Hohenheimer Box: Entwicklung einer Methode zur Vor-Ort-Massenzucht der Erzwespe Lariophagus distinguendus gegen Vorratsschädlinge.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21545/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>