<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nebenwirkungen auf den Fruchtansatz der Behandlungen von Schwefelkalk in die Blüte mit der Beregnung bzw. mit dem Sprüher</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mateazzi, Aldo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>K-phosphite is very efficient against several plant diseases. Nevertheless at the moment there is no official registration in Europe as a plant protection material. In conventional winegrowing K-phosphite is used in different countries to regulate the main disease ‘Plasmopora viticola’ under the disguise of a foliar fertilizer or a plant strengthener. In organic apple production only a few fungicides to regulate scab are available. In addition, copper products are limited by European and national legislations. The discussion about K-phosphite for organic farming points always at the problem of synthetic residues on the edible parts of the vegetables. The aim of this field-trial carried out during the season of 2005 was to assess the residues on apples after applications of K-phosphite at different moments during the season. The results show that treatments before blossom leave no residues wheras treatments after blossom lead to the same level of residues independently of the period of application.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9025/1/ecofruit_12th_39.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Mateazzi, Aldo and Casera, Claudio    (2006) Nebenwirkungen auf den Fruchtansatz der Behandlungen von Schwefelkalk in die Blüte mit der Beregnung bzw. mit dem Sprüher.  [Effects of the period of application of K-phosphite on residues on apple fruits.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 225-227.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9025/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>