<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Growing Methods and Nutrient Management in Organic Greenhouse Production of Vegetables</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Babik, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaniszewski, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Babik, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Greenhouses and coverings</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The research cycle encompass year-long organic vegetable greenhouse production. Spring crop was grown pickling cucumbers followed by autumn tomato. During winter month without heating annual cover crops (mixture of oat, hairy vetch and field peas) were grown and as an green manure incorporated to the soil in spring before cucumber cultivation. Additional organic fertilizers (compost and chicken manure) were applied before cucumber and tomato planting. In the period between cucumber and tomato cultivation the soil in greenhouse was solarizated. In both crops soil surface was mulched with black fleece or fresh red clover biomass. Transplants of both species were produced in organic substrate. Cucumbers were planting in the soil but tomatoes in bottomless containers of 0,5 dm3, placed directly on the soil surface. The period of cucumbers growing was 90 days and tomatoes 120 days. Every 2 – 3 weeks in cultivation period nutrients concentration in soil solution was monitored on the depth of 30 and 60 cm. Growth development, earliness, yield and quality of fruits were determined. Red clover mulch positively influenced on cucumber and tomato growth and yield when applied early in the season, soon after transplant planting. In the initial period of plant growth (till fruiting) considerable amounts of nutrients (mainly nitrogen and potassium) were leached to the soil depth of 30 and 60 cm. After fruits setting and during fruits growth nutrient contents in soil solution considerably decreased and necessity of additional nutrients supply appeared. It was done by fertigation. In Polish climate condition soil solarization in summer months decreased the total number of soil microorganisms and was more effective while good insolation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Society for Horticultural  Science (ISHS)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rallo, Luis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>De la Rosa, Raul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Monteiro, Antonio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>De Oliveira, Pedro Bas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17445/1/17445.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Babik, J.; Kaniszewski, S. and Babik, I.    (2010) Growing Methods and Nutrient Management in Organic Greenhouse Production of Vegetables.   In: Rallo, Luis; De la Rosa, Raul; Monteiro, Antonio and De Oliveira, Pedro Bas (Eds.)  Abstracts. Volume II (Symposia), International Society for Horticultural Science (ISHS), Lisboa, p. 641.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17445/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>