<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DIFFERENTIATION OF REARING SYSTEMS: IS THERE A MARKET FOR ORGANIC BEEF FROM EXTENSIVE SUCKLER COW HUSBANDRY?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Korn, Antje</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of the main reasons for buying organic products is the animal friendly production system. However, due to an undifferentiated marketing, there is no possibility so far for German consumers to purchase a beef product according to the rearing system of the cattle - except for the possibility to purchase directly from farms.Yet, there is only little research published on the potential of a differentiated marketing approach for beef from animal-friendly rearing systems, such as extensive suckler cow husbandry.The objective of the present paper is to present findings from a project that assessed the potential for a differentiation of rearing systems for the German organic beef market. Results of the study indicate that the price is not of high importance for consumers of organic beef. Consumers tend to prefer an organic production, but also the rearing system is an important product attribute. Especially if consumers were informed about the rearing system, consumers preferred beefsteak from a suckler-cow-based rearing. Additionally, ethical values like the protection of the environment and biological diversity seem to be important facets. Organic products should not only focus on the production system, but also differentiate according to the rearing system.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23949/1/23949_Korn_owc_scientific%20track_2014_DIFFERENTIATION%20OF%20REARING%20SYSTEMS_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Korn, Antje and Hamm, Ulrich    (2014) DIFFERENTIATION OF REARING SYSTEMS: IS THERE A MARKET FOR ORGANIC BEEF FROM EXTENSIVE SUCKLER COW HUSBANDRY?   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 449-452.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23949/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>