<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spring barley grain quality changes in conventional and organic growing conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kokare, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Legzdina, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lammerts van Bueren, Edith T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>While breeding for organic farming it is necessary to identify the most appropriate&#xD;
growing conditions in which to perform the selection process. Soil fertility, crop&#xD;
management, yield level and other factors may vary very much between each organic&#xD;
farm, and between organic farms and research institutions where the selection is usually&#xD;
performed. Since plant breeding requires considerable input of resources and the market&#xD;
for organic varieties is limited, it is essential to find the most appropriate selection&#xD;
conditions that will provide acceptable varieties for organic farms.&#xD;
Spring barley breeding lines selected from two cross combinations (Primus/Idumeja and&#xD;
Anni/Dziugiai) at two distinctive organic and two conventional locations were used in the&#xD;
study. The organic location 1 was situated in a research field of the plant breeding&#xD;
institute (with green manure as fertilizer), the organic location 2 included an organic&#xD;
farmer’s field (with stable manure as fertilizer), the conventional location 1 was located&#xD;
in a barley breeding field (with medium level of mineral fertilizer input) and the&#xD;
conventional location 2 in a seed production field of the institute (with high mineral&#xD;
fertilizer input).&#xD;
Selection of the breeding lines was done under the respective growing conditions starting&#xD;
from F3 generation. Most appropriate lines for growing in organic farming were selected&#xD;
at all 4 environments. Selected breeding lines were evaluated in F5 (n=20-23 per cross&#xD;
combination, without replications) and F6 generations (n=10 per cross combination, 3&#xD;
replications).&#xD;
Correlations between barley traits and the environments and cross combinations will be&#xD;
compared in the presentation.&#xD;
The analysis of the correlation between grain yield and observed plant traits of F5 lines&#xD;
indicated that tendencies between the lines obtained from both cross combinations as well&#xD;
as between the environments were dissimilar in most of the cases. Soil shading&#xD;
(evaluated at early stem elongation stage) correlated positively with grain yield in all&#xD;
cases; the correlation was always significant for lines from the cross Primus/Idumeja, but&#xD;
only at the conventional location 2 for Anni/Dziugiai lines&#xD;
(p&lt;0.05). A significant positive correlation between grain yield and plant development&#xD;
speed at tillering stage as well as between yield and plant height at the beginning of stem&#xD;
elongation was found for Primus/Idumeja lines at both organic&#xD;
locations and at the conventional location 1 (p&lt;0.05). Plant height before harvest did not&#xD;
correlate significantly with yield under organic conditions which is in contradiction with&#xD;
some other studies. There was a tendency for planophyle growth&#xD;
habit to correlate positively with yield under organic and conventional conditions for&#xD;
lines from both cross combinations.&#xD;
The analysis of correlation of the F6 lines will be included in the presentation.&#xD;
This study was performed with financial support of EEA grant EEZ08AP-27and&#xD;
European Social Fund co-financed project&#xD;
2009/0218/1DP/1.1.1.2.0/09/APIA/VIAA/099.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA and ITAB</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Goldringer, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19198/1/2468.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kokare, A.; Legzdina, L. and Lammerts van Bueren, Edith T.    (2010) Spring barley grain quality changes in conventional and organic growing conditions.  [Kwaliteit van zomergerst verandert onder conventionele en biologische teeltomstandigheden.]      Poster at:   Breeding for Resilience: a strategy for organic and low-input farming systems? Eucarpia 2nd Conference of the Organic and Low-Input Agriculture section, Paris, 1 - 3 december 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19198/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>