<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleichende Untersuchungen zur Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers &#xD;
(Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) mit Pyrethrum/Rapsöl-, Neemöl- und &#xD;
Bacillus thuringiensis-Präparaten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kühne, PD Dr. Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pallut, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahn, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moll, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Colorado Potato Beetle is one of the most important pests of potatoes. The effect of various plant protection products with neem oil (NeemAzal-T/S), pyrethrum/rape oil (Spruzit Neu) and Bacillus thuringiensis-B.t.t.(Novodor Neu) against this pest was compared in a field experiment 2004. Neem oil and B.t.t. reduced the number of Colorado Potato Beetle larvae as well as the losses of plant material due to feeding by beetle larvae significantly in the same way. Beneficial arthropods were not affected. The application of pyrethrum/rape oil has shown in this experiment no significant effect to reduce the number of Colorado Potato Beetles. However, the number of beneficial arthropods was reduced from 2.2 individuals/plant (untreated control) to 1.0 individual/plant.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3577/1/3577.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kühne, PD Dr. Stefan; Pallut, B.; Jahn, M. and Moll, E.    (2005) Vergleichende Untersuchungen zur Regulierung des Kartoffelkäfers (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) mit Pyrethrum/Rapsöl-, Neemöl- und Bacillus thuringiensis-Präparaten.  [Comparative investigations to control Colorado Potato Beetle (Leptinotarsa decemlineata Say) by Neem, Pyrethrum/Rape oil and Bacillus thuringiensis.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3577/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>