<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A construção social da agroecologia no assentamento Tapera, em Riacho dos Machados, MG.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lteif, Ana Paula Alves Silva</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present work analyzes the social construction of development alternatives, expressed through the proposal of the agroecology, bringing as empiric reference for analysis the experience in agroecology of a rural settlement. That Settlement is called Tapera and it is located in the district of Riacho dos Machados, in the North area of the Minas Gerais state, and its technique is advised and politically for an organization of the civil society, more precisely for an Non-Govemmental Organization (NGO) dedicated to the rural development, that has as proposal to promote the maintainable rural development based in the Agroecology beginnings. However, previous to the study of the case in subject, it was looked for understanding the emergency of conceptions and proposed development alternatives and the mobilization of the organized civil society starting from partner-environrnental problerns, above all to those related to the agriculture. For so much, it had as emphasis to the concepts and representations reated around the agroecology and the potential of the proposal for the rural development. This way, this research puts in interaction themes as development, agroecology, social mediators, developrnent NGOs and rural settIement, so that it allows an including understanding of the complexity and of the meaning of the experience that it intended to analyze.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-05-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21962/1/Lteif_Construcao.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lteif, Ana Paula Alves Silva   (2008) A construção social da agroecologia no assentamento Tapera, em Riacho dos Machados, MG.  [The social construction of agroecology in the settlement Tapera in Riacho dos Machados, MG.]   Masters thesis, Universidade Federal de Viçosa, PPG em Extensão Rural.  .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21962/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>