<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analyse af fødevarekæder</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mogens, Lund</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jesper, Graversen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Janus, Søndergaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paul, Kledal</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The working paper contains a description of the methods used in the analysis of selected supply chains in the Danish food and agricultural industry. The analyses, which include the supply chains for pork, chickens, eggs, beef meat and fur production, are part of a greater research project focusing on cost-benefit analyses of Danish food products with special emphasize on food quality and safety. This working paper only review the adopted methods in the analyses, as separate reports will be published for each of the investigated supply chains. The reviewed analytical methods are used to describe and analyse the firms and actors in the individual food chain, their activities and economic value added, organisation and regulation schemes as well as the incentives and barriers in the chain towards producing food products with specific quality and safety attributes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3684/1/3684.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mogens, Lund; Jesper, Graversen; Janus, Søndergaard and Paul, Kledal    (2003) Analyse af fødevarekæder.  [Analysis of food chains.]   FØI working papers, no. 16/2003, Farm Management and Production System Division, Danish Research Institute of Food economics.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3684/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>