<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analyse und Bewertung der Energie-, Eiweiß- und Mineralstoffversorgung von Milchkühen im ökologischen Landbau am Beispiel des Lehr- und Versuchsbetriebes Gladbacherhof</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sommer, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof.Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid-Eisert, Dipl.-Ing.agr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An optimal supply of dairy cows with energy and nutritive substances is just as important for the organic as it is for the conventional milk production. The current project examined if in organic rural economy the feeding meets the required demand. In the trial period from 10 Nov. 2001 till 17 Oct.2003 data of the milk performance test were gathered for 11 capacity control days. The energy and nutritive substance made a silage food capacity of 17 -24 kg milk per cow and day possible, so a milk capacity of 8157 kg milk per cow and year could be realized. A suspected shortage of nitrogen based on the low milk urea concentration caused by the normal milk protein concentration could not be confirmed. The result of the capacity control showed that only     76 % of the theoretically possible milk capacity were yielded. Thus the food intake is much lower than the supplied dry matter. An adaptation of the quantity of rations to the required amount is recommended. Furthermore, grain legumes should be used as an equal crude protein component.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3648/1/3648.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sommer, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Hendrik; Leithold, Prof.Dr. Günter and Schmid-Eisert, Dipl.-Ing.agr. Andreas    (2005) Analyse und Bewertung der Energie-, Eiweiß- und Mineralstoffversorgung von Milchkühen im ökologischen Landbau am Beispiel des Lehr- und Versuchsbetriebes Gladbacherhof.  [Analysis and evaluation of the energy, protein and mineral supply of dairy cows in ecological farming showed at the trial station Gladbacherhof.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3648/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>