<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Potenziale und Hemmnisse der Entwicklung&#xD;
Sozialer Landwirtschaft in Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kalisch, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Elsen, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper summarises the methods and outcomes of the first German platform within&#xD;
the European SoFar project (www.sofar-d.de). The national platform took place in May&#xD;
2007 and aimed to bring forward the development of social farming, to enhance the&#xD;
exchange between different practitioners, to build a national platform of social farming&#xD;
stakeholders and find out requirements for further developments and recommendations&#xD;
for political actions on regional, national or European level. Methods of the discussions&#xD;
and their analysis are reviewed and the outcomes are presented in a SWOT&#xD;
analysis summarizing the strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats of social&#xD;
farming. As a consequence of platform and analysis the “Witzenhausen Position&#xD;
Paper on the Added Value of Social Farming” in Germany was compiled in a participatory&#xD;
process with 104 contributers and signatories. Its main points get presented here.&#xD;
It was written as a call to decision-makers in administration, politics and the public to&#xD;
support German social agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14123/1/Kalisch_14123.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kalisch, Marie and van Elsen, Thomas    (2009) Potenziale und Hemmnisse der Entwicklung Sozialer Landwirtschaft in Deutschland.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14123/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>