<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Chemische Zusammensetzung und sensorisches Profil von&#xD;
UFA/CLA angereicherter Butter im Vergleich zu konventioneller&#xD;
Butter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mallia, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Piccinali, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rehberger, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlichtherle-Cerny, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the last years, there has been a growing demand by consumers for foods combining an increased nutritional value and benefits on human health. Butter enriched in unsaturated fatty acids/conjugated linoleic acids (UFA/CLA) could become a food with added value for its increased content in essential fatty acids, in vitamins and CLA, which has been reported to show potential anticarcinogenic and cholesterol lowering effects. &#xD;
The aim of the present study was to evaluate the chemical composition and the sensory and odour profiles of UFA/CLA enriched butter in comparison to conventional butter.&#xD;
Their fatty acid composition, vitamin and metal ion contents were determined in both kinds of butter. Descriptive sensory analysis and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry coupled to olfactometry (GC/MS/O) were applied to UFA/CLA enriched and conventional butter. The UFA/CLA enriched butter contained significantly higher CLA than conventional butter. α-Tocopherol and iron contents were also significantly higher in UFA/CLA enriched butter. The sensory profile of the UFA/CLA enriched butter showed a less intense creamy odour and cooked milk aroma than conventional butter. UFA/CLA enriched butter revealed a better spreadability. The olfactometric results of the fresh butter samples indicated that the enriched butter had more intense green, sulphury and fruity notes, due to (Z)-3-hexenol, dimethyl disulphide, 2-phenylethyl acetate and δ-decalactone, respectively, compared to conventional butter.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14553/1/Mallia_14553.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mallia, S.; Piccinali, P.; Rehberger, B. and Schlichtherle-Cerny, H.    (2009) Chemische Zusammensetzung und sensorisches Profil von UFA/CLA angereicherter Butter im Vergleich zu konventioneller Butter.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, ETH Zürich, Schweiz, 11.-13- Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14553/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>