<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC FARMING AND SUSTAINABLE RURAL DEVELOPMENT: ÇORUH VALLEY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erdogan, Ummugulsum</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Erdogan, Yasar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cakmakci, Ramazan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turan, Metin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming has potential for reducing some of the negative impacts of conventional agriculture on the environment. Organic farming contributes to rural development and economy. These farming systems can also be the most important contributor to the rural economy of region and Çoruh Valley. Çoruh Valley contains rich biological diversity of plants, wildlife, and ecosystems. These natural and environmental resources will play an important role for rural development in this area.  Some evidences suggested that an important benefit of organic farming is the creation of jobs in the rural economy and prevention of human erosion. Effective use of the source will come true with production, processing and marketing of organic products such as spices, pekmez, honey, fruit and vegetable juices, thyme juices, vegetable oils, herbal tea, chemical compounds of plant and food additives in Çoruh Valley.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24895/1/PT_24895_MTuran.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Erdogan, Ummugulsum; Erdogan, Yasar; Cakmakci, Ramazan and Turan, Metin    (2014) ORGANIC FARMING AND SUSTAINABLE RURAL DEVELOPMENT: ÇORUH VALLEY.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24895/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>