<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Local food in municipal catering - a survey of local food purchasing in Finnish municipalities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Muukka, Eija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuosmanen, Leena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ylinampa, Meeri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blomquist, Ulla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kärkkäinen, Irma</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Malaska, Kirsi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soininen, Taira</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soininen, Jukka</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report is the first published report on the use of local food in almost all of Finland's municipalities, and covers the use of local food products in public municipality catering fairly comprehensively.&#xD;
&#xD;
The report presents the results of the telephone survey for the catering managers of Continental Finland carried out by EkoCentria's Lähikeittiöhanke's Local Cuisine Advisors in 2007. The count of participating municipalities totals to 366 which equals 92 % of municipalities in Continental Finland.&#xD;
&#xD;
In conclusion, there would be room for local products in public municipality catering if production, harvest and processing quantities could be raised and the supply chain between producers was coalesced.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15953/1/Local.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Muukka, Eija; Kuosmanen, Leena; Ylinampa, Meeri; Blomquist, Ulla; Kärkkäinen, Irma; Malaska, Kirsi; Soininen, Taira and Soininen, Jukka         (2008) Local food in municipal catering - a survey of local food purchasing in Finnish municipalities.   Publication series A of Savo Consortium for Education, Studies and reports, publication, no. 4. EkoCentria.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15953/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>