<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The restriction of grazing duration does not compromise lamb meat colour and oxidative stability</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luciano, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biondi, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pagano, R.I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scerra, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vasta, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>López-Andrés, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valenti, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lanza, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priolo, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Avondo, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Over 72 days, 33 lambs were fed: concentrates in stall (S), grass at pasture for 8 hours (8 h), or grass at pasture for 4 hours in the afternoon (4 h-PM). The 4 h-PM treatment did not affect the carcass yield compared to the 8 h treatment. Meat colour development after blooming was unaffected by the treatments. The 4 h-PM treatment increased the proportion of polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA; Pb0.0005) and of the highly peroxidizable fatty acids (HP-PUFA; Pb0.001) in meat compared to the 8 h treatment. The S treatment increased lipid oxidation (higher TBARS values) and impaired colour stability (higher H* values) of meat over storage compared to the 8 h and 4 h-PM treatments (Pb0.0005 and P=0.003, respectively). No difference in meat oxidative stability was found between the 8 h and the 4 h-PM treatments. In conclusion, growing lambs can tolerate a restriction of grazing duration without detrimental effects on performances and meat oxidative stability.&#xD;
© 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21715/1/Luciano-etal-2012-MeatScience-92-p30-35.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Luciano, G.; Biondi, L.; Pagano, R.I.; Scerra, M.; Vasta, V.; López-Andrés, P.; Valenti, B.; Lanza, M.; Priolo, A. and Avondo, M.   (2012) The restriction of grazing duration does not compromise lamb meat colour and oxidative stability.   Meat Science, 92, pp. 30-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21715/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>