<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of bovine sub-clinical mastitis by using herbal extract during lactation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Giacinti, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rosati, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boselli, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tammaro, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amatiste, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ronchi, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Objective of the study was to evaluate the effects of feeding administration of herbal extracts for the control of bovine subclinical mastitis during lactation. A total of 36 Italian Friesian lactating cows with subclinical mastitis were randomly divided into three homogeneous groups: phyto-treated group, placebo-treated group, and control group. In phyto-treated group, cows received 5 gr. of standardised fluid extract of Spirea ulmaria L. and 6 gr. of standardised extract of Astragalus membranaceus BUNGE, administered orally as complex once daily for 15 days. Milk samples were collected from the mammary quarters before the beginning of the experiment, and  then 14, 28 and 56 days after for analysis of bacteria, and somatic cells count (SCC). Milk flow and production were also recorded. The treatment positively influenced the health status of mammary glands, resulting particularly effective against Coagulase Negative Staphilococci. A reduction of infected quarters was highlighted in treated group ( 16.7% vs 30.2% and 37.5%, respectively in control and placebo groups; P&lt;0.05). Further studies are needed to ascertain some aspects of herbal extracts action in ruminants and their effectiveness in different experimental and practical conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12239/1/Giacinti_12239_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Giacinti, G.; Rosati, R.; Boselli, C.; Tammaro, A.; Amatiste, S. and Ronchi, B.    (2008) Control of bovine sub-clinical mastitis by using herbal extract during lactation.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12239/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>