<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Weed - spring barley competition for applied nitrogen in pig slurry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Petersen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The experiments were carried out in the two spring barley ﬁelds of the organic six-course cattle:crop rotation at Foulumgaard,Denmark. The weed density was 300 and 1800 plants m-2 respectively. Pig slurry was applied by hand in microplots by four methods:broadcasting followed by incorporation,or injected in bands to depths of 5,10 or 15 cm. Spring barley and weeds were sampled separately six times during the tillering and elongation phase of the spring barley. The effect of application method on dry-matter (d.m.)production, nitrogen uptake and recovery of applied nitrogen in the spring barley and the weeds is reported. Slurry banding halved the weed d.m. and weed N uptake compared with broadcasting,irrespective of weed density. Weeds recovered up to 12%of the applied nitrogen, which made them a signi ﬁcant competitor when the slurry was broadcast and incorporated. Banding by direct injection reduced the slurry:soil contact and the weed:crop competition balance for applied nitrogen moved in favour of the crop. Thus, the crop recovery of applied nitrogen at the end of the sampling period was increased from approximately 45% for broadcast and incorporated to approximately 50% for injected slurry, and coincidental weed recovery was reduced to a maximum of 5%. As the nitrogen supply normally affects plant d.m. production, banding of slurry might well improve crop competitiveness and its tolerance to mechanical weed control.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>European Weed Research Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/280/2/The_paper_is_available_at_the_library.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/280/3/Weed_spring_barley_competition_for_applied_nitrogen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Petersen, J.   (2003) Weed - spring barley competition for applied nitrogen in pig slurry.   Weed Research (43), pp. 33-39.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/280/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>