<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Monitoring strategies and scale-appropriate hydrologic and biogeochemical modelling for natural resource management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bende-Michl, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volk, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Harmel, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Newham, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This short communication paper presents recommendations for developing scale-appropriate monitoring and modelling strategies to assist decision making in natural resource management (NRM). These ideas presented here were discussed in the session (S5) ‘Monitoring strategies and scale-appropriate hydrologic and biogeochemical modelling for natural resource management’ session at the 2008 &#xD;
&#xD;
International&#xD;
Environmental Modelling and Simulation Society conference, Barcelona, Spain. The outcomes of the session and recent international studies exemplify the need for a stronger collaboration and communication between researcher and model developer on the one side, and natural resource &#xD;
managers and the model users on the other side to increase knowledge in: 1) the limitations and uncertainties of current monitoring and modelling strategies, 2) scale-dependent linkages between monitoring and modelling techniques, and 3) representation of hydrologic and biogeochemical phenomena in model development and practical application for natural resource management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18942/4/18942.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bende-Michl, U.; Volk, M.; Harmel, D.; Newham, L. and Dalgaard, T.   (2011) Monitoring strategies and scale-appropriate hydrologic and biogeochemical modelling for natural resource management.   Environmental Modelling &amp; Software, 26, pp. 538-542.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18942/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>