<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Varieties and integrated pest and disease management for organic apple production (LINK)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Horticulture Link Proposal No 237/3&#xD;
The aim is to develop an effective Integrated Pest and Disease Management (IPDM) programme for organic apple production in the UK. Important components of this aim are the evaluation and refinement of a prototype IPDM programme, the identification of apple varieties of low disease susceptibility that meet a range of market requirements (dessert, culinary, processing, juice) for organic production and the evaluation of treatments for the control of the most important pests and diseases of apple - scab, mildew and rosy apple aphid. &#xD;
Objective 1. To evaluate and refine an innovative Integrated Pest and Disease Management (IPDM) programme for organic apple production in the UK (programme specified in table 1).&#xD;
Objective 2. To identify 4-6 varieties of apple of low susceptibility to diseases that have high fruit quality, a range of seasons (storage potentials) and markets (dessert, culinary, processing) and are suitable for UK organic production.&#xD;
Objective 3. To determine the activity (eradicant, protectant, antisporulant), persistence and efficacy of eight alternative organically acceptable fungicides for scab and mildew control.&#xD;
Objective 4. To determine and optimise the efficacy of six organically acceptable foliar spray treatments for control of rosy apple aphid.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6763/1/Document.aspx%3FDocumentID%3D322</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Varieties and integrated pest and disease management for organic apple production (LINK).    Runs 2000 - 2005.      Project Leader(s):  Barlow, Adrian and Cross, Jerry, East Malling Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6763/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>