<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ausbreitung des Rapsglanzkäfers innerhalb eines Feldes und in der Landschaft</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Géneau, Céline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlatter, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pollen beetles (Meligethes sp.) are important pests in oilseed rape (Brassica napus). In&#xD;
our study we wanted to determine which landscape structures have an influence on pollen beetle&#xD;
population in early spring. The dynamics of pollen beetle population and the damages on rape were&#xD;
studied on field scale level with 100 sampling points per field and on landscape scale level with 18&#xD;
organic oilseed rape fields which differed by the complexity of the surrounding landscapes. The&#xD;
number of pollen beetle was strongly correlated with the distance to a forest. At the beginning of&#xD;
the flight period more pollen beetles were found close to the forest, later they migrated to the rest of&#xD;
the field. In addition, agricultural practices appeared to be determinant for pest control. Less pollen&#xD;
beetles per plant were found in fields with a higher density of rape plants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20493/1/2009_12RGKMigrationDgaaE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Géneau, Céline; Schlatter, Christian and Daniel, Claudia   (2009) Ausbreitung des Rapsglanzkäfers innerhalb eines Feldes und in der Landschaft.   Mitteilungen der Deutschen Gesellschaft für allgemeine und angewandte Entomologie , 17, pp. 253-256.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20493/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>