<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Presence of predators and parasitoids of Lobesia botrana Den. &amp; Schiff. (Lepidoptera : Tortricidae) in the Mediterranean vineyard.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BEN MOSBAH, Amira</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lobesia botrana is the key pest of vineyard, it presents two to five generations per year which cause a direct damage to grapes by perforating berries and an indirect damage by favoring the installation of rot fungi like Botrytis cinerea. In organic vineyard, L. botrana is biologically controlled by means of predators and parasitoids. For this purpose, field survey, monitoring and sampling were conducted in five different farms in Apulia region as in Tunisia in order to identify the predators and parasitoids of Lobesia botrana. The continuous sampling of nests and infested berries showed in Apulia farms the presence of predators that belong to the order of: Neuroptera, Dermeptera, Orthoptera and Arachnida. The parasitoids found belong to the Diptera order, family of Tachinidae and the order of Hymenoptera, family of Braconidae, subfamily of Aghatidinae.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7013/1/Amirabenbmosbah05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>BEN MOSBAH, Amira   (2005) Presence of predators and parasitoids of Lobesia botrana Den. &amp; Schiff. (Lepidoptera : Tortricidae) in the Mediterranean vineyard.  [Présence des prédateurs et parasitoïdes de Lobesia botrana Den. &amp; Schiff. (Lépidoptères: Tortricidés) dans le vignoble méditerranéen.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 409. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7013/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>