<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Baltic Ecological Recycling Agriculture and Society (BERAS) - Local ecological consumer-producer cooperation for sustainable rural development</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Strategic focus of project is documentation, evaluation, overcoming of obstacles and promotion of ongoing local interaction to achieve more sustainable rural development. The project will increase knowledge, competence and implementation of local, ecological recycling-based food chains to reduce consumption of limited resources, greenhouse gas emissions and eutrophication in the Baltic Sea drainage area. &#xD;
&#xD;
Case studies complemented with scenarios and consequence analyses, of ongoing practical, local ecological initiatives to promote local food supply cooperation between consumers and ecological producers (organic farmers, local food processors and distributors). These studies will be promoted in rural villages in the countries around the Baltic Sea, with the aim of learning and promoting more sustainable food supply systems and lifestyles. &#xD;
&#xD;
The serious environmental situation in the Baltic Sea is a consequence of the unsustainable lifestyle prevailing in the countries around the Baltic Sea (i.e. in its drainage basin). Several studies indicate that, by increasing the production and consumption of ecologically and locally produced food, it is possible to achieve benefits for both the distant and the ambient environment, locally and globally. Reduced use of limited energy resources, resulting in less pollution of air, water and soil, and increased recycling of nutrients in agriculture, reducing leaching from fields, are important goals for a more sustainable lifestyle. They will also contribute positively to regional development, increasing employment and enhancing health and quality of life. Significant local initiatives in this direction can be found in small rural communities in the countries of the Baltic Sea region. Also there is a need to analyze their environmental and economic consequences, as well as the opportunities and obstacles facing different actors along the food chain (individuals, associations, farms and companies). It is also necessary to develop knowledge and skills in this area, and to recognize the potential for and consequences of a larger-scale changeover to such systems throughout the region. &#xD;
&#xD;
The aim is to develop a knowledge base regarding possible means of significantly decreasing consumption of non-renewable energy and other limited resources, and of reducing the negative environmental impacts of production, distribution, processing and consumption of food. At the same time, the measures identified should enhance landscape diversity and promote local economies and employment in rural areas of the Baltic Sea countries.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    BERAS: Baltic Ecological Recycling Agriculture and Society (BERAS) - Local ecological consumer-producer cooperation for sustainable rural development.  [Itämeren alueen ekologisesti kierrättävä maatalous ja yhteiskunta (BERAS) - Kuluttajien ja paikallisten luomutuottajien yhteistyö osana maaseudun kestävää kehitystä.]   Runs 2004 - 2004.      Project Leader(s): Seuri, Pentti and Kuisma, Miia, MTT Agrifood Research Finland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5716/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>