<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer attitudes and expectations of organic wine</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within the European Union-funded research project ORWINE (Organic viticulture and wine-making) a qualitative consumer study was carried out in 2006 in the four case study countries Italy, France, Germany and Switzerland. The aim of the study was to identify consumers’ attitudes and expectations of organic wine. In all case study countries, organic wine has a positive image regarding grape production and wine processing. Furthermore, organic wine is perceived as being healthier compared to conventional wine. However, regarding the sensorial quality, organic wine still faces image problems, although the taste image has improved. Consumers expect that organic wine is healthy, pure and naturally produced. A majority are sceptical of using sulphites and other additives and processing aids in organic wine processing. &#xD;
If organic wine processing is regulated on EU-level, consumers will expect that these rules governing organic wine fit with the image and expectations of organic wine being a “natural” and healthy product, which obtains as much as possible the original attributes and quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13974/1/stolz-schmid-2008-IFOAM_WineCongress_Consumer_study-final_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stolz, Hanna and Schmid, Otto    (2008) Consumer attitudes and expectations of organic wine.       Paper at:   Organic wine and viticulture conference, Levizzano near Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13974/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>