<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of disinfectants on viability of Ascaris suum and&#xD;
Ascaridia galli eggs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gautam, Susmita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Petkeviciute, Egle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Takeuchi-Storm, Nao</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thapa, Sundar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ascaris suum and Ascaridia galli, the large round worm of pigs and poultry, respectively, persist even in intensive management systems, where a high level of hygiene is practiced. It is necessary to control these helminths to minimize production losses and improve animal welfare. Commercial disinfectants are commonly used to clean pens in conventional pig and poultry farms but their efficacy against the thick-shelled nematode eggs has not been sufficiently documented. However, it might be difficult to control these parasites because of their complex thick-shelled eggs, which can resist harsh environmental conditions. Commonly used disinfectants such as Virkon S速, FL-des GA速 typically claim efficacy against viruses, bacteria and some fungi, but very few disinfectants (FL-des Allround速) claim to also eliminate parasite eggs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27348/7/27348.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gautam, Susmita; Petkeviciute, Egle; Takeuchi-Storm, Nao; Thapa, Sundar and Mejer, Helena    (2014) Effect of disinfectants on viability of Ascaris suum and Ascaridia galli eggs.       Poster at:   Spring Symposium of the Danish Society for Parasitlogy, Frederiksberg Campus, B端lowsvej 17, 1870 Frederiksberg C, 28th March 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27348/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>