<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>iPOPY – innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth. School meals – and more!</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spigarolo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roos, Gun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of eight pilot projects in the European CORE Organic programme, innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth, (iPOPY) will study efficient ways of implementing organic food in public serving outlets for young people (2007-10). By analysing practical cases of school meal systems and other food serving outlets for youth, we will identify hindrances and promoting factors in the participating countries (Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway). Policies, supply chains, certification systems, the young consumers’ perception and participation, and health effects of implementation of organic policies and menus are focussed in iPOPY. The main aim is to suggest efficient policies and comprehensive strategies to increase the consumption of organic food among young consumers in a public setting, and fostering sustainable nutrition. Interdisciplinary project tools under development will be presented along with the first project results, which will be available by June 2008.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12447/1/Loes_12447_ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin; Nölting, Benjamin; Kristensen, Niels Heine; Spigarolo, Roberto; Strassner, Carola; Roos, Gun; Mikkola, Minna and Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg    (2008) iPOPY – innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth. School meals – and more!       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12447/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>