<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutritional value of organic raw material for poultry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Juin, Hervé</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feuillet, Dalila</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roinsard, Antoine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of the present study was to evaluate the nutritive interest of different organic and local raw material for  organic broiler nutrition.&#xD;
Chemical analysis and balance study on 35 days old broilers (slow growth strain) were conducted to esti mate metablizable energy and protein digestibilty of 11 raw materials.There was a positive correlation between fat content and metabolizable energy. The results indicated that forages and larva of  insects could contribute to protein feeding in organic  broilers. Technolgy could represent an interesting wazy to increase nutritional value of local seeds (such as linseed, sunflower). There is need to complementary study like amino acid profile or incorporation in the diet during the life of animal.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23930/1/23930_nutritional_value_of_organic_raw_material_poultry_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Juin, Hervé; Feuillet, Dalila and Roinsard, Antoine    (2014) Nutritional value of organic raw material for poultry.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 291-294.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23930/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>