<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Digging deeper: How do different types of organic consumers influence the increasing organic market share?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Laura M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lund, Thomas B</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Danish market for organic foods is one of the most mature markets in the world. The organic budget share is among the highest, and the share of sales through conventional supermarkets is very large. After a period of stagnation the organic budget share is now again increasing in Denmark. This paper identifies six consumer segments with different attitudes towards food in general and organic production and products in particular, and investigates differences in purchasing patterns with regards to organic budget share. The segmentation splits consumers into a positive and a non-positive half, each half consisting of three different segments. The segments behave very differently both in terms of development in general organic consumption, and with regard to developments in the consumption of organic food in specific product categories. The positive half of the population has driven the overall growth in organic budget share at the Danish market over the period 2005 to 2007, while the other half have not changed their consumption significantly. The results also indicate that for the most dedicated organic consumers, the organic budget share may be approaching a saturation point in some commodity groups.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18694/1/18694.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Andersen, Laura M and Lund, Thomas B    (2010) Digging deeper: How do different types of organic consumers influence the increasing organic market share?    Food Policy.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18694/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>