<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of different forages on gastrointestinal namatode infections in grazing lambs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thamsborg, S.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bandier, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nematode infections of sheep may be influenced by secondary compounds in the diet, e.g. condensed tannins. A study was performed with 7 groups of lambs experimentally infected with Teladorsagia circumcincta and Trichostronglylus vitrinus. All groups were grazed on clean clover-grass pasture and then moved to paddocks with bioactive forages with either sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia) (groups Pre-S and Post-S), chicory (Cichorium intybus, cv. Grasslands Puna) (Pre-C and Post-C) or clover-grass as reference (Pre-G and Post-G). Pre-groups were infected before the move to bioactive forages, whereas all Post-groups were infected after the move. Group Pre-ctrl. was slaughtered for worm counts at the time of the move while the other groups were slaughtered after 5-8 weeks on bioactive forages. The faecal egg counts of pre-groups dropped markedly after the move, and Pre-S showed the fastest decline, by 80% within 3 weeks after the move. The mean faecal egg counts of Post-S was reduced by 40% 4 weeks p.i. compared to Post-G (p&lt;0.01) whereas Post-C was 30-100% higher (p&lt;0.01). T. circumcincta worm counts of Pre-S, Pre-C and Pre-G were 4300, 3200 and 7000 but differences were not significant due to large variation within groups (Pre-C vs. Pre-G: p=0.12). Other worm counts were not significantly different. The study indicates a marked reduction in faecal egg counts when lambs graze sainfoin and a possible anti-parasitic effect of chicory on abomasal worms.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Harrington, Kathleen Story</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4520/1/4520.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thamsborg, S.M.; Mejer, H.; Bandier, M. and Larsen, M.    (2003) Influence of different forages on gastrointestinal namatode infections in grazing lambs.   In: Harrington, Kathleen Story (Ed.)  Proceedings of the 19th International Conference of the World Association for the Advancement of Veterinary Parasitology, August 10th-14th 2003, New Orleans, Louisiana, USA, p. 189, p. 189.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4520/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>