<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Esparsettensamen in der Ferkelaufzucht – Leistungsdaten und Blutparameter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hagmueller, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baldinger, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Minihuber, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The seeds of sainfoin (Onobrychis viciifolia) are rich in protein and show a very attractive amino acid pattern for growing pigs. Nevertheless sainfoin is mainly used as a forage legume. Due to its content of condensed tannins it is especially beneficial for small ruminants battling gastrointestinal nematodes. Apart from that sainfoin is also used as green manure in some Austrian regions. As part of the EU Core Organic II research project ICOPP (Improved contribution of local feed to support 100 % organic feed supply to pigs and poultry) a feeding trial was conducted in which sainfoin seeds replaced peas and soybean cake. The proportion of sainfoin ranged between 10 % and 16 % (as fed basis), seeds were either dehulled (G10, G16) or used untreated (S10). Neither body weight gain nor feed intake differed between treatments. Due to higher crude protein in the experimental diets, serum urea was significantly higher in the sainfoin groups at the end of the trial. It is concluded that sainfoin seeds are an adequate protein source for piglets and can replace peas and soybean cake in rearing diets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21385/1/21385_Hagmueller.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hagmueller, Werner; Baldinger, Lisa; Minihuber, Ulrike and Zollitsch, Werner    (2013) Esparsettensamen in der Ferkelaufzucht – Leistungsdaten und Blutparameter.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21385/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>