<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Multielemental fingerprinting as a tool for authentication  of organic wheat, barley, faba bean and potato</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, Kristian Holst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjoerring, Jan K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halekoh, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The multielemental composition of organic and conventional winter wheat, spring barley, faba bean, and potato was analyzed with inductively coupled plasma−optical emission spectrometry (ICP-OES) and −mass spectrometry (ICP-MS). The crops were cultivated in two years at three geographically different field locations, each accommodating one conventional and two organic cropping systems. The conventional system produced the highest harvest yields for all crops except the nitrogen-fixing faba bean, whereas the dry matter content of each crop was similar across systems. No systematic differences between organic and conventional crops were found in the content of essential plant nutrients when statistically analyzed individually. However, chemometric analysis of multielemental fingerprints comprising up to 14 elements allowed discrimination. The discrimination power was further enhanced by analysis of up to 25 elements derived from semiquantitative ICP-MS. It is concluded that multielemental fingerprinting with semiquantitative ICP-MS and chemometrics has the potential to enable authentication of organic crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19091/4/19091.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Laursen, Kristian Holst; Schjoerring, Jan K.; Olesen, Jørgen E.; Askegaard, Margrethe; Halekoh, Ulrich and Husted, Søren   (2011) Multielemental fingerprinting as a tool for authentication of organic wheat, barley, faba bean and potato.   Journal of Agricultural and Food chemistry, 59, pp. 4385-4396.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19091/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>