<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Repeated use of green-manure catch crops in organic cereal&#xD;
production - grain yields and nitrogen supply</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Trond Maukon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eltun, Ragnar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sjursen, Helge</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>By restricted access to manure, nitrogen (N) supply in organic agriculture relies on biological N-fixation. This study compares grain yields after one full-season green manure (FSGM) to yields with repeated use of a green-manure catch crop. At two sites in south-eastern Norway, in a simple 4-year rotation (oats/wheat/oats/wheat), the repeated use of ryegrass, clover, or a mixture of ryegrass and clover as catch crops was compared with an FSGM established as a catch crop in year 1. The FSGM treatments had no subsequent catch crops. In year 5, the final residual effects were measured in barley.&#xD;
&#xD;
The yield levels were about equal for grains with no catch crop and a ryegrass catch crop. On average, the green-manure catch crops increased subsequent cereal yields close to 30%. The FSGM increased subsequent cereal yields significantly in two years, but across the rotation the yields were comparable to those of the treatments without green-manure catch crop. To achieve acceptable yields under Norwegian conditions, more than 25% of the land should be used for full-season green manure, or this method combined with green-manure catch crops. The accumulated amount of N in aboveground biomass in late autumn did not compensate for the N removed by cereal yields. To account for the deficiency, the roots of the green-manure catch crops would have to contain about 60% of the total N (tot-N) required to balance the cereal yields. Such high average values for root N are likely not realistic to achieve. However, measurement of biomass in late autumn may not reflect all N made available to concurrent or subsequent main crops</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18531/1/Final_version_March_2011_Repeated_use_of_green_manure_catch_crops.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/vnd.ms-powerpoint</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18531/4/Field_photo_for_Acta_Fig_3.ppt</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18531/5/QLIF_Hohenheim_mars_2007_final_file%2C_Loes-etal-undersowing-of-legumes-2007.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin; Henriksen, Trond Maukon; Eltun, Ragnar and Sjursen, Helge   (2011) Repeated use of green-manure catch crops in organic cereal production - grain yields and nitrogen supply.   Acta Agriculturae Scandinavica Section B Soil and Plant Science, 61 (2), pp. 164-175.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18531/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>