<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Versuche mit Milasana@ und B.brevis auf Nebeneffekte gegen Typhlodromus pyri (Acari, Phytoseiidae) und Aphidius rhopalosiphi (Hymenoptera, Braconidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schuld, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>White, Duncan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seddon, Barrie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ernst, Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmitt, Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Data from laboratory range-finder and field test indicate that both biological agents, Milsana (VP 2000) and B. brevis WT, can be judged well-suitable for use in organic or integrated control systems. There were no negative effects recorded against Typhlodromus pyri (Laboratory and field) and Aphidius rhopalosiphi (Iaboratory). For further confirmation, limit tests under GLP (with the highest tested concentration) will be performed in the near future. When Myco-Sin was applied in combination with Milsana in the field, population levels of T. pyri were raised compared to the control.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14637/1/schuld_231.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schuld, Michael; White, Duncan; Seddon, Barrie; Ernst, Annegret and Schmitt, Annegret    (2002) Versuche mit Milasana@ und B.brevis auf Nebeneffekte gegen Typhlodromus pyri (Acari, Phytoseiidae) und Aphidius rhopalosiphi (Hymenoptera, Braconidae).  [Tests with Milsana@ and Brevibacillus brevis for side-effects against Typhlodromus pyri (Acari, Phytoseiidae) and Aphidius rhopalosiphi (Hymenoptera, Braconidae).]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing and Viticulture. Proceedings to the Conference from 4th to 7th Feb. 2002 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 231-235.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>