<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetic uniqueness and socio-cultural conservation values of the endangered Yakutian Cattle</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kantanen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Granberg, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kopoteva, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Partanen, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pääkkönen, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soini, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At the local level the values of the cattle were more related to everyday livelihood strategies of single households and families, whereas the representatives of the republic, in line with the newspapers, highlighted the importance of the cattle for Sakha's food production and for national identity. Thus, individuals at different levels were in favour of conserving the cattle, but for different reasons. The local residents and experts were more concerned about developing economically sustainable cattle production, whereas the experts in Yakutsk were concerned about the conservation of genetic resources. The genetic studies have indicated that Yakutian Cattle show genetic distinctiveness and have genetic value for the maintenance of cattle diversity.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18056/1/Kantanen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kantanen, J.; Granberg, L.; Kopoteva, I.; Partanen, U.; Pääkkönen, E. and Soini, K.    (2010) Genetic uniqueness and socio-cultural conservation values of the endangered Yakutian Cattle.       Paper at:   9th World congress on genetics applied to livestock production, Leipzig, Germany, August 1-6, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18056/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>