<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Grain yield of different winter pea genotypes in pure and mixed stands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graß, Rüdiger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schüler, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schliephake, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trautz, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming, harvest of spring peas is a problem because of the often high density of weeds, but also the low yield stability. In the present experiments, seven different genotypes of winter peas (six regular types and one semi-leafless type) and one spring pea (semi-leafless) were examined between 2004  and 2007 in pure and mixed stands (with cereals) in terms of their suitability as a harvest crop at two different sites per season in Germany (experimental fields of the University of Kassel Frankenhausen (2004-2007), Hebenshausen (2004) and  the experimental farm of the University of Applied Sciences Osnabrueck, Waldhof (2005-2007).&#xD;
Grain yields of the regular leaf type in mixed stands during the first three years varied because of varying N supply (preceding crops and weather conditions). When availability of N was relatively low, pea grain yield ranged between 2.5 and 4.0 t ha-1 in Frankenhausen and 1.5 and 2.5 t ha-1 in Waldhof, and were at levels comparable to spring pea yield, which varied from 2.0-3.4 to 1.5 t ha-1, respectively. In addition, mixtures contribute rye yield. At a relatively high N supply, pea yields were relatively low, but rye yields relatively high. Crude protein concentration and concentration of some amino acids (lysine, tryptophan and arginine) partially were significantly (p&lt;0.05) higher in the regular leaf types than in the semi-leafless types.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11803/1/Urbatzka_11803_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, Peer; Graß, Rüdiger; Schüler, Christian; Schliephake, Ulrike; Trautz, Dieter and Heß, Jürgen    (2008) Grain yield of different winter pea genotypes in pure and mixed stands.       Paper at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11803/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>