<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diversity of organic farming systems: Challenges for the construction of markets, varieties and plant breeding techniques</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DESCLAUX, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>CHIFFOLEAU, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>NOLOT, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>New societal values call for the diversification of agriculture to fit contrasted environments. This process can be depicted by four models defined by two axes, a socio-economic axis (individual logic vs. collective governance), and an agro-ecological axis (analytical vs. systemic approaches). These models differ in: (i) their objectives (from improvement in yield to the empowerment of farmers), (ii) their specific expectations with respect to genotypes (from inherited genetic resources to varieties that represent genetic, ethical and social progress), and (iii) their representations of the environment (from a simple interaction between the bio-physical environment and crop management, to a complex interaction including the skills of stakeholders, outlets, regulations and society). Taking this diversity into account changes the way plant improvement is envisioned. Depending on the model, the five classic stages of plant improvement (setting objectives, creating variability, selecting, evaluating and disseminating) may be called into question. Between the existing analytical model (model I) and a holistic model (model IV) that remains to be developed, lies the challenge of ensuring the sustainability, efficiency and acceptability of plant breeding and resulting innovations.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15496/1/41-Desclaux.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>DESCLAUX, D. ; CHIFFOLEAU, Y.  and NOLOT, J.M.    (2009) Diversity of organic farming systems: Challenges for the construction of markets, varieties and plant breeding techniques.  [Pluralité des agricultures biologiques : Enjeux pour la construction des marchés, le choix des variétés et les schémas d’amélioration des plantes.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 297-306.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15496/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>