<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic and conventional public food procurement for youth in Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Young consumers are an important target group, because habits are established at young age. Hence, introducing children to organic food in public settings such as schools may be an efficient way to increase the consumption of organic food.&#xD;
In Norway, public procurement of food to youth is not well developed in comparison to many other European and Scandinavian countries. Many kindergartens provide some simple dishes for the children, and upper secondary schools usually have canteens where food items, sometimes also warm dishes, may be purchased. Canteens are becoming more common in other schools, especially on the lower secondary level. However, the usual lunch for most children in Norway in 2010 is a packed lunch (sandwiches) brought from home, consumed in the class room. School subscription schemes for milk were introduced around 1970, and for fruit around 1995. By June 2010, organic milk in 0.25 litre containers (“school milk”) is offered only in Mid-Norway, and organic fruit is hardly offered at all. Since 2007, fruit is served without payment in all schools with a lower secondary level (class 8-10 or 1-10). This effort was introduced as a first step to develop a free school meal in all public schools, but has not been further developed so far.&#xD;
As in many other European countries, free school meals were offered (especially to poor children) in schools in the larger Norwegian cities around 1900. However, these meals were criticised for being unhealthy, and replaced by whole grain bread, milk and vegetables around 1930. Increasing private wealth, and increased demand for investments in school buildings, books etc changed the public priority and free school meals gradually disappeared. Today, there is not a general agreement about the optimal school meal composition, and whether or not the meals should be funded by the public. Several factors such as increasing lengths of the school day, and unsatisfactory scores in international comparison tests (e.g. PISA), should awake people‟s interest in school food. However, the public debate about school meals is in 2010 almost absent in Norway. The number of schools offering some kind of foods for sale e.g. in canteens is however rapidly increasing, which may contribute to change the school food situation.&#xD;
As a part of the ”Økoløft” (“Organic lift”) project and other initiatives, organic food has been presented and served for children in kindergartens, schools and other settings in several municipalities. Some cities (Trondheim, Stavanger) have set up public goals of organic consumption, including organic shares of food served in schools and child care. Such cases are briefly described, along with the Øya music festival and the Norwegian Armed Forces. The two latter cases serve significant amounts of organic food for relatively young consumers.&#xD;
The report was produced in the iPOPY project, “innovative Public Organic food Procurement for Youth”. Similar reports have been produced for the other iPOPY countries; Denmark, Finland and Italy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioforsk Organic Food and Farming</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17411/1/NATIONAL_REPORT_BIOFORSK_RAPPORT__NORWAY_siste_utgave.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin         (2010) Organic and conventional public food procurement for youth in Norway.    Bioforsk Organic Food and Farming, Tingvoll, Norway.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17411/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>