<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessment of four compost types on the nematode population dynamics in the soil sown with okra</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Olabiyi, Timothy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oladeji, O.O</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two parallel experiments were conducted at the Teaching and Research Farm, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology and Papa Aireke Farm, both at Ogbomoso, Nigeria, to assess the effect of four different compost types on the nematode population dynamics; the growth and yield of okra, sown into nematode infested soil. Each of the compost was prepared through Rapid Composting Technology with Trichoderma harzianum as decomposer, using Windrow method. The four compost types were neem based, cassava peel based, sawdust based and Tithonia based. Nematode susceptible okra variety (NHAe-84-1) was used as test plant. The compost was applied at the rate of 1ton/ha to the treated okra while the okra plants on the untreated soil served as the control. The experimental design was randomized complete block. Data collected included nematode root damage (root gall index), population of juvenile nematode in 10g root and the population dynamics of different nematodes species in the soil. Data were also collected on the plant height, number of leaf/plant, root length, number of pod/plant, pod weight, number of seed/pod of okra. Application of the composts significantly (p&lt;0.05) enhanced plant height, number of leaf, root length, number of pod, pod weight and number of seed of okra. The result showed that the compost significantly (p&lt;0.05) reduced the root damage (root gall index).  The population of Meloidogyne, Heterodera, Tylenchus, Tylenchulus species (nematode population dynamics) in the soil treated with composts and of root knot nematode juveniles in the root were significantly reduced.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-02-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28203/7/28203.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Olabiyi, Timothy and Oladeji, O.O   (2014) Assessment of four compost types on the nematode population dynamics in the soil sown with okra.   International Journal of Organic Agriculture Research and Development, 9, pp. 146-155.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28203/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>