<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results and discussion</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vesala, Kari</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this chapter, the interdisciplinary synthesis of the results of the BERAS project is presented and discussed. First, the effects of localisation and enhanced recycling on the ecological, economic and social dimensions of sustainability based on the case studies are reported, the cases where food systems and farms studied in their present state. Thereafter, the positive additional effects on sustainability obtainable by further promotion of localisation and recycling in the cases are suggested. The impact of total conversion to recycling organic agriculture is then considered. Obstacles to and solutions for localisation and recycling are identified. An finally, on the basis of these, conclusions about the sustainable way to localise and recycle are presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Berg, Per G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Granstedt, Artur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fischer, Holger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Thomsson, Olof</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8777/1/BERAS5.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kahiluoto, Helena and Vesala, Kari    (2006) Results and discussion.    In: Kahiluoto, Helena; Berg, Per G.; Granstedt, Artur; Fischer, Holger and Thomsson, Olof (Eds.)  The power of local - sustainable food systems around the Baltic sea : interdisciplinary synthesis of the BERAS project. Baltic Ecological Recycling Agriculture and Society (BERAS), no. 7. Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences, Centre for Sustainable Agriculture, pp. 32-51.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8777/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>