<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Visual ecology of aphids – a critical review on the role of colours in host finding</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chittka, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We review the rich literature on behavioural responses of aphids (Hemiptera: Aphididae) to stimuli of different colours. Only in one species there are adequate physiological data on spectral sensitivity to explain behaviour crisply in mechanistic terms. &#xD;
Because of the great interest in aphid responses to coloured targets from an evolutionary, ecological and applied perspective, there is a substantial need to expand these studies to more species of aphids, and to quantify spectral properties of stimuli rigorously. We show that aphid responses to colours, at least for some species, are likely based on a specific colour opponency mechanism, with positive input from the green domain of the spectrum and negative input from the blue and/or UV region. &#xD;
We further demonstrate that the usual yellow preference of aphids encountered in field experiments is not a true colour preference but involves additional brightness effects. We discuss the implications for agriculture and sensory ecology, with special respect to the recent debate on autumn leaf colouration. We illustrate that recent evolutionary theories concerning aphid–tree interactions imply far-reaching assumptions on aphid responses to colours&#xD;
that are not likely to hold. Finally we also discuss the&#xD;
implications for developing and optimising strategies&#xD;
of aphid control and monitoring.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19804/1/2007.Doring_%26_Chittka.APIS.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Döring, Thomas F. and Chittka, Lars   (2007) Visual ecology of aphids – a critical review on the role of colours in host finding.   Arthropod Plant Interactions, 1, pp. 3-16.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19804/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>