<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE EFFECT OF COMBINATIONS OF ORGANIC MATERIALS AND BIOFERTILISERS ON PRODUCTIVITY, GRAIN QUALITY, NUTRIENT&#xD;
UPTAKE AND ECONOMICS IN ORGANIC FARMING OF WHEAT</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Davari, Mohammadreza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, Shri Niwas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mirzakhani, Mohammad</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming often has to deal with a scarcity of readily available nutrients, and this is in contrast to chemical farming which relies on soluble fertilisers. The present study was conducted to ascertain the effect of different combinations of organic manures, rice residues and biofertilisers in organic farming of wheat. The field experiments were carried out on the research farm of Indian Agricultural Research Institute (IARI), New Delhi in 2006-07 and 2007-08. Treatments consisted of a control (no fertiliser) and six fertiliser treatments, namely, farmyard manure (FYM), vermicompost (VC), FYM + rice residue (RR), VC + RR, FYM + RR + biofertilisers (B), and VC + RR + B. FYM and VC were applied on nitrogen basis (60 kg ha-1), whereas RR was applied at 6 t ha-1. For biofertilisers, Azotobacter, cellulolytic culture (CC) and phosphate solubilising bacteria (PSB) were used. The combinations of FYM + RR + B and VC + RR + B resulted in the highest increased growth and yield attributing characters of wheat and increased grain yield of wheat over the control by 81% and 89% (Year 1 &amp; Year 2), and net return by 82% and 73%. These combinations were significantly superior to all other combinations for all the growth and yield parameters, yield, net profit and grain quality of wheat. The results of this study show that VC + RR + B was the most productive treatment, while FYM + RR + B was the most economical treatment with respect to increasing net profit. This was because of the higher price of vermicompost compared with FYM. Both of these combinations resulted in improved grain quality and nutrient uptake by grain. The present study thus indicates that a combination of FYM + RR + biofertilisers or VC + RR + biofertilisers hold promise for organic wheat farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21901/7/21901.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Davari, Mohammadreza; Sharma, Shri Niwas and Mirzakhani, Mohammad   (2012) THE EFFECT OF COMBINATIONS OF ORGANIC MATERIALS AND BIOFERTILISERS ON PRODUCTIVITY, GRAIN QUALITY, NUTRIENT UPTAKE AND ECONOMICS IN ORGANIC FARMING OF WHEAT.   Journal of Organic Systems, 7 (2), pp. 26-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21901/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>