<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PRODUCCIÓN DE TOMATE EN INVERNADERO CON COMPOSTA Y&#xD;
VERMICOMPOSTA COMO SUSTRATO</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Efraín, de la Cruz-Lázaro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maximiano A, Estrada-Botello</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valentín , Robledo-Torres</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rodolfo, Osorio-Osorio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Candido, Márquez-Hernández</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rufo, Sánchez-Hernández</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic production of food is an alternative for consumers that prefer food free of pesticides, synthetic&#xD;
fertilisers, and with a high nutritional value. The purpose of this study was to evaluate substrates prepared with&#xD;
mixtures of compost and vermicompost with sand, at various levels, under greenhouse conditions. The tomato hybrid&#xD;
SUN-7705 (Lycopersicon esculentum Mill) was analized in four substrates that included compost and vermicompost&#xD;
mixed at three different proportions (100, 75 y 50 %). The treatments were distributed in a completely randomised&#xD;
design with a factorial arrangement of 4x3 and five replicates. The greatest average yield (39.811 t ha) was obtained with the compost generated by decomposing bovine manure, corn stover (Zea mays L.), elephant grass (Pennisetum purpureum Schumacher) and black earth (CEMZT) at 75% + sand, and with the vermicompost generated by manure, bahiagrass (Paspalum notatum Flügge) and black earth (VEPT) at 100 and 50% + sand. This yield was greater than that recorded for organic tomato production in the field, without affecting the quality of the fruit.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universidad  Juáez Autónoma de Tabasco</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16034/2/16034.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Efraín, de la Cruz-Lázaro; Maximiano A, Estrada-Botello; Valentín , Robledo-Torres; Rodolfo, Osorio-Osorio; Candido, Márquez-Hernández and Rufo, Sánchez-Hernández   (2009) PRODUCCIÓN DE TOMATE EN INVERNADERO CON COMPOSTA Y VERMICOMPOSTA COMO SUSTRATO.  [Tomato production in greenhouse using compost and vermicompost as sustrate.]  Universidad y Ciencia, 25 (1), pp. 59-67.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16034/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>