<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Leaching of Mineral Nitrogen, Organic Nitrogen and Phosphorous in Conventional &amp; Organic Farming in Korean Greenhouse</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sohn, Sang-Mok</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kim, Young-Ho</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yoon, Deok-Hoon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuecke, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to receive basic data on the transport of mineral and organic N and P from the top soil to the subsoil in conventional and organic farming in Korea. It was focused to deliver the information about the environmental impact of Korean organic farming systems with regards to ground water pollution. High ammonium concentrations have been recorded in the seepage waters from the organic farming system, while the concentrations were negligibly low in the conventional farming plots as also found in other open field studies. The content of organic nitrogen in the seepage water from conventional farming systems were up to 4 % of the total nitrogen in the seepage water, while it was increased to 8% in organic farming systems. The content of total organic phosphorous are is 6 times higher in the organic farming soils under greenhouse conditions compared to the conventionally fertilized soils under greenhouse. It was concluded that the Korean organic farming system shows some ecological risks in term of ground water pollution not only by nitrate and mineral phosphate, but also by organic nitrogen and phosphorus.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4479/4/Sohn_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sohn, Sang-Mok; Kim, Young-Ho; Yoon, Deok-Hoon and Kuecke, Martin    (2005) Leaching of Mineral Nitrogen, Organic Nitrogen and Phosphorous in Conventional &amp; Organic Farming in Korean Greenhouse.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4479/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>