<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Residents’ preferences and use of urban and peri-urban green spacesin a Swiss mountainous region of the Southern Alps</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Conedera, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Del Biaggio, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seeland, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moretti, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Home, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Urban sprawl and population growth lead to loss of contact with nature for urban residents; thus giving more importance to the remaining urban green spaces for the residents’ well-being. In this study, weassess the preferences and uses of urban and peri-urban green spaces by inhabitants of the city center andof the bordering areas of the pre-alpine city of Bellinzona in southern Switzerland. In a quantitative surveyin which a questionnaire was mailed to a selective quota of 1000 local households, we asked about generalperceptions of the quality of life; the general importance of the green on the surrounding mountain slopes; the frequency of urban and peri-urban green space visitation including the activities undertaken in them;and the motivations for engaging in those activities. The results of a multivariate analysis, which includedlinear modeling and ordinal regression, show that visual contact with the green slopes of the mountainsis a decisive contribution to the perceived general quality of life for the inhabitants of Bellinzona and surroundings. This positive perception tends to increase with closer proximity of available private or urbangreen spaces. Different motivations for visiting urban green spaces were found, and vary among inhabitants according to age and gender, which indicates the existence of different user groups with differentperceptions and also different (and potentially contrasting) needs with respect to the green areas. Thepractical implications of these differences for managing and planning urban green spaces are discussed.&#xD;
© 2015 Elsevier GmbH. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28888/1/Conedera-etal-2015_urban-green-Bellinzonese.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Conedera, M.; Del Biaggio, A.; Seeland, K.; Moretti, M. and Home, R.   (2015) Residents’ preferences and use of urban and peri-urban green spacesin a Swiss mountainous region of the Southern Alps.   Urban Forestry &amp; Urban Greening, 14, pp. 139-147.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28888/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>