<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic certification labels from the perspective of consumers in Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Janssen, Meike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic labels have been established to communicate the consumer that a certain product has been produced according to defined organic standards. The aim of the research presented in this paper was to investigate i) how Swiss organic consumers perceived different organic labels and ii) if Swiss organic consumers prefer particular organic certification schemes over others. To achieve these objectives, we carried out focus group discussions with organic consumers, and conducted consumer choice experiments&#xD;
that were combined with a subsequent structured questionnaire. We focused on two labels that are well established in the Swiss market – one mostly in specialised organic shops (Demeter label), the other one also found widely in a larger retail shop (Bio Suisse label «Knospe&#xD;
»). Our analysis shows the high level of awareness of the Bio Suisse label among Swiss consumers. Furthermore, the study provides evidence for the importance of trust in labels in the Swiss organic market.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22257/8/stolz-etal-2013-YSA2013-abstract.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stolz, Hanna; Moschitz, Heidrun and Janssen, Meike   (2013) Organic certification labels from the perspective of consumers in Switzerland.   Yearbook of Socioeconomics in Agriculture, 2013, pp. 225-246.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22257/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>