<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Practice Oriented Results on Use and Production of Neem - Ingredients and Pheromones</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Contents:&#xD;
&#xD;
General Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
TECHNICAL AND MARKETING ORIENTATION OF NATURAL PRODUCTS TO&#xD;
APPLICATIONS&#xD;
Samitha Senevirathne, Samadara Dissanayake&#xD;
&#xD;
RECHTLICHE SITUATION ZUR ANWENDUNG VON PFLANZENSCHUTZMITTELN (INSBESONDERE HERSTELLUNG IM EIGENEN BETRIEB)&#xD;
Joachim Kunze&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Neem - Products for Insect Control&#xD;
&#xD;
ECONOMICS OF NEEM PROCESSING BY SMALL-SCALE ENTREPRENEURS IN THAILAND, KENYA AND THE DOMINICAN REPUBLIC - RESULTS OF AN EVALUATION OF GTZ-ASSISTED PROJECTS&#xD;
Peter H. Foerster, W. Leupolz, H. Quentin, S. Praneetvatakul&#xD;
&#xD;
USE OF NEEM (AZADIRACHTA INDICA A. JUSS) AND ITS BY-PRODUCTS IN ORGANIC FARMING&#xD;
C. M. Ketkar&#xD;
&#xD;
NEEMAZAL-T/S AGAINST DIFFERENT PESTS IN SWITZERLAND 1998 /1999&#xD;
Daniel Zingg&#xD;
&#xD;
RESULTS OF NEEMAZAL-T/S AGAINST WHITE FLIES IN PRACTICE&#xD;
Wim Manger&#xD;
&#xD;
FIRST RESULTS OF NEEM APPLICATION BY TREE INFUSION AND TRUNKPAINTING AGAINST LEAF DESTROYING INSECTS&#xD;
Manfred Lehmann&#xD;
&#xD;
THE EFFECT OF NEEM EXTRACTS ON THE TURNIP ROOT FLY AND THE CABBAGE MOTH&#xD;
Richard Meadow, Randi Seljåsen and Per Brynildsen&#xD;
&#xD;
EFFECTS OF NATURAL AND SYNTHETIC INSECTICIDES ON THE SWEET POTATO WHITEFLY [BEMISIA TABACI (GENNADIUS)] (HOMOPTERA: ALEYRODIDAE) AND OTHER INSECT PESTS OF TOMATO AND PUMPKIN IN PANAMA&#xD;
Juan A. Bernal Vega, Thies Basedow and José A. Guerra&#xD;
&#xD;
WIRKSAMKEIT VON NEEMAZAL-T/S GEGEN DIE KIRSCHBLÜTENMOTTE (ARGYRESTHIA PRUNIELLA L.) IM RAHMEN DER BEKÄMPFUNG DES FROSTSPANNERS (OPEROPHTHERA BRUMATA L.) IN SAUERKIRSCHEN&#xD;
Harald Rank&#xD;
&#xD;
BEOBACHTUNGEN ZUR VERMEIDUNG DURCH NEEM BEDINGTER PFLANZENSCHÄDEN&#xD;
Gabriele Köhler, Heidi Baresch, Jutta Petzold&#xD;
&#xD;
DIVERSE EFFECTS OF NEEMAZAL-T/S REVEALED BY PREIMAGINAL STAGES OF COLORADO POTATO BEETLES, LEPTINOTARSA DECEMLINEATA SAY&#xD;
Külli Hiiesaar, Luule Metspalu, Juhan Jõudu, Aare Kuusik&#xD;
&#xD;
ON THE INFLUENCE OF NEEM PREPARATIONS ON SOME AGRICULTURAL AND FOREST PESTS&#xD;
Luule Metspalu, Anne Luik, Külli Hiiesaar, Aare Kuusik and Ivar Sibul&#xD;
&#xD;
POTENTIALE VON NEEMAZAL-T/S IN DER BEKÄMPFUNG DER MEHLIGEN KOHLBLATTLAUS (BREVICORYNE BRASSICAE)&#xD;
Raschid El Khafif und Jan Plagge&#xD;
&#xD;
EFFECTS OF SOME COMMERCIAL NEEM-BASED INSECTICIDES AGAINST NILAPARVATA LUGENS (BPH), SOGATELLA FURCIFERA (WBPH) AND NEPHOTETTIX VIRESCENS (GLH) - PART 1&#xD;
K. Mahesh Kumar, N. V. Krishnaiah, T. Lingaiah, I. C. Pasalu, K. Krishnaiah&#xD;
&#xD;
EFFECTS OF SOME COMMERCIAL NEEM-BASED INSECTICIDES AGAINST NILAPARVATA LUGENS (BPH), SOGATELLA FURCIFERA (WBPH) AND NEPHOTETTIX VIRESCENS (GLH) - PART 2&#xD;
K. Mahesh Kumar, N. V. Krishnaiah, T. Lingaiah, I. C. Pasalu, K. Krishnaiah&#xD;
&#xD;
THE EFFECT OF NEEMAZALÒ-T/S, A COMMERCIAL NEEM PRODUCT, ON DIFFERENT DEVELOPMENTAL STAGES OF THE COMMON GREENHOUSE WHITE FLY TRIALEURODES VAPORARIORUM WESTWOOD (HOM.: ALEYRODIDAE)&#xD;
Kerstin von Elling, Christian Borgemeister, Mamoudou Sétamou and Hans-Michael Poehling&#xD;
&#xD;
EFFECTS OF AQUEOUS NEEM AND MELIA AZEDARACH EXTRACTS ON THE EARLY DEVELOPMENT OF EUREMA BLANDA (LEPIDOPTERA: PIERIDAE)&#xD;
Alois S. Jenkihau, Bowin S. Tuman, Michael F. Schneider&#xD;
&#xD;
COMBINATION OF BACILLUS THURINGIENSIS-PRODUCTS AND NEEMAZAL-T/S FOR THE CONTROL OF THE WINTER MOTH OPEROPHTERA BRUMATA L.&#xD;
Christof Schulz, Jutta Kienzle, Philipp Haug, Sophia Kumpmann, Claus P.W. Zebitz&#xD;
&#xD;
HARICOT VERT - ESSAI PHYTOSANITAIRE&#xD;
Vincent Salat&#xD;
&#xD;
PROSPECTS OF USING NEEM PRODUCTS AND PHEROMONES AS PEST CONTROL TOOLS ON TARGET ORGANISMS IN TEA IN SRI LANKA&#xD;
Sushila I. Vitarana&#xD;
&#xD;
EFFECTS OF NEEMAZAL ON FISH: FULL LIFE CYCLE TEST WITH THE ZEBRAFISH, DANIO RERIO&#xD;
Achim Schmitz, Christoph Schäfers, Ralf Troß, Beate Ruch and Hubertus Kleeberg&#xD;
&#xD;
HPTLC (HIGH PERFORMANCE THIN LAYER CHROMATOGRAPHY) ANALYSIS OF NEEM SAMPLES&#xD;
G. Srimannarayana, T. J. Dennis&#xD;
&#xD;
MALARIA-CONTROL WITH NEEM PRODUCTS IN THE MOPTI REGION IN MALI, WEST AFRICA&#xD;
Jörg Grunewald and Andreas Vollmer&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Other Plant Extracts&#xD;
&#xD;
REPELLENT AND TOXIC EFFECTS OF DIFFERENT PLANT EXTRACTS ON RETICULITERMES SANTONENSIS (ISOPTERA: RHINOTERMITIDAE)&#xD;
Verena-Ulrike Bläske&#xD;
&#xD;
THE EFFECTS OF BOTANICAL PESTICIDES ON DIAMONDBACK MOTH&#xD;
Almie M. van den Berg&#xD;
&#xD;
PURIFICATION AND VALUATION OF INSECT GROWTH REGULATORS FROM LEAVES AND ROOTS OF GLYCOSMIS PENTAPHYLLA (RUTACEAE)&#xD;
Klaus H. Hoffmann, Matthias W. Lorenz and Jayarama Muthukrishnan&#xD;
&#xD;
NEEM OIL AGAINST PLANT DISEASES IN SWITZERLAND 1999&#xD;
Daniel Zingg&#xD;
&#xD;
EXTRASOL - A NEW MULTIFUNCTIONAL BIO-PREPARATION FOR ECOLOGICALLY SAFE AGRICULTURE&#xD;
Vladimir Chebotar, Anatoly Khotyanovich, Alexandr Cazacov&#xD;
&#xD;
WILDVERGRÄMUNGS- UND ABLENKUNGSEFFEKTE VON "REHPELL"- DISPENSERN IN NICHT GEWERBSMÄßIG GEFÜHRTEN GEHÖLZBESTÄNDEN&#xD;
Manfred Lehmann&#xD;
&#xD;
PRELIMINARY RESULTS ON THE USE OF ANTI-MARTEN DISPENSERS "MARDER-STUNK" IN MOTOR CARS&#xD;
Manfred Lehmann&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Pheromones&#xD;
&#xD;
ANFORDERUNGEN AN PHEROMONE BEI DEREN ANWENDUNG IM MASSENFANG AM BEISPIEL DES PHEROMONS FÜR DEN PFIRSICHWICKLER GRAPHOLITA MOLESTA B. (LEP., TORTRICIDAE)&#xD;
Nikolai Atanov, Ju. B. Pyatnova&#xD;
&#xD;
NEUE ERGEBNISSE ZUR ÜBERWACHUNG DES KIEFERNSPINNERS (DENDROLIMUS PINI L.) MIT HILFE VON PHEROMONEN&#xD;
Dietrich Häußler&#xD;
&#xD;
UNTERSUCHUNGSERGEBNISSE ZUR PHEROMON-ANWENDUNG BEI DER KONTROLLE DES AUFTRETENS DES KIEFERNSPINNERS (DENDROLIMUS PINI L.) IN BRANDENBURG&#xD;
Dietrich Häußler und Winfried Hackbarth&#xD;
&#xD;
VERGLEICH VON PHEROMONFALLEN UND LEIMRINGEN ZUM MONITORING DES GEMEINEN FROSTSPANNERS OPEROPHTHERA BRUMATA L. (LEP. GEOMETRIDAE) IM NORDRHEINGEBIET&#xD;
Gerhard Greib&#xD;
&#xD;
PRAXISERFAHRUNGEN DER ANWENDUNG DES PHEROMONES ACENOL IM VERWIRRUNGSVERFAHREN AM BEISPIEL DES PFIRSICHWICKLERS GRAPHOLITA MOLESTA B. (LEP., TORTRICIDAE)&#xD;
Nikolai Atanov&#xD;
&#xD;
PHEROMONES OF IPS DUPLICATUS AND THEIR APPLICATION&#xD;
Miloš Knížek, Fredrik Schlyter, Jan Vrkoc&#xD;
&#xD;
CONTROL OF HYLOBIUS ABIETIS L. BY CARVONE: LABORATORY AND FIELD TESTS&#xD;
Petr Fojtík, Fredrik Schlyter, Jan Vrkoc, Pavlína Vrkocová&#xD;
&#xD;
MÖGLICHKEITEN EINES MANIPULATIVEN EINGRIFFS IN DAS PAARUNGSUND BRUTSUBSTRATSUCHVERHALTENS BEIM HAUSBOCKKÄFER HYLOTRUPES BAJULUS L.&#xD;
Bill Landsberger&#xD;
&#xD;
STUDIES ON THE EFFECTS OF PHEROMONE MATING DISRUPTION IN PECTINOPHORA GOSSYPIELLA (SAUND.) (LEP., GELECHIIDAE), IN COTTON FIELDS IN EGYPT, AS COMPARED WITH INSECTICIDE USE&#xD;
Curt v. Boguslawski and Thies Basedow</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Trifolio, Germany</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Kleeberg, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2338/1/kein-dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kleeberg, H. and Zebitz, C.P.W. (Eds.)    (2000) Practice Oriented Results on Use and Production of Neem - Ingredients and Pheromones.   Trifolio, Germany.  Proceedings of 9th Workshop „Practice Oriented Results on Use and Production of Neem-Ingredients and Pheromones", Hohensolms, Germany, 13.03.2000 - 15.03.2000.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2338/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>