<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Echter Mehltau an Petersilie – Erarbeitung von Screeningmethoden für die Resistenzzüchtung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marx, Peggy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gärber, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Powdery mildew occurs increasingly on parsley during hot summer periods, which has already become the main problem in some cultures when potted. Therefore a screening system of parsley is being elaborated in a cooperation project to be able to check breeding material for resistance and develop varieties resistant to powdery mildew. The project aims to find a screening system well practicable under greenhouse conditions for a multitude of breeding material. This requires both finding optimal conditions as well as climatic factors for best infection and development of the pathogen and simple rating methods. Investigations into sporulation, germination of spores, and incubation period have revealed that they are influenced by temperature and relative humidity. 25 °C and 70 % rf have proved to be the best conditions for powdery mildew to develop most effectively. Selecting aggressive isolates is another important impact factor for screening system methods. A collection of 16 isolates sent in from all over Germany could not only show their exclusive affiliation to the genus Erysiphe but also their differences in aggressiveness. This will support an effective selection of isolates for the screening system. The remaining year of the project will see comparative studies of the aggressive isolates on 20 varieties in greenhouse and field trials to evaluate the method. Rating methods applied so far will be optimized to detect differences in the susceptibility to powdery mildew most clearly.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21435/1/21435_marx.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Marx, Peggy and Gärber, Ute    (2013) Echter Mehltau an Petersilie – Erarbeitung von Screeningmethoden für die Resistenzzüchtung.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21435/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>