<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Distribution and use of grasslands in the Czech Republic and biodiversity of invertebrates</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bohac, Jaroslav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kolarova, Pavlina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the Czech Republic the major focus of organic farming lies in permanent grasslands management. Animal production is mostly focused on non-milk pasture beef-raising on almost the whole farm area. By contrast conventional farms do not grass sufficiently, even in areas with higher elevation. This fact is influenced by subvention programmes motivating farmers to fulfil the agroenvironmental function of agriculture using grassing, however there is no support for agriculture on arable land. Permanent grasslands are predominantly used for beef grazing. Large areas are harvested too, which affects biodiverzity. Grasslands utilized for pasture are rich in biodiversity which enhance ecosystem services. The effect of grassland management on the different taxa and assamblages is discussed. This work is focused on permanent grasslands utilization and distribution and invertebrate abundance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21032/1/Moudry_-_Distribution%5B1%5D...2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moudry, Jan (Jr.); Bohac, Jaroslav; Konvalina, Petr; Moudry, Jan and Kolarova, Pavlina   (2008) Distribution and use of grasslands in the Czech Republic and biodiversity of invertebrates.   Lucrări Ştiinţifice, Seria Agronomie, 51 (2008), pp. 233-240.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21032/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>