<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innovative strategies for physical weed control on processing tomato in the Serchio Valley (Central Italy)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peruzzi, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raffaelli, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ginanni, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lulli, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frasconi, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fontanelli, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An “on-farm” open field research on processing tomato weed control was carried out during 2006 in a conventional farm in the Serchio Valley (Pisa, Central Italy). The aim of the experiment was to test innovative strategies and operative machines for non-chemical (physical) weed control.&#xD;
The innovative strategy was compared with the farm traditional technique. The innovative strategy consisted in the application of the stale-seedbed technique (by means of a rolling harrow and a flaming machine in the pre-transplanting phase) and precision hoeing interventions in post-transplanting phase (with an innovative machine equipped with rigid elements, for inter-row weed control, and elastic tines for selective intra-row weed control). Traditional technique consisted in two chemical pre-transplanting interventions and two post-transplanting rotary hoe treatments.&#xD;
Innovative operative machines performances, weed density during the crop cycle, dry weed biomass at harvest and crop fresh yield were recorded.&#xD;
The innovative strategy allowed to reach significantly higher yield values (+18%), a good weed control and a relevant increase of gross marketable production with respect to traditional strategy (+4500 € ha-1 as net value of weed management costs).&#xD;
The experiment is still on-going and it will finish in 2008.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12323/1/Peruzzi_12323_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Peruzzi, A.; Raffaelli, M.; Ginanni, M.; Lulli, L.; Frasconi, C. and Fontanelli, M.    (2008) Innovative strategies for physical weed control on processing tomato in the Serchio Valley (Central Italy).       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12323/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>