<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of turning to 100% organic feed on metabolic status of Swedish organic dairy cows</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Blanco-Penedo, Isabel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fall, Nils</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Emanuelson, Ulf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since January 2008 the ration for organic herds has been required to be 100% organic (Regulation No. 889/2008). However, this may not satisfy the high energy demands of early lactation cows. We thus investigated the possible effects of 100% organic feed on the energy balance in Swedish organic dairy herds as indicated by the following blood parameters (n = 739 observations): Beta-hydroxybutyrate (BHBA), non-esterified fatty acid (NEFA) and insulin, and the occurrence of clinical ketosis (n = 8769 observations). Thirteen organic and 13 conventional herds were visited and blood samples from 81 cows around parturition ( &gt;= 3 cows per herd) were used. The metabolic status of the same herds under the previous rules was available for comparison. The BHBA, NEFA and insulin levels were different before and after the change of legislation, but the effects were similar in organic and conventional cows. The incidence of clinical ketosis was not associated with herd type or the change of legislation. Thus the change in legislation did not appear to have had any detrimental effects on the metabolic profiles of organic cows in early lactation and there was no evidence that organic cows were metabolically more challenged or had a severe negative energy balance. (C) 2011 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25063/1/livsci_143_242_248.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Blanco-Penedo, Isabel; Fall, Nils and Emanuelson, Ulf   (2012) Effects of turning to 100% organic feed on metabolic status of Swedish organic dairy cows.   Livestock Science, 143, pp. 242-248.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25063/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>