<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wissensstandanalyse zur Tiergesundheit ausgewählter Nutz-tierarten im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bender, Sophia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmann, Regine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simoneit, Celine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This research report is about animal health in organic farming. It has been intended for providing recommendations for future research in order to optimize organic farming. An evaluative review and assessment of searchable publications, which cover the period from 1991 to 2011, national as well as international, has been conducted. A total of recorded 569 publications on animal health in livestock production were found. This included articles on general topics (42 publications), on cattle (211), on pigs (181), on poultry (100), on small ruminants (25) and on other species (10). There is a lack of research to examine a practical realisation (n = 124). In organic cattle farming the subject of mastitis has been edited very often. Problems such as lameness, metabolic disorders or calves' diseases were studied subordinately. Mortality of piglets, poor body condition of sows after weaning, parasites and other difficulties in consequence of free-range-systems are described frequently. Articles concerning health in poultry farming attend mostly to feather pecking and hygienic problems due to the free-range system. Status information of animal health of minor species is described rarely. After all, the problems of animal health in organic and in conventional farming are comparable. In general, an implementation-oriented and at once high-quality scientific research is needed to optimize the conditions for animal health and animal welfare in organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21485/1/21485_bender.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bender, Sophia; Koopmann, Regine and Simoneit, Celine    (2013) Wissensstandanalyse zur Tiergesundheit ausgewählter Nutz-tierarten im Ökologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21485/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>