<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erträge und Nährstoffgehalte von alten, biologisch und&#xD;
konventionell gezüchteten Winterweizensorten in&#xD;
verschiedenen landwirtschaftlichen Systemen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hildermann, Isabell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thommen, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boller, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiemken, Andres</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Due to limited nutrient conditions in organic farming winter wheat cultivars can often&#xD;
not perform to the full extent of their genetic potential. This study aims to assess&#xD;
nutrient acquisition potential and yields of old, organically and conventionally bred&#xD;
winter wheat cultivars. Ten cultivars were tested within the DOK long-term experiment&#xD;
in two organic systems at low and moderate intensity, a conventional stockless system&#xD;
and an unfertilized control. Yields and nutrient contents of grain and straw were&#xD;
significantly affected by cultivars and systems. Cultivar x system interactions were not&#xD;
detected. Yields were increasing with nutrient level and year of release of cultivars.&#xD;
Under organic conditions all cultivars performed equally well with respect to yield.&#xD;
Grain nitrogen content was increasing in line with nitrogen input, but dropping along&#xD;
year of release of cultivar.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14030/1/Hildermann_14030.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hildermann, Isabell; Thommen, Andreas; Dubois, David; Boller, Thomas; Wiemken, Andres and Mäder, Paul    (2009) Erträge und Nährstoffgehalte von alten, biologisch und konventionell gezüchteten Winterweizensorten in verschiedenen landwirtschaftlichen Systemen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14030/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>