<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biological control of apple scab and fire blight by the application of the non-pathogenic bacterium Pseudomonas fluorescens Bk3 to the leaf surface</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmoock, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kürkcüoglu, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gau, A. E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The biological control of plant diseases by application of antagonistic microorganisms to&#xD;
the plant phyllosphere is an alternative strategy to prevent the frequent treatment of plants&#xD;
by pesticides. Microbiological antagonists can firstly interact directly against the pathogen&#xD;
by releasing antimicrobial compounds and/or secondly induce the plant resistance of the&#xD;
host plant by expression of pathogenesis-related proteins (PR proteins). The focus of our&#xD;
study is on the interaction of the non-pathogenic bacterium Pseudomonas fluorescens Bk3&#xD;
to the plant phyllosphere of Malus domestica cv. Holsteiner Cox. After application of P.&#xD;
fluorescens Bk3 to the phyllosphere of M. domestica cv. Holsteiner Cox we observed&#xD;
dramatic changes in the protein composition of the apoplast of the host plant. Sequencing&#xD;
of the induced proteins by ESI-Q-ToF mass spectrometry and homology search identified&#xD;
these additional proteins as pathogenesis related proteins (PR) like ß-1,3- glucanase,&#xD;
thaumatin-like protein, chitinase and hevein-like protein. To confirm these findings, a&#xD;
suppressive subtractive hybridization with total RNA from leaves before and after&#xD;
inoculation of P. fluorescens Bk3 to the leaves of the host plant was performed. It revealed&#xD;
an increased expression level of many PR and stress related genes.&#xD;
The induction of PR proteins and plant defence genes in host plants after application of&#xD;
non-pathogenic bacterial antagonists to the plant phylloshere can presumably prevent or&#xD;
reduce successful infections by plant pathogens.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13736/1/306-309.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmoock, S.; Kürkcüoglu, S. and Gau, A. E.    (2008) Biological control of apple scab and fire blight by the application of the non-pathogenic bacterium Pseudomonas fluorescens Bk3 to the leaf surface.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 306-309.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13736/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>