<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Enhancing Biodiversity and Multifunctionality of an Organic Farmscape in California’s Central Valley</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smukler, S.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jackson, L.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sánchez Moreno, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fonte, S.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferris, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klonsky, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O'Geen, A.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scow, K.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cordova-Kreylos, A.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmers in the USA increasingly manage the margins of previously monocultured farmed landscapes to increase biodiversity, e.g. they restore and protect riparian corridors, plant hedgerows and construct vegetated tailwater ponds. This study attempts to link habitat enhancements, biodiversity and changes in ecosystem functions by: 1. inventorying the existing biodiversity and the associated belowground community structure and composition in the various habitats of an organic farm in California’s Central Valley; and 2. monitoring key ecosystem functions of these habitats. Two years of inventories show greater native plant diversity in non-cropped areas. While nematode diversity did not differ between habitats, functional groups were clearly associated with particular habitats as were soil microbial communities (phospholipid fatty acid analysis). Earthworm diversity did not differ between habitats, but biomass was higher in non-cropped areas. Habitats with woody vegetation stored 20% of the farmscape’s total carbon (C), despite their relatively small size (only 5% of the total farm). Two years of monitoring data of farmscape C and nitrogen (N) through emissions, run-off and leaching showed distinct tradeoffs in function associated with each habitat.  Clearly habitat restoration in field margins will increase both landscape biodiversity and the multifunctionality of the farmscape as a whole.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12512/1/12512.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smukler, S.M.; Jackson, L.E.; Sánchez Moreno, S.; Fonte, S.J.; Ferris, H.; Klonsky, K.; O'Geen, A.T.; Scow, K.M. and Cordova-Kreylos, A.L.    (2008) Enhancing Biodiversity and Multifunctionality of an Organic Farmscape in California’s Central Valley.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12512/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>