<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil treatments and rootstocks for organic apple production.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Hanne Lindhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Birgitte</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>6 different soil treatments: Mechanical weeding to the middle of the alleyway, mechanical&#xD;
weeding using 3 different equipments Clemens, Humus and a dish harrow, Soil covering&#xD;
with wheat straw and natural vegetation were combined with 3 rootstocks: M9, J9 and M26&#xD;
to find the best combination for the apple variety ‘Retina’. The trees were planted in the&#xD;
winter 1997/1998, only sprayed at primary RIMpro warnings and drip irrigated. The tree&#xD;
growth, nutrient content of the leaves in august, yield and fruit quality were determined.&#xD;
The rootstock J9 had the highest yield and the biggest amount marketable fruit.&#xD;
Mechanical cleaning to the middle of the alleyways, tree row weed control using Humus or&#xD;
soil covering with straw gave the highest yield and marketable fruit. A one meter weeded&#xD;
strip in the tree row did not remove the competition of the clover grass alleyway. Natural&#xD;
vegetation (weed) in the tree row reduced the yield with more than 50 percent. There was&#xD;
a break down of the Vf resistance of ‘Retina’</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14524/1/26_Pedersen_137_143.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pedersen, Hanne Lindhard and Pedersen, Birgitte    (2004) Soil treatments and rootstocks for organic apple production.  [Bodenbearbeitung und Unterlagen für den ökologischen Apfelanbau.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 137-143.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14524/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>