<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Report on the development of political institutions involved in policy elaborations in organic farming for selected European states</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Michelsen, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As organic farming has become an instrument of European agricultural policy the organic sector is required more and more to get politically active. This report presents results from the EU-funded project EU-CEEOFP on the development of organic farming institutions for the period of 1997-2003 in eleven European countries. Institutions of the organic farming sector in new EU member states are still developing and their relation with mainstream farming institutions is characterised by a state of competition. In (old) EU 15 countries and Switzerland this relation is more oriented towards co-operation and has been described as in a state of creative conflict. Countries with a high share of organic farming show signs of consolidation of their institutions. The report concludes with recommendations for a succesful development of organic farming institutions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4799/1/EUCEEOFP_D7_final_report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun; Stolze, Matthias and Michelsen, Johannes         (2004) Report on the development of political institutions involved in policy elaborations in organic farming for selected European states.   Further Development of Organic Farming Policy in Europe with Particular Emphasis on EU Enlargement. QLK5-2002-00917, no. D7. .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4799/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>