<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prototyping of organic dairy production systems self-sufficient with feed – consequences on productivity, environment and economy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mogensen, Lisbeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Troels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Danfær, Allan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2005, 100% organically grown feed become a requirement for all organic dairy cows in EU. To create a better understanding of which effect introducing 100% organically grown feed will have on the whole farming system, six production strategies was set up and the effects on productivity, environment effect and economy were analysed. The strategies differ with respect to type of concentrated feed, level of fresh grass-clover in the ration and length of the calving interval. It was found that supplement of cereal, rapeseed/cereals or grass pellets gave very similar productivity and economic result, but supplement of rapeseed cake reduced crop production and economic result. Increased level of grazing has a smaller positive effect on the economic result. On the assumption of a positive effect on milk yield persistency and feed intake per cow, increased calving interval has a positive effect on the productivity and economic result of the organic dairy farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6033/1/6033.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mogensen, Lisbeth; Kristensen, Troels and Danfær, Allan   (2007) Prototyping of organic dairy production systems self-sufficient with feed – consequences on productivity, environment and economy.   Biological Agriculture &amp; Horticulture, 25, pp. 13-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6033/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>