<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Practice Oriented Results on Use and Production of Plant Extracts and Pheromones in Integrated and Biological Pest Control</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Contents:&#xD;
&#xD;
Modern Developments of Methods for the Control of Plant Pests and Ectoparasites in Agriculture&#xD;
Hubertus Kleeberg&#xD;
&#xD;
Possible Uses of neem – Traditional Methods of India and Modern Methods of&#xD;
Pest Control&#xD;
Hubertus Kleeberg&#xD;
&#xD;
Neem in Brazil - Plantations, extracts, research and utilization&#xD;
Sueli S. Martinez&#xD;
&#xD;
Properties of NeemAzal-T/S – experiences and possibilities in biological plant&#xD;
protection&#xD;
Edmund Hummel and Hubertus Kleeberg&#xD;
&#xD;
Main Pests which Can Potentially Be Controlled with Techniques based on&#xD;
Neem Products in Brazil&#xD;
Sueli S. Martinez&#xD;
&#xD;
Processing of Neem for plant protection – simple and sophisticated,&#xD;
standardized extracts&#xD;
Beate Ruch and Reinhard Wolf&#xD;
&#xD;
Quality control of Neem material&#xD;
Beate Ruch&#xD;
&#xD;
NeemAzal-T/S – Estimation of residue data based on the analytics of the leading compound Azadirachtin A&#xD;
Beate Ruch&#xD;
&#xD;
Semiochemicals in Agriculture: the Use of Pheromones and Alelochemics in Plant Systemic Resistance&#xD;
Geraldo Deffune&#xD;
&#xD;
Possibilities of the Use of Pheromones for Pest Control in Brazil&#xD;
Armin Kratt &amp; Edmund Hummel&#xD;
&#xD;
Potential of Use, Production of Extracts and Development of Products of Neem based Medicaments and Uses in Agriculture&#xD;
Mauro Luiz Begnini</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Trifolio, Germany</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Soares de Faria, R.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kleeberg, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Web product</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2337/1/kein-dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>(2001) Practice Oriented Results on Use and Production of Plant Extracts and Pheromones in Integrated and Biological Pest Control.   Trifolio, Germany.  Online at &lt;http://www.trifolio-m.de/info_service/workshops/Brasil_Workshop_1_Abstracts.pdf &lt;http://www.trifolio-m.de/info_service/workshops/Brasil_Workshop_1_Abstracts.pdf&gt;&gt;.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2337/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>