<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Open access repository for the brazilian literature on agroecology.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alencar, Maria de Cléofas Faggion</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Brazilian technical and scientific literature on Agroecology is plentiful, is scattered and of difficult access and the hypothesis is that the knowledge of the area was produced but is composed by a knowledge to be organized. These features are barriers and constrains for farmers to use agricultural information as well as for providers of extension services to meet information needs of farmers. In this direction there is a consensus among researchers who study the information that the adequate alternative and adopted in the entire world are the open access digital repositories. Besides taking into account all essential actions to manage technical and scientific information, the open access digital repositories contribute to better communication process of Science. This occurs because such tools create necessary conditions to researchers to have timely, quickly, easy and perpetual access to the information they need to develop their activities. Also help to disseminate the results and provide increase on citation, researcher and institution visibility. A digital repository can be institutional or by topic where the institutional manages and fosters the scientific production of the institution as a whole. Repositories by topic make evident the stage of development of a scientific community. The objective is to describe how the collection of journal and magazines articles, conference papers, documents published by NGOs, government papers, dissertations and thesis, documents on the Internet, agricultural research produced by institutes and universities, etc. will be redeem to create and manage an open access digital repository of the Brazilian bibliographic production on Agroecology host by the Organic Eprints.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22761/1/open_access_repository_for_the_brazilian_literature_on_agroecology-1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alencar, Maria de Cléofas Faggion    (2010) Open access repository for the brazilian literature on agroecology.  [Repositório aberto de acesso para a literatura brasileira sobre agroecologia.]  Revista de Ciência da Informação e Documentação, 1 (2), pp. 153-160.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22761/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>