<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gestion du Parasitisme des petits ruminants en Agriculture Biologique</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The general objective of the project was to evaluate alternative methods of control of nematode parasitism in small ruminants.  &#xD;
&#xD;
More specifically, the project aimed at &#xD;
&#xD;
1 developing novel methods of diagnosis in order to use more efficiently the available chemical anthelmintics. Novel methods have been developed  &#xD;
either on animals or through  analysis of the pasture grazing system &#xD;
 &#xD;
2 assessing the interest in organic farming of mixed grazing between cattle and &#xD;
sheep for the control of  helminth  parasitism of the gastrointestinal tract.&#xD;
&#xD;
The materials and methods used are:&#xD;
&#xD;
- In vivo parasitological and pathophysiological measurements on two flocks: one of cattle plus sheep in mixed grazing conditions and one of sheep alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
- Improvement of diagnosis on animals : development of methods of measurement of antibodies against nematode and Oestrus ovis in milk. Comparisons with  similar parameters  measured on blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
- Risk  analysis of pasture system  to approach the level and dynamics of   parasite infections and predict when to use efficiently chemical drugs.  &#xD;
&#xD;
*A guide  on  “Better use of pasture in goat production “ is currently being developed  for  goat farmers which include our main results on risk analysis through examination of pasture systems</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Gestion du Parasitisme des petits ruminants en Agriculture Biologique.  [MANAGEMENT OF PARASITISM IN SMALL RUMINANTS UNDER ORGANIC FARMING RULES.]   Runs 2000 - 2004.      Project Leader(s): Hoste, Dr Hervé, INRA.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6526/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>