<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Inokulierung auf Ertrag, Rohproteingehalt und N-Gehalt der Gesamtpflanze unterschiedlicher Sojabohnensorten (Glycine max) am Versuchsstandort Osnabrück 2011</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hüsing, Bianka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wessel-Terharn, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vergara, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schön, Hans</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trautz, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A field experiment was conducted during the 2011 growing season to determine the effect of inoculation with Bradyrhizobium japonicum on yield, crude protein content (%) and nitrogen content of five inoculated and not -inoculated soybean varieties (Klaxon, Protina, Gallec, ES Mentor and Aveline). At three defined points of time (BBCH 23, BBCH 69, BBCH 75) plant samples including the root system were taken for analysis regarding the nitrogen content. Soil analysis to determine the N-min content had been carried out. Concluding the yield and crude protein content of the varieties was determined. Significant differences between inoculated and not inoculated varieties could be verified concerning yield, crude protein content and nitrogen content.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21522/1/21522_Huesing.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hüsing, Bianka; Wessel-Terharn, Michael; Vergara, Maria; Schön, Hans and Trautz, Dieter    (2013) Einfluss der Inokulierung auf Ertrag, Rohproteingehalt und N-Gehalt der Gesamtpflanze unterschiedlicher Sojabohnensorten (Glycine max) am Versuchsstandort Osnabrück 2011.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21522/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>