<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigations of organic food and health</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Dr. Kirsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Erik Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Numerous studies have attempted to elucidate if there is a difference in&#xD;
the effect on human health, between food produced according to the&#xD;
organic standards compared with conventionally produced food. While&#xD;
many studies support a few general trends of differences in food&#xD;
composition, none have provided any conclusive evidence for differences&#xD;
in the effects on human health. Most of the studies have been inadequate&#xD;
in size or focus to allow any definitive conclusions. The major problem is&#xD;
the complexity of the issue, and the general paucity of knowledge about&#xD;
the impact of food on health, which means that it is virtually impossible&#xD;
to tackle all relevant uncertainties in any one study. Instead a whole range&#xD;
of different types of studies are needed to provide a conclusion.&#xD;
Presently, a study is in progress, which attempts to provide some of&#xD;
the missing key information on this issue. This study comprises controlled&#xD;
cultivation of plants in three different models of growing systems for two&#xD;
years, and feeding rats for 3 generations on diets composed of these&#xD;
plants. It will show if food from different growing systems can result in&#xD;
differences in health of rats, and if so, which aspects of health are&#xD;
affected. However, if differences are found, subsequent studies will be&#xD;
necessary to determine the applicability and possible consequences for&#xD;
human health. Still, together with other existing and planned studies it&#xD;
might soon be possible to determine some of the consequences for&#xD;
human health of the methods used for food production. This could result&#xD;
in increased demand for organic food, and it could at the same time lead&#xD;
to changes in the farming methods in either organic or conventional&#xD;
production systems. In any case, this type of research will improve crucial&#xD;
aspects of the knowledge base, which is needed also in other contexts, to&#xD;
support the efforts to improve food safety and quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Print Workshop</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Davies, Hugh</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1486/1/DANISH_INSTITUTE_SCAN_EDIT.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brandt, Dr. Kirsten and Kristensen, Erik Steen   (2003) Investigations of organic food and health.  [Undersøgelser af økologiske fødevarer og sundhed.]  Innovations in Food Technology (20), pp. 68-69.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1486/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>