<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung der Darmflora von Sauen bei wechselnden Fasergehalten in der Ration</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sappok, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perez Gutierrez, Odette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smidt, Hauke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pellikaan , Wilbert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verstegen, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In vitro gas production studies can be used in pig nutrition to assess the metabolic capacity of intestinal microbiota to ferment fibre. The intestinal microbiota are obtained from faeces of animals adapted to a certain diet. However, the necessary adaptation time of faecal donor animals to attain a stable microbial population whose fermentation capacity is representative for a different fibre content in the diet is largely unknown. Therefore a study was carried out where two groups of sows where either changed from a diet high in fibre to a diet low in fibre or vice versa. After the diet was changed, the large intestinal microbiota was characterized every three days during a period of 19 days with a phylogenetic microarray. The diet change led to significant changes in relative abundance of specific bacteria. Bacteroidetes increased and Bacilli decreased after the diet was changed from low to high fibre while the opposite occurred when the diet was changed from high to low fibre.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21584/1/21584_Sappok.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sappok, Maria; Perez Gutierrez, Odette; Smidt, Hauke; Pellikaan , Wilbert and Verstegen, Martin    (2013) Entwicklung der Darmflora von Sauen bei wechselnden Fasergehalten in der Ration.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21584/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>