<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Intercropping, an application of ecological principles to  improve nitrogen use efficiency in organic farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bedoussac, Laurent</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Journet, Etienne-Pascal</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauggaard-Nielsen, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Naudin, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prieur, Loïc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Erik Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Justes, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Increasing concerns about environmental impacts and reduction of inputs require a transformation of current cropping systems for better efficiency and sustainability (Cox and Atkins 1979; Jackson and Piper 1989; Vandermeer et al. 1998; Griffon 2006). New agronomic solutions are needed including multiple objectives like i) yield, ii) quality, iii) provision of ecological benefits and iv) the adaptation of production systems to climate change. Organic farming is regarded as a prototype to enhance the sustainability of present cereal-rich cropping systems. Organic farming is in general assumed to rely on higher crop diversity than its conventional counterpart. Nevertheless, organic arable crop rotations in temperate regions consist mainly of sole crops (SC) with the more diverse pastures being an exception. Diversification of farming systems by increasing the number of cultivated species and including a larger proportion of legumes was proposed as one way  responding to the challenges of tomorrow’s agriculture. It is important to emphasize that the development of intercrops cannot take place without the assent and collaboration of all the actors in the value chain : i) the farmers of course who need technical support since the new generation of farmers may not possess the know-how to grow arable crops as mixtures, ii) the seed companies  which will have to adapt their collecting, sorting and storage equipment to satisfy the processors’ quality demands, iii) the breeders expected to select varieties suited to intercropping, iv) the technical institutions which must acquire technical knowledge, and v) the national and European authorities to consider relevant policy activities to help –reintroducing these cropping strategies.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18985/4/18985.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bedoussac, Laurent; Journet, Etienne-Pascal; Hauggaard-Nielsen, Henrik; Naudin, Christophe; Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle; Prieur, Loïc ; Jensen, Erik Steen and Justes, Eric    (2011) Intercropping, an application of ecological principles to improve nitrogen use efficiency in organic farming systems.    In:      Organic Farming, prototype for sustainable agricultures?.  Springer, Berlin, Germany,  - .     [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18985/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>