<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic hospital food is desired by patients and engages the kitchen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koesling, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Birkeland, Liv</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Behrens, Gesine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In December 2005 a questionnaire survey was conducted at the University Hospital in Trondheim, Norway. Patients and personnel expressed that food is important for their health and well-being. Good taste, appearance and right nutrition were mentioned as being important factors for food quality. About 80 % of the respondents were positive to the use of organic food at the hospital, even though only about half of them agreed that it is worth the price. The absence of pesticides, artificial fertilizers and preservatives in food was ranked to be more important than organic production of food. All respondents seemed to be critical to the use of pesticides and preservatives in food production and processing.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9406/1/Koesling-etal-2007-HospitalSurvey.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koesling, Matthias; Birkeland, Liv and Behrens, Gesine    (2007) Organic hospital food is desired by patients and engages the kitchen.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9406/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>