<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>GRASS SILAGE IN DIETS FOR ORGANIC GROWING-FINISHING PIGS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bikker, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Binnendijk, G.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vermeer, H. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Peet-Schwering, C.M.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, organically raised pigs received an increasing proportion of grass silage up to 10 and 20% dry matter in the daily ration in the grower and finisher period, respectively, to determine the effects on feed intake and growth performance. The pigs receiving a mixture of grass silage and compound feed ingested 0.3 kg DM/d (13% of their daily ration) as grass silage and realised a similar daily net energy intake as pigs fed compound feed only. However, the silage fed pigs realised a lower daily gain (37 g/d) and a lower calculated net energy utilisation (1.6 MJ/kg) for gain and a lower dressing percentage (1.1%) of the carcass. The nutritive value of grass silage for growing pigs requires further investigation to clarify and minimise the loss in animal performance.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24257/1/24257%20growing%20pigs_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bikker, P.; Binnendijk, G.P.; Vermeer, H. M. and van der Peet-Schwering, C.M.C.    (2014) GRASS SILAGE IN DIETS FOR ORGANIC GROWING-FINISHING PIGS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 815-818.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24257/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>