<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulierung der Apfelsägewespe im Ökologischen Obstbau und Nebenwirkungen der Strategien auf die Blutlauszehrwespe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klopp, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Yamada, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bathon, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effects of Quassia extract on eggs and larvae of the apple sawfly Hoplocampa testudinea were studied in the laboratory. The efficacy of this extract was mainly due to an oral toxicity to neonate sawfly larvae. The main active ingredients, Quassin and Neoquassin, were tested sepa-rately as pure substances. While Quassin had a considerable efficacy also on older larvae, Neo-quassin was less efficient in this case. Since Quassin and Neoquassin were found in different Quassia sources in varying relations to each other and had different efficacy, they have to be considered separately in the definition of extract quality by the content of active ingredients. This requires the application of Quassia extracts before larval hatch. It was shown that low concentra-tions of Quassin (4-6 g/ha) can achieve very good control in the field, in other cases the concentra-tions for good efficacy are much higher. These varying results seem to be connected with applica-tion technique and application date. Trials in 2004 showed that the best way of application is with plenty of water (500 to 1000 l/ha) and the best date is during the stage when blossom is fading. &#xD;
The side effects of Quassin, Neoquassin and Quassia extract on Aphelinus mali and other benefi-cial arthropods were tested. Quassia is harmless to all organisms tested.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4277/1/4003.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.; Zimmer, J.; Klopp, K.; Maxin, P.; Yamada, K. and Bathon, H.    (2005) Regulierung der Apfelsägewespe im Ökologischen Obstbau und Nebenwirkungen der Strategien auf die Blutlauszehrwespe.  [Strategy for the control of the apple sawfly in organic fruitgrowing and possible side effects on Aphelinus mali Hald.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4277/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>