<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Wirksamkeit von Anthelminthika bei&#xD;
erstsömmrigen Rindern in Europa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Demeler, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kleinschmidt, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmann, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Samson-Himmelstjerna, von, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Resistance to anthelmintics is a threat to several animal industries world wide. Nevertheless,&#xD;
the use of effective anthelmintics to control nematode infections in cattle&#xD;
still remains irreplaceable. Anthelmintic resistance in cattle has been reported in New&#xD;
Zealand, North and South America and England but so far not in Europe. To be able&#xD;
to determine the extent of anthelmintic resistance in nematodes of farm animals and to&#xD;
monitor the success of any resistance management requires reliable tests for the&#xD;
detection of anthelmintic resistance. One of the objectives of PARASOL, a European&#xD;
Framework 6 funded project, is to produce standard operating procedures for the&#xD;
running of a faecal egg count reduction test (FECRT). Standardized procedures for&#xD;
the FECRT have been developed and surveys with injectable ivermectin were then&#xD;
performed in Germany, Sweden and Belgium in 2006 and 2007. Additional tests using&#xD;
benzimidazoles were performed in Sweden and Germany in 2007. Furthermore, some&#xD;
of the refractory strains will be isolated to test whether the phenomena observed in the&#xD;
field was due to the evolution of anthelmintic resistance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14455/1/Demeler_14455.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Demeler, J.; Kleinschmidt, N.; Koopmann, R. and Samson-Himmelstjerna, von, G.    (2009) Untersuchungen zur Wirksamkeit von Anthelminthika bei erstsömmrigen Rindern in Europa.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14455/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>