<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SENSORY AND HEALTH-RELATED FRUIT QUALITY OF ORGANIC APPLES. A COMPARATIVE FIELD STUDY OVER THREE YEARS USING CONVENTIONAL AND HOLISTIC METHODS TO ASSESS FRUIT QUALITY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Treutter, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Häseli, Andi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graf, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a 3 years lasting field study with the ‘Golden Delicious’ cultivar, we compared fruits of 5&#xD;
pairs of organic/integrated fruit farms. The orchards were similar in microclimate, soil conditions and&#xD;
planting system. To assess inner fruit quality we investigated at the beginning and at the end of cold&#xD;
storage: (i) standard parameters (firmness, sugar, malic acid., mineral content); (ii) sensorial quality&#xD;
by panel tests; (iii) health related components (23 phenolic compounds, nutritional fibres; vitamins);&#xD;
and (v) fruit «vitality quality» by holistic approaches (crystallisation in copper chloride, self degradation&#xD;
tests, feeding preference tests with laboratory rats).&#xD;
The most significant differences were found in year one of the study, and were by tendency&#xD;
confirmed in the following two years. In year one all fruit samples of organic orchards had significantly&#xD;
firmer fruit flesh (14%), a 10 % higher index of inner quality (on basis of sugar and malic acid&#xD;
content and fruit flesh firmness), and 15% higher taste scores than conventional ones. Phosphorus&#xD;
content of the fruit flesh was 31% higher in organic apples and closely correlated (r2 = 0.93) with the&#xD;
index of inner quality and sensory score (r2 = 0.69). No extraction method of Phosphorus in the soil&#xD;
(water, NH4-EDTA, citric acid, CAL) correlated with the P-content in the fruits. However, P in the fruit&#xD;
flesh correlated by r2 = 0.72 with the microbial activity of the soil expressed as the ratio of microbialbound&#xD;
Nitrogen and Carbon in the soil. With a value of 3.85 the Cmic:Nmic ratio was 44.5 % lower&#xD;
(thus more favourable) in organic tree strips. Flavanols, with 65.7 % of the total polyphenol content&#xD;
were the dominant group of polyphenols. The content of flavonols was 22.7 % higher in organic apples&#xD;
in the first year and 15.6 % in the average of the three years. The self-degradation test didn't&#xD;
provide significant differences. Laboratory rats, showed a tendency to prefer IP apples probably due&#xD;
to their advanced ripeness. Thus rat behaviour did not correspond with the sensory panel judgement.&#xD;
The picture forming method provided a correct reproducibility with repeated blind samples&#xD;
before and after storage (r2 = 0.83), and distinguished 100 % correctly organic an IP fruit in the first&#xD;
year. In the second year there was one miss qualification. The average value over three dates of&#xD;
the index for «vitality quality», which was especially created for this study, was 44.6 % higher with&#xD;
organic apples The picture forming methods correlated well with sensory scores and standard quality&#xD;
(r2 = 0.63) in the first year. The study revealed interesting and consumer-relevant differences between&#xD;
organic and integrated apples with standard and holistic methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14536/1/35_Weibel_185_195.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, Franco P.; Treutter, Dieter; Häseli, Andi and Graf, Ursula    (2004) SENSORY AND HEALTH-RELATED FRUIT QUALITY OF ORGANIC APPLES. A COMPARATIVE FIELD STUDY OVER THREE YEARS USING CONVENTIONAL AND HOLISTIC METHODS TO ASSESS FRUIT QUALITY.  [GESCHMACKS- UND GESUNDHEITSRELEVANTE QUALITÄT VON ÖKOLOGISCH ANGEBAUTEN ÄPFELN: EINE 3JÄHRIGE FELDVERGLEICHSSTUDIE MIT STANDARD- UND GANZHEITLICHEN UNTERSUCHUNGSMETHODEN.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 185-195.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14536/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>