<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Plants for health - primary production of plants containing bioactive compounds that hold a preventive effect towards diabetes II</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Dr. Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ecologically grown medicinal plants containing bioactive compounds hold great potential as high-value niche crops for farmers. However, the way to grow these plants differs from traditional crops. Growing techniques, harvest methods and post-harvest handling of the raw material plays a crucial role regarding the quality of the raw material that the farmers can offer. The purpose of a new research project financed by EU-Interreg IIIA programme is among other things to carry out production, harvest and processing experiments with plants containing bioactive plant compounds that hold a preventive effect towards diabetes II. &#xD;
One of the project’s goals is to draw up cultivation instructions for the primary producers to use when cultivating the plants in question. Examples of the plants that are being examined in the project are Goat’s Rue (Galega officinalis) and Fenugreek (Trigonelle foenum-graecum)</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7581/1/Plants_for_health_by_Ralf_Loges_and_John_Henriksen.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Loges, Dr. Ralf and Henriksen, John    (2006) Plants for health - primary production of plants containing bioactive compounds that hold a preventive effect towards diabetes II.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7581/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>