<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison of Organic and Conventional Beef-Suckler Farms in Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hörning, Prof. Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feige, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dollinger, Julia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study aims to compare conventional and organic farms with beef-suckler herds. Addresses were collected mainly by contacting breeding associations and farmers' magazines. 216 questionnaires were evaluated (34.1% of them organic). Beef-suckler production in Germany is an extensive production system (small farms, small herd sizes, high percentage of grassland, low soil points, etc.). 39% of farms had to fulfil special regulations for extensive grassland production and 43% carried out landscape conservation measures. Farmers specialize in beef-suckler production. 60% of them are part-time farmers. Beef production amounts to two thirds of their agricultural income. Most farmers keep only beef cattle on the farms. Other farm animals are kept in small stock sizes. This study has found only a few differences between conventional and organic farms. Organic farmers more often keep breeds of low intensity but more of them use direct marketing channels. On organic farms cows more frequently stay outside all year. Animal performances were the same in both production systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12021/1/Hoerning_12021_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hörning, Prof. Bernhard; Feige, Martina and Dollinger, Julia    (2008) Comparison of Organic and Conventional Beef-Suckler Farms in Germany.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12021/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>