<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Glucosinolate profiling of seeds and sprouts of B. oleracea varieties used for food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bellostas, Natalia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kachlicki, Piotr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Jens Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Hilmer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Consumption of Brassica vegetables is related to a decreased incidence of certain cancer forms, and it has been linked to the presence of glucosinolates in these vegetables. After ripe seeds, Brassica sprouts contain the highest concentration of these compounds and are therefore a good source of glucosinolates for chemoprotection. In the present experiments, the content and distribution of glucosinolates in five varieties of B. oleracea (white cabbage, red cabbage, Savoy cabbage, broccoli and cauliflower) was determined in ripe seeds and sprouts of up to seven days by High Performance Liquid Chromatography. The type and concentration of individual glucosinolates varied according to B. oleracea variety, plant part and length of the sprouting period. Concentration of alkyl glucosinolates decreased whereas that of indol-3-ylmethylglucosinolates increased throughout the sprouting period. Roots had the highest glucosinolate concentration in four and seven day old sprouts whereas at both sprouting times, cotyledons had the highest concentration of alkylthio- and alkylsulphinylglucosinolates.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11395/1/11395.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bellostas, Natalia; Kachlicki, Piotr; Sørensen, Jens Christian and Sørensen, Hilmer   (2007) Glucosinolate profiling of seeds and sprouts of B. oleracea varieties used for food.   Scientia Horticulturae.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11395/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>