<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Research on the productivity of maize intercropped with common bean in two spatial arrangements, in the organic agriculture system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DUSA, Elena Mirela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The researches was oriented towards studying the productivity and land equivalent ratio of maize and bean in intercropping, in two spatial arrangements, in the ecological agriculture conditions.&#xD;
The experiment was carried out in Moara Domnească Experimental Field, on redish preluvosoil, in randomised blocks in 4 replications. It was sown an simple, early maize hybrid (Zea mays - DK 391) and bean (Phaseolus vulgaris – Diva variety). &#xD;
Maize was sown at 70 cm between rows and 28,6 cm between plants per row, at a density of 5 plants/m2. Bean was sown between maize plants at a density of 4 plants/m2 and between maize rows at a density of 12 plants/m2.&#xD;
Average grain yield for maize in monoculture was 5044.2 kg/ha and in the first spatial arrangement was 184,1 kg/ha, higher than the maize from the second spatial arrangement.&#xD;
In monoculture, bean yield was 1361 kg/ha and in intercropping with maize, in the first spatial arrangement, it was obtained 791 kg/ha. In the second spatial arrangement of maize-bean intercropping yield decreased by only 149 kg.&#xD;
The value of the land equivalent ratio (LER) ranged between 1.3 for the first spatial arrangement of the maize-bean intercropping and 1.75 for the second arrangement.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-05-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/zip</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16645/1/Lucrare_extenso_Mirela_Dusa.zip</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>DUSA, Elena Mirela    (2009) Research on the productivity of maize intercropped with common bean in two spatial arrangements, in the organic agriculture system.   In:     Scientific Papers, UASVM Bucharest.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16645/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>