<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Efficacy of products allowed in organic olive farming against Bactrocera oleae (Gmel.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iannotta, Nino</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Belfiore, Tiziana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noce, Maria Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perri, Luigi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scalercio, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic olive farming one of the most problems is how to control the olive fly. The present study has been performed in two different Calabrian olive areas in order to test some active molecules allowed by regulation concerning organic farming. The tested compounds were Rotenone, Azadiractin, Copper, Kaolin and Propolis. The results showed that, at harvesting time (end of October), the lowest infestation has been registered on the trees treated with Propolis and Kaolin in both investigated fields. The obtained results display that the restraining of the active infestation of Bactrocera oleae within limits of 20%, compatible with a quality production, turns to be possible also in Southern olive areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Campo Artigrafiche, Alcamo, Trapani</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12896/1/Iannotta_Scalercio_et_al_2006h.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Iannotta, Nino; Belfiore, Tiziana; Noce, Maria Elena; Perri, Luigi and Scalercio, Stefano    (2006) Efficacy of products allowed in organic olive farming against Bactrocera oleae (Gmel.).   In:     Proceedings of the Second International Seminar on "Biotechnology and Quality of Olive tree Products around the Mediterranean basin", Olivebioteq, Campo Artigrafiche, Alcamo, Trapani, Vol. II, pp. 324-326.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12896/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>