<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Constraints on developing organic poultry production OF0128T</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Sue</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rajah, Kanes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McDougall, Iain</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langstaff, Lesley</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O'Regan, Tony</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharples, Trevor</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study aimed to provide MAFF with an assessment of the potential for organic poultry production in England and Wales and, in particular, to identify likely constraints on the development of organic poultry production enterprises, including physical, financial and market factors.  The study will e composed of 3 specific objectives outlines as follows, together with ways in which they might be achieved: 1. Definition of the physical production parameters for alternative poultry production to organic standards, with particular emphasis on free range and perchery systems and their respective input requirements and output potential.  A detailed literature review will be conducted and consultations will be made with existing organic poultry producers.  Direct experience with conventional free range and perchery production systems at the National Institute of Poultry Husbandry and other published information will be utilised to identify potential areas for improvement and/or future research; 2. Investigation of market opportunities for organic poulry meat and egg production in England and Wales, through an examination of the existing market structure and an appraisal of existing and potential marketing strategies.  The market for organic poultry meat and eggs will be analysed for shape, size and future potential.  Alternative marketing approaches for this sector will be considered and a desk study will be conducted involving a review of trade journals and poultry sector business reports, together with consultation with key players in the sector; and 3.Formulation of an appropriate farm business plan to illustrate the relative profitability of alternative systems of organic poultry production, including the projection of cash flows under given assumptions and the application of sensitivity analyses to key variables influencing profitability.  The business plan will cover a wide range of areas, including: industry and market size; producer strategy; capital requirements,; marketing strategy; projected funds; and building, labour and statutory requirements.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1997-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9975/1/Organic_Poulty_Production.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lampkin, Nicolas; Padel, Susanne; Fowler, Sue; Rajah, Kanes; McDougall, Iain; Langstaff, Lesley; O'Regan, Tony and Sharples, Trevor     (editor): Lampkin, Nicolas (Ed.)    (1997) Constraints on developing organic poultry production OF0128T.    University of Wales, Aberystwyth, Institute or Rural Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9975/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>