<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Humic acid and manure tea affected reproductive stage and fruit quality factors of pepino in organic production system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Javanmardi, Jamal</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hasanshahian, Ozra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pepino (Solanum muricatum) a Solanaceous fruit vegetable has been of an increased interest in exotic fruit markets. An experiment was carried out to evaluate the effects of sheep and cow manure teas in water (1:5 and 1:10 w/v) in combination with humic acid on reproductive stage and qualitative characteristics of pepino fruit in organic production system. All traits were affected by combination of manure teas and humic acid except for fruit total soluble solid content. Application of sheep manure tea at 1:10 w/v caused the greatest total soluble solid content as about 20% greater than control. Sheep manure tea (1:10 w/v) in combination with humic acid lead to lowering required days preceding the first flower formation by 8 days. The highest fruit dry matter percentage was obtained in the same treatment and about 10 times greater than control. Comparing to control the total phenolic content were obtained about 62 and 37% greater, in cow manure tea (1/10 w/v) and humic acid treatments, respectively.  Greatest number of flowers, fruit set percentage, earliness and ascorbic acid content were greatest when humic acid applied solely.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23677/1/23677_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Javanmardi, Jamal and Hasanshahian, Ozra    (2014) Humic acid and manure tea affected reproductive stage and fruit quality factors of pepino in organic production system.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 683-686.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23677/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>