<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Konzepte und Strategien der Biogaserzeugung im Ökologischen&#xD;
Landbau – Ergebnisse des Bio-Biogas-Monitoring 2007</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Anspach, Dipl.-Ing.agr. Victor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Prof. Dr. Detlev</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biogas production is becoming increasingly important for organic farms. Based on an&#xD;
empirical study, designed as a census, the structure and specifics of organic biogas&#xD;
production were investigated. Today an estimated 150 organic biogas plants in&#xD;
Germany exist; this corresponds to 5% of all biogas plants. The number of plants has&#xD;
doubled since 2004 and the installed electric. power has increased six-fold. Mainly&#xD;
organic farms with long experience in organic farming have started biogas production.&#xD;
Most characteristic for organic biogas plants is first the intensive use of low-priced&#xD;
substrates like manure and grass-clover, but also maize silage is used. Secondly the&#xD;
average use of waste heat is very high and utilised in many different ways. Thirdly the&#xD;
internal benefits of biogas slurry are very important. This leads to higher field yields&#xD;
and better product quality of field crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14299/1/Anspach_14299.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Anspach, Dipl.-Ing.agr. Victor and Möller, Prof. Dr. Detlev    (2009) Konzepte und Strategien der Biogaserzeugung im Ökologischen Landbau – Ergebnisse des Bio-Biogas-Monitoring 2007.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14299/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>