<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Using Copper in Organic Viticulture: Doing it best with less?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heibertshausen, Dagmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baus-Reichel, Ottmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hofmann, Uwe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kogel, Karl-Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berkelmann-Löhnertz, Beate</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>For many years, applications of copper fungicides have been used to control downy mildew on grapes. Nowadays, its intensive use is under consideration due to ecotoxicological aspects, especially in organic viticulture. As a result, this project made allowance for consumer perception about organic viticulture and is seeking suitable alternatives. The project includes an association of six research facilities, four organic wineries, several consultant agencies for organic viticulture as well as SME (small and medium-sized enterprise) partners, which are working together in four work packages. The aim of this work is to obtain an array of products that provide sufficient control of Plasmopara viticola with the lowest possible input of copper. As a longterm intention, copper-containing products should be totally replaced by other effective agents. Progress to-date suggests that some non-copper products and several copper-based products using less than 3 kg/(ha*a) have potential to effectively control the disease with less ecological residue.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9738/1/Heibertshausen-etal-2007-CopperWine.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heibertshausen, Dagmar; Baus-Reichel, Ottmar; Hofmann, Uwe; Kogel, Karl-Heinz and Berkelmann-Löhnertz, Beate    (2007) Using Copper in Organic Viticulture: Doing it best with less?       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9738/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>