<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>References for organic farming systems: proposal for an innovative analytical frame</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fourrié, Laetitia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cresson, Céline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Letailleur, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sautereau, Natacha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willot, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berthier, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vallas, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The RefAB project, associating about twenty people from research, training and development produced methodological framework of production of references at the level of the agricultural systems, built for organic farming but relevant to any type of agriculture. It is thus proposed to analyze the agricultural systems (in their economic, social and environmental performances) via five fundamental principles and properties in organic farming: resilience, autonomy, diversity, equity and ecology (referring to IFOAM principles). Various criteria, evaluated by indicators, make it possible to characterize the organic agricultural systems. If certain indicators are classically used in production of references, others are more innovative. The potential of the approach relies in the global approach that is proposed at the level of the farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26276/1/Fourrie_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fourrié, Laetitia; Cresson, Céline; Letailleur, F.; Sautereau, Natacha; Willot, M.; Berthier, C. and Vallas, M.   (2013) References for organic farming systems: proposal for an innovative analytical frame.  [RefAB : Des références pour les systèmes agricoles biologiques : proposition d’un cadre méthodologique innovant.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 271-284.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26276/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>