<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A model analysis on nitrate leaching under different soil and climate conditions and use of catch crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stoumann Jensen, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The use of crops and catch crops with deep rooting can strongly improve the possibility of retaining nitrate-N that will otherwise be leached to the deeper soil layers and end up in the surrounding environment. But will it always be an advantage for the farmer to&#xD;
grow a catch crop? This will depend on factors such as soil mineral nitrogen level, soil water holding capacity, winter precipitation, rooting depth and N demand of the scceeding crop. These factors interact, and it can be very difficult for farmers or advisors to use this information to decide whether growing a catch crop will be beneficial. To analyse the effect of catch crops under different Danish soil and precipitation conditions, we used the soil, plant and atmosphere model Daisy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7831/1/7831.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pedersen, Anders; Stoumann Jensen, Lars and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian    (2005) A model analysis on nitrate leaching under different soil and climate conditions and use of catch crops.       Poster at:   at 14th N WORKSHOP “N management in agrosystems in relation to the Water Framework Directive”, Maastricht, The Netherlands, 24-26 October 2005,.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7831/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>