<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hat der ökologische Landbau in Europa eine Zukunft?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Offermann, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nieberg, Hiltrud</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming in Europe has increased rapidly since the early 1990s but still only accounts for a small share of production. This article analyses the structure and financial performance of organic farming in Europe using data from 18 countries. In the countries analysed, organic farms achieved significant price preniia for their outputs and were able to compete financially with conventional farms, with equal or higher profits in most cases, even though yields were up to 40 per cent lower. There was, however, a wide variation in performance within the samples and between countries and farm types. Consumer willingness to pay higher prices for organic products along with European Union and government support payments for organic farming and the design of the Common Agricultural Policy contributed to the success of the farms. Except for extensive livestock farms, labour requirements on organic farms were generally higher than in conventional agriculture but remuneration of family labour was generally equal to or higher than in conventional farms. Any moves towards more decoupled payments to farmers under the EU's Agenda 2000 should increase the relative competitiveness of organic farming systems. A key factor in the future development of organic farming will be growth in the number of consumers willing to pay a price premium for organic products.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Agricultural Economics Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/827/1/scanned_fulltext.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Offermann, Frank and Nieberg, Hiltrud   (2002) Hat der ökologische Landbau in Europa eine Zukunft?  [Does organic farming have a future in Europe?]  EuroChoices : agri-food and rural resources issues, 1 (2), pp. 12-17.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/827/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>