<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of feeding prebiotics to pigs for 1 or 2 weeks before slaughter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Annette Nygaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mølbak, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Laurits Lydehøj</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baggesen, Dorte Lau</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Prebiotics are non-digestible oligosaccharides acting by stimulating the growth of bacteria being beneficial for the gastrointestinal health of the host and may serve as a means to control pathogens. This study aimed to assess if inclusion of chicory or lupins (prebiotics) in the diet of pre-slaughter pigs for just 1 or 2 weeks could change the  composition of their intestinal microbiota and help to lower the level of the important foodborne pathogen Campylobacter spp.&#xD;
The study showed that even a short-term alternative feeding strategy with prebiotics in the diet of pre-slaughter pigs elicited changes in the composition of intestinal microbiota with stimulation of the growth of bifidobacteria in caceum and a reduction of the Campylobacter spp. excretion level.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19883/9/19883.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Annette Nygaard; Mølbak, Lars; Hansen, Laurits Lydehøj and Baggesen, Dorte Lau    (2010) Effects of feeding prebiotics to pigs for 1 or 2 weeks before slaughter.   In:     Abstract book, 22nd International ICFMH Symposium, Food Micro 2010.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19883/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>