<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Klimaschutz mit pilzresistenten Rebsorten - Fallstudie eines&#xD;
langjährigen Bioweinbaubetriebes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strasser, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Coray, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Our biodynamic winery is located near Lake Constance in Switzerland. Since 1989,&#xD;
we have cultivated resistant grape varieties such as Maréchal Foch, Léon Millot,&#xD;
Muscat Bleu, Cabernet Jura, Chancellor and Monarch (red), and Seyval Blanc,&#xD;
Bianca, Solaris, Phoenix and Excelsior (white). As a rule, we avoid applying even&#xD;
organic pesticides, and use solely biodynamic compounds (4 applications/year). The&#xD;
elimination of practically all plant-protection products has enabled us to establish a&#xD;
highly biodiverse organic agro-ecosystem with reduced impact on the environment. In&#xD;
addition, over a 20-year period, this system has resulted in the application of 270 kg&#xD;
less copper over our 4.5-ha surface area, as well as the saving of 18 t of fuel, which&#xD;
can be remarked as the “non-emission” of 47 t of carbon dioxide. In Switzerland,&#xD;
whose vineyards have a combined surface area of 15’000 ha, the potential annual&#xD;
savings in pesticides and fuel, to the benefit of nature, environment and climate, can&#xD;
be estimated at 225’000kg (225 t) pesticides and 1.5 Mio l (1500 t) fuel respectively,&#xD;
equating to the “non-emission” of 3.9 Mio kg (3900 t) of carbon dioxide.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13902/1/Strasser_13902.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strasser, Alfred and Coray, Maria    (2009) Klimaschutz mit pilzresistenten Rebsorten - Fallstudie eines langjährigen Bioweinbaubetriebes.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13902/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>