<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards Improved Quality in Organic Food Production</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From 21 to 23 January 2009 the fifth QLIF training and exchange workshop took place. Inspired by the theme “Towards improved quality in organic food production” a group of 20 participants and 11 lecturers had intensive days with lectures, discussion, exchange and some practical experience in research set-up and taste experiments. Fifteen nationalities exchanged their experiences in research in product quality. Many results from comparative studies between conventional and organic products were presented and discussed. In some presentations more emphasis was laid on exploring the mechanism behind the presence or absence of certain health-influencing plant components. Comparative studies will be continued, but exploring the mechanisms behind found differences in substances is suggested as an important direction for future research.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hospers-Brands, M.Sc. Monique</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>van der Burgt, M.Sc. Geert-Jan</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15398/1/2099.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hospers-Brands, M.Sc. Monique and van der Burgt, M.Sc. Geert-Jan (Eds.)    (2009) Towards Improved Quality in Organic Food Production.    . Proceedings of 5th QLIF Training and Exchange Workshop, Driebergen (Netherlands), 21 - 23 January 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15398/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>