<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Legehennefutter mit 100% Öko-Komponenten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Andersson, Robby</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyer zu Bakum, R.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schreiber, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>EC Regulation 1804/99 requires organic sources of all components of feed in organic husbandry. Especially for organic pig and poultry nutrition it is not researched which components ensure the supply of amino acids. &#xD;
In our previous studies in 2003 with laying hens with genetics of TETRA, the effect of a high percentage of linoleic acids coming from soybeans was demonstrated. The egg weight increased to an average of 73 g in laying week 38 (ANDERSSON et al. 2004). Consequently we tried in 2004 to reduce the egg weights  &#xD;
•	by using the genetics of ISA XH &#xD;
•	by using components with less linoleic acid in the feed. &#xD;
Using the genetics of ISA XH was one advisable result to reduce egg weights. In this actual study, the hens fed with soybeans laid eggs with highest weight, but on an acceptable level of about 60 – 68 g / egg. Rations with very low energy concentration (9,6 MJ ME, 21 g/kg linoleic acid) were accepted by the hens, while feed consumption increased to more than 145 g/ hen and day. Therefore it seems possible to lower concentrations of amino acids, especially methionine, if the feed intake increases. The laying performance of hens fed with energy concentrations of 9,4 – 9,8 MJ ME was during the laying period of first 14 weeks comparable with the performance of the control group fed with a “standard” ration, later (data only until week 22) it was on a lower but acceptable level.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3398/1/3398.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Andersson, Robby; Meyer zu Bakum, R.J. and Schreiber, A.    (2005) Legehennefutter mit 100% Öko-Komponenten.  [Using 100% organic feed in laying hens.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3398/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>