<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Possible roles, positions, factors and components of dairying in organic farming – a rewiev, mapping, survey and comparison in the Czech Republic</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hanuš, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roubal, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vorlíček, Zdeněk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rozsypal, Roman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Janů, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genčurová, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pozdíšek, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The full-value experiment is questionable in evaluation organic dairying. It is problem to do a trial under&#xD;
comparable conditions for comparison of organic and conventional farming because of legislative reasons&#xD;
and necessity of long period of such event. Most of comparisons are carried out as practice descriptive&#xD;
observations and any of them has been carried out about milk production. That is main reason, why the aim of&#xD;
this work is to carry out a opening of monitoring of some production conditions and results of bio-dairying in&#xD;
the Czech Republic (CR). The quality aspects of sources, procedures and products are main topics of solution&#xD;
of projects about organic farming philosophy, in particular in solution of organic dairy foodstuff chain. There&#xD;
were choosen twelve organic dairy farms (survey II, 2006) for more detail research of production conditions&#xD;
according to results of exploratory questionnaire (2006, survey I, n = 85 pieces of questionnaire and 58&#xD;
organic farms, which practicise dairying) in the CR. The climatology characteristics of selected organic dairy&#xD;
farms were as follows: (I) 562±149 m above sea level on the average (from 270 to 970 m a. s. l.); (II)&#xD;
571.0±69.9 m above sea level, mean year temperature 6.0±1.1 ºC and average year rainfall sum 843.0±184.3&#xD;
mm. It is clear according to previously mentioned figures that the organic (ecology) dairy farming is realized&#xD;
mostly in the mountain or sub-mountain areas (less favourable areas, LFAs) as compared to climatic&#xD;
conditions of CR mean profile.&#xD;
The results of investigation of organic farm (E) and breeder conditions and dairy cow health state,&#xD;
reproduction performance and milk quality in organic farms (I data file) as compared to conventional dairy&#xD;
cow herds (K) were: milk yield (E) was 14.2±3.4 kg of milk/cow/day on average and 5165±1112 kg/cow/year;&#xD;
E farms have 50 % free stables, some of them as different untraditional modifications (mostly in herds with&#xD;
low number of dairy cows); it is necessary to increase this amount for welfare improvement in the future;&#xD;
there are 52 % of binding stables in K herds; there (E) is high occurrence frequency of can milking&#xD;
equipments (46.4 %); there are 5.4 % cases of hand milking, 21.4 % of pipeline milking equipments and 26.8&#xD;
% of milking parlours; there (K) are 3 % of can milking equipments, 50 % of pipeline milking equipments&#xD;
and 47 % of milking parlours; the average organic herd has 60±91 heads it means about 1/3 of K herd in the&#xD;
CR; geometrical average (xg) of organic herd size is 17 heads; daily milk deliveries were 1318±1475 kg in&#xD;
summer and 976±1368 kg in winter season (there is too high variability in the mentioned indicators); breed&#xD;
structure of E herds is 59.8 % of Bohemian Spotted cattle, 18.8 % of Holstein (H), 12.5 % of Jersey breed; H&#xD;
breed is dominating 47.5 % in K herds; average ratio of excluded milk (for secretion disorders or treatment)&#xD;
is 2.99 % in E herds and 4.6 % in K herds (P&lt;0.01); also there (E) is lower occurrence of clinical mastitis&#xD;
0.53±1.97 %; service period is 124.3 days in K and 98.7±46,1 days in E herds on average (P&lt;0.01); there (E)&#xD;
is better insemination index 1.66±0.45 in comparison to K herds 2.07 (P&lt;0.01); there is longer longevity as&#xD;
duration of production life of dairy cows in E herds (6.02 lactations, „about 141 % better”) in comparison to&#xD;
K herds (2.50 lactations, P&lt;0.01); milk quality showed the average total mesophilic bacteria count (CPM)&#xD;
36.0±26.8 ths. CFU/ml in organic farms (E), which is comparable to the conventional farms (K); somatic cell&#xD;
count (PSB) was 192±87 ths./ml in E herds and 256 ths./ml in K herds, which is in connection with the lower ratio of milk exclusion from delivery in E herds; an occurrence of residues of inhibitory substances (RIL) was&#xD;
not reported in E herds, which is more advantageous in comparison to the K herds (0.16 %) and it could be&#xD;
an impact of lowered antibiotica drug use; the average fat and lactose contents (T; 4.05±0.19 %) and (L;&#xD;
4.83±0.15 %) are well comparable with K farms and the results show on higher energy deficiency in E herd&#xD;
nutrition.&#xD;
The water quality (II) is necessary in dairying as well. Drinking water is necessary for health of animals&#xD;
(their watering) and for milk quality (milking equipment sanitation) as well. Drinking water is asked in dairy&#xD;
farms by legislation. The E farm water quality: the nitrate level varied in the range from 1.63 to 28 mg/l with&#xD;
average 10.5 mg/l in ecological farms and standard limit 50 mg/l was not exceeded; the levels of nitrite and&#xD;
ammonia ions were mostly under detection limit of method; legislative limit &lt;0.5 mg/l was not exceeded by&#xD;
nitrite and once by ammonia ions 0.81 mg/l. The microbiological indicators are more sensitive of course. In&#xD;
total the limits were exceeded 7× u in coliform bacteria, 3× in streptococci and Escherichia coli was&#xD;
confirmed 3× (in comparison to demand 0). Therefore it is necessary to take care of incidental water source&#xD;
sanitation.&#xD;
The effect of origin of water source (communal water pipes or own well in the organic farm area) which&#xD;
was used in the organic farming (II) was: the more marked result differences were not observed between own&#xD;
wells (S) and communal water supply (V) in E farms; an exception was stated in insignificantly better results&#xD;
of hygienic indicators of communal supply; therefore it is necessary to put the higher importance on&#xD;
sanitation of own water sources. There were identified eight own wells and four communal supply. E. g.&#xD;
nitrate levels were a little higher for wells 11.7 &gt; 8.2 mg/l. The nitrites were not different. Chemical oxygen&#xD;
consumption was 0.45 and 0.52 mg/l. The more expressive differences were identified in chlorides, sulphates&#xD;
and Mg: 8.33 and 3.02 mg/l; 27.9 and 16.8 mg/l; 18.9 and 3.5 mg/l.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21323/1/Str%C3%A1nky_z_Bulletin-1_2008-vnit%C5%99ek.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hanuš, O.; Roubal, P.; Vorlíček, Zdeněk; Rozsypal, Roman; Janů, L.; Genčurová, V. and Pozdíšek, J.   (2008) Possible roles, positions, factors and components of dairying in organic farming – a rewiev, mapping, survey and comparison in the Czech Republic.  [Možné role, pozice, faktory a složky mlékařství v ekologickém zemědělství – rešerše, mapování, přehled a srovnání v České republice.]  Cattle Research, 181 (1), pp. 13-37.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21323/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>