<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Root growth vigour is a better predictor than root hair traits of early nutrient uptake in spring wheat plants grown at low soil fertility</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Yaosheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Stoumann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background and Aims A number of root and root hair traits have been proposed as important for acquisition of P. However, it remains unknown whether these traits are most important in determining macro- and micronutrient uptake at low soil fertility. This study investigated the variations in root and root hair traits among spring wheat genotypes and examined which root and root hair traits are most important for high uptake of macro- and micronutrients. &#xD;
Methods Six spring wheat genotypes were grown in a soil with low nutrient availability. The root and root hair traits as well as the content of macro- and micronutrients were identified. &#xD;
Results A significant genetic variability in root and root hair traits was found. High root growth vigour and long and dense root hairs enhanced uptake of macro- and micronutrients under low soil nutrient availability. Root growth vigour, however, was a better predictor of early nutrient acquisition than root hair length and density. &#xD;
Conclusions Selection and breeding for high root growth vigour and long and dense root hairs is a promising strategy to ensure efficient acquisition of both macro- and micronutrients in the early establishment of spring wheat in nutrient-limited soil and low nutrient input cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27912/2/27912.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wang, Yaosheng; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Jensen, Lars Stoumann  and Magid, Jakob   (2014) Root growth vigour is a better predictor than root hair traits of early nutrient uptake in spring wheat plants grown at low soil fertility.   Plant and Soil.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27912/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>