<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Determining the effect of organic and low-input production methods on food quality and safety. QLIF subproject 2: Effects of production methods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objectives of QLIF subproject 2 were to: (i) identify the effect of production systems (organic, low-input and conventional) on food quality and safety parameters; (ii) identify agronomic parameters responsible for differences in food quality and safety; (iii) carry out a pilot study into the effect of consumption of organic crops on hormonal balances and immune status in a model experimental animal system. The results showed that organic food production methods resulted in: (a) higher levels of nutritionally desirable compounds (e.g., vitamins/antioxidants and poly-unsaturated fatty acids such as omega-3 and CLA); (b) lower levels of nutritionally undesirable compounds such as heavy metals, mycotoxins, pesticide residues and glyco-alkaloids in a range of crops and/or milk; (c) a lower risk of faecal Salmonella shedding in pigs. These nutritional benefits were linked to specific agronomic practices that are prescribed by organic farming standards. Pilot studies showed that these composition differences may translate into measurable health benefits in a model experimental system with rats. Further elaboration on the complex interaction between production methods and health benefits will have to be addressed in future studies.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Elsgaard, L</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16589/1/folder_2_small.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leifert, C     (editor): Elsgaard, L (Ed.)    (2009) Determining the effect of organic and low-input production methods on food quality and safety. QLIF subproject 2: Effects of production methods.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16589/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>