<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anbau transgener Pflanzen – Räumliche Aspekte der Koexistenz</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schlatter, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oehen, Bernadette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Most of the farmers in Switzerland won’t apply GMO farming. Their organisations support a five-year ban for the marketing of transgenic plants. However, in Switzerland there is no political discussion on co-existence as in the European community and their member states. In this study, the spatial aspects of coexistence of transgenic, conventional and organic farming in Switzerland are investigated. It shows that there are only 28 communities of 2848 where all farmers are bound by different labels to produce GMO-free. Most of these communities are situated in high altitude regions. In contrast, in arable regions of Switzerland, few farmers produce organic crops. In most of the communities in Switzerland, the simultaneous production with and without transgenic plants will be a huge problem. Special attention must be devoted to neighbouring producers all along the national boundary.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3596/1/3596.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schlatter, Christian and Oehen, Bernadette    (2005) Anbau transgener Pflanzen – Räumliche Aspekte der Koexistenz.  [Cultivation of transgenic plants - Spatial aspects of coexistence.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3596/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>