<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Resistenzzüchtung in Dresden-Pillnitz - Der Apfel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peil, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lesemann, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dunemann, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Höfer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flachowsky, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hanke, V.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Institute of Fruit Breeding has a long tradition in breeding resistant apple cultivars. Systematic resistance breeding started in the 1930 ties in Müncheberg. Material developed in Müncheberg was transferred in the 1970 ties to the Institute for Fruit Research, the antecessor of the Institute of Fruit Breeding. Based on this material, a couple of multiple resistant cultivars were generated. The time schedule for combining biotic and abiotic resistant traits which  demonstrates the long-lasting period necessary for systematic resistance breeding is given. An overview of resistant cultivars of Dresden-Pillnitz and the respective resistant traits is presented. This assortment of cultivars was developed to provide a resistant cultivar for each ripening group and every application in fruit growing. &#xD;
Modern resistance breeding is focused on quality and combination of different resistance genes for each pathogene to achieve durable resistance. Selection is facilitated by genetic markers. Likewise the look for new resistance genes, the analyses of genetics and the development of basic material are main areas of interest. Practical approaches in apple breeding to reach these aims are reported.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8931/1/ecofruit_12th_29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Peil, A.; Lesemann, S.; Dunemann, F.; Höfer, M.; Flachowsky, H. and Hanke, V.-M.    (2006) Resistenzzüchtung in Dresden-Pillnitz - Der Apfel.  [Resistance Breeding at Dresden-Pillnitz - Apple.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Weinsberg, Germany, pp. 161-164.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8931/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>