<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An interdisciplinary approach to analyse production, marketing and consumption of organic products</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fonseca, Maria Fernanda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilkinson, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper analyses the networks of production, marketing, and consumption of organics products understood as specific quality products, using an interdisciplinary approach to understand how institutions are constructed, how standards and rules are established and implemented, and which values and habits are negotiated, enforced, and regulated. Governments and Civil Society are both important for coordinating the organic agrifood systems, given the diversity of cultures, ideas, policies, territories, habits and regulatory systems. Transaction Costs Theory, French Convention Theory, Social Network Analyses, and Actor-Network Theory are all approaches that help to analyse the diversity of relations established between actors in agrifood systems designed to protect the environment and defend issues of social justice.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4345/4/Fonseca_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fonseca, Maria Fernanda and Wilkinson, John    (2005) An interdisciplinary approach to analyse production, marketing and consumption of organic products.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4345/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>