<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ß-Glucan contents of groats of different oat cultivars in official variety, in organic cultivation, and in nitrogen fertilization trials in Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saastamoinen, Marketta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hietaniemi, Veli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pihlava, Juha-Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eurola, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kontturi, Markku</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tuuri, Hannu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niskanen, Markku</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kangas, Arjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>ß-Glucan is a beneficial chemical compound in the diet of humans by decreasing the levels of serum cholesterol and blood glucose. The ß-glucan contents of oat groats were studied in official variety trials (1997-1999), nitrogen fertilization trials (1997-1999) and organic variety trials (1997-1998) in Finland. Eight cultivars were studied in the organic variety trials. Two of them, cultivars Puhti and Veli, were cultivated also with a conventional method at the same fields. The years 1997 and 1999 were very warm and dry and 1998 very cool and rainy. The effects of year and cultivar on ß-glucan content were significant in all three trial series. The Kolbu oat cultivar had a significantly lower ß- glucan content than other cultivars in all trials. N fertilization did not increase the ß-glucan contents of oats in Finland. The effect of cultivation method (traditional vr organic cultivation) had no significant effect on the ß-glucan content. The year x cultivar interaction significantly affected the ß-glucan contents of oat groats in N fertilization trials. The reaction of different cultivars to weather conditions was different. Kolbu oat cultivar had significantly lower ß-glucan contents in 1998 than in warm years in all three trial series.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16820/1/saastamoinen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Saastamoinen, Marketta; Hietaniemi, Veli; Pihlava, Juha-Matti; Eurola, Merja; Kontturi, Markku; Tuuri, Hannu; Niskanen, Markku and Kangas, Arjo   (2004) ß-Glucan contents of groats of different oat cultivars in official variety, in organic cultivation, and in nitrogen fertilization trials in Finland.   Agricultural and Food Science, 13 (1-2), pp. 68-79.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16820/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>