<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Baking Quality of Winter Wheat Varieties in Organic Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The technological value of wheat is negatively influenced by organic methods of cultivation. The critical factor is the crude protein content and quality. The aim of this paper is to identify diferences in the quality of eight varieties and two strains of wheat recommended in conventional or organic conditions. Correlation analysis of the qualitative parameters of wheat shows a clear relationship between crude protein content, wet gluten content and Zeleny - sedimentation value. According to the test results, it is appropriate to use the content and quality of protein as selective criteria for the selection of varieties. The Level of baking quality is never reduced below the quality level of the worstquality varieties grown in the same conditions. On the other hand, the best quality varieties provide grains characterized by better baking quality, but lower yield level, than the others.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20773/1/Agronomy_research_-_Konvalina_a_kol._II.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Konvalina, Petr; Moudry, Jan (Jr.); Capouchova, Ivana and Moudry, Jan   (2009) Baking Quality of Winter Wheat Varieties in Organic Farming.   Agronomy Research, 7, pp. 612-617.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20773/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>