<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>CorePig: Prevention of selected diseases and parasites in organic pig herds - by means of a HACCP based management and surveillance programme</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project was initiated at the project kick-off meeting in Denmark, August 30-31st 2007, where all project partners met to discuss the planning of the project in detail. The group comprises about 20 researchers from 10 research institutes in DK, DE, SE, UK, CH, IT, AU and FR, respectively. The project is composed of three work packages, with WP1 and WP2 starting in 2007, while WP3 is building on the results from WP1 and WP2 and therefore starts later - in 2008. The UK and CH-partners only participate in WP1 and WP3 while the remaining partners participate in all three WP’s. The second project meeting was organised in Austria, December 10-11th 2007, the third project meeting in Denmark, February 18-19th 2008 (WP2 activities), the forth in France, July 7-9th 2008, the fifth in Bologna, December 4.-7th 2008, the sixth in Sweden, June 29-30th 2009 and a final seventh project meeting is scheduled to take place in Germany, April 8-10th 2010.&#xD;
The present annual abstract is a follow-up on the annual abstract covering the period June 1st –July 31st, 2008 and the mid term report covering the period July 1st 2007 – December 31st 2008. Additional to these reports remarks on milestone and deliverable plans are given.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18673/1/18673.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    CorePig: Prevention of selected diseases and parasites in organic pig herds - by means of a HACCP based management and surveillance programme.    Runs 2009 - 2009.      Project Leader(s): Nielsen, Tine Rousing, University of Aarhus.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18673/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>