<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Efficacy of different insecticides and a repellent against the European pear sucker (Cacopsylla pyri)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The efficacy of different insecticides (neem, pyrethrin, spinosad, and rotenone) and a repellent (kaolin)&#xD;
applied with different strategies (single or repeated applications) against the over-wintering pear&#xD;
suckers (Cacopsylla pyri) and nymphs of the first generation was tested in a field trial in Switzerland&#xD;
in spring 2003.&#xD;
Rotenone, the only admitted product in Swiss organic agriculture, showed good effects. But, since&#xD;
Rotenone is toxic for non-target insects we looked for an alternative. The application of spinosad&#xD;
(Audienz) in combination with rape oil (Telmion) as well as the application of pyrethrum showed&#xD;
similar efficacy as rotenone. Neem had no or a very low impact on the pear sucker populations. The&#xD;
repellent kaolin (Surround® WP) showed the best efficacy against the European pear sucker: triple&#xD;
application of kaolin before blossom was most efficient. Since kaolin is not toxic for beneficials this&#xD;
product might be an alternative to rotenone.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14029/1/7_Daniel_35_40.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia and Wyss, Eric    (2004) Efficacy of different insecticides and a repellent against the European pear sucker (Cacopsylla pyri).  [Wirkung verschiedener Insektizide und Repellentien gegen den Gemeinen Birnenblattsauger (Cacopsylla pyri).]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 35-40.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14029/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>