<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A comparison between organic and integrated apple production: First results after 5 years of observation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzwieser, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic apple production is of increasing commercial importance throughout Europe, but&#xD;
especially in South Tyrol where about 25% of the whole European organic apple crop is&#xD;
produced.&#xD;
In organic apple production, producers face the challenge of choosing varieties that are&#xD;
both in demand and also resistant to the main pests and diseases. Every now and then,&#xD;
the question arises, if yields, losses and profitability are different in integrated and organic&#xD;
orchards and in how great are the differences between single apple varieties.&#xD;
In 1999 the Laimburg Research Centre started a field trial to observe the effects of&#xD;
different cultivation methods on 18 apple varieties in a randomised block design. In the first&#xD;
four years of production, significant differences in the yield potential between the varieties&#xD;
as well as between integrated and organic production were observed. In organic farming,&#xD;
yields were lower and organic fruits were of smaller size. In organic production the leaves&#xD;
contained less nitrogen in spring. In summer there were no more significant differences&#xD;
concerning nitrogen.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14546/1/43_Kelderer_227_234.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kreuzwieser, Andreas and Kelderer, Markus    (2004) A comparison between organic and integrated apple production: First results after 5 years of observation.  [Biologischer und integrierter Apfelanbau im Vergleich: Eine Zwischenbilanz nach 5 Standjahren.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 227-234.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14546/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>