<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Veränderungen der Konsumintensität von Öko-Lebensmitteln&#xD;
in Haushalten mit Kindern</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Riefer, Dipl.-Soziologin Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Prof.Dr. Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Considering results of consumer surveys the question arises that on the one hand the&#xD;
health of children is a major motive for organic food consumption in households with&#xD;
children and why on the other hand consumption intensity decreases as children get&#xD;
older. The contribution presents results of a qualitative study investigating changes in&#xD;
families’ organic food consumption and their reasons from the subjective perspective&#xD;
of consumers. The findings are based on information gained by problem centred&#xD;
interviews with family members responsible for food purchases; data analysis was&#xD;
done by means of Grounded Theory. It was found that children can be reasons for an&#xD;
increase of organic food consumption by indirectly influencing parents’ willingness to&#xD;
purchase organic food in the time of pregnancy and the transition to a complementary&#xD;
diet for babies. In contrast to that children also can directly affect a decrease of organic&#xD;
food consumption in their families by actively rejecting particular organic food&#xD;
products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14018/1/Riefer_14018.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Riefer, Dipl.-Soziologin Angelika and Hamm, Prof.Dr. Ulrich    (2009) Veränderungen der Konsumintensität von Öko-Lebensmitteln in Haushalten mit Kindern.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14018/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>