<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of organic fruit in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willer, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwartau, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Europe is both a leading world market for and world producer of organic food. Growth of organically managed land and of domestic market values was strong in the past and continued during the financial recession, although at a slower rate. Many countries have specific plans for priority organic research and investment. Europe is a major producer of organic fruit crops, including a total of more than 900,000 ha consisting of 367,000 ha of olives, 92,700 ha of grapes, 187,000 ha of nuts, 94,800 ha of temperate fruit, 26,096 ha of berries, 31,800 ha of citrus, and 11,000 ha of subtropical fruit (2010). Western Europe added 4,000 ha of organic apples (Malus ×domestica) in 2010 and 2011 due to growth of the organic fruit market, a decline in conventional fruit prices, and improved organic production methods and input products. Market saturation has occurred in years of high organic apple yields, and thus organic fruit growers and retailers are working to gain new customers, especially lifestyle of health and sustainability (LOHAS) consumers. Tools to help organic fruit growers better evaluate farm economics (e.g., Arbokost) are available and needed as increased prices are often nearly matched by increased production costs. New disease control products and models are helping address key fruit diseases such as apple scab (Venturia inaequalis) and sooty blotch (Gloedes pomigena and Schizotorium pomi), yet barriers for other fruits remain. As conventional fruit production embodies more sustainability and reduces pesticide residues, consumers perceived added value of organic fruit could diminish. Research at the Swiss Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and elsewhere is attempting to redesign organic fruit systems to be more self-regulating by choosing fruit genetics that minimize input needs and increasing biodiversity in the farm ecosystem, thus continuing to distinguish organic production from other methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23575/1/OrganicFruitEurope_WeibelEtal_2013.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, F.P.; Daniel, C.; Tamm, L.; Willer, H. and Schwartau, H.    (2013) Development of organic fruit in Europe.   In:     Acta Horticulturae, 1001, pp. 19-34.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23575/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>