<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mineral load on the paddock of organic sows in the Netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivanova-Peneva, Sonya</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aarnink, Andrè</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verstegen, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main aim of this study was to quantify nutrient deposition on the paddock in Dutch organic pig farms. Observations of excreting behaviour of grazing sows were carried out at three farms in each of two measuring seasons (spring/summer and autumn). The nutrient loads of N, P and K were calculated according to their content in urine and faeces, average weight of urine and faeces per excretion, and number of urinations and defecations done in the paddock. The N and P loads on the paddock varied greatly between the organic pig farms (P&lt;0.01 for N, not significant for P and P&lt;0.05 for K).  The total amount of nutrients on two of the farms far exceeded the permitted levels (170 kg.ha-1year-1 for N and 44  kg.ha-1year-1 for P). On all three farms, faeces were unevenly distributed in the paddock. Regular rotation of paddocks resulted in a more uniform distribution.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4377/4/4377-Ivanova-Peneva_etal_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivanova-Peneva, Sonya; Aarnink, Andrè and Verstegen, Martin    (2005) Mineral load on the paddock of organic sows in the Netherlands.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4377/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>