<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Localisation and recycling in rural food systems - impact and solutions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Granstedt, Artur</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bäckman, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fischer, Holger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hannula, Annamari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kakriainen, Salla</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krumalova, Veronica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsson, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehto, Tiina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nousiainen, Marko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pylkkänen, Päivi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seppänen, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seuri, Pentti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sumelius, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsson, Olof</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vesala, Kari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vihma, Antto</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the study was to assess the impact of an increased share of local organic food based on local resources, especially on increased recycling (i.e. the impact of increased locality or localization), on sustainability of rural food systems around the Baltic Sea. Obstacles and solutions for sustainable localization and recycling were also identified. In addition to these main objectives, a methodological interest in developing interdisciplinary research processes was also incorporated. Case food systems in eight Baltic countries were studied on the basis of interviews and stakeholder workshops, as well as by analysis of environmental indicators and economic parameters at farm and food system level by a European multidisciplinary research group. According to the results, marked benefits on environment, local economy and social sustainability can be obtained through enhanced recycling and an increased share of local organic food in the rural food systems. These benefits require, however, well-informed choices for performing&#xD;
localization and recycling in a sustainable manner. Recycling, especially in agriculture, but also at the food system level, ensures environmental benefits while locality relieves that and is crucial for the benefits in local economy and social sustainability. The scale of sustainable localization varies, however, according to the product and process concerned. In some cases, recycling between the farms seems to require smaller&#xD;
economic compensation than recycling within the farms. To realize the potential of localization and recycling, marked obstacles have to be overcome by providing economic incentives for recycling to farmers, a local certificate and information to consumers and intensified cooperation between the local stakeholders.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), Bonn; Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cornish, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, William</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5942/1/Kahiluoto.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kahiluoto, Helena; Granstedt, Artur; Bäckman, Stefan; Fischer, Holger; Hannula, Annamari; Kakriainen, Salla; Krumalova, Veronica; Larsson, Markus; Lehto, Tiina; Nousiainen, Marko; Pylkkänen, Päivi; Schneider, Thomas; Seppänen, Laura; Seuri, Pentti; Sumelius, John; Thomsson, Olof; Vesala, Kari and Vihma, Antto    (2005) Localisation and recycling in rural food systems - impact and solutions.       Paper at:   Researching sustainable systems : first scientific conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), held in cooperation with IFOAM and NASAA, Adelaide, South Australia, 21-23 September 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5942/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>