<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Die Rolle der Erzeugergemeinschaften auf dem deutschen Markt für ökologisch produzierte Produkte - Eine empirische Untersuchung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, Gudula</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There are inadequate reliable data about the organic food market in Germany. Producer cooperatives (Erzeugergemeinschaften-EZG) play an important role in distributive trade. The research objective is to identify the amount of products brought to the market by the EZGs as well as their position in the market. The analysis is empirical. The interviews are conducted by telephone. Particularly EZGs deal with raw products and mainly with the products of their members. Small purchases are only made to ensure continuous supply to customers. The relevance of own processing is small. EZGs made a contribution to the development of the market of organic food by providing a good supply for their customers. They combine the offers of their members into a bundle, they implement quality control and via reasonable purchases they offer a wise range of products. EZGs market a quarter of all organic food, which is produced in Germany.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3657/1/3657.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Madsen, Gudula    (2004) Die Rolle der Erzeugergemeinschaften auf dem deutschen Markt für ökologisch produzierte Produkte - Eine empirische Untersuchung.  [The role of producer cooperatives in the German market of organic food.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3657/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>