<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farm size and landscape composition in relation to landscape changes in Denmark</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Levin, Gregor</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper explores relationships between farm size and landscape composition in terms of densities of uncultivated landscape elements and sizes of agricultural fields. The study is based on national agricultural registers for Denmark and on aerial photo interpretation of three study areas, representing different Danish landscape types.  Results indicate significantly smaller fields and significantly higher densities of unculti-vated landscape elements on small farms (&lt;25ha). At national level, current differences between small and large farms are to some extent caused by landscape changes between 1998 and 2004. Analyses of the study areas indicate that current differences between small and large farms mainly evolved between 1982 and 2002, while the influences of changes between 1954 and 1982 are limited. Relationships between farms size and landscape composition are independent of spatial variations in soil type and slope conditions. Consequently, attention must be paid to other parameters linked to farm size. In particular, the effects on landscape composition of part-time and hobby farming, as well as production type, must be considered.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9836/1/9836.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Levin, Gregor   (2006) Farm size and landscape composition in relation to landscape changes in Denmark.   Danish Journal of Geography, 106 (2), pp. 45-59.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9836/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>