<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spiders (Araneae)in organically managed ley and pasture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pommeresche, Reidun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study focusses on the spider fauna in two organically managed leys in different stages of a crop rotation and in one permanent pasture, all on the Tingvoll Farm in northwestern Norway. Spiders were collected by means of pitfall traps; the sampling period lasted from 28 April to 23 June 2000. Altogether 2415 specimens, representing 48 species, were found. A DCA-analysis shows differences in the spider populations found in the leys compared with the pasture, but less difference between the young and older ley. However, the number of species and the dominance pattern of the spider populations differ between the young and older ley. A total of 16 species were found in the young ley, 26 species in the older ley and 34 species in the pasture. Bathyphantes gracilis, Erigone atra, Oedothorax fuscus and Savignia frontata were the most abundant species in the leys, with Pardosa amentata and Silometopus elegans the most abundant in the pasture. Collinsia inerrans was represented by 83 specimens in the leys. This species is previously recorded only twice in Norway, and has been placed on the national Red List proposal.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>The Norwegian Entomological Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sømme, Lauritz</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6829/1/Artikkel_pdf_Pommeresche_2002.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pommeresche, Reidun   (2002) Spiders (Araneae)in organically managed ley and pasture.   Norwegian Journal of Entomology, 49, pp. 51-58.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6829/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>