<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil Fertility: Organic vs. Conventional Farming Systems in Vojvodina, northern Serbia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Manojlovic, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cabilovski, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalentic, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to examine on-farm the influence of organic farming systems on soil fertility, in order to recommend agrotechnical practices that will contribute to increase soil fertility, thus the yield and quality of cultivated plants. The survey was conducted at 7 representative farms in the system of control and certification in Vojvodina, northern Serbia, and within them, 55 production fields with different history of farming practices. Optimal to high soil fertility found in average in all investigated sites indicates that there are necessary natural preconditions for successful organic farming. The results showed high variability in soil fertility, both, between organic farming systems and between different sites. Significant differences in soil fertility between organic and conventional production, have not been found.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic, Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19838/1/19838.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Manojlovic, M.; Cabilovski, R. and Kalentic, M    (2011) Soil Fertility: Organic vs. Conventional Farming Systems in Vojvodina, northern Serbia.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic, Drazen; Hashem, Yousry and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstract. International Conference on ORGANIC AGRICULTURE and AGRO-ECO TOURSIM in the Mediterranean, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19838/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>