<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integration of organic poultry in whole farm systems:&#xD;
manure nutrient budgets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gordon, Susan H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bhogal, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walker, Andrew W</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. The aim of this project was to examine how rotations incorporating organic poultry use the cycling of nutrients between soil, crops and birds. Poultry studies have measured nutrient values of manure in slow growing meat birds at about day 81 when fed typical broiler rations versus “Label Rouge” rations. Nutrient (N, P, K) balances were constructed to assess the viability of integrating poultry production within a theoretical organic rotation. The readilyplant- available nitrogen in manure from Ross 308 birds fed either presumed non-limiting rations or Label Rouge rations was within the range reported for intensive broilers. For ISA 657 birds, the manure readily-plant-available nitrogen was similar to the mean value reported for broilers, when fed presumed non limiting rations, but towards the lower range when fed Label Rouge rations. As breed growth and feed intakes differ it is suggested that to optimise the utilisation of nutrients, the nutrient content of table bird manures should be checked prior to land application. The nutrient budgets were similar for N and P regardless of the length of rotation or form of poultry production. On average, there was a surplus of 85 kg/ha N over all the scenarios. There tended to be a deficit of K in all scenarios (average: 10 kg/ha).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8285/1/gordon_poultry__manure_nutrient.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gordon, Susan H; Bhogal, Anne and Walker, Andrew W    (2002) Integration of organic poultry in whole farm systems: manure nutrient budgets.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 263-268.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8285/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>