<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Factors influencing biodiversity within organic and conventional systems of arable farming – methodologies and preliminary results</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Norton, Lisa R</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. This paper describes the approaches and preliminary results of a study that is designed to provide a large amount of data at a range of scales in order to investigate the potential factors influencing biodiversity on arable farmland on comparable organic and conventional farms. In particular, the study examines the role of non-crop habitats within the different farming systems and how the extent and management of non-crop habitats differs between them. A detailed description of the methodologies being employed to establish differences in non-crop habitat, plant, invertebrate and bird diversity is given. The study remains in its early stages as a result of the impact of Foot and Mouth disease on the fieldwork schedule during 2001. The process of setting up the study revealed that the numbers of farmers growing cereals organically are low as a proportion of the organic sector as a whole, despite recent large increases in numbers of farmers converting to organic production. Preliminary results from the first year of fieldwork on plants reveal significant differences between organic and conventional farms in terms of the numbers of weed species on fields and non-significant differences in numbers of species found on non-crop habitats.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8413/1/norton_Factors_biodiversity_arable_farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Norton, Lisa R    (2002) Factors influencing biodiversity within organic and conventional systems of arable farming – methodologies and preliminary results.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 231-236.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8413/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>