<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ist die Behandlung von subklinischen Mastitiden mit Homöopathika empfehlenswert?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Werner, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effectiveness of homeopathic treatment in the case of subclinical bovine mastitis was assessed. 39 cows with 65 udder quarters, infected with environmental associated pathogens, were treated. Two therapeutical methods, classical homeopathy and antibiotics were compared to the application of a placebo. Milk samples were collected for bacteriology and milk somatic cell count. The results showed that the cure rate was on a low level. The success of homeopathic therapy (7 %) was in midway between antibiotics and placebo. It can be concluded that the homeopathic treatment is not recommended for the therapy of subclinical bovine mastitis caused by environmental associated pathogens.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3792/1/3792.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Werner, C. and Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert    (2004) Ist die Behandlung von subklinischen Mastitiden mit Homöopathika empfehlenswert?  [Is homeopathic treatment recommended for subclinical mastitis?]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3792/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>