<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bicropping-Verfahren von Winterungen (Getreide und Raps) mit&#xD;
Beisaaten abfrierender Körnerleguminosen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bachinger, Dr. Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fischer, Holger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Bicropping systems based on forage legumes undersown in winter cereals can&#xD;
achieve yield and quality improvements with sufficient water supply during the main&#xD;
growth phase, but fail under dry site conditions (continental climate, sandy soil). To&#xD;
improve the N-supply without the risk of interspecific water and nutrient competition,&#xD;
bicropping systems were developed with simultaneously or parallel intercropped nonhardy&#xD;
grain legumes at in early sown winter cereals or oil seed rape. They were tested&#xD;
in practice with on-farm experiments carried out in Brandenburg and Bavaria. Besides&#xD;
a sufficient erosion protection, a significant N-input can be achieved with grain&#xD;
legumes in autumn especially within rape and early sown winter cereals. But only&#xD;
cereals showed a significant increase of yield and quality. Lodging frozen biomass&#xD;
(e.g. pea) can cause yield losses in rape.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14353/1/Bachinger_14353.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bachinger, Dr. Johann and Fischer, Holger    (2009) Bicropping-Verfahren von Winterungen (Getreide und Raps) mit Beisaaten abfrierender Körnerleguminosen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14353/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>