<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of diet on the milk quality of organic dairy cows</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weller, Richard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Davies, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Changes in milk quality were evaluated with spring-calving dairy cows and heifers fed organic diets and different levels of concentrates during early lactation. The diets were based on ad libitum forage and either 2 kg of concentrates/day (Diet 1) or concentrates fed according to milk yield up to a maximum of 7 kg/day (Diet 2). Average milk yields during the study for the cows and heifers were 23.1 and 20.1 kg/day (Diet 1) and 25.8 and 24.0 kg/day (Diet 2), respectively. The highest number of samples with a fat to protein ratio of 1.4 or &gt; were found in samples collected from cows and heifers fed Diet 1 (20.9 and 50.0%). The lowest milk protein value of 2.86% was recorded from the heifers fed Diet 1. Low milk lactose values were correlated to high somatic cell counts.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8391/1/weller_davies_diet_milk_quality.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weller, Richard and Davies, Robert    (2002) The effect of diet on the milk quality of organic dairy cows.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 197-198.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8391/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>