<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of Laying Hen Strains for biodynamic Farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zeltner, Esther</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In biodynamic and organic agriculture mostly the same strains of laying hens as in conventional agriculture are used. These strains require feed with a high nutrition level to tap the full potential of their genetic. When this feed is not available it may lead to health problems and ethological interferences as well as to a deficiency of performance. In this study, four potential adequate strains are evaluated and compared with a commercial strain using health and ethological parameters as well as characteristics of performance under biodynamic conditions. After one laying period the laying performance of Amberlik, Hyline, Sperber and Sussex was high but only the plumage condition of Sussex was acceptable. Therefore this strain will be used for further investigations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12203/1/Zeltner_12203_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zeltner, Esther    (2008) Evaluation of Laying Hen Strains for biodynamic Farms.       Paper at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science. 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), in the Frame of the 16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12203/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>