<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gründe für die Veränderung oder Einstellung des Angebotsprogramms ökologischer Lebensmittel in der&#xD;
Außer-Haus-Verpflegung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rückert-John, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>John, René</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The supply of organic food is constantly increasing in Germany. This development is accompanied by increasing research, certification, consultancy and wholesale towards this business. Nevertheless, implementing organic food in eating out facilities (EOF) faces several challenges. As part of an ongoing research project, we examined the reasons for the adoption or rejection of the supply of organic food in EOFs. The empirical base consists of 20 case-studies on EOFs using expert-interviews with several persons-in-charge. The reasons for adoption or rejection of the supply of organic food are various and dependent on internal or external factors of the organizations. The most important results regarding certification, low acceptance of offers by customers and the lack of regional provenance will be presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14038/1/Niessen_14038.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niessen, Jan; Rückert-John, Jana and John, René    (2009) Gründe für die Veränderung oder Einstellung des Angebotsprogramms ökologischer Lebensmittel in der Außer-Haus-Verpflegung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14038/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>