<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Systems for testing the efficacy of&#xD;
biofungicides and resistance inducers against grapevine downy mildew&#xD;
(REPCO project)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schweikert, Carmen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mildner, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vollrath, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kassemeyer, Dr. Hanns-Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract –At present grapevine downy mildew is controlled by fungicides mostly not suitable for or-ganic viticulture. The aim of REPCO (Replacement of Copper Fungicides in Organic Production if Grapevine and Apple in Europe) is to find new copper replacing products. Also the activation of the innate defence response by resistance inducers is a potential ap-proach for the biological control of grapevine downy mildew in organic viticulture. The efficacy of potential biofungicides and resistance inducers against grape-vine downy mildew was tested on leaf discs and on cell suspension culture, respectively. In a first step the direct effect on the pathogen is assessed in a leaf disc test. The activation of defence response is de-termined in a cell suspension culture. Molecules from microbes, products from the secondary plant metabo-lism and oligosaccharides from animals and plants showed an efficacy against the pathogen and induced resistance response.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7492/1/Abstract_Schweikert_et_al.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schweikert, Carmen; Mildner, Manuel; Vollrath, Claudia and Kassemeyer, Dr. Hanns-Heinz    (2006) Systems for testing the efficacy of biofungicides and resistance inducers against grapevine downy mildew (REPCO project).       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7492/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>