<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic food and farming research needs in the UK:A report on a stakeholder participatory consultation process</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pearce, Dr. Bruce</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gibbon, Dr. David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Dr. Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Ms S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moore, Dr. Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>During 2005 Defra commissioned a study to identify and analyse issues and aspirations that organic stakeholders felt should be addressed by publicly funded organic food and farming research in the UK.  How this was undertaken is presented in this paper.  A series of 12 workshops were undertaken with stakeholders throughout the UK. Nearly 300 stakeholders attended the workshops. These workshops used participatory approaches to identify and record the most important issues and aspirations from those attending.  &#xD;
	The use of a highly participatory style was greatly appreciated by stakeholders. In most cases the interaction between stakeholders worked well and resulted in lively discussions.  The workshops have served to open up a useful dialogue between groups of stakeholders who do not normally communicate directly.  They have produced a significant number of interesting and challenging issues and aspirations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7412/1/RandD_consultation_process_1.0.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7412/2/7412.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pearce, Dr. Bruce; Gibbon, Dr. David; Watson, Dr. Christine; Fowler, Ms S. and Moore, Dr. Charlotte    (2006) Organic food and farming research needs in the UK:A report on a stakeholder participatory consultation process.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7412/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>