<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Populationsgenetik der Minderempfindlichkeit des Apfelwicklers gegenüber Cydia pomonella Granulovirus (CpGV)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Asser, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gund, Nadine A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eberle, K. E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matt-Schmid, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reineke, Annette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckel, David G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, Claus P. W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jehle, J. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Codling moth granulovirus (Cydia pomonella granulovirus, CpGV, Baculoviridae) is one of the most important bio control agents of the codling moth in apple production. Since 2003, codling moth populations have been observed in Germany and France, which show an up to thousand fold decreased susceptibility to CpGV. A spread of this phenomenon is a severe threat to the efficient control of the codling moth, particularly in organic farming. In order to prevent this development, investigations on the popula-tion genetics of codling moth populations in Germany were initiated to assess the baseline susceptibilities of selected populations. Furthermore, the genetic and biologi-cal background of resistance of the codling moth to CpGV are being elucidated by crossing susceptible and low susceptible codling moth populations. These investiga-tions will help to develop new control strategies or to restore high susceptibility to-wards CpGV. &#xD;
Mapping of traits involved in resistance will be performed. Involved loci will be identi-fied with the help of amplified fragment length polymorphism (AFLP). Loci coupled with susceptibility can help to elucidate resistance mechanisms. Analysis of comple-mentary DNA amplified fragment length polymorphism (cDNA-AFLP) will be per-formed to display differences in expression rate of particular genes. If there are differ-ences between sensitive and non-sensitive strains, the genes will be isolated and sequenced. Putative sequence homologies give the direction of the functional sense of the mentioned gene and further conclusion of the mechanisms of the susceptibility of CpGV.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9829/1/9829_Asser_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Asser, Sabine; Gund, Nadine A.; Eberle, K. E.; Matt-Schmid, A.; Reineke, Annette; Heckel, David G.; Zebitz, Claus P. W. and Jehle, J. A.    (2007) Untersuchungen zur Populationsgenetik der Minderempfindlichkeit des Apfelwicklers gegenüber Cydia pomonella Granulovirus (CpGV).  [Analyses of the Population Genetics of the Low Susceptibility of codling moth against Cydia pomonella granulovirus (CpGV).]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9829/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>