<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modeling demand for organic foods</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wier, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smed, Sinne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The market of organic foods has experienced tremendous growth during the period 1997-1998. Highest growth is&#xD;
experienced at the bread/cereal group where the volume share has increased by 143% during the whole period.&#xD;
During this period, relative organic prices have decreased, except for meat. Organic volume shares are highest for dairy products (10%), which is more than twice the share for bread/cereals (5%) and other foods (4%), which covers fruit and vegetables. In the bottom is the share of organic meat (1%). The model estimates price and&#xD;
budget elasticities. The consumption of animal products (dairy, meat) is more sensitive to price changes than&#xD;
consumption of vegetables, cereals, fruit and bread. The demand is characterized by very high elasticities,&#xD;
especially for organic foods. The high price elasticities can be explained by the fact that conventional and organic&#xD;
commodities are very similar. The high budget elasticity can be explained by the luxury nature of organic&#xD;
commodities. In the study, scenario analyses are carried out. These scenarios show that if the relative organic price decreases by 20% consumption grows considerably. The volume share of organic dairies will increase to 15%, the&#xD;
share of organic bread/cereals to 7%, the share of organic meat to 2% and the share of fruit/vegetables to 6%.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/71/1/confpap.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wier, Mette and Smed, Sinne    (2000) Modeling demand for organic foods.       Paper at:   The 13th International Scientific IFOAM Conference, Basel, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/71/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>