<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exploiting grain bioactivity for improved nutrition and health</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Poutanen, Kaisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Foods should be made available to deliver more grain fibre and outer layers of the grains,&#xD;
while also addressing the consumer expectations of palatability and convenience. This&#xD;
demands for new ingredients high in grain phytochemicals and with good technological&#xD;
properties. The natural diversity in grains offers a good basis for tailored fractionation&#xD;
and bioprocessing. The grain chain from plant breeding and crop selection should take&#xD;
into account the nutritional quality criteria set by the end-use. This was the approach in&#xD;
the EU integrated project HEALTHGRAIN running in 2005-2010 (www.healthgrain.org),&#xD;
which addressed the whole grain chain to provide consumers with healthy grain-based&#xD;
foods and ingredients (Poutanen et al 2008). It included studies of consumer&#xD;
expectations, development of a biotechnology toolbox for plant breeding, development of&#xD;
wet and dry milling and novel bioprocessing technologies for grain processing, studies of&#xD;
mechanisms behind the metabolic merits of foods in a series of in vitro, animal and&#xD;
human studies, and identification of health-relevant cereal food criteria.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18283/1/Poutanen.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Poutanen, Kaisa    (2010) Exploiting grain bioactivity for improved nutrition and health.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18283/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>