<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Veränderung der Effizienz der Regenwurmaustreibung mit Senfsuspensionen im Tagesverlauf</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kautz, Timo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lee, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Görtz, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Täufer, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We tested the effect of sampling time on the efficiency of mustard extractions for earthworms in a field study. On an organic experimental farm (alluvial loams; Hennef/Germany) earthworm extractions were started on two consecutive days hourly from 10 am to 5 pm and 6 pm respectively. Significant effects of daytime on extracted earthworm biomass occurred on both days. Maximum biomass was extracted in the early afternoon in each case. Additional pot experiments have shown a significant temperature dependence of the mustard extraction method which at least partially explains the differences in on-site extracted earthworm biomass in the course of the day. We conclude that daytime has to be considered as a factor when using mustard extraction methods. When used in factorial field experiments, the extractions in different field plots should therefore be operated simultaneously.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17709/3/Kautz_17709.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kautz, Timo; Lee, J.; Görtz, M. and Täufer, Frank    (2011) Veränderung der Effizienz der Regenwurmaustreibung mit Senfsuspensionen im Tagesverlauf.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17709/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>