<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic livestock production - trapped between aroused consumer expectations and limited resources</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Literature reviews reveal that the implementation of organic standards have failed to clearly improve status of animal health and welfare on many farms in comparison to conventional production. The a huge variability with respect to this issue between organic farms indicate profound discrepancies between claim and reality of organic livestock farming. Thus, the hypothesis that the implementation of minimum standards will automatically provide benefits for the issue of animal health and welfare has been refuted by farm practice. As a consequence, organic farmers and retailers can no longer stick to the claim that organic products of animal origin are of higher value with respect to the issue of animal health and welfare. Reasons for the limited effects of the organic standards are multi-factorial and assumed to be farm specific in the fist place. On the other hand, limited availability of resources such as nutrients, labour time and investments within organic farm systems together with a high pressure on the production costs by retailers make any improvments very difficult. In order to preserve the credibility of organic agriculture and the confidence of the consumers in organic products there is a need for more transparency and for a change in the paradigm from a standard-oriented to an output-oriented approach. Credible information about the specific level of product and process qualities emerged by each farm has to be provided. Simultaneously, a high level of animal health and welfare has to be honoured by premium prices to cover the additional costs and efforts that are needed to improve the current situation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11813/1/11813.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Albert    (2008) Organic livestock production - trapped between aroused consumer expectations and limited resources.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11813/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>