<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The potential for mass trapping Lygus rugulipennis&#xD;
and Anthonomus rubi; trap design and efficacy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fountain, Michelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shaw, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trandem, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Storberget, Sverre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baroffio, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ralle, Baiba</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rendina, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richoz, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hall, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cross, Jerry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wibe, Atle</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cross vane funnel bucket traps with water and detergent captured significantly more A. rubi than sticky traps. L. rugulipennis catches were higher in the cross vane traps, but catches were impeded by the bee excluder grid. There were fewer of the target pest species captured on sticky traps and these devices tended to capture significantly more by-catch (e.g. Diptera) including beneficial insects, e.g. spiders and Carabidae. In the second experiment, the height of the green cross vane had no effect on the numbers of male L. rugulipennis trapped in the funnel traps. However, the higher cross vanes captured more coccinelids and opiliones. In the A. rubi trials there were significantly more individuals in the full height cross vane compared to the half-height or no cross vane treatments.&#xD;
Hence, the most effective trap for A. rubi and L. rugulipennis is a green Unitrap with no bee excluder grid. We are currently testing this device for mass trapping of both pests.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28904/1/Fountain%20et%20al%2095-97.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fountain, Michelle; Shaw, B; Trandem, Nina; Storberget, Sverre; Baroffio, Catherine; Ralle, Baiba; Rendina, P; Richoz, P; Sigsgaard, Lene; Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin; Hall, David; Cross, Jerry and Wibe, Atle   (2015) The potential for mass trapping Lygus rugulipennis and Anthonomus rubi; trap design and efficacy.   IOBC-WPRS Bulletin, 109, pp. 95-97.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28904/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>