<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative analysis of conventional and organic farming systems: Nitrogen surpluses and nitrogen losses</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelm, Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Dr. Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nutrient management is a key factor for both economic viability and environmental performance of farming systems. On 32 representative conventional and organic farms in Northern Germany, nutrient management was analyzed in the interdisciplinary monitoring project “COMPASS”. Organic farms had significantly lower nitrogen (N) surpluses compared with conventional farms. The majority of organic farms had very low or even negative N surpluses, indicating insufficient N supply in the cropping system. Nitrogen leaching, however, was too high in many cases on both conventional and organic farms. Strategies for a more targeted nutrient supply in organic farming need to be developed and implemented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11679/1/11679.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelm, Dr. Michael; Loges, Dr. Ralf and Taube, Prof. Dr. Friedhelm    (2008) Comparative analysis of conventional and organic farming systems: Nitrogen surpluses and nitrogen losses.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11679/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>