<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Specificity of soil-borne pathogens on grain legumes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Birgit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bødker, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knudsen, Jens Chr.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørnsgaard, Bjarne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Specificity of soil-borne legume pathogens on pea, lupin and faba bean is currently investigated in fields where grain legumes are intensively cultivated.&#xD;
The study has so far lead to the following conclusions&#xD;
-Legume host-pathogen interactions demonstrate specificity of pathogen populations particularly in pea and lupin.&#xD;
-A. euteiches rot root was specified to pea in Denmark as root rot symptoms and oospores of the pathogen never were observed in roots of faba bean and lupin&#xD;
-F. oxysporum followed by F. solani were most frequently isolated from plant roots in plots highly infested by lupin pathogens &#xD;
-F. avenaceum was most frequently isolated from plant roots in plots highly infested by pea pathogens &#xD;
-Pathogenicity tests showed F. solani followed by F. avenaceum to be the most pathogenic Fusarium species on pea while F. avenaceum was the most destructive pathogen on faba bean. In contrast F. avenaceum was non-pathogenic on lupin.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3522/1/3522.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Birgit; Bødker, Lars; Larsen, John; Knudsen, Jens Chr. and Jørnsgaard, Bjarne    (2004) Specificity of soil-borne pathogens on grain legumes.       Poster at:   5th European Conference on grain legumes, Dijon, France, 7-11 June 2004.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3522/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>