<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Developing LCA-based benchmarks for sustainable consumption - for and with users</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nissinen, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heiskanen, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grönroos, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Honkanen, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katajajuuri, J.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kurppa, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäkinen, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seppälä, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Timonen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Usva, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Virtanen, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Voutilainen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This article presents the development process of a consumer-oriented, illustrative benchmarking tool enabling consumers to use the results of environmental life cycle assessment (LCA) to make informed decisions. Active and environmentally conscious consumers and environmental communicators were identified as key target groups for this type of information. A brochure presenting the benchmarking tool was developed as an participatory, iterative process involving consumer focus groups, stakeholder workshops and questionnaire-based feedback. In addition to learning what works and what does not, detailed suggestions on improved wording and figures were obtained, as well as a wealth of ideas for future applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11268/1/LCA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nissinen, A.; Heiskanen, E.; Grönroos, J.; Honkanen, A.; Katajajuuri, J.-M.; Kurppa, S.; Mäkinen, T.; Seppälä, J.; Timonen, P.; Usva, K.; Virtanen, Y. and Voutilainen, P.    (2005) Developing LCA-based benchmarks for sustainable consumption - for and with users.       Paper at:   10th European roundtable on sustainable consumption and production, Antwerp, Belgium, October 5-7, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11268/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>