<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tracing Food Education for Sustainable Development in iPOPY countries. Recommendations for learning about sustainability and organic food within educational contexts.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roos, Gun</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Food Education for Sustainable Development (FESD) is evolving into a topical entity included in education in&#xD;
European countries due to the growing focus on environmental and health problems, which cause a&#xD;
‘sustainability deficit’ within the food system. This paper presents qualitative and exploratory research results&#xD;
from iPOPY project, carried out in Denmark, Finland, Italy and Norway regarding FESD and organic food in&#xD;
public food service for young people. The national core curricula in the studied countries seem to allow FESD&#xD;
although it is addressed in school contexts in varying ways through different school subjects; to some&#xD;
extent, the implementation depends on teachers’ other school activities and school food culture. There are&#xD;
teachers who engage in innovative FESD with students, creating new connections between conceptual,&#xD;
practical and experiential education by networking with other teachers and food system actors. Results&#xD;
suggest that pupils and students would achieve more profound learning outcomes if a whole school&#xD;
approach with integrative and coherent educational strategies would be applied and school food culture&#xD;
would be considered from the point of view of SD. The school caterers seem not to be too much involved in&#xD;
FESD but their and their organization’s roles are becoming more important. For successful learning about&#xD;
sustainability and organic food among young people, teachers, caterers, students and school administration&#xD;
have to be included in the process.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Strassner, Carola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Nölting, Benjamin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kristensen, Niels Heine</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-02-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17141/1/CORE_Proc_BioFach_2010_ipopy_VF_MM_GR.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkola, Minna and Roos, Gun    (2010) Tracing Food Education for Sustainable Development in iPOPY countries. Recommendations for learning about sustainability and organic food within educational contexts.   In: Strassner, Carola; Løes, Anne-Kristin; Nölting, Benjamin and Kristensen, Niels Heine (Eds.)  Organic Food for Youth in Public Settings: Potentials and Challenges. Preliminary Recommendations from a European Study. Proceedings of the iPOPY session held at BioFach Congress 2010. CORE Organic Project Series Report. , ICROFS, CORE Organic Project Series Report, Tjele, Denmark, pp. 29-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17141/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>