<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Low Greenhouse Gas Agriculture: Mitigation and Adaptation Potential of Sustainable Farming Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hepperly, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scialabba, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Is low greenhouse gas emission (GHG) agriculture possible? Is it, in fact, desirable? In seeking answers to these two basic but extremely relevant questions, this study examines current farming practices, and incorporates scientific databases from longterm field experiments as case studies for low GHG agriculture. Further, the study examines the changes that will be needed for low greenhouse gas agriculture systems to become a reality. It also elucidates the adaptive capacity of agro-ecological farming system approaches, using organic system case studies from the scientific literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
Each year, agriculture emits 10 to 12 percent of the total estimated GHG emissions, some 5.1 to 6.1 Gt CO2 equivalents per year. Smith, et al. (2007) and Bellarby, et al. (2008) have proposed mitigation options for GHG emissions, finding that both farmers and policymakers will face challenges from the GHG-related changes needed in agriculture. Areas for improvement include increased use of no-till cropping, agro-forestry, and integrated crop and animal farming, and decreased use of external inputs in food and agriculture. The techniques offered by organic agriculture are valuable for consideration in these efforts.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15690/1/niggli-etal-2009-lowgreenhouse.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niggli, U.; Fließbach, A.; Hepperly, P. and Scialabba, N.    (2009) Low Greenhouse Gas Agriculture: Mitigation and Adaptation Potential of Sustainable Farming Systems.     Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, Rome.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15690/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>