<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The status of Lobesia botrana (Lepidoptera: Tortricidae) in Albania and its management with Bacillus thuringiensis var. kurstaki &amp; aizawai</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DANO, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lobesia botrana is the key pest of grape in Albania. On 2005 we started a study which aims at knowing the status of pest and evaluating its management with two varieties of Bacillus thuringiensis, kurstaki &amp; aizawai in several grape cultivars in four farms in 3 different climatic areas. Pheromone Traptest traps were used to monitor the male flight for the best moment of intervention and 400 clusters per ha were sampled to estimate the infestation. Four complete generations appear in all the farms. In three of them, infestation level was under the economic threshold, so treatment were not justified. Bt shows a very good efficacy (75 – 100%), whereas not significant differences are observed between two varieties. The cultivars Black magic, Cabernet sauvignon, Shesh i Zi (autochthonous) showed a good resistance or tolerance to pest, while Shesh I Bardhë was the most susceptible one.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7003/1/StefanDano04.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>DANO, Stefan   (2005) The status of Lobesia botrana (Lepidoptera: Tortricidae) in Albania and its management with Bacillus thuringiensis var. kurstaki &amp; aizawai.  [La présence de Lobesia botrana (Lépidoptère: Tortricidé) en Albanie et la stratégie de lutte basée sur le Bacillus thuringiensis var. kurstaki &amp; aizawai.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 390. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7003/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>