<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Systemaufstellungen in der ökologischen Landwirtschaft: Fallstudien zur Wirksamkeit systemischer Zusammenhänge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wesseler, Dr. Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fink-Keßler, Dr. Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project has been designed to investigate potential effects of systemic constellations in agricultural contexts. The project invited farmers and rural extension workers to experiment with systemic constellations during three workshops. Specific situations have been set up, such as conversions to organic agriculture, farm transfer from generation to generation (including gender issues), risky investments, farm “survival” and family crises. The constellations proved to contribute to rapid and deep insights. Hidden potentials, which may lead to new solutions, became evident.&#xD;
After the constellations, the participants showed stronger self-esteem, higher decision-making power, enhanced creativity and activity. Several weeks after the workshops, selected participants reported on tangible impacts on their farms. Constellations provide an opportunity for a felt experience of systemic relations and their effective potentials. This may contribute in strengthening organic farming and ecological agriculture in general. New projects and new strategic alliances will emerge. Essential conditions for positive results are the participants’ disposition to confront themselves with deeper experiences, and the professional competence of the guides.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3323/1/3323.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wesseler, Dr. Matthias and Fink-Keßler, Dr. Andrea    (2003) Systemaufstellungen in der ökologischen Landwirtschaft: Fallstudien zur Wirksamkeit systemischer Zusammenhänge.  [Systemic Constellations in Organic Farming.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3323/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>