<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving farm-level physical and financial data availability at EU level</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boone, Koen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kramer, Klaas Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rippin, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfert, Sjaak</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper summarises the main findings and recommendations of the EISFOM project with respect to organic farm level data. At the EU level, the Farm Structure Survey and EU Reg. 2092/91 provide the most detailed data on production structures (crop areas and livestock numbers), and EU and national FADNs are becoming a useful source of financial data, but good quality data on output and prices of specific crop and livestock products are lacking. To improve the situation, more effort is needed on accurate iden-tification of organic holdings and individual crop and livestock products, including the harmonisation of classification systems and improved sample selection. The common nature of problems identified across different existing databases suggests an integrated approach to identifying solutions is needed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8239/2/lampkin_et_al_EISFOM.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lampkin, Nicolas; Boone, Koen; Kramer, Klaas Jan; Rippin, Markus; Willer, Helga and Wolfert, Sjaak    (2006) Improving farm-level physical and financial data availability at EU level.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8239/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>