<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Three Perspectives on Motivation and Multi-Criteria Assessment of Organic Food Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Læssøe, Jeppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ljungdalh, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Noe, Egon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kastberg, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Christensen, Tove</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olsen, Søren Bøye</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kærgård, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubgaard, Alex</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The complexity of values related to organic food systems is normally difficult to ascertain, understand and act upon for both producers and consumers, as well as for other agents. In this paper we have suggested MCA as a method that may help in coping with this complexity. Furthermore, we have pointed to the importance of addressing the challenge of motivation when designing such an MCA tool. In doing so, we have applied three very different concepts of motivation – an economic, a psycho-social and a relational concept. While they represent fundamentally different perspectives, by incorporating all three within a multi-perspective approach, we have been able to explore ’a broader array of relevant aspects of motivation when designing a MCA tool to be used by consumers when dealing with organic food issues. From an economic perspective, motivation is closely related to the buying situation and consumers’ need to choose between products. This stresses the importance of gaining a quick overview and of support in assessing the options. From a psycho-social perspective, the key point is to design the tool in a way that makes it possible for the consumer to include his or her experiences and specific lifeworld strategies in the assessment process. This highlights the importance of an MCA tool which enables users to influence and change criteria and values in decision-making and reflexive processes. Finally, from a relational perspective, motivation is a matter of social interaction and the tool should therefore be designed so as to allow dialogue between the agents involved in the value chain of the organic food system. Applying the three perspectives on motivation to the issue has proven the value of a multi-perspective approach and provided input qualifying the development of a prototype MCA tool for agents participating in the organic food system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-13</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24665/7/24665.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Læssøe, Jeppe; Ljungdalh, Anders; Alrøe, Hugo Fjelsted; Noe, Egon; Kastberg, Peter; Christensen, Tove; Olsen, Søren Bøye; Kærgård, Niels and Dubgaard, Alex   (2013) Three Perspectives on Motivation and Multi-Criteria Assessment of Organic Food Systems.   Ecology and Society,  19 (3),  7- .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24665/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>