<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Presentations from the workshop "Organic market data collection and publication procesures: the Code of Practice of the OrganicDataNetwork (OrMaCode)"</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>France</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the workshop is to present the Code of Practice for the initiation and maintenance of good organic market data collection and publication procedures (OrMaCode). The Code of Practice consists of a list of principles/objectives and related indicators covering the different key areas of organic market data collection, processing, storage and publication /dissemination. Associated to the OrMaCode a practical Manual will be produced. The Manual contains specific guidelines for applying OrMaCode. It also contains guidelines for the collection of relevant sets of data and how to ensure that quality criteria specified in the Code of Practice will be met.&#xD;
The OrMaCode and the Manual, together with the enhanced Database produced throughout the project, are the core outputs of our OrganicDataNetwork project. We want them to be thoroughly discussed among stakeholders. &#xD;
&#xD;
- Introduction to the workshop (Raffaele Zanoli – OrganicDatanetwork coordinator)&#xD;
- The OrganicDataNetwork online database (Helga Willer, FiBL – Switzerland- Diana Schaack, AMI – Germany)&#xD;
- Improving organic market data: results of  six case studies  (Susanne Padel, ORC – UK) &#xD;
- OrMaCode: the Code of Practice and the future of the organic market data collection network (Raffaele Zanoli, Università Politecnica delle Marche - Italy)</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28172/1/Zanoli_Introduction%20to%20the%20workshop.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28172/7/Schaack-Willer_The%20OrganicDataNetwork%20online%20database%20.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28172/13/Padel_Improving%20organic%20market%20data_results%20of%20six%20case%20studies.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28172/14/Zanoli_OrMaCode_the%20Code%20of%20Practice%20and%20the%20future%20of%20the%20organic%20market%20data%20collection%20network.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>OrganicDataNetwork (Ed.)    (2014) Presentations from the workshop "Organic market data collection and publication procesures: the Code of Practice of the OrganicDataNetwork (OrMaCode)".    . Proceedings of 18th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Istanbul, Turkey, October 13-15, 2014.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28172/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>