<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Land Management Strategies on the Dispersal&#xD;
Pattern of a Beneficial Arthropod</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marchi, Chiara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Liselotte Wesley</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loeschcke, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Several arthropods are known to be highly beneficial to  agricultural production. Consequently it is of great relevance to study the importance of land management and land composition for the conservation of beneficial aphid-predator arthropod species in agricultural areas. Therefore our study focusing on the beneficial arthropod Bembidion lampros had two main purposes: I) identifying the physical barriers to the species’ dispersal in the agricultural landscape, and II) assessing the effect of different land management strategies (i.e. use of pesticides and intensiveness) on the dispersal patterns. The study was conducted using genetic analysis (microsatellite markers) applied to samples from two agricultural areas (in Denmark) with different agricultural intensity. Land management effects on dispersal patterns were investigated with particular focus on: physical barriers, use of pesticide and intensity of cultivation. The results showed that Bembidion lampros disperse preferably through hedges rather than fields, which act as physical barriers to gene flow. Moreover the results support the hypothesis that organic fields act as reservoirs for the re-colonization of conventional fields, but only when cultivation intensity is low. These results show the importance of non-cultivated areas and of low intensity organic managed areas within the agricultural landscape as corridors for dispersal (also for a species typically found within fields). Hence, the hypothesis that pesticide use cannot be used as the sole predictor of agriculture’s effect on wild species is supported as land structure and agricultural intensity can be just as important.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23289/7/23289.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Marchi, Chiara ; Andersen, Liselotte Wesley and Loeschcke, V.   (2013) Effects of Land Management Strategies on the Dispersal Pattern of a Beneficial Arthropod.   Plos One, 8 (6), e66208.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23289/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>