<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modelling Organic Dairy Production Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nicholas, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Topp, K</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weller, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, a large number of organic dairy production strategies were compared in  terms of physical and financial performance through the integrated use of computer simulation models and organic case study farm data. Production and financial data from three organic case study farms were used as a basis for the modelling process to ensure that the modelled systems were based on real sets of resources that might be available to a farmer. The case study farms were selected to represent a range of farming systems in terms of farm size, concentrate use and location. This paper describes the process used to model the farm systems: the integration of the three models used and the use of indicators to assess the modelled farm systems in terms of physical sustainability and financial performance.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>British Grassland Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hopkins, A</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10999/1/modelling_organic_dairy_production_systems.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nicholas, P; Padel, S; Lampkin, N; Fowler, S; Topp, K and Weller, R    (2004) Modelling Organic Dairy Production Systems.   In: Hopkins, A (Ed.)  Organic farming: science and practice for profitable livestock and cropping. Occasional Symposium of the British Grassland Society, British Grassland Society (37), pp. 145-148.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10999/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>