<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung einer modernen Bio-Tafelkirschenproduktion&#xD;
Erhebungsresultate 2004 - 2007</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häseli, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently the market demand for Swiss organic sweet cherries is far above the actual&#xD;
production. However, organic sweet cherry production is under high pressure to&#xD;
change the cultivation system and cultivars in order to meet the new requirements of&#xD;
the market for a regular supply of faultless and big-sized fruit. Additionally there is a&#xD;
necessity to for a more economical management. In this study we assessed the&#xD;
agronomic and economic result of a modern organic sweet cherry orchard over the&#xD;
first 4 cropping years. The orchard is equipped with modern cultivars like Kordia,&#xD;
Regina etc. and a plastic cover to prevent rain-due cracking and Monilia disease.&#xD;
Sideward’s an insect net is fitted to exclude cherry fly infestation. The results prove&#xD;
that diseases and pests could be sufficiently controlled. Yields were regular, high and&#xD;
economically valuable with cv. Merchant, Kordia and Regina. We conclude that with&#xD;
well managed modern orchard systems there are appealing options to extend organic&#xD;
sweet cherry production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14660/1/H%C3%A4seli_14660.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häseli, Andreas and Weibel, Franco    (2009) Entwicklung einer modernen Bio-Tafelkirschenproduktion Erhebungsresultate 2004 - 2007.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, ETH Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14660/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>