<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>System Comparisons between Organic, Biodynamic, Conventional and GMO’s in cotton production &amp; Organic, Biodynamic, Conventional systems in Soya and Wheat in Central India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baruah, Rajeev</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Over the past 05 years the organic cotton production in India has grown many folds. In the conventional cotton arena the genetically modified cotton is growing at an unprecedented rate. Considering the above factors it was considered necessary to carry out a `System’ comparisons in which the four systems can be compared. Further the research hopes to answer the larger questions &#xD;
o Put the discussion regarding the benefits and drawbacks of organic agriculture on a rational footing; &#xD;
o Help to identify challenges for organic agriculture that can then be addressed systematically; &#xD;
o Provide physical reference points for stakeholders in agricultural research and development and thus support decision-making and agricultural policy dialogue at different levels. &#xD;
&#xD;
At the farmers level the following outcomes are expected: &#xD;
What happens to yields of the crops when you stop using fertilizers and pesticides ? &#xD;
What happens to the pests when you don’t usefertilizers and pesticides? &#xD;
How do the crops grow when only farmyard manure or compost is used? &#xD;
Can we effectively control pests in the organic and biodynamic systems using a range of botnaical sprays ? &#xD;
Are the biodynamic preparations effective? &#xD;
What are the costs of cultivation of the different systems that we are comparing? &#xD;
What are impacts on the qulaity of the produce in the different systems ? &#xD;
What are impacts on t soils of the different systems?</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18367/1/baruah-2008-ifoam-organic-world-congress.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baruah, Rajeev    (2008) System Comparisons between Organic, Biodynamic, Conventional and GMO’s in cotton production &amp; Organic, Biodynamic, Conventional systems in Soya and Wheat in Central India.       Paper at:   16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Organic Textile Conference, Carpi, Italy, 16-20 June 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18367/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>