<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zur Eutergesundheit in der Trockenperiode in ökologisch wirtschaftenden&#xD;
Milchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krömker, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zinke, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paduch, Jan-Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Doris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a part of the study „Health and performance of dairy cows in organic farming from&#xD;
an interdisciplinary point of view – an (intervention-) study on metabolic disorders and&#xD;
mastitis with regard to forage production, feeding management and husbandry practices”&#xD;
quarter milk samples from cows at dry off and after calving were taken by farmers&#xD;
in 86 dairy farms in Germany between January and July 2008. The objective of this&#xD;
study was to evaluate mastitis prevalence at dry off and at calving and the evaluation&#xD;
of different therapeutic regimes at dry off. 681 cows from 86 dairy farms were examined.&#xD;
Mastitis prevalence at dry off was comparable to conventional farms. At calving&#xD;
organic farms have high mastitis prevalence due to a low cure rate and a high new&#xD;
infection rate in the dry period. The non-use of dry cow antibiotics or teat sealers result&#xD;
in significantly lower cure rates on quarter level (29.4% vs. 37.4%) and higher new&#xD;
infection rates (34.1% vs. 39.5%). The results show, that dry period is a high-risk&#xD;
period for udder health in organic dairy farms. Improvements of the hygienic conditions,&#xD;
the immune defence and the therapeutic regimes offer high potentials for improvement&#xD;
of udder health.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14112/1/Kr%C3%B6mker_14112.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krömker, Volker; Zinke, Claudia; Paduch, Jan-Hendrik and Klocke, Doris    (2009) Zur Eutergesundheit in der Trockenperiode in ökologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14112/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>