<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Phosphorus forms and enzymatic hydrolyzability of organic phosphorus in soils after 30 years of organic and conventional farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keller, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Annaheim, Kathrin E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamburini, Federica</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bünemann, Else K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lower P-input levels in organic than conventional farming can decrease soil total and available P, which can potentially be resupplied from soil organic P. We studied the effect of 30 y of conventional and organic farming on soil P forms, focussing especially on organic P. Soil samples (0–20 cm) were taken in a field experiment with a nonfertilized control, two organic systems receiving P inputs as animal manure, and two conventional systems receiving only mineral P or mineral P and manure. Soils were analyzed for total, inorganic, organic, and microbial P, by sequential P fractionation and by enzyme additions to alkaline soil extracts. Samples taken prior to starting the experiment were also analyzed. Average annual P balances ranged from –20 to +5 kg ha–1. For systems with a negative balance, labile and moderately labile inorganic P fractions decreased, while organic and stable inorganic P fractions were hardly affected. Similar quantities and proportions of organic P extracted with NaOH-EDTA were hydrolyzed in all soils after addition of an acid phosphatase, a nuclease, and a phytase, and enzyme-stable organic P was also similar among soils. Thus, neither sequential fractionation nor enzyme addition to alkaline soil extracts showed an effect of the type of applied P (manure vs. mineral) on organic P, suggesting that organic P from manure has largely been mineralized. Thus far, we have no indication that the greater microbial activity of the organic systems resulted in a use of stable P forms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26071/1/Keller_etal_ETH_2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Keller, Martina; Oberson, Astrid; Annaheim, Kathrin E.; Tamburini, Federica; Mäder, Paul; Mayer, Jochen; Frossard, Emmanuel and Bünemann, Else K.   (2012) Phosphorus forms and enzymatic hydrolyzability of organic phosphorus in soils after 30 years of organic and conventional farming.   Journal of Plant Nutrition and Soil Science, 175 (3), pp. 385-393.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26071/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>