<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrogen efficiency in organic farming using a GPS precision farming technique</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zanen, Marleen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koopmans, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the coming years, agriculture in the Netherlands will be forced to produce more high quality produce with smaller inputs of fertilisers. Organic agriculture should play a leading role and set an example for sustainable soil management. This implies greater nutrient use efficiency and fewer inputs. GPS-controlled precision tillage using the same tracks in the field year after year offers the opportunity to improve soil structure. The tracks become compacted, improving trafficability (Vermeulen &amp; Klooster, 1992). Our hypothesis is that the soil structure of the remaining beds will improve, providing better aeration and rooting for the crop and access to necessary nutrients. This would mean that nutrient use efficiency would improve in GPS-controlled precision tillage systems. The aim of this study was to assess the effects of a GPS-controlled precision tillage system using permanent tracks on soil structure, nutrient use efficiency and spinach yield. The study was carried out at an organically-managed arable farm in the Netherlands.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4504/4/Zanen_Koopmans_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zanen, Marleen and Koopmans, Chris    (2005) Nitrogen efficiency in organic farming using a GPS precision farming technique.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4504/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>