<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prevalence of Anaplasma phagocytophilum infection and effect on lamb growth</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grøva, Lise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Ingrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, Håvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stuen , Snorre</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background: A major challenge in sheep farming during the grazing season along the coast of south-western&#xD;
Norway is tick-borne fever (TBF) caused by the bacteria Anaplasma phagocytophilum that is transmitted by the tick&#xD;
Ixodes ricinus.&#xD;
Methods: A study was carried out in 2007 and 2008 to examine the prevalence of A. phagocytophilum infection&#xD;
and effect on weaning weight in lambs. The study included 1208 lambs from farms in Sunndal Ram Circle in Møre&#xD;
and Romsdal County in Mid-Norway, where ticks are frequently observed. All lambs were blood sampled and&#xD;
serum was analyzed by an indirect fluorescent antibody assay (IFA) to determine an antibody status (positive or&#xD;
negative) to A. phagocytophilum infection. Weight and weight gain and possible effect of infection were analyzed&#xD;
using ANOVA and the MIXED procedure in SAS.&#xD;
Results: The overall prevalence of infection with A. phagocytophilum was 55%. A lower weaning weight of 3%&#xD;
(1.34 kg, p &lt; 0.01) was estimated in lambs seropositive to an A. phagocytophilum infection compared to&#xD;
seronegative lambs at an average age of 137 days.&#xD;
Conclusions: The results show that A. phagocytophilum infection has an effect on lamb weight gain. The study&#xD;
also support previous findings that A. phagocytophilum infection is widespread in areas where ticks are prevalent,&#xD;
even in flocks treated prophylactic with acaricides.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19866/1/PAPER_I.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Grøva, Lise; Olesen, Ingrid; Steinshamn, Håvard and Stuen , Snorre   (2011) Prevalence of Anaplasma phagocytophilum infection and effect on lamb growth.   Acta Veterinaria Scandinavica, 53 (30), pp. 1-7.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19866/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>