<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Low-P solution culture may assist screening of root growth vigor in soil for high nutrient uptake of spring wheat varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Yaosheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Sven Bode</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Stoumann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Root and root hairs of plants have been intensively studied in solution culture; however, correlation of such measurements in solution culture with development in soil is poorly understood. This study compared growth of roots and root hairs as well as uptake of macro- and micronutrients of six spring wheat varieties in solution culture under P stress and P abundance and in a low fertility soil. Results showed that root length and surface area under P stress was significantly positively correlated with that in the low fertility soil, while no such correlation was apparent for root hair length and density. In absolute terms the root length, surface area, root hair length and density of spring wheat varieties were substantially higher in soil than in solution culture, while the concentration and content of macro- and micronutrients in soil differed from solution culture in a complex way. The early uptake of macro- and micronutrients was intimately associated with root length and surface area as well as root hair length and density in soil but not in solution culture. Since root length under P stress was linearly correlated with early root growth vigor in soil, root measurement performed in solution culture may assist the prediction of early uptake of nutrients from low fertility soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27913/3/27913.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wang, Yaosheng; Andersen, Sven Bode; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Jensen, Lars Stoumann  and Magid, Jakob   (2014) Low-P solution culture may assist screening of root growth vigor in soil for high nutrient uptake of spring wheat varieties.   Soil Science and Plant Nutrition.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27913/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>