<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von Habitatmanagement auf die Reduktion von&#xD;
Schadlepidopteren im Kohl</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Luka, Henryk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leimgruber, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Willareth, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nagel, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfiffner, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlatter, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schied, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Traugott, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Beneficials can prevent or reduce outbreaks of pest species. To strengthen the&#xD;
populations of beneficials, their food sources must be improved in cultivated areas.&#xD;
The effects of habitat management for augmenting beneficial population on parasitism&#xD;
and predation rates of three lepidopteran pest species were investigated on two&#xD;
organic fields in Alten (Switzerland). The aim was to improve pest regulation through&#xD;
wild flower strips along fields and by planting Centaurea cyanus as companion plant&#xD;
within the crop. Strips of Centaurea cyanus and Fagopyrum esculentum increased&#xD;
parasitsm on the lepidopteran pests. C. cyanus planted as companion plant&#xD;
furthermore increased predation on the eggs and parasitism of the larvae of Mamestra&#xD;
brassicae. Several technical and methodological aspects still need to be improved&#xD;
before the approach is ready for practical use.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14127/1/Luka_14127.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Luka, Henryk; Leimgruber, Andrea; Willareth, Martin; Nagel, Peter; Pfiffner, Lukas; Wyss, Eric; Schlatter, Christian; Schied, Johannes and Traugott, Michael    (2009) Einfluss von Habitatmanagement auf die Reduktion von Schadlepidopteren im Kohl.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14127/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>