<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biological activity of Citrus spp. metabolites on Ceratitis capitata (Wiedemann).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Faraone, Nicoletta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caleca, Virgilio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruno, Maurizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vitagliano, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Cristofaro, Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Mediterranean fruit fly (medfly), Ceratitis capitata (Wiedemann) (Diptera: Tephritidae), is one of the most injurious pest at global level. During the last years, several electrophysiological and behavioural studies have been carried out in order to investigate plant volatile compound-insect interactions with the aim to use this knowledge in sustainable control techniques.&#xD;
It has been observed that lemons are not attacked by medfly, probably because of the peel oil, that is toxic to other fruit flies. In the present paper electrophysiological recordings were conducted to evaluate the insect sensitivity to peel extract and peel oil of two Sicilian cultivars (Interdonato and Lunario) of Citrus x limon (L.) Burm.f. on C. capitata females. Behavioural bioassays were also performed to show their possible biological activity (repellent, antioviposition, insecticidal). C. limon peel extracts in different solvents (petroleum ether, dichloromethane and methanol) were investigated at various concentrations using a single cell recording technique (stimulation of tarsal taste chemosensilla). Different tarsal taste cell responses to the two cultivars were recorded. The higher sensitivity was evoked by C. limon Interdonato, particularly to the methanol extract, which elicited significant increases in the spike frequency at increasing concentrations. The peel oil of the same cultivars as well as that ones of other two C. limon varieties (Monachello and Femminello) have been tested by EAG techniques. The EAG data showed a high sensitivity (about -8.0/8.5mV) of the medfly antennae to the oils of Citrus spp. and a clear dose-response relationship. Responses of adult females (virgin and mated) to Citrus spp. peel extract were quantified in a double-choice test using yellow spheres (diameter 7.0cm) housed in field cages. Preliminary tests conducted on three extracts of C. limon Interdonato and Lunario have provided interesting results. It was recorded a general decrease of the oviposition on treated spheres compared to control and in the case of the cultivar Lunario, a mortality of insects.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20566/1/F_167-173_Faraone.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Faraone, Nicoletta; Caleca, Virgilio; Bruno, Maurizio; Vitagliano, Silvia and De Cristofaro, Antonio   (2012) Biological activity of Citrus spp. metabolites on Ceratitis capitata (Wiedemann).   IOBC/wprs Bulletin, 74, pp. 167-173.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20566/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>