<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic farming and measures for European agricultural policy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>H채ring, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aurbacher, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bichler, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eichert, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gambelli, Danilo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Offermann, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olmos, Santiago</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tuson, Jon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This book analyses the impact of the Agenda 2000 reform on the Common Agricultural Policy on organic farming -  as one of the most established examples of environmentally freindly farming systems. The authors provide comparative assessments of the impact of first and second pillar measures on conventional and organic farms, analysing the impacts of direct payments, price support measures (agri-environmental measures, investment support, processing and marketing measures, training measures and Less Favoured Area support) for a range of countries and farm types. Finally, an outlook of possible effects of the CAP Reform 2003 on organic farming systems and recommendations on how to maximise the positive effects of agricultural policy on organic farming are given. &#xD;
This book provides policy makers, the private sector, researchers and students in the field of general and organic agricultural policy with the most comprehensive quantitative and qualitative evaluation of support for organic farms in the EU within the Agenda 2000 framework.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universit채t Hohenheim</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3092/1/Organic_Farming_in_Europe_Volume11_Organic_farming_and_measures_of_European_agricultural_policy.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>H채ring, Anna; Dabbert, Stephan; Aurbacher, Joachim; Bichler, Barbara; Eichert, Christian; Gambelli, Danilo; Lampkin, Nicolas; Offermann, Frank; Olmos, Santiago; Tuson, Jon and Zanoli, Raffaele    (2004) Organic farming and measures for European agricultural policy.    Organic Farming in Europe: Economics and Policy, no. Vol. 11. Universit채t Hohenheim.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3092/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>