<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic farming values in Switzerland – results of a focus group study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kilchsperger, Rahel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bodini, Antonella</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Eight focus group discussions, conducted in 2004 and 2005, about ethical values among established and recently converted organic producers (mountain and lowland area) and other stakeholders in Switzerland are summarised. The aim was to contrib-ute to the elaboration of principles for the new EU regulation for organic food and farming as part of the EU Organic-Revision project. The participants’ values were contrasted with the four new principles of organic production of IFOAM (International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements). Health and ecological sustainability were key issues. The producers saw secure livelihood, the maintenance of their family farm, authenticity, animal welfare and farming with nature as major issues. The sys-tem approach was important for other stakeholders. The major value conflicts were seen to arise from conventionalization and globalisation of the organic agriculture sector. Another central discussion point was the overregulation and inspection. Ethical values and principles should play a more important role in standard setting and trade.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9805/1/9805_Schmid_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, Otto; Kilchsperger, Rahel and Bodini, Antonella    (2007) Organic farming values in Switzerland – results of a focus group study.       Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9805/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>