<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dairy farming in Uganda. Production Efficiency and Soil Nutrients under Different Farming Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baltenweck, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mubiru, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nanyeenya, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Njororge, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romney, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Prior to the 1980s, milk production in Uganda occurred largely in two contrasting production systems. In the wetter parts of the country, especially in the southwest, there were a few large, mostly government-owned commercial dairy farms on which exotic and cross-bred dairy cattle were kept in paddocks and grazed on improved or natural pastures. In the drier eastern and northeastern parts of the country, pastoralists kept large numbers of local cattle breeds, notably the Small East African Zebu (SEAZ), under traditional extensive management systems. Although the pastoralists marketed some milk, most was consumed by the household. Cattle were also valued as an expression of cultural prestige and a means of accumulating capital and meeting planned and emergency expenses. Smallholders, who tended to keep a few low yielding indigenous cattle as well as growing crops, made little contribution to the nation’s marketed milk and were primarily subsistence-oriented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15549/1/15549.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baltenweck, I.; Mubiru, S.; Nanyeenya, W.; Njororge, L.; Halberg, N. and Romney, D.         (2007) Dairy farming in Uganda. Production Efficiency and Soil Nutrients under Different Farming Systems.   Research Report, no. 1. International Livestock Research Institute (ILRI).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15549/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>