<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of ploughing depth on decomposition of barley straw in organically managed soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pommeresche, Reidun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meisingset, Erling L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Sissel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Litterbag were used to study the effects of different ploughing depths on decomposition rate of barley straw with different ploughing depths. The burying depth of the litter (13 vs 25 cm) affected the decomposition rate of barely straw more than the different ploughing depths (13 vs 25 cm). From our results we suggest that slowly decomposable organic matter, such as leached barley straw, may be incorporated deeply by ploughing in organic cereal production systems, in order to regulate perennial weeds. In soils with good structure and porosity, the decomposition rate of straw can even be larger with deep ploughing. In dense, clayey soils it is important to be very accurate in ploughing time in order to secure that the ploughing is in fact loosening the soil. Otherwise, lack of oxygen and low decomposition of straw is likely to be the results.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioforsk- Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Web product</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8765/1/barley_t_1_24_pommeresche_2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pommeresche, Reidun; Løes, Anne-Kristin; Meisingset, Erling L. and Hansen, Sissel    (2006) Effects of ploughing depth on decomposition of barley straw in organically managed soil.   Bioforsk- Norwegian Institute for Agricultural and Environmental Research.  Online at &lt;http://www.bioforsk.no/dok/senter/adm/tema/t_1_24_pommeresche.pdf &lt;http://www.bioforsk.no/dok/senter/adm/tema/t_1_24_pommeresche.pdf&gt;&gt;.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8765/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>