<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Performance and carcass quality of fully on partly outdoor reared pigs in organic production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strudsholm, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, John E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Outdoor rearing of finishers can be considered a relevant option in organic pig production. The performance and carcass characteristics of 245 organically produced and free-range born crossbred pigs allocated to five treatments were compared. The five treatments were: transfer to a barn with free access to feed (1) at weaning and until slaughter, (2) at a live weight of 40 kg and until slaughter, (3) at live weight of 80 kg and until slaughter, or reared at pasture (4) with free or (5) limited access to concentrates until slaughter. Pigs fed ad libitum fed indoor compared to pigs fed ad libitum outdoor had a significant lower feed consumption (5 MJ ME /kg gain), lower lean percentage (2.3%), and a higher backfat depth (1.1 mm)(all P &lt; 0.05). Compared with outdoor pigs fed ad libitum, restricted feeding outdoor resulted in a significantly lower daily gain (107 g), a lower feed consumption (6.3 MJ ME/kg gain), higher lean percentage (2.1% units), and a reduced backfat (1.8 mm) (all P &lt; .001). Pigs, which at a live weight of 40 kg, were transferred to indoor facilities with free access to feed compensated almost completely before slaughter, while pigs transferred at 80 kg live weight only compensated little. Although the housing environment (in- or outdoor) seems to affect performance and carcass traits, the length of energy restriction appears to be of greater importance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6093/1/6093.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strudsholm, Karin and Hermansen, John E.   (2005) Performance and carcass quality of fully on partly outdoor reared pigs in organic production.   Livestock Production Science, 96, pp. 261-268.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6093/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>