<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Beauveria bassiana strain ATCC 74040 (Naturalis®), a valuable tool for the control of the cherry fruit fly (Rhagoletis cerasi)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ladurner, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benuzzi, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fiorentini, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franceschini, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Naturalis® is a bioinsecticide based on living conidiospores of the naturally occuring&#xD;
Beauveria bassiana strain ATCC 74040. The entomopathogenic fungus acts primarily by&#xD;
contact: once attached to the insect’s cuticle, the conidiospores germinate producing&#xD;
penetration hyphae, which enter and proliferate inside the insect’s body. The fungus&#xD;
invades and feeds on its host, causing its death due to dehydration and/or depletion of&#xD;
nutrients. Several years of laboratory, semi-field and field studies showed that also Tephritid&#xD;
flies (Ceratitis capitata, Rhagoletis cerasi, Bactrocera oleae) are susceptible to infection by&#xD;
B. bassiana strain ATCC 74040. The results of efficacy trials conducted in 2004-05 are&#xD;
reported. Naturalis was tested both alone and in an integrated pest management strategy.&#xD;
The product showed high efficacy in controlling R. cerasi, comparable to or higher than&#xD;
that of the chemical reference treatment. The B. bassiana-based product Naturalis can thus&#xD;
be considered an efficient tool for the control of the cherry fruit fly.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13651/1/093-097.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ladurner, E.; Benuzzi, M.; Fiorentini, F. and Franceschini, S.    (2008) Beauveria bassiana strain ATCC 74040 (Naturalis®), a valuable tool for the control of the cherry fruit fly (Rhagoletis cerasi).   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 93-97.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13651/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>