<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Animal dietary intervention study of effect of organic vs conventional food production methods on health and well – being of rats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rembiałkowska, prof. Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to the research studies conducted during last 20 years the wholesomeness and nutritive value of the organically produced crops is often higher than of conventional plant products. Organic crops contain less harmful substances (e.g. pesticide residues, nitrates) and more desirable compounds (e.g. vitamin C, flavonoids) than conventional ones. &#xD;
   However, the impact of the organic food consumption on animal and human health and well being still remains almost unknown. Small experimental mammals fed organically showed in some experiments better health and fertility parameters, but much more research studies are needed in order to broaden our knowledge. &#xD;
  Therefore a dietary intervention study on rats will be conducted at Warsaw Agricultural University. &#xD;
   The rat feed will consist of wheat, potatoes, carrots and onions produced organically vs. low input vs. conventionally. In order to meet all nutritional demands of rats the appropriate amount of casein, lactoalbumin, rape seed oil, minerals and vitamins will be added. &#xD;
   The main research hypothesis claims that rats consuming different diets would perhaps show different feed uptake, behavior pattern and health parameters, including immune system, due to different composition of the experimental diets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8237/1/Odense_rat_article_6__April_2006_final.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8237/2/8237_Rembialkowska.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rembiałkowska, prof. Ewa    (2006) Animal dietary intervention study of effect of organic vs conventional food production methods on health and well – being of rats.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8237/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>