<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic farming on grasslands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friebel, Ludvik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friebelova, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainable agriculture has currently been considerably supported by the EU which positively affects development of organic farming in EU member states.  Along with expansion of organic farming itself, importance of its production and non-production function rises as well. Both these functions are expected to be mutually balanced so as the organic farms were not focused on one-sided production. To reach such balance the grant programmes should be suitably set so that the farms were motivated to farm on arable land and permanent grasslands on one side and fulfil non-production function of agriculture on the other side as well. The balance of grant programmes can be estimated according to the way how organic farming is carried on. This article is focused on assessment of condition of organic farming in the Czech Republic and taking advantage of agroenvironmental programmes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21036/1/Moudry_-_Organic_Farming_On_Grasslands_%28final%29_%282009_-_Bulharsko%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moudry, Jan (Jr.); Friebel, Ludvik; Konvalina, Petr and Friebelova, Jana   (2009) Organic farming on grasslands.   Proceedings Of Second International Conference, 1 (2009), pp. 57-63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21036/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>