<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC FARMING INTERNSHIP AND VOLUNTEER PROGRAMS IN INDIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>TEWARI, HARISH CHANDER</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>TEWARI, POONAM</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Established in 2007, Worldwide Opportunities On Organic Farms India (WWOOF INDIA) www.wwoofindia.org facilitates cultural and educational exchange between its 170+ member farming communities and volunteers from all over the world. Spanning 16 of India’s 35 states and union territories, all farms are associated with organic gardening, orchards, spices, tea and other sustainability projects. WWOOFers learn local organic farming procedures and issues while helping with farm duties. WWOOF India is a member of the International WWOOF Association(www.wwoofinternational.org). There are following opportunities to work in various organic farming projects. WWOOF INDIA is gradually involving more and more organic farmers into WWOOF India network, from just 14 organic farms in 2007 it has now more than 180 organic hosts farms including many NGOs) under its network. The  WWOOF India Network has now spread across 16 states in India in next five years it plans to include more than 5000 host farms in its network. WWOOF India has helped many farmers to convert towards organic farming, the farmers were supported through volunteers help. More than 50 new organic host farms under its network across the country were started through this process. Through WWOOF India host members (including many NGOs) over the past 5 years more 2000 volunteers and 15 Interns from various Universities of EU and USA were trained in organic farming. These volunteers come from various countries across the world . The number of volunteers and interns coming to join WWOOF India is increasing each passing year.These volunteers were mainly youths who were interested in green living and sustainable agriculture practices. These volunteers were trained in host organic farms who provided them on farm opportunity to live and learn. Interns were mostly final year students from various Universities of different countries. In next 5 years WWOOF India plans to include 1000 Organic farms for placement of more than 5000 Volunteers and  200 Interns in various projects and learn. The learning opportunities are about crop rotation, preceding crops benefits, resistant varieties, composting, mixed cropping, no tillage crop production and pest prevention , green manure, soil covers, mulches, nutrient balance, nutrient cycles, resource recycling and nutrient. They design and implement a pest management system where observation, prevention and monitoring are main components. Important requirements for careful organic processing and discuss issues of contamination with non organic substances, non organic products. They also understand the structures of potential markets of various organic products produced and marketed  by WWOOF India host farmers. They learn to differentiate marketing channels (direct marketing, farmers markets, specialised shops, retailers etc.) and to characterise them. They also get opportunity to analyse the certification process and understand the different issues to consider when developing an export marketing strategy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23172/7/23172.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>TEWARI, HARISH CHANDER and TEWARI, POONAM    (2014) ORGANIC FARMING INTERNSHIP AND VOLUNTEER PROGRAMS IN INDIA.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23172/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>