<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sulphate leaching and sulphur balances of an organic crop rotation on three Danish soils</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sulphate leaching may reduce the long-term possibility of maintaining the sulphur (S) supply of crops in low input farming systems. Sulphate leaching and S balances were investigated in an organic cereal crop rotation with barley (Hordeum vulgare), grass-clover (Lolium perenne/Trifolium repens and pratense), winter wheat (Triticum aestivum) and barley/pea (Pisum sativum) in mixture at three sites during the first 3 years after conversion to organic farming. Sulphate leaching decreased significantly during the 3 years, and the concentration of drainage water was lowered 1.85.5 times in the third year. Similarly, the S-content of the crops decreased significantly over the years, reflecting lower soil S availability. Sulphur application to spring barley at all sites in Year 2 and at one site in Year 3 increased straw yield by 23% (P&lt;0.01) and grain yield by 13% (NS) on average. Significant fertiliser-S response was restricted to the two sandy soils. Sulphate leaching was quantitatively the most important item affecting the S balance, since excess S was lost by leaching. The S-balance indicated that no substantial S-deficit may be expected in the longer term provided excess S is maintained in the system and the availability is synchronised with plant needs. Otherwise it will in the longer term be necessary on sandy soils to apply S in a plant-available form to avoid the negative effects of S deficiency on yield and quality of crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/159/1/S_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J.; Olesen, J.E. and Askegaard, M.   (2002) Sulphate leaching and sulphur balances of an organic crop rotation on three Danish soils.   European Journal of Agronomy, 17, pp. 1-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/159/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>