<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of agricultural liberalisation on the relative importance of price premiums for the profitability of organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sanders, Jürn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the literature, impressive evidences can be found with respect to the importance of price premiums for the absolute and relative profitability of organic farms. However, depending on the agricultural support framework, the relative economic importance of price premiums varies considerably. Model results presented in this paper suggest that the relative importance is likely to decline, if producer prices decline substantially and more support payments are transferred directly to farmers as envisaged in the framework of currently discussed liberalisation reforms in Switzerland or the EU.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>International Society of Organic Agriculture Research and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, CH-Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12546/1/Sanders_12546_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sanders, Jürn; Stolze, Matthias and Lampkin, Nicolas    (2008) Impact of agricultural liberalisation on the relative importance of price premiums for the profitability of organic farming.   In:     Cultivating the Future Based on Science, International Society of Organic Agriculture Research and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, CH-Frick, 2, pp. 238-241.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12546/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>