<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Molecular diversity of the Metarhizium anisopliae lineage in an agricultural field</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinwender, Bernhardt M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Enkerli, Jürg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Widmer, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eilenberg, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyling, Nicolai V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Entomopathogenic fungal isolates identified by morphology  as Metarhizium anisopliae may belong to different species when identified by molecular characters. We isolated Metarhizium spp. from an experimental agricultural field under both conventional and organic farming regimes using Tenebrio molitor as bait insect to assess the molecular diversity within the soil. Isolates were analyzed using DNA sequencing and applying SSR markers. Within the former M. anisopliae lineage, we found M. brunneum (86.3%), M. robertsii (11.3%) and M. majus (3.4%) in the soil samples. Several genotypes of each species were identified based on SSR markers. Differences in abundance of the species and their genotypes suggest different adaptations to the soil environment of the agricultural field. There were no effects of conventinal or organic farming regimes on diversity of the fungi.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19302/4/19302.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinwender, Bernhardt M.; Enkerli, Jürg; Widmer, Franco; Eilenberg, Jørgen and Meyling, Nicolai V.   (2011) Molecular diversity of the Metarhizium anisopliae lineage in an agricultural field.   IOBC/WPRS Bulletin, 66, pp. 113-115.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19302/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>