<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Final Report of the SOLINSA project. Project Deliverable D8.2 of the SOLINSA project (GA 266306)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moschitz, Heidrun</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tisenkopfs, Talis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brunori, Gianluca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Home, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kunda, Ilona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sumane, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Final Report outlines results of the Project “Agricultural Knowledge Systems in Transition: Towards a more effective and efficient support of Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture” (Project acronym: SOLINSA). &#xD;
&#xD;
The project was conceived and implemented as a response to the need for identifying new ways of transition from “productivist” practices to more sustainable agriculture and rural development, where traditional institutions in charge of fostering innovation are not always relevant and effective. &#xD;
The EU SOLINSA project proposes a new organisational pattern aimed at fostering innovation for transition. It illuminates the role of learning and innovation in transition processes, explores networks as drivers of innovation and proposes the concept of Learning and Innovation Networks for Sustainable Agriculture (LINSA) as policy device to help farmers and rural actors generate innovations for transition.&#xD;
The consortium was comprised by 11 research institutions from 8 European countries. To achieve the project objective of identifying effective and efficient approaches for the support of successful LINSA, researchers collaborated with 17 LINSA using a transdisciplinary method based on participation. &#xD;
This report is a summary of the most relevant empirical results and theoretical advancements achieved in the project.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25520/1/D%208.2%20SOLINSA%20Final%20Report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moschitz, Heidrun; Tisenkopfs, Talis; Brunori, Gianluca; Home, Robert; Kunda, Ilona and Sumane, Sandra         (2014) Final Report of the SOLINSA project. Project Deliverable D8.2 of the SOLINSA project (GA 266306).    Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25520/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>