<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innovatiecentrum Biologische Landbouw van Wageningen UR</dc:title>
  <dc:description>The Innovation Centre Organic Agriculture of Wageningen UR (IBL) co-ordinates, stimulates and initiates the disclosure, development and integration of knowledge of organic agriculture and food. It focuses on developing (new) knowledge and skills as well as on disclosing (existing) knowledge. The innovative aspect of the Innovation Centre mainly relates to the development of new skills in education and research. These skills should coincide with the character of organic agriculture. Integrating and interdisciplinary thinking are new key concepts in this respect. Eventually IBL aims to become the prime source of knowledge of organic agriculture in Wageningen UR and beyond. &#xD;
The Innovation Centre Organic Agriculture mainly delivers services varying from organising workshops to feeding the public debate with knowledge about organic agriculture and food. IBL stimulates researchers in organic agriculture to increase their co-operation and intensify their contacts with the (primary) actors in the chain of organic agriculture in The Netherlands.&#xD;
Important products of IBL are the Project Bank, a database with all the organic projects and experts and the Knowledge Bank with scientific and practical knowledge of organic agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Organization description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Organization}     IBL: Innovatiecentrum Biologische Landbouw van Wageningen UR.  [Innovation Centre Organic Agriculture of Wageningen UR.]    Organization Leader(s): Blom-Zandstra, dr.ir. M. (Greet).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5256/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>