<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bioethology differences between Orius laevigatus and Orius niger (Hemiptera : Anthocoridae) in Mediterranean region.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BRANKO, Djuric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Several characteristics of Orius laevigatus (Fieber) and Orius niger (Wollf) (Hemiptera: Anthocoridae) are investigated in the laboratory and in the vineyards. Indigenous O.laevigatus, O. niger and O.laevigatus from biofactory are compared as for the following characteristics: morphological differences among these three insects, life duration, length of the oviposition period, number of laid eggs, number of hatched eggs, percentage of hatched eggs, population dynamics of O.laevigatus and O.niger in the region of Apulia, population density of Frankliniella occidentalis and Orius spp. in the vineyard at flowering, presence of Orius spp. in South Bosnia and Herzegovina. Indigenous Orius laevigatus has a longer life than Orius laevigatus from biofactory and than Orius niger. The same order applies to the duration of the oviposition period, number of laid eggs and number of hatched eggs. The percentage of hatched eggs is higher for the indigenous O.laevigatus than that of O.niger followed by O.laevigatus from biofactory. In Apulia O.niger was prevailing in the wintertime and O.laevigatus in May when the temperature exceeds 15°C. The population density of Frankliniella occidentalis at the grapevine flowering time was very high and the number of Orius spp. very low. Orius spp. are present in South Bosnia and Herzegovina an area which is close to the sea, with favorable climatic conditions. Indigenous Orius laevigatus should be used for the biological control of Frankliniella occidentalis because of its characteristics and  for its presence in the vineyards when this plant pest must be controlled. Results are discussed in relation to significant bioethology differences among the three Orius spp.; the importance of Orius spp. in the control of Frankliniella occidentalis is also emphasized.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6656/1/BrankoDjuric03.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>BRANKO, Djuric   (2003) Bioethology differences between Orius laevigatus and Orius niger (Hemiptera : Anthocoridae) in Mediterranean region.  [Différences bioéthologiques entre Orius laevigatus et Orius niger (Hemiptera: Anthocoridae) dans la région méditerranéenne.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 297. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6656/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>