<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Can solution culture assist in screening root growth vigour and root hair development in soil?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wang, Yaosheng</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Sven Bode</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Stoumann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Root and root hairs of plants have been intensively studied in solution culture; however, correlation with such measurements in solution culture to development in soil is poorly understood. This study compared early (up to 30 d) root and root hair growth as well as uptake of macro- and micronutrients of spring wheat plants at similar growth stage grown in solution culture with varied P conditions and in a low fertility soil. Results showed that root and root hairs between genotypes displayed similar variations in solution culture at the low P concentration and in soil. Moreover, root length and surface area in low-P solution was significantly positively correlated with that in low fertility soil; thus solution culture at low P concentration is apparently able to assist in screening root growth vigour and root hair development in soil. In absolute terms the root length and surface area as well as root hair length and density of wheat were substantially higher in soil than in solution culture, indicating that root and root hair traits measured in solution culture are not able to accurately represent the root and root hair development in soil. Moreover, the concentration and uptake of macro- and micronutrients in soil were substantially different from those in solution culture. However, since the early uptake of macro- and micronutrients was intimately associated with root length, root surface area and root hairs in soil, and since,root length measured in low-P solution may predict early root growth vigor in soils, we maintain that solution culture may assist the prediction of early uptake of nutrients from low fertility soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24766/7/24766.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wang, Yaosheng; Andersen, Sven Bode; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Jensen, Lars Stoumann  and Magid, Jakob   (2014) Can solution culture assist in screening root growth vigour and root hair development in soil?    ,  ,  .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24766/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>