<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Which carabid species benefit from organic agriculture? -&#xD;
a review of comparative studies in winter cereals from Germany and Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kromp, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Data of comparative studies about carabid beetles in organically  and conventionally managed winter cereal fields of central  Europe, using the pitfall trapping method, were collected from the  literature and unpublished data sources and were then pooled and  analysed. According to an index, which was designed to calculate  how much a species benefits from organic management, Carabus  auratus turned out to benefit most. Some Amara species (A.  familiaris, A. similata and A. aenea) as well as Pseudoophonus  rufipes and Harpalus affinis also showed high index values. When  analysing the traits of the carabids, the habitat preference was the  most important variable for the differentiation of organic and  conventional management. The stronger the preference for open  field, the more the species are supported by organic agriculture.  For the promotion of the agricultural carabid fauna it is suggested  that weedier and less densely cropped fields be tolerated.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elesevier Science B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1106/1/kein-Dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Döring, Thomas F. and Kromp, Bernhard   (2003) Which carabid species benefit from organic agriculture? - a review of comparative studies in winter cereals from Germany and Switzerland.   Agriculture Ecosystems &amp; Environment, 98, pp. 153-161.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1106/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>