<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>INSTITUTIONAL STRUCTURE DEVELOMENT IN THE FIELD OF ORGANIC FARMING IN TURKEY</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>KARAARSLAN, VİLDAN</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Practices in the field of organic farming have been carried out within the scope of legal framework since 2003. In Turkey, organic farming activities are conducted under the auspices of Department of Good Agriculture Practices and Organic Farming of the General Directorate of Plant Production of the Ministry of Food Agriculture and Livestock. There are Organic Farming Committee and Organic Farming National Guidance Committee. Besides, there are Organic Farming Units in 81 Provincial Directorates. The Ministry has assigned its control and certification authority for organic farming to private bodies. In Turkey, organic farming practices has commenced in 1985-86 because of increasing demand of foreign buyers and request of export companies and has pursued so on till 1994. Within the structure of the Ministry, Department responsible for coordinating and managing organic farming practices in 2003 and 5262 Numbered Organic Farming Law was ratified and connected regulation for Procedures and Principles of Organic Farming was issued in 2004 and afterwards, regulation has been revised in harmonization with EU Legislation. Revisions made for EU Organic Farming Regulations have been closely monitored so as to protect export chance of the Turkish organic products and supply our citizens with safe products. Alternative Production Methods Department was established in 2003 under the umbrella of the Ministry for the purpose of extension of organic farming. In Turkey, activities in the field of organic farming have been supervised by Department of Good Agricultural Practices and Organic Farming of the General Directorate of Plant Production of the Ministry of Food, Agriculture and Livestock. As defined in the legal framework in force, there are Organic Farming Committee and Organic Farming National Guidance Committee. Moreover, Organic Farming Units have been established within the body of 81 provincial directorates. Control and Certification authority has been assigned to private bodies. Data on organic farming are recorded in Organic Farming Information System.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23592/9/23592.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>KARAARSLAN, VİLDAN    (2014) INSTITUTIONAL STRUCTURE DEVELOMENT IN THE FIELD OF ORGANIC FARMING IN TURKEY.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23592/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>