<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Selective flowers to enhance biological control of cabbage pests by parasitoids</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Géneau, Céline E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wäckers, Felix L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luka, Henryk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Balmer, Oliver</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Habitat management is an important element in sustainable agriculture and can be used to maximize a range of ecosystem services that support crop production. An important example of such ecosystem services is biological control of pests which can be enhanced by providing arthropod natural enemies with suitable floral resources. The potential risk of this approach, however, is that flowering plants may enhance the fitness of the targeted pests as well. We conducted experiments to identify selective plant species that would improve the longevity and parasitization rate of the parasitoid wasp Microplitis mediator without benefiting its host pest, the cabbage moth Mamestra brassicae. Effects on longevity were also assessed for Diadegma fenestrale, a generalist parasitoid wasp attacking lepidopteran pests. Additionally, we compared the effects of floral and extrafloral nectar, the latter being formed in some plant species and can significantly prolong the duration of nectar availability for natural enemies. Longevity of M. mediator and D. fenestrale as well as parasitization rates of M. mediator were significantly increased by the presence of Fagopyrum esculentum (floral nectar), Centaurea cyanus (floral and extrafloral nectar) and non-flowering Vicia sativa (extrafloral nectar). M. mediator parasitized 202.3 ± 29.7 M. brassicae larvae during its lifetime when presented F. esculentum, compared to 14.4 ± 3.4 larvae in the absence of floral resources. Extrafloral nectar of C. cyanus and V. sativa was as suitable for M. mediator as floral nectar and significantly increased longevity and parasitization rates. Longevity and fecundity of M. brassicae were not supported by the plant species tested. These results stress the importance of plant screening to achieve plant selectivity and to maximize biological control. F. esculentum, C. cyanus and V. sativa are recommended as selective plant species to enhance parasitoids of M. brassicae. &#xD;
© 2011 Gesellschaft für Ökologie. Published by Elsevier GmbH. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-10-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19939/4/Geneau-etal-2012-BasicApplEcol2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Géneau, Céline E.; Wäckers, Felix L.; Luka, Henryk; Daniel, Claudia and Balmer, Oliver   (2012) Selective flowers to enhance biological control of cabbage pests by parasitoids.   Basic and Applied Ecology, 13, pp. 85-93.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19939/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>