<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecology and trust in mangement and business research 1995-2010. Tentative findings. MULTI-TRUST research paper</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rittenhofer, Iris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Trust’ is considered an important driving factor for the development of ‘green growth’ strategies. An understanding of how ‘trust’ is created and maintained is crucial for those strategies. However, b&amp; m research does neither offer consistent nor conclusive definitions of ‘trust’. Based on the review, a tentative suggestion is that the development of promising practices for the creation and maintenance of ‘trust’ is to be related to the organic complexities located in Denmark that characterize the transformation of the social space of organic agribusiness. Organic complexities are amongst others characterized by the highly fragmented meaning and current restructuring of the content of ‘organic’, diverse sale challenges, interdependences in the accreditation and certification processes, and the limited information value of eco labels. In order to meet related trust challenges, the concept of ‘high-trust relationships’ seems to be useful for this pursuit.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-04-24</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20781/4/20781.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rittenhofer, Iris    (2012) Ecology and trust in mangement and business research 1995-2010. Tentative findings. MULTI-TRUST research paper.    MULTI-TRUST, Organic RDD, Organic RDD 435377 8610.   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20781/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>