<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diplodia seriata, cause of black fruit rot in organically grown apples in Holland, Belgium and Northern Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weber, Roland W. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A fruit rot resembling Gloeosporium infections but appearing on fruits prior to harvest was&#xD;
noticed in organic apple orchards in Holland, Belgium and Northern Germany in 2007.&#xD;
Infections were most commonly observed on ‘Elstar’, but other cultivars were also&#xD;
affected. Fruit colonisation progressed in two steps, whereby a latent stage of sunken&#xD;
black lesions in immature fruits gave rise to a rapidly spreading firm brown rot upon fruit&#xD;
ripening. Isolation experiments from both stages consistently yielded a single species of&#xD;
fungus identified as Diplodia seriata, formerly known under the teleomorph name&#xD;
Botryosphaeria obtusa. Lesions of D. seriata were also seen on leaves as necrotic light&#xD;
brown spots surrounded by a purple halo, and occasionally on small twigs as cankers.&#xD;
Fruit mummies on apple twigs were heavily colonised by D. seriata and are thus likely to&#xD;
carry inoculum for fruit infections during late summer or in the following growing season.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13668/1/177-181.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trapman, Marc; Maxin, Peter and Weber, Roland W. S.    (2008) Diplodia seriata, cause of black fruit rot in organically grown apples in Holland, Belgium and Northern Germany.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 177-181.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13668/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>