<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>α-Tocopherol in plasma and milk from organically managed dairy cows fed natural or synthetic vitamin E or seaweed</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, Håvard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luteberget, Ingvild Steinnes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Søren K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thuen, Erling</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective was to compare the effects of supplementing lactating dairy cows with synthetic (All-rac), natural (RRR) α-tocopheryl acetate or seaweed with a control on the concentration of α-tocopherol in blood and milk. Twenty four dairy cows in mid lactation, fed an organic feed ration, were randomly allocated to the four treatments in a replicated Latin square design. Plasma and milk α-tocopherol concentrations were higher in RRR and All-rac than in the other treatments and higher in RRR than in All-rac. RRR-α-tocopherol was the predominant steroisomer (&gt; 86%), in both plasma and milk, whereas the remaining part was largely made up by the three synthetic 2R isomers. In cows fed the control, seaweed and RRR, the proportion of RRR-α-tocopherol in plasma and milk constituted more than 97% of the total α-tocopherol. The study demonstrated that dairy cows in mid and late lactation have preferential uptake of RRR-α-tocopherol compared to other stereoisomers</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>(German) Agriculture and Forestry Research</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21667/1/Steinshamn_et_al_2012_alpha-tocopherol_dairy_cows.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinshamn, Håvard; Luteberget, Ingvild Steinnes; Jensen, Søren K. and Thuen, Erling    (2012) α-Tocopherol in plasma and milk from organically managed dairy cows fed natural or synthetic vitamin E or seaweed.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Tackling The Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, (German) Agriculture and Forestry Research, Braunschweig, Germany, Agriculture and Forestry Research, Special Issue No 362 , no. 362, pp. 450-453.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21667/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>