<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>State of organic seeds in France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rey, F</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sinoir, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wohrer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Touret, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mazollier, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A comprehensive range of investigations carried out between 2010 and 2012 provided information on the state of organic seeds in France. Results fit with the hypothesis that the market is a significant factor influencing the choice of seeds and cultivars (local cultivars, landraces, modern cultivars). Expectations and practices of producers selling on a local market (i.e., direct sale) differ radically from those of producers selling to long food supply chains.&#xD;
This study showed that the availability and use of organic seeds have significantly improved over the last three years. A vast majority of organic producers willingly use organic seeds, with, on average, 45-70 % (cereals), and 75%-100 % (vegetables) of organic seeds being planted on farms. However, the total number of derogations remained quite high: there is still space for improvement in organic seed use and supply in France. Several limiting factors and levers were identified during the study, as well as farmers’ expectations for the future on cereals, forage crops and vegetables. This study described an action plan, which must be carefully implemented. The organic sector depends on the development of a wide and adapted range of organic seeds.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26337/1/Rey_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rey, F; Sinoir, N.; Wohrer, J.; Touret, C. and Mazollier, C.   (2013) State of organic seeds in France.  [Semences biologiques en France : quelles pratiques, quelles attentes ?]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 413-425.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26337/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>