<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainability assessment of wheat production using Emergy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Coppola, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haugaard-Nielsen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bastianoni, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Østergård, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainability of crop production has to be given high priority when global biomass resources are limited. Here emergy evaluation is applied in order to assess sustainability of crop production exemplified by winter wheat. Emergy evaluation takes into account all inputs involved in a production system (i.e. renewable and non-renewable, local and imported) and transforms them into a common measure of direct and indirect solar energy requirement. The evaluation of winter wheat production is conducted by comparing conventional and organic management on two soil types using Danish reference conditions. The resource use efficiency of wheat production per kg biomass is higher using conventional management practices. This is due to high yield based on large use of non-renewable resources. The environmental loading ratio from organic management practices is about a third of the conventional implying that the organic management can be considered more sustainable.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11381/2/11381.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Coppola, F.; Haugaard-Nielsen, H.; Bastianoni, S. and Østergård, H.    (2008) Sustainability assessment of wheat production using Emergy.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11381/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>