<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reihenapplikation von Komposten zur Kontrolle bodenbürtiger Krankheiten – technische Lösungen für Kartoffeln und Leguminosen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bohne, Björn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hensel, Oliver</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In principal suppressive effects with composts on soilborne diseases are well known. In practise, however, a targeted utilisation is not common due to technical constraints. The more precise composts are applied at the site of action the more effective they are as shown in potatoes to control Rhizoctonia solani with a strip application of composts compared to broadcast application. Similar effects were achieved in peas. Therefore, dosage tools were developed for the use in potato planting machines and sowing machines for grain legumes. It was shown with defined composts (yard waste composts with size fraction &lt;10 mm, 30-40  % humidity) that the developed tools will provide exact longitudinal and lateral application.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21591/1/21591_Bohne.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bohne, Björn; Hensel, Oliver and Bruns, Christian    (2013) Reihenapplikation von Komposten zur Kontrolle bodenbürtiger Krankheiten – technische Lösungen für Kartoffeln und Leguminosen.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21591/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>