<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aim of the breeding research in LIB-SP3 and the methods to&#xD;
be used</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Merks, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>‘Low input’ pig production systems are usually characterised by smaller herd size, more space per animal, lower capital investment, often outdoor management, provision of bedding, greater labour requirement and focus on animal welfare. Examples of ‘low input’ pig production systems are “Iberico” in Spain, “Neuland” pigs in Germany, “Scharrelvarkens” in The Netherlands, “Natura Farm” in Switzerland, “Label Rouge” in France and “Freedom Food” in United Kingdom.&#xD;
Organic pig production systems have similar characteristics to those described for ‘low input systems’ above. However, organic farming standards prescribe e.g. low stocking densities, access to outdoor runs, restrict the level of ‘bought in, non-organic’ feeds etc, which usually results in higher management and feed costs and more limited dietary composition choices than in other ‘low input’ systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-03-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18708/1/Merks-Pigs-aims.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18708/4/Merks-Pigs-aims-presentation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Merks, Jan    (2011) Aim of the breeding research in LIB-SP3 and the methods to be used.       Paper at:   First LowInputBreeds Symposium on Ethical Consideration in Livestock Breeding, Wagningen, The Netherlands, March 15 and 16, 2011.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18708/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>