<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Outline of the Finnish system of certified carbon footprints of food products</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saarinen, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hongisto, Mikko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Usva, Kirsi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kurppa, Sirpa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nissinen, Ari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Katajajuuri, Juha-Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The basic structure of a system called Certified Footprints of Products (CFP system) is outlined in this discussion paper. The CFP system could produce strict and reliable data needed for generating product-oriented carbon footprints in Finland. Central parts of the CFP system are a national CFP programme, product category rules (PCRs), a chain or actor-wise monitoring plan, validation of the monitoring plan, and reporting and verification of data, and an ICT-system to support data sharing. The system is designed around activity-based monitoring data, and every actor would be responsible for data on its own activities. Linkages to existing environmental management systems are taken into account. The CFP system is still just a theoretical structure. It needs further development prior to full-scale introduction. For the food sector, a new architecture for data acquisition and quality assurance, development of existing mechanisms and consolidation of them in the CFP system are needed. Additional research is needed regarding emissions from agricultural production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>BOKU university</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17561/1/saarinen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Saarinen, Merja; Hongisto, Mikko; Usva, Kirsi; Kurppa, Sirpa; Nissinen, Ari and Katajajuuri, Juha-Matti    (2010) Outline of the Finnish system of certified carbon footprints of food products.       Paper at:   9th European IFSA symposium, Vienna, 4-7 July, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17561/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>