<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Koberwitz (Kobierzyce): In the footsteps of Rudolf Steiner</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Austria</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>France</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sweden</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Switzerland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>“Now once again we have made a great step forward!” exclaimed Rudolf Steiner on the drive back from Koberwitz. Koberwitz (now Kobierzyce, Poland) can fairly be regarded as the birthplace of biodynamic agriculture. Rudolf Steiner delivered eight lectures at the Koberwitz Chateau (Schloss Koberwitz) in German in the summer of 1924 (7-16 June). There were 111 attendees, 30 women and 81 men, who came from six countries: Germany, Poland, Austria, Switzerland, France, and Sweden. The audience included farmers, estate managers, doctors, priests, teachers, artists, and engineers who all came to hear Steiner’s vision for agriculture. A witness observed “Seldom have I seen him so joyfully moved after the completion of a task as in this moment after the agricultural conference”. The Agriculture Course laid the foundation for the development of biodynamic agriculture. Photographs included are of the Koberwitz Chateau, the lecture room, the vestibule, the foyer, stairs and the trompe l’oeil ceiling.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22491/17/22491.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22491/12/KoberwitzChateau.JohnPaull.JPG</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22491/7/KoberwitzLectureRoom.JohnPaull.JPG</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2013) Koberwitz (Kobierzyce): In the footsteps of Rudolf Steiner.   Journal of Bio-Dynamics Tasmania, 109 (Autumn), pp. 7-11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22491/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>