<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of false flax oilcake in thermophilic biogas production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paulsen, Hans-Marten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Xiaming, Wei</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sun, Yongming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>False flax oilcake has been found to be suitable for anaerobic fermentation in mixtures with cattle slurry and straw. In organic farms, digestion of cattle dung and wheat straw with 8 % dry matter content mixed with 5 % of total material weight false flax oilcake is a feasible option for utilizing false flax oilcake to produce farm-own renewable energy and offering farm-own high nitrogen (ammonia) content fertilizer (2.48 g kg-1 wet wt).&#xD;
In field digesters, the biogas yield of 8 % dry matter pure material under thermophilic condition was 0.24 l g-1 VS fed. The biogas yield could be increased by mixing 5 % false flax oilcake to get 0.37 l g-1 VS fed and a VS conversion efficiency with 0.83 l g-1 VS destroyed. Under laboratory controlled conditions, the biogas yield of slurry with 0.5 % oilcake was a little higher than biogas yield of the digestion of pure material, which was 0.26 and 0.24 l g-1 VS fed, respectively. Compared with the field experiment, only small amounts of biogas were produced in the lab-scale when 5 % oilcake was mixed in. The mixing can improve the biogas yield and substrate reduction in the digesters which have sufficient material. &#xD;
Further research is needed to find out the best controlled conditions (high-efficient bacteria, mixing frequency and time) and best equipment (for example: two phases digesters).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut - Bundesforschungsinstitut für Ländliche Räume, Wald und Fischerei (vTI)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17027/1/06_HP_Biogas.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paulsen, Hans-Marten; Xiaming, Wei; Sun, Yongming; Rahmann, Gerold and Böhm, Herwart    (2009) Effect of false flax oilcake in thermophilic biogas production.    In: Rahmann, Gerold (Ed.)   Ressortforschung für den ökologischen Landbau 2008.  Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut - Bundesforschungsinstitut für Ländliche Räume, Wald und Fischerei (vTI), Braunschweig, pp. 47-60.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17027/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>