<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economic profitability of organic vs. conventional cotton-based production systems in a long-term field trial in India</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Forster, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andres, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verma, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zundel, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messmer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The debate on the relative benefits of conventional and organic farming systems is more topical than ever. The achievements of conventional high-input agriculture were largely brought about at the cost of deteriorating soil fertility; furthermore, they were based to a large extent on fossil fuels. Developing more sustainable farming practices on a large scale is of utmost importance.&#xD;
However, information about the performance of agricultural production systems under organic and conventional management in tropical and subtropical regions is largely lacking. This study aimed to assess agronomic and economic data from a long-term farming systems comparison trial under semi-arid conditions in central India.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24836/1/Andres-etal-2013-1stGlobalFoodSecurity-Conference.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Forster, D.; Andres, C.; Verma, R.; Zundel, C.; Messmer, M. and Mäder, P.    (2013) Economic profitability of organic vs. conventional cotton-based production systems in a long-term field trial in India.       Poster at:   First International Conference on Global Food Security, Noordwijkerhout, The Netherlands, 29 September - 2 October 2013.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24836/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>