<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development and survival of Ascaris suum eggs in deep&#xD;
litter of pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Katakam, Kiran Kumar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thamsborg, Stig Milan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kyvsgaard, Niels Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalsgaard, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Indoor transmission of Ascaris suum partly depends on the physico-chemical conditions in bedding material. Temperature,pH, aqueous ammonia, moisture, occurrence and development of A. suum eggs were therefore compared in different areas(resting, intermediate and latrine) of two deep litter pens on an organic farm in four seasons. There was some variation, but mean ammonia levels were generally very low (1·0–2·6mM) and pH levels were moderate (8·04–8·88) in all three areas. Relatively, resting areas were characterized by overall moderate moisture (36%) and moderately high temperature (35·7 °C)levels. The area contained few eggs (50 eggs g−1 DM) of which 17% were viable, and though only 4% were larvated and 0·7% appeared infective, it was more than in the other areas. Intermediate areas had moderate moisture (43%) and high&#xD;
temperature (43·6 °C) levels. There were many eggs (523 eggs g−1 DM), but overall viability was very low (5%) and few eggs were larvated (0·004%) or even infective (0·002%). Latrines typically had high moisture (79%) and moderate temperature 30 °C) levels. The concentration of eggswas very high (1444 egg g−1DM)and though 32%were viable, none had developed larval stages. The large majority of A. suum eggs appear to die and only few become infective while in the deep litter. However, a large fraction of eggs may remain viable for some time and could thus contaminate agricultural land and develop to infectivity, if the manure is not composted appropriately.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27345/7/27345.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Katakam, Kiran Kumar; Thamsborg, Stig Milan; Kyvsgaard, Niels Christian; Dalsgaard, Anders and Mejer, Helena   (2014) Development and survival of Ascaris suum eggs in deep litter of pigs.   Parasitologi, 141, pp. 1646-1656.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27345/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>