<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interactions between nutrition and gastrointestinal&#xD;
infections with parasitic nematodes in goats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>H., Hoste</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>J.F., Torres-Acosta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>V., Paolini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>A., Aguilar-Caballero</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>E., Etter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Y., Lefrileux</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., Chartier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., Broqua</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Parasitic nematodes of the digestive tract remain one of the main constraints to goat production both in temperate and tropical&#xD;
countries. The usual mode of control of these gastrointestinal nematodes (GIN) based on the repeated use of anthelmintics&#xD;
is now strongly questioned because of the increasing development of resistance to these molecules. Among the alternative&#xD;
methods to anthelmintics currently available, the manipulation of host nutrition in order to improve the host resistance and/or&#xD;
resilience to parasitic infections seems to represent one of the most promising options to reduce the dependence on conventional&#xD;
chemotherapy and to favour the sustainable control of gastro intestinal nematode infections. This paper will review the available&#xD;
information on the interactions between nutrition and nematode parasitism in dairy or meat goats both in temperate and tropical&#xD;
conditions. It will refer to quantitative aspects of the diet (influence of the protein and/or energy parts) as well as to qualitative&#xD;
components (effects of plant secondary metabolites on worm biology) and will discuss the specificities of goats in regard of&#xD;
theses interactions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6986/1/NutritionreviewSRR.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>H., Hoste; J.F., Torres-Acosta; V., Paolini; A., Aguilar-Caballero; E., Etter; Y., Lefrileux; C., Chartier and C., Broqua   (2005) Interactions between nutrition and gastrointestinal infections with parasitic nematodes in goats.   Small Ruminant Research (60), pp. 141-151.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6986/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>