<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFECT of CONVENTIONAL and ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEMS on&#xD;
YIELD and QUALITY of VINEYARDS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erdal, Ülfet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sökmen, Ömer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ongun, Ali Rıza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ertem, Atila</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study, the aim was to compare changes in yield and various qualities in vineyards where conventional farming systems (CFS) and organic farming systems (OFS) are practiced. The experiment was carried out in 5 replicates with a completely randomized design in Manisa-Salihli, Poyrazdamları Village over a period of 9 year between 2000 and 2008. According to soil analysis results, certified fertilizer, green manure and vineyard pruning waste were applied in organic plots. 21% ammonium sulphate, 26% ammonium nitrate, 43% triple super phosphate as P2O5 and 48-52% potassium sulphate as K2O were applied in conventional plots. When the yields were assessed, table grape and raisin yields were higher in conventional plots at a statistically significant degree.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10-13</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27699/1/organic%20vineyard-poster%20IFOAM2%20%282%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Erdal, Ülfet; Sökmen, Ömer; Ongun, Ali Rıza and Ertem, Atila    (2014) EFFECT of CONVENTIONAL and ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEMS on YIELD and QUALITY of VINEYARDS.       Poster at:   ‘Building Organic Bridges’, at the Organic World Congress, Istanbul, Turkey, 2014, 13-15 Oct.,.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27699/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>