<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Zur Genotyp-Umwelt-Interaktion in der ökologischen Schweinemast</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Horst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baulain, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brade, Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weissmann, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The suitability of indigenous or modern genotypes for organic conditions and the necessity of a specific organic breeding programme are intensively discussed in the organic pig fattening scene. To clarify both items information about Genotype-Environment-Interaction (GEI) is necessary. Therefore 682 pigs of 7 different genotypes with widely spread protein synthesis capacity were tested for growth performance and carcass quality under conventional and organic environments at two performance testing stations in order to verify GEI. The modern genotypes were superior to the old ones, all genotypes achieved significantly better results within the conventional environment and there were significant interactions between genotype and environment for all criteria of growth performance and carcass quality. The interactions were mainly caused by varying differences between organic and conventional environment within genotypes, but without a shift of the ranking order within environment between genotypes.&#xD;
Hence no special breeding programme is necessary for organic pig fattening under relatively similar marketing systems for conventionally and organically produced pork.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13985/1/Brandt_13985.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brandt, Horst; Baulain, Ulrich; Brade, Wilfried; Werner, Daniela and Weissmann, Friedrich    (2009) Zur Genotyp-Umwelt-Interaktion in der ökologischen Schweinemast.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13985/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>