<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Gebrauch biologischer Insektizide im Kampf gegen den&#xD;
Scaphoideus titanus, den Vektor von Flavescence dorée</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jermini, Mauro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gusberti, Michele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trivellone, Valeria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Erich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Linder, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Flavescence dorée and the mandatory control of its vector Scaphoideus titanus pose&#xD;
important problems in organic vineyards. The goal of our field studies conducted in the&#xD;
Ticino was to develop a pest control strategy conform to the guidelines of organic&#xD;
production. Insecticides containing pyrethrin were the only organic products showing&#xD;
an efficacy higher than 90% against the immature stages of S. titanus. However, these&#xD;
products had no effect on adult leafhoppers. Repeated applications of pyrethrin&#xD;
proved to be toxic against the predatory mite species Amblyseius andersoni. Despite&#xD;
this toxicity, the only efficient and recommended control strategy in organic vineyards&#xD;
is their application. Pyrethrin should be applied three times at an interval of ten days&#xD;
after the first appearance of individuals of the 3rd nymphal stage. Symptomatic plants&#xD;
must be eradicated from the vineyard to remove the phytoplasma inoculum.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14238/1/Jermini_14238.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jermini, Mauro; Gusberti, Michele; Trivellone, Valeria; Wyss, Erich and Linder, Christian    (2009) Gebrauch biologischer Insektizide im Kampf gegen den Scaphoideus titanus, den Vektor von Flavescence dorée.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14238/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>