<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of different Agents on the Efficacy of Codling Moth Granulovirus in Tank Mixtures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fritsch, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Undorf-Spahn, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the control of codling moth it is common to combine the granulovirus with other agents,&#xD;
especially fungicides, in spray application. Therefore the knowledge about the influence of&#xD;
these agents on the efficacy of the virus in tank mix is very important. Studies on this&#xD;
subject were part of a project supported by BMELV (German Federal Ministry for Food,&#xD;
Agriculture and Consumer protection) at the Institute for Biological Control of JKI in&#xD;
Darmstadt.&#xD;
The granulovirus of Cydia pomonella (L.) (CpGV) was mixed with 10 different agents at&#xD;
concentrations as applied in the field. After the exposure the virus activity was calculated&#xD;
from larval mortality determined in bioassays with neonates of a susceptible codling moth&#xD;
strain.&#xD;
Only two agents with a pH of 11 (sodium silicate (water glass) and calcium polysulfide&#xD;
(lime sulphur)) reduced the virulence of CpGV significantly.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13704/1/252-255.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fritsch, E.; Undorf-Spahn, K.; Huber, J. and Kienzle, J.    (2008) Impact of different Agents on the Efficacy of Codling Moth Granulovirus in Tank Mixtures.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 252-255.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13704/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>