<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of soil fertility, soil quality, nutritional status and fruit quality in a Citrus orchard in Southern Italy.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the work is to evaluate on a long term perspective the effect of application of different organic fertilizers on tree nutritional status, yield, fruits quality and soil fertility in a orange [Citrus sinensis (L.) Osbeck, cv. ‘Valencia late’], grafted on C. aurantium (L.) orchard cultivated on sandy loam soil, sized 1.8 hectars and located in Eastern Sicily.&#xD;
In a randomized block experimental design with three replicates (60 trees each plot), four treatments are compared. Treatments 1 and 2 receive two different composts; treatment 3 is fertilized using dried poultry manure and the control treatment is treated by mineral/synthetic fertilizers. Every year, each plot receives the same amount of total N, matching the needs of the crop. &#xD;
Nutritional status of trees and yield are evaluated determining the leaf content of macro and micro elements, chlorophyll content, xylem potential, trunk circumference, total yield, fruits weight and a number of fruit quality characters. The soil sampled in each plot was analyzed for total organic carbon, total nitrogen, C/N ratio, humified fraction, biomass carbon, potentially mineralisable N in anaerobic conditions, potentially mineralisable C, carbon mineralisation quotient and metabolic quotient. Moreover, the Community Level Physiological Profile (by Biolog technique) has been defined, also calculating derived biodiversity and versatility indexes.&#xD;
According to the obtained results, the long term application of organic fertilizers has determined: i) high yields, similar to those obtained with the application of mineral/synthetic fertilizers; ii) better fruit quality characteristics; iii) increase of long term soil potential fertility.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Research facility description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Facility}   Palap9: Evaluation of soil fertility, soil quality, nutritional status and fruit quality in a Citrus orchard in Southern Italy.    Start 1995.       Facility Leader(s): Roccuzzo, Dr Giancarlo and Canali, Dr Stefano, CRA-Istituto Sperimentale per l'Agrumicoltura; CRA-Istituto Sperimentale per la Nutrizione delle Piante.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8701/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>