<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung einer Methode zum Wirkungsnachweis resistenzinduzierender Präparate (Pflanzenstärkungsmittel)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marx, Peggy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kühne, Stefan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahn, Marga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Makulla, Alexandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A method for testing the efficacy of products which improve the resistance of plants was developed in the Julius Kühn-Institute. The susceptible radish (Raphanus sativus) cultivar ´Saxa 3` was infected with Peronospora parasitica isolated in the field. Different plant resistance improvers (PRI) like plant or algal extracts were tested compared to aqua dest. as control and ß-aminobutyric acid (BABA) as a standard. PRI were sprayed twice on intact plants (BBCH 10: Cotyledons completely unfolded; growing point or true leaf initial visible). 24 h, 48 h or 72 h after the last application with PRI, the plants were inoculated with P. parasitica. 10 to 14 days after inoculation, the concentration of spore suspension from cotyledons was determined. The efficacy of all tested products was shown. Optimum time lags between two PRI applications as well as last application and inoculation were defined. This method is useful as a standard method in the lab to test the efficacy of products for improving the resistance of plants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17342/3/Makulla_17342.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Marx, Peggy; Kühne, Stefan; Jahn, Marga and Makulla, Alexandra    (2011) Entwicklung einer Methode zum Wirkungsnachweis resistenzinduzierender Präparate (Pflanzenstärkungsmittel).       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17342/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>