<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic versus conventional dairy farming – studies from the Öjebyn Project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bystrom, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jonsson, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinsson, Kjell</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. A study (the Öjebyn Project) was conducted to determine differences between organic and conventional dairy farming systems. Comparisons of feed intake, milk production, live weight (LW), feed efficiency and animal health were conducted, based on records from 145 dairy cows (238 parities). A lower daily metabolisable energy (ME) intake, lower milk yield and a higher protein content were recorded in the organic herd during the first ten weeks of lactation. No differences were recorded between the systems in either average total DM intake or efficiency of feed conversion, calculated as MJ of feed/kg of energy-corrected milk (ECM). There were a trend to lower LW change and better health in the organic herd. Most differences between the systems were recorded during the early lactation period.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8390/1/bystrom_organic_conventional_dairy_ojebyn.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bystrom, Sara; Jonsson, Simon and Martinsson, Kjell    (2002) Organic versus conventional dairy farming – studies from the Öjebyn Project.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 179-184.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8390/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>