<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The impact of agro-biodiversity and eco-system services in development or A new vision for a just, sustainable and productive agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Perfecto, Ivette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this presentation I challenge the assumption that increasing yields should be a priority under all circumstances. &#xD;
Today we produce enough food to feed the world but still there are 1 billion people that are hungry. The problem is not that there isn’t enough food but the poor people don’t have access to that food.&#xD;
Then I examine the relationship between biodiversity and agriculture and the idea that biodiversity provides ecosystem services. I describe an example showing that complex ecological interaction result in the control of insect pests. Then I discuss the debate between two paradigms regarding agriculture and conservation of biodiverisy: separation (land sparing) versus integration (land sharing), and argue that the separation paradigm is flawed. &#xD;
I finish with a discussion of what I perceived is needed to solve the biodiversity and food crises in the world: a focus on small-scale agroecological farms with strong social and ecological relationships.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-12-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18247/1/18247.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Perfecto, Ivette    (2010) The impact of agro-biodiversity and eco-system services in development or A new vision for a just, sustainable and productive agriculture.       Lecture at:   Agro-biodiversity and Ecosystem services, Washington DC, USA, 16th Dec. 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18247/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>