<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic cash crop farms as net energy producers: Energy balances and environmental effects</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berntsen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming (OF) principles include the idea of reducing dependence on fossil fuels, but little has been achieved on this objective so far in Danish OF. Energy use and greenhouse gas emissions from an average 39 ha cash crop farm were calculated and alternative crop rotations for bio-energy production were modelled. Growing rapeseed on 10% of the land could produce bio-diesel to replace 50-60% of the tractor diesel used on the farm. Increasing Grass-clover area to 20% of the land and using half of this yield for biogas production could change the cash crop farm to a net energy producer, reduce green house gas emissions and improve the nutrient management on the farm while reducing overall output of products only marginally.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4364/4/halberg_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Halberg, Niels; Dalgaard, R.; Berntsen, J.; Olesen, J.E. and Dalgaard, T.    (2005) Organic cash crop farms as net energy producers: Energy balances and environmental effects.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4364/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>