<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evapotranspiration and crop coefficient for potato in organic farming.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carvalho, Daniel F. de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva, Dione G. da</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rocha, Hermes S. da</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almeida, Wilk S. de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sousa, Eraldo da S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to quantify the water consumption and the crop coefficients (Kc) for the potato (Solanum tuberosum L.), in Seropédica, Rio de Janeiro (RJ), Brazil, under organic management, and to simulate the crop evapotranspiration (ETc) using the Kc obtained in the field and the ones recommended by the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO). The water consumption was obtained through soil water balance, using TDR probes installed at 0.15m and 0.30m deep. At the different stages of development, the Kc was determined by the ratio of ETc and reference evapotranspiration, obtained by Penman-Monteith FAO 56. The crop coefficients obtained were 0.35, 0.45, 1.29 and 0.63. The accumulated ETc obtained in the field was 109.6 mm, while the ETc accumulated from FAO's Kc were 142.2 and 138mm, respectively, considering the classical values and the values adjusted to the local climatic conditions. The simulation of water consumption based on meteorological data of historical series from 1961 to 2007 provided higher value of ETc when compared with the one obtained in the field. From the meteorological data of historical series, it was observed that the use of Kc recommended by FAO may overestimate the amount of irrigation water by 9%, over the same growing season.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28510/1/Carvalho_evapotranspiration.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Carvalho, Daniel F. de; Silva, Dione G. da; Rocha, Hermes S. da; Almeida, Wilk S. de and Sousa, Eraldo da S.   (2013) Evapotranspiration and crop coefficient for potato in organic farming.  [Evapotranspiração e coeficiente de cultivo da batata em sistema agroecológico de produção.]  Engenharia Agrícola, 33 (1), pp. 201-211.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28510/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>