<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Eprints: Ein wichtiges Kommunikationstool für die Forschung zum ökologischen Landbau weltweit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meier, Julia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic Eprints is an open access archive for papers related to research in organic agriculture. The archive contains full-text papers in electronic form together with bibliographic information, abstracts and other metadata. The database is available at www.orgprints.org and was set up by the Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming - DARCOF (now ICROFS). The Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL Germany and Switzerland) is a major partner and contributes to the development of the database within a project under the German Federal Organic Farming Scheme (BOEL). In the frame of the European ERA-Net project CORE Organic, the archive was used to map research programmes, projects and publications in the field of organic agriculture in eleven European countries and thus a good overview was gained of organic farming research in these countries. This paper gives a summary of the current status of the Organic Eprints archive and states that it should be developed further in order to serve as an international communication tool on organic farming research.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13636/1/willer-meier-2009-eprints.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13636/2/willer-meier-2009-eprints-poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga and Meier, Julia    (2009) Organic Eprints: Ein wichtiges Kommunikationstool für die Forschung zum ökologischen Landbau weltweit.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, ETH Zürich; Schweiz, 11.-13- Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13636/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>