<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Opportunities and Obstacles in Adoption of Biodiversity-Enhancing Features on California Farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brodt, Sonja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klonsky, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jackson, Louise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brush, Steve</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smukler, Sean</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The USDA National Organic Program requires the conservation of biodiversity and the maintenance or improvement of natural resources on organic farms.  On-farm biodiversity-enhancing features such as border plantings can provide many of these ecosystem services. However, which practices farmers currently use to manage non-cropped edges, why and how they use these practices, and how subsidies and technical assistance affect farmers’ ability and willingness to manage farm edges for biodiversity are little studied topics.  Our study set out to identify the range of practices currently used to manage non-cropped field edges, roadsides, pond edges, and banks of permanent watercourses (sloughs, canals, ditches) in a case study area in California.  Secondary objectives were to gauge local farmers’ awareness of planted hedgerows and vegetated waterways and to gather preliminary information about the range of incentives and constraints to installing such features.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12026/1/12026.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brodt, Sonja; Klonsky, Karen; Jackson, Louise; Brush, Steve and Smukler, Sean    (2008) Opportunities and Obstacles in Adoption of Biodiversity-Enhancing Features on California Farms.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12026/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>