<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of the organisation and economic efficiency of organic and conventional farms in the Kujawsko-Pomorskie voivodship</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stalenga, Dr Jaroslaw</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kus, Prof. Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kopinski, Dr Jerzy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the research was the evaluation of the structure, agricultural production and economic efficiency of 20 organic compared with conventional farms. It was conducted in 2003-2004 on the basis of a special questionnaire. Market value of agricultural production and final agricultural gross output were the main criteria used in the evaluation of economic efficiency of the farming systems. In 2004, the average market value of all agricultural products sold from the investigated group of organic farms was about 720 Euro/ha of Utilised Agricultural Area (UAA). Animal products had a 68% share in this value. Higher than average (in the voivodship) prices received by organic farmers for their products significantly influenced the final value of their sale. Direct subsidies and organic area subsidies were a very important element of total personal incomes of the investigated farms. The results of the analyses showed that moderate specialisation in organic farming sometimes may improve economic efficiency. Organic mixed farms usually had the worst economic results.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8221/1/Stalenga_Kus_Kopinski_2_pages.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stalenga, Dr Jaroslaw; Kus, Prof. Jan and Kopinski, Dr Jerzy    (2006) Evaluation of the organisation and economic efficiency of organic and conventional farms in the Kujawsko-Pomorskie voivodship.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8221/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>