<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of amino acid level and production system on performance, health and behaviour in organic growing pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Høøk Presto, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersson, H.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wallgren, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindberg, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The influence of dietary amino acid levels (recommended, 7% and 14% lower) on performance and carcass quality was studied in organic indoor and outdoor pigs fed ad libitum in a 2-phase feeding system. The outdoor pigs grew faster during phase 2 than the indoor pigs (p=0.001), although feed conversion ratio did not differ (p=0.358). Dressing percentage was higher for outdoor than for indoor pigs (p=0.011) but lean meat content did not differ (p=0.904). The results indicate a discrepancy between pigs housed in different production systems rather than between pigs directed to different dietary amino acid levels. This suggests that growing/finishing pigs fed ad libitum can compensate for dietary amino acid levels lower than the current Swedish recommendations without affecting production results.&#xD;
Behaviour was affected by production system and showed that outdoor pigs walked significantly more (p=0.012) and tended to be rooting more (p=0.098) than indoor pigs. Sniffing, nibbling, pushing (p=0.001 for all) and tail manipulation (p=0.002) occurred more often indoors than outdoors. The incidence of pigs seropositive to erysipelas was higher outdoors (χ2-test; p=0.001). Ascaris suum infections were present in both production systems, whereas Eimeria sp only was found among outdoor pigs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11707/1/Hook_Presto_11707_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Høøk Presto, M.; Andersson, H.K.; Wallgren, P. and Lindberg, J.E.    (2008) Influence of amino acid level and production system on performance, health and behaviour in organic growing pigs.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11707/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>