<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutrient budgeting for trace elements: Examples from Scottish organic farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Owens, Katie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Watson, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Farmgate nutrient budgets have been calculated for Cu, Co and Mo for six farms in NE Scotland. All five livestock farms studied had a positive balance for Co, one showed a negative balance for Cu and two showed negative balances for Mo. The stockless farm studied showed a positive balance for Cu but negative balances for Co and Mo. These balances were calculated for a one-year period only and may thus have been strongly influenced by one-off purchases e.g. calcified seaweed. Future work will calculate budgets over whole rotations to provide a clearer picture of the long-term sustainability of trace element use on organic farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8385/1/owens_watson_Nutrient_budgeting_trace.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Owens, Katie and Watson, Christine    (2002) Nutrient budgeting for trace elements: Examples from Scottish organic farms.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 147-148.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8385/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>