<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Forschung zur ökologischen Land- und Lebensmittelwirtschaft - Ansatzpunkte für eine Interessensvertretung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häring, Anna Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blodau, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Braun, Charis</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meyerhof, Carsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winkler, Christiane</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Innovations may help in dealing with key problems the agro-food sector is facing. The overall study objective is to identify starting points for improving how the interests of the organic agro-food innovation system are represented in Germany. The status quo of research for the sector, the sector’s innovative ability and innovation requirements and the framework conditions for research funding were analysed. The study shows that research is often applied and inter- or transdisciplinary and thus contributes to the sector’s innovative ability. The structural capacity of the sector and research funding, however, lag behind its requirements. Professional representation of the needs of the organic agro-food innovation system may strengthen it.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde (FH)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22477/1/Schrift_2012_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häring, Anna Maria; Blodau, Simon; Braun, Charis; Meyerhof, Carsten and Winkler, Christiane         (2012) Forschung zur ökologischen Land- und Lebensmittelwirtschaft - Ansatzpunkte für eine Interessensvertretung.   Schriften zu den Wirtschafts- und Sozialwissenschaften der Land- und Lebensmittelwirtschaft, no. 1/2012, 2., überarbeitete Auflage. Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde (FH), D-Eberswalde.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22477/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>