<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Overview of supply and demand for concentrated organic feed in the EU in 2002 and 2003. Summary of draft project report of EEC 2092/91 (Organic) Revision</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Annex IB of the EU Regulation on organic farming (2092/91) sets out that animals on organic farms should be fed with feed stuffs from organic farming systems. Only if organic feed is not available in sufficient quantity and quality, can a set percentage of those non-organic components be used that are listed in Annex II. The derogations for using conventional feed are due to expire in August 2005 and currently negotiations in Brussels are concerned with what rules will apply after August. Several Organisation of  the organic sector have already taken significant steps to reduce the reliance on conventional feed for ruminants. In Denmark, all organic cattle have to be fed 100% organic diets, and BIOLAND and DEMETER in Germany have also included this in their standards. Other producer organisations (for example BIO SUISSE and NATURLAND) have reduced the number conventional components that are still permitted. In France, the percentage of permitted conventional has been reduced to 10% for all categories of animals, including pigs and poultry. However, concerns have been expressed that this might lead to a high reliance of imported feed stuff (mainly Soya) in organic rations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10985/1/padel_wp42_efrc.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne   (2005) Overview of supply and demand for concentrated organic feed in the EU in 2002 and 2003. Summary of draft project report of EEC 2092/91 (Organic) Revision.   Elm Farm Research Centre Bulletin (78), pp. 4-6.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10985/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>