<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anbau und Düngung von Winterraps (Brassica napus L.)&#xD;
im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stumm, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berg, Dr. Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Prof. Dr. Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At the experimental farm Wiesengut in Hennef (Germany) in 2007/8 four different&#xD;
cultivation methods of rapeseed and an application of fertiliser in springtime were&#xD;
tested in order to manage weeds, to reduce nitrogen losses during wintertime and to&#xD;
enhance grain yield. Cultivation methods tested included i. narrow row distance (12&#xD;
cm), no mechanical weed control; ii. wide row distance (24 cm), mechanical hoeing;&#xD;
iii. rapeseed sown in double rows intercropped with buckwheat (Fagopyrum&#xD;
esculentum Moench) sown in double rows, row distance 12 cm, no mechanical weed&#xD;
control; iv. rapeseed sown in double rows and left double rows free, row distance&#xD;
12 cm, mechanical hoeing. In a two factorial completely randomised block design&#xD;
these treatments were fertilised (I. 80 kgN/ha as PPL, Potato Protein Liquid) and not&#xD;
fertilised (II.) in March 2008 at EC 30. In contrast to the hypothesis treatment iii.&#xD;
(rapeseed intercropped with buckwheat) did not control weeds efficiently nor&#xD;
enhanced nitrogen uptake before winter. Grain yield was significantly lower in this&#xD;
treatment compared to all other treatments. The most cost-efficient treatment i.&#xD;
controlled weeds effectively. Grain yield was not significantly lower in this treatment&#xD;
compared to the more cost-intensive treatments (ii. &amp; iv.) where hoeing was&#xD;
performed. Across treatments calculated, application of PPL increased grain yield&#xD;
significantly.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14338/1/Stumm_14338.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stumm, Christoph; Berg, Dr. Martin and Köpke, Prof. Dr. Ulrich    (2009) Anbau und Düngung von Winterraps (Brassica napus L.) im Ökologischen Landbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14338/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>