<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Wirkung alternativer Saatgutbehandlungen gegen Auflaufschaderreger in Getreide</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Waldow, Franziska</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jahn, Marga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wächter, Rebecca</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koch, Eckhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogt-Kaute, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spieß, Hartmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Karl-Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilbois, Klaus-Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since all plant material used for organic farming should have been produced under organic farming conditions, and due to the generally occurring expansion of organic agriculture, the significance of healthy seed in organic farming is increasing. In a joint research project (2004-2006) the currently available as well as some promising methods and substances were tested and evaluated for their use in practice. Results of investigations concerning the control of pathogens affecting field emergence of rye and wheat by different natural products and physi-cal methods are presented. It has been proved that hot water treatment as well as several plant strengthening products (Tillecur®, LEBERMOOSER, Milsana®) and microbial products (Serenade, Cerall) can improve the field emergence and the development of the plants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9742/1/9742_Waldow_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Waldow, Franziska; Jahn, Marga; Wächter, Rebecca; Koch, Eckhard; Vogt-Kaute, Werner; Spieß, Hartmut; Müller, Karl-Josef and Wilbois, Klaus-Peter    (2007) Untersuchungen zur Wirkung alternativer Saatgutbehandlungen gegen Auflaufschaderreger in Getreide.  [Investigations in the effectiveness of alternative seed treatments against pathogens affecting field emergence of cereals.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9742/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>