<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A primary survey of aphid species on almond and peach, and natural enemies of Brachycaudus amygdalinus in As-Sweida, Southern Syria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Almatni, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Khalil, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Syria is one of the biggest almond producer country in the world. Few arthropdes that&#xD;
live on almond are consider as pests. Aphids are one of the major pests their. In&#xD;
order to change the product to organic we should know more about the pests and&#xD;
their natural enemies in order to use better bio- and organic decisions. A field survey&#xD;
was done to aphids that attack Almond and Peach in Al-Arab mountain at As- Sweida&#xD;
governorate, between 2002 and 2006. Three species of aphids were considered as&#xD;
important pests on both trees. They are Brachycaudus amygdalinus and&#xD;
Brachycaudus helichrysi, which are aphids that feed on the young leaves causing&#xD;
stunted growth; and Pterochloroides persicae which is a species that attack the bark&#xD;
and excretes large quantities of honeydew. A survey of natural enemies of B.&#xD;
amygdalinus has been done in addition to study its population dynamics during the&#xD;
seasons of 2002, 2003 and 2004. 30 species of natural enemies were recorded&#xD;
includes 15 Coccinellidae, 4 of each Anthocoridae and Miridae, 3 of Syrphidae, one&#xD;
species of each of Chrysopidae and Chamaemyiidae, and one beetle, in addition to&#xD;
one parasitoid. Some Arachinids were also mentioned to prey on this aphid. Most&#xD;
numerous predator at the beginning of the season was Coccinella septempunctata&#xD;
followed later with Scymnus (Pullus) subvillosus and Hyppodamia variegate. Most&#xD;
numerous predatory bug was Orius horvathi.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13654/1/109-115.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Almatni, W. and Khalil, N.    (2008) A primary survey of aphid species on almond and peach, and natural enemies of Brachycaudus amygdalinus in As-Sweida, Southern Syria.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 109-115.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13654/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>