<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Utilising intrinsic robustness in agricultural production systems: Inventions for a sustainable development of agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Napel, J. ten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bianchi, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bestman, Monique</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper explores the potential of utilising robust crops and livestock for improving sustainability of agriculture. Two approaches for dealing with unwanted fluctuations that may influence agricultural production, such as diseases and pests, are discussed. The prevailing approach, which we call the ‘Control Model’, is to protect crops and livestock from disturbances as much as possible, to regain balance with monitoring and intervention and to look for add-on solutions only. There are a number of problems associated with the Control Model, including reduced animal welfare, environmental pollution and low public support. An alternative approach, which we call the ‘Adaptation Model’, is based on reducing the consequences of disturbances rather than taking disturbances out</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>TransForum Agro &amp; Groen</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16807/1/Transforum_robustness_ENG.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Napel, J. ten; Bianchi, F. and Bestman, Monique    (2006) Utilising intrinsic robustness in agricultural production systems: Inventions for a sustainable development of agriculture.    In:      Inventions for a sustainable development of agriculture .  TransForum Agro &amp; Groen, Zoetermeer, pp. 32-53.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16807/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>