<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecosystem properties and principles of living systems as foundation for sustainable agriculture – Critical reviews of environmental assessment tools, key findings and questions from a course process</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ekbladh, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grönlund, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ingemarson, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karlsson, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nilsson, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strid Eriksson, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With increasing demands on limited resources worldwide, there is a growing interest in sustainable patterns of utilisation and production. Ecological agriculture is a response to these concerns. &#xD;
&#xD;
To assess progress and compliance, standard and comprehensive measures of resource requirements, impacts and agro-ecological health are needed. Assessment tools should also be rapid, standardized, userfriendly, meaningful to public policy and applicable to management. Fully considering these requirements confounds the development of integrated methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
Currently, there are many methodologies for monitoring performance, each with its own foundations, assumptions, goals, and outcomes, dependent upon agency agenda or academic orientation. Clearly, a concept of sustainability must address biophysical, ecological, economic, and sociocultural foundations. &#xD;
&#xD;
Assessment indicators and criteria, however, are generally limited, lacking integration, and at times in conflict with one another. A result is that certification criteria, indicators, and assessment methods are not based on a consistent, underlying conceptual framework and often lack a management focus.&#xD;
&#xD;
Ecosystem properties and principles of living systems, including self-organisation, renewal, embeddedness, emergence and commensurate response provide foundation for sustainability assessments and may be appropriate focal points for critical thinking in an evaluation of current methods and standards. A systems framework may also help facilitate a comprehensive approach and promote a context for meaningful discourse. Without holistic accounts, sustainable progress remains an illdefined concept and an elusive goal.&#xD;
&#xD;
Our intent, in the work with this report, was to use systems ecology as a pedagogic basis for learning and discussion to:&#xD;
- Articulate general and common characteristics of living systems.&#xD;
- Identify principles, properties and patterns inherent in natural ecosystems.&#xD;
- Use these findings as foci in a dialogue about attributes of sustainability to:&#xD;
a. develop a model for communicating scientific rationale.&#xD;
b. critically evaluate environmental assessment tools for application in land-use.&#xD;
c. propose appropriate criteria for a comprehensive assessment and expanded definition of ecological land use.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Doherty, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rydberg, T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2832/1/ekolantbruk32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ekbladh, G.; Grönlund, E.; Ingemarson, F.; Karlsson, L.; Nilsson, S. and Strid Eriksson, I.     (editor): Doherty, S. and Rydberg, T. (Eds.)    (2002) Ecosystem properties and principles of living systems as foundation for sustainable agriculture – Critical reviews of environmental assessment tools, key findings and questions from a course process.   Ekologiskt lantbruk, no. 32. Centre for Sustainable Agriculture.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2832/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>