<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hortibot: Feasibility study of a plant nursing robot performing weeding operations – part IV</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Claus G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nørremark, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Rasmus N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Kjeld</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maagaard, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Aa.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Based on the development of a robotic tool carrier (Hortibot) equipped with weeding tools, a feasibility study was carried out to evaluate the viability of this innovative technology. The feasibility was demonstrated through a targeted evaluation adapted to the obtainable knowledge on the system performance in horticulture.&#xD;
&#xD;
A usage scenario was designed to set the implementation of the robotic system in a row crop of seeded bulb onions considering operational and functional constraints in organic crop, production. This usage scenario together with the technical specifications of the implemented system provided the basis for the feasibility analysis, including a comparison with a conventional weeding system. Preliminary results show that the automation of the weeding tasks within a row crop has the potential of significantly reducing the costs and still fulfill the operational requirements set forth. &#xD;
&#xD;
The potential benefits in terms of operational capabilities and economic viability have been quantified. Profitability gains ranging from 20 to 50% are achievable through targeted applications. In general, the analyses demonstrate the operational and economic feasibility of using small automated vehicles and targeted tools in specialized production settings.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11263/1/ASABE_paper_%282007%29_-S%C3%B8rensen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sørensen, Claus G.; Nørremark, Michael; Jørgensen, Rasmus N.; Jensen, Kjeld; Maagaard, Jørgen and Jensen, Lars Aa.    (2007) Hortibot: Feasibility study of a plant nursing robot performing weeding operations – part IV.       Paper at:   2007 ASABE Annual International Meeting, Minneapolis, Minnesota, US, 17 - 20 June 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11263/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>