<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Datenbanktechnische Voraussetzungen zur Schaffung eines Rückverfolgbarkeitssystems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Rolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The traceability and safeguarding of origin of organic products shall be improved by the development of an overlapping technical data base traceability system. This is to contribute to the prevention and mitigation of scandals and strengthen consumers` trust in organic products. &#xD;
Data base systems existing so far or just being developed do serve different purposes depending on the respective fabricator. There are data bases for the acquisition of basic and company related data of the client, systems to delineate the processes of control and certification as well as data bases for the provision of information for the participants of the market, such as information related to products, the products` properties and availability, as well as internal inventory control systems of the company. All of these systems are isolated applications so far, suited for the specific demands of the operator. &#xD;
The precondition for the development of an overlapping system is the integration and linkage of the existing systems. To enable a data exchange among the different data base systems or the concentration of data in a centralised data base a standard of data shall be developed. By this means, data base based traceability along the entire value-added chain would be ensured.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3405/1/3405.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mäder, Rolf    (2005) Datenbanktechnische Voraussetzungen zur Schaffung eines Rückverfolgbarkeitssystems.  [Data base related technical preconditions for the development of a traceability system.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3405/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>