<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Förderung der Mulchsaat im Ökolandbau - das Auflaufverhalten&#xD;
von Zwischenfrüchten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wilhelm, Birgit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hensel, Oliver</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The several advantages of conservation tillage systems are interesting for organic&#xD;
farmers too. The positive effects concerning the reduction of soil erosion are well&#xD;
known and documented. The more residues are left on the soil surface the higher&#xD;
reduction of soil erosion is achieved. Nevertheless the plough is still the main tillage&#xD;
equipment in organic agriculture systems. A first step towards conservation tillage&#xD;
might be the tillage before intercrops. In a three years project the relationship of&#xD;
emergence rate from straw quantity, working depth and residue cover is investigated.&#xD;
Thick mulch layers have negative effects on the emergence rate of the followed crop.&#xD;
Modern machinery for conservation tillage improve the incorporation of crop residues&#xD;
which effects the residue cover after tillage. Especially at deep working depth (above&#xD;
13 cm) the benchmark of 30% residues cover can’t be achieved any more. The results&#xD;
of the trials support the conservation tillage system before intercrops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14288/1/Wilhelm_14288.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wilhelm, Birgit and Hensel, Oliver    (2009) Förderung der Mulchsaat im Ökolandbau - das Auflaufverhalten von Zwischenfrüchten.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14288/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>