<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of ridging on crop performance and symbiotic N2 fixation of fababean (Vicia faba L.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vinther, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dahlmann-Hansen, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The success of organic cropping systems depends on symbiotic N2 fixation by leguminous crops, and it is important to explore new management systems to improve the nitrogen input through N2 fixation. During two growing seasons the possible advantage of growing fababean in ridges in comparison to the traditional method on the flat was studied. Differences in soil physical parameters resulted in a significantly greater microbial activity and a deeper root system at the flowering stage when grown in ridges than on the flat. Consequently, the amount of fixed N at flowering was significantly greater in ridges than in flat soil. However, during the period from flowering until harvest, when the major part of the N uptake and N2 fixation took place the differences between the treatments disappeared. Average values for the growing season of fluorescein diacetate hydrolysis, arylamidase activity and arylsulfatase activity were significantly greater in the ridges than on the flat, and the microbial biomass-C, derived from substrate induced respiration (SIR), was on average 232 and 223 µg C g-1 soil in the ridged and on the flat, respectively. Measured total N-uptake, including root N (0-30 cm), ranged from 206 to 247 kg N ha-1 of which 182-201 kg N ha-1 was fixed N. From 154 to 173 kg N ha-1 was removed in grain resulting in a soil-N balance at +28 kg N ha-1 in both years. However, by including estimates of total root N and rhizodeposition-N the soil-N balance ranged from +52 to +62 kg N ha-1.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5203/1/5203.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vinther, F.P. and Dahlmann-Hansen, L.   (2005) Effects of ridging on crop performance and symbiotic N2 fixation of fababean (Vicia faba L.).   Soil Use and Management, 21, pp. 205-211.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5203/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>