<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Net mineralization rate of selenium from plant material and inorganic salts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stavridou, Eleftheria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Broadley, Martin R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Young, Scott D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Selenium (Se) is an essential nutrient for animals, humans and microorganisms. The importance of Se in the prevention, as well as the treatment, of chronic and degenerative diseases in humans has been established. Catch crops have been used successfully in agriculture to improve soil fertility, increase nitrogen and sulfur content in the soil and avoid nutrient leaching. The intention of the present study was to estimate the net Se mineralization rate from plant material, relative to inorganic salts, and to evaluate the risk of Se leaching after their application.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Science and Technology of China Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Banuelos , Gary S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lin, Zhiqing</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yin, Xuebin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19591/1/NetMineralizationRateOfSeleniumProceeding_ELST.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19591/4/19591.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stavridou, Eleftheria; Broadley, Martin R.; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian and Young, Scott D.    (2009) Net mineralization rate of selenium from plant material and inorganic salts.   In: Banuelos , Gary S.; Lin, Zhiqing and Yin, Xuebin (Eds.)  Selenium deficiency toxicity and biofortification for human health, University of Science and Technology of China Press, China, pp. 44-45.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19591/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>