<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biotic indicators of carabid species richness on organically and conventionally managed arable fields</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Döring, T. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hiller, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wehke, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulte, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Broll, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Carabids, a species rich arthropod family, potentially contribute  much to biodiversity in agroecosystems, but assessing and  monitoring carabid diversity is costly and time consuming.  Therefore, this study aimed at finding more easily measurable  parameters indicating high carabid diversity within organic and  conventional management systems. Cover and number of weed  species as well as activity density of single carabid species and of  total carabids were investigated as potential indicators of carabid  species richness. The study was carried out near Reckenfeld in  Westphalia on sandy Plaggenesch soils. Three organically and  four conventionally managed fields (cereals and corn) were  investigated at the field margins and in the field centres from April  to August 1999. Additionally, data of carabid catches and weed  flora in winter cereals from an extended study in Düren  (Northrhine-Westphalia) were reanalysed to validate the results.  However, neither of the potential indicators showed consistently  significant positive correlation with carabid diversity. This is partly  attributed to the low variability of management conditions within  the management systems in the studies presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier Science B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1107/1/kein-Dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Döring, T. F.; Hiller, A.; Wehke, S.; Schulte, G. and Broll, G.   (2003) Biotic indicators of carabid species richness on organically and conventionally managed arable fields.   Agriculture Ecosystems &amp; Environment, 98, pp. 133-139.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1107/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>