<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulierung der Krautfäule(Phytophthora infestans) mit reduzierten Kupfer-Aufwandmengen im Kartoffelanbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wohlleben, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bartels, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four field experiments were conducted in 2004 to analyse the efficacy of reduced rates of copper fungicides against Phytophthora infestans (3 x organic and 1 x conventional growing). Copper (Cu-hydroxide, Cu-oxychloride or Cu-octanoate) was sprayed in a weekly routine or according to the decision support system SIMPHYT with total dosages ranging from 0.57 kg/ha to 4.0 kg/ha. The results revealed in almost all treatments a significant reduction of late blight, except for the lowest rates (e.g. 4 x 0.14 kg/ha Cu as Cu-octanoate or 6 x 0.15 kg/ha Cu as Cu-hydroxide). There was a clear dose-response relation between increasing rates of copper and control of late blight in each experiment. Marketable yields varied from 132 dt/ha to 238 dt/ha in organic field trials depending on trial site and copper treatment. Generally, an effect of copper treatment and late blight on yield could be shown. Even a slight reduction of P. infestans increased yield by 10 % to 20 %. The influence of copper dosage on late blight was more obvious than influence of copper spraying on yield. A dropleg spraying system (copper application within the crop canopy) which was tested on one trial site did not improve blight control compared to conventional application.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3585/1/3585.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wohlleben, S. and Bartels, G.    (2005) Regulierung der Krautfäule(Phytophthora infestans) mit reduzierten Kupfer-Aufwandmengen im Kartoffelanbau.  [Control of late blight (Phytophthora infestans) with reduced dose rates of copper in potatoes.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3585/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>