<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exchangeable potassium and potassium balances in organic crop rotations on a coarse sandy soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Crops on sandy soils (&lt;5% clay) are exposed to K deficiency due to the small release and high leaching losses of K. Reliable tools are needed to improve the K management in cropping systems with limited K input, such as organic farming where import of nutrients are restricted according to the EC regulations. We investigated K balances and exchangeable K (Kexch) changes in an organic crop rotation experiment. Potassium leaching decreased from 42 kg ha-1 in 1998/99 to 21 kg ha-1 in 2000/01 as an average of a crop rotation (spring barley, grass-clover, winter wheat and pea/barley) with manure application and without catch crops. In the same period, spring Kexch decreased from 5.0 to 3.0 mg K 100 g-1 soil (0-20 cm). The retention of the straw K left in the field after harvest increased with decreasing levels of Kexch. The cereal crops did not respond to K application but in the pea/barley mixture the pea yield increased by 46%. The concordance between measured K balances and changes in Kexch was weak. Exchangeable K is suitable as a tool for K management on a crop rotational basis, and a Kexch above 3 mg 100 g-1 soil in the autumn should be avoided to minimize K leaching.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3898/1/3898.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Askegaard, Margrethe; Eriksen, Jørgen and Olesen, Jørgen E.   (2003) Exchangeable potassium and potassium balances in organic crop rotations on a coarse sandy soil.   Soil Use and Management, 19, pp. 96-103.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3898/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>