<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Study of trapping systems for control of bactrocera oleae (gmelin)(diptera:tephritidae) in crete olive groves</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alexandrakis, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Varikou, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kalaitzaki, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Studies have been carried out the last four years to search for improved mass trapping systems for the control of olive fruit fly in olive groves in Chania, Crete (Greece). Trapping materials, which include various food and sex attractants and different types of traps (liquid and paper traps), were tested for their attractiveness and effectiveness in field trials. &#xD;
Among the tested attractants (Entomella 50 (E50), Entomella 75 (E75), Dacus bait 100 (Db100), Ammonium sulphate (As) and Sex pheromone (Sp)), the hydrolyzed protein ‘Db100’ showed the highest attractiveness regardless of the ‘Sp’. Among the tested traps (Daidalos, Elcofon, Zervas, Agrisense &amp; Ecotrap), Daidalos captured significantly more flies than the other traps.&#xD;
When the traps were tested in mass trapping conditions, no statistical differences were observed among the tested traps (chemical control was applied when was necessary) , but all were different from the reference product (classical chemical control).&#xD;
In addition, when Spinosad, a novel natural compound derived from fermentation of the bacterium Saccharopolyspora spinosa,  was applied as complementary sprays in the Mass trapping field, it also provided comparable and significant control for B. oleae (Gmel.) in comparison to the classical control.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4226/3/Alexandrakis_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alexandrakis, V.; Varikou, K. and Kalaitzaki, A.    (2005) Study of trapping systems for control of bactrocera oleae (gmelin)(diptera:tephritidae) in crete olive groves.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4226/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>