<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of US Brown Swiss genetics on milk quality from low-input herds in Switzerland: Interactions with grazing intake and pasture type</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stergiadis, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bieber, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franeschin, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Isensee, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eyre, M.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chatzidimitriou, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cozzi, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bapst, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stewart, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gordon, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Butler, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigated the effect of, and interactions between, contrasting crossbreed genetics (US Brown Swiss [BS] x Improved Braunvieh [BV] x Original Braunvieh [OB]) and feeding regimes (especially grazing intake and pasture type) on milk fatty acid (FA) profiles. Concentrations of total polyunsaturated FAs, total omega-3 FAs and trans palmitoleic, vaccenic, a-linolenic, eicosapentaenoic and docosapentaenoic acids were higher in cows with a low proportion of BS genetics. Highest concentrations of the nutritionally desirable FAs, trans palmitoleic, vaccenic and eicosapentaenoic acids were found for cows with a low proportion of BS genetics (0–24% and/or 25–49%) on high grazing intake (75–100% of dry matter intake) diets. Multivariate analysis indicated that the proportion of OB genetics is a positive driver for nutritionally desirable monounsaturated and polyunsaturated FAs while BS genetics proportion was positive driver for total and undesirable individual saturated FAs. Significant genetics x feeding regime interactions were also detected for a range of FAs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28021/1/Stergiadis_etal_2015_FoodChemistry.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stergiadis, S.; Bieber, A.; Franeschin, E.; Isensee, A.; Eyre, M.D.; Maurer, V.; Chatzidimitriou, E.; Cozzi, G.; Bapst, B.; Stewart, G.; Gordon, A. and Butler, G.   (2015) Impact of US Brown Swiss genetics on milk quality from low-input herds in Switzerland: Interactions with grazing intake and pasture type.   Food Chemistry, 175, pp. 609-618.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28021/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>