<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exploring The Gap Between Attitudes And Behaviour: Understanding Why Consumers Buy Or Do Not Buy Organic Food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Foster, Carolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The purpose of the paper is to explore the values that underlie consumers purchasing decisions of organic food. It draws on data from focus groups and laddering interviews with a total of 181 regular and occasional consumers of organic food that were contrasted with survey results of other studies.  The results show that most consumers associate organic at first with vegetables and fruit and a healthy diet with organic products. Fruit and vegetables are also the first and in many cases only experience with buying organic product. The decision-making process is complex and the importance of motives and barriers may vary between product categories. Future research should consider tradeoffs that consumers make between values and product as well as consumer segmentation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Emerald</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>McEachern, Morven</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Seamann, Claire</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8072/2/BFJ_Consumers0701070805.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, Susanne and Foster, Carolyn   (2005) Exploring The Gap Between Attitudes And Behaviour: Understanding Why Consumers Buy Or Do Not Buy Organic Food.   British Food Journal, 107 (8), pp. 606-625.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8072/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>