<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lammfleischqualität von extensiv gehaltenen und seltenen&#xD;
Schweizer Schafrassen (Engadinerschaf, Schwarznasenschaf,&#xD;
Spiegelschaf) im Vergleich zum Weißen Alpenschaf</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Probst, Johanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leiber, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigates meat quality of four autochthonous Swiss ovine breeds, White&#xD;
Alpine (WAS, n=15), Walliser blacknose sheep (SN, n=8), Engadine sheep (EN, n=9)&#xD;
and the Mirror sheep (SP, n=10). Especially for the latter two breeds, which are rare&#xD;
and endangered, information about meat quality and constitution is important for&#xD;
merchandising issues. All lambs (LW 20-25 kg) of each breed were fattened on pasture&#xD;
for 208 d and subsequently slaughtered. Evaluations were carried out for slaughter&#xD;
yield and classifications, pH-value, colorimetry (L*a*b*-System), shear force (Warner&#xD;
Bratzler method) and cooking losses in the Musculus longissimus dorsi. The results&#xD;
showed no meat quality defects in any breed. The main differences between breeds&#xD;
arose in slaughter yield (p&lt;0.001) with SN being significantly inferior to WAS, and CHTAX&#xD;
where WAS was clearly superior to all other breeds. Compared to WAS, SN meat&#xD;
was less colored (L*-value; p&lt;0.001) which is probably related to the higher pH24h&#xD;
(p&lt;0.01) of SN when compared to WAS. Overall, this study showed that meat quality&#xD;
of WAS is superior with low-land pasture based fattening conditions in Switzerland. It&#xD;
is however possible that other fattening conditions (i.e. mountainous) would lead to&#xD;
different results because Black nose, Engadine and Mirror sheep are traditional alpine&#xD;
breeds which might substantially alter their production optimum.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14393/1/Probst_14393.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Probst, Johanna; Leiber, Florian and Heckendorn, Felix    (2009) Lammfleischqualität von extensiv gehaltenen und seltenen Schweizer Schafrassen (Engadinerschaf, Schwarznasenschaf, Spiegelschaf) im Vergleich zum Weißen Alpenschaf.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14393/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>