<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Experience with new fireblight resistant rootstocks in South Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ruess, Franz</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fireblight (Erwinia amylovora) was detected on rootstocks in several apple orchards in Baden-Württemberg.&#xD;
In Germany the mostly used rootstocks on apple ‘M9’ and ‘M26’ are known to be susceptible to fire blight.&#xD;
Therefore the LVWO Weinsberg participated in the “European Cornell-Geneva rootstocks trial” which is a&#xD;
common experiment of seven research institutes over whole Europe. Six fire blight resistant or tolerant rootstocks&#xD;
from the Geneva® breeding program were tested in comparison to ‘M9’ (Type T337 and Pajam 2).&#xD;
The variety was ‘Golden Delicious’ and the trees were planted in 2001 . An outstanding new rootstock was&#xD;
‘Geneva® 11’. The tree size was similar to ‘M9’ (above 7% more growth in comparison to ‘T337’). Besides&#xD;
that the influence on the fruit size is positive (bigger fruits) and the relationship yield to growth (kg/cm2 trunk&#xD;
diameter) better than on ‘M9’. A further interesting new rootstock is Geneva® 41 which is in tree size similar&#xD;
to ‘M26’. It’s efficiency was as good as ‘M9’ and the fruit size was better. The Geneva® rootstocks seem to&#xD;
be better adapted to the hot climate and dry soil conditions of the Neckar region than ‘M9’. Alternate bearing&#xD;
could not be seen until today, but might be a problem in 2006 because of heavy bearing in 2005. Further&#xD;
experiments concerning the influence of those rootstocks on the colouring of fruits will follow.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13855/1/ecofruit_12th_28.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ruess, Franz    (2006) Experience with new fireblight resistant rootstocks in South Germany.  [Erfahrungen mit neuen feuerbrandresistenten Unterlagen in Süddeutschland.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 161-164.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13855/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>