<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Resistenzinduktion bei Tomaten gegen Phytophthora infestans&#xD;
durch Biodüngemittel und Pflanzenstärkungsmittel</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, MSc Kalpana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulte-Geldermann, Dr. Elmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Dr. Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Prof. Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Three biofertilizers (BF) and three plant strengtheners (PS) were tested in comparison&#xD;
to chemical fertilizer application and BABA (DL-3-amino-n-butanoic acid), respectively&#xD;
for their effects on the reactions of six different tomato varieties against three isolates&#xD;
of Phytophthora infestans in detached leaf disk assays. All experiments were repeated&#xD;
twice with six replicates each. Two of the BF (BioIlsa and Biofeed Quality) significantly&#xD;
reduced late blight severity as compared to horn meal and chemical fertilizer with no&#xD;
fertilizer by isolate and fertilizer by variety interactions. All PS significantly reduced&#xD;
susceptibility of all tomato varieties. However, the interactions among PS, variety and&#xD;
isolates were highly significant suggesting that different resistance mechanisms might&#xD;
be affected by the PS and BABA. Preliminary results indicate that the combined&#xD;
effects of PS and BF are additive without interactions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14360/1/Sharma_14360.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sharma, MSc Kalpana; Schulte-Geldermann, Dr. Elmar; Bruns, Dr. Christian and Finckh, Prof. Maria R.    (2009) Resistenzinduktion bei Tomaten gegen Phytophthora infestans durch Biodüngemittel und Pflanzenstärkungsmittel.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14360/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>