<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Long-term experiments as a platform for monitoring bread wheat quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, Ingrid K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Both winter wheat and spring wheat have the potential for producing grain of bread wheat quality under North European conditions. The two crops may due to their different growth length respond differently to previous use of green manure and to the soil organic matter content. To compare winter wheat and spring wheat for their ability to produce quality grain for bread production, both crops are included in a long-term experiment (LTE) at Askov Experimental Station. The LTE provides a unique platform for such comparison, as the two crops can be grown under identical conditions regarding previous management, soil and climate. The bread wheat experiment is part of the project AGronomical and TEChnological methods to improve ORGanic wheat quality (AGTEC-Org) funded by CORE Organic.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Faculty of Agricultural Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Christensen, Bent T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Petersen, Jens</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schacht, Margit</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-06-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16391/1/16391_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16391/2/16391_Paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thomsen, Ingrid K.    (2008) Long-term experiments as a platform for monitoring bread wheat quality.   In: Christensen, Bent T.; Petersen, Jens and Schacht, Margit (Eds.)  Long-term field experiments - a unique research platform, Faculty of Agricultural Sciences, pp. 84-85.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16391/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>