<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Futterwahlversuche mit Nagern zur Überprüfung der Qualität von Produkten aus biologischem und konventionellem Anbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Velimirov, Alberta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a substantial amount of evidence to support the concept, that animals are&#xD;
capable of choosing a balanced diet. This capability is used in food preference tests&#xD;
with laboratory animals. So far it has been postulated, that for animals to be able to&#xD;
choose, at least one of the offered foods has to be nutritionally unbalanced, otherwise&#xD;
there would be no benefit in choosing (Forbes and Kyriazaks 1995). But in organic&#xD;
quality research food preference tests with laboratory rats have shown, that even in&#xD;
cases of comparable nutritional value significant preferences took place, when the test&#xD;
products originated from different growing systems. Examples are comparative studies&#xD;
with wheat, carrots, beet root, celeriac and apples of organic vs conventional origin.&#xD;
The aim of these animal feeding studies is to define product properties beyond&#xD;
chemical composition, due to potential interactions within and between biological&#xD;
systems. In a current project (http://qaccp.coreportal.org/) effects on the quality of&#xD;
carrots within the whole food chain are investigated. Preliminary results of food preference&#xD;
tests with laboratory rats and mice are mentioned.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14437/1/Velimirov_14437.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Velimirov, Alberta    (2009) Futterwahlversuche mit Nagern zur Überprüfung der Qualität von Produkten aus biologischem und konventionellem Anbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, ETH Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14437/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>