<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrating willow-based bioenergy and organic dairy production – the role of tree fodder for feed supplementation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Jo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leach, Katharine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rinne, Marketta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuoppala, Kaisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Silvopastoral systems that combine livestock and trees offer two main advantages for the animals. First, trees modify microclimatic conditions which can have beneficial effects on pasture growth and animal welfare. Second, trees also provide alternative feed resources during periods of low forage availability. This paper reports on research carried out within the Sustainable Organic and Low Input Dairying (SOLID) project to investigate the multifunctional potential of a novel integrated willow-based bio-energy/organic dairy production system in the UK, especially the role of tree fodder for feed supplementation in organic dairy systems. The nutritional value of two ages (1st and 2nd year re-growth) of short rotation coppiced willow was assessed in two seasons (late spring and late summer) in 2011.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, D</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-09-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21758/1/Smith_2OAHC%20proceedings_2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Smith, Jo; Leach, Katharine; Rinne, Marketta and Kuoppala, Kaisa    (2012) Integrating willow-based bioenergy and organic dairy production – the role of tree fodder for feed supplementation.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, D (Eds.)  Agriculture and Forestry Research (362), pp. 394-397.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21758/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>