<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Artenreiches Rauhfutter als Alleinfutter und Fettsäurenmuster der Milch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leiber, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzer, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scheeder, Martin R.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wettstein, Hans-Ruedi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In two experiments it was investigated which factors to what extent determine the fatty acid composition milk when cows are grazing high alpine pastures. The influences of altitude per se, of alpine forage quality, of concentrate-free diet type and of the overall grazing effect were separated by the experimental design. The most important factor which significantly elevated the concentrations of CLA, α-linolenic acid (ALA) and n-3 PUFA in milk fat was found to be the alpine diet type, i.e. the feeding of roughage-only (as well hay as pasture of as well lowland as alpine origin) with omission of concentrates and maize. Additionally a clear positive effect of the forage quality of alpine pastures on ALA concentration in milk fat was found. The latter effect is assumed to be linked to specific plant ingredients (eg. tannins) and to the low energy density of the alpine flora, which may influence the ruminal biohydrogenation of native ALA. An effect of altitude per se (hypoxia) was not found.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3659/1/3659.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leiber, Florian; Kreuzer, Michael; Scheeder, Martin R.L. and Wettstein, Hans-Ruedi    (2005) Artenreiches Rauhfutter als Alleinfutter und Fettsäurenmuster der Milch.  [Milk fatty acid profile of cows fed biodiverse forages only.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3659/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>