<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How can private standard accelerate the development of organic production?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gauffin, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hällbom, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sjödahl Svensson, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It is possible to use private standards to increase the speed in development of organic production in a wide range of areas and to do that on a solid scientific basis. KRAV has recently improved the standard performance in reducing climate impact of the production and the methodology from this work will be possible to use in several areas such as reduction of environmental impact, animal welfare and reduction of health risk for consumers&#xD;
It is obvious, though, that we need to get more knowledge on how consumers value our extra requirements in the standard and their willingness to pay for these since this is of crucial importance to motivate the producers to accept more stringent standards.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24567/1/24567.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gauffin, E.; Hällbom, L. and Sjödahl Svensson, K.    (2013) How can private standard accelerate the development of organic production?   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 85-86.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24567/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>