<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integration of organic outdoor pig production within crop rotation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Quintern, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within an interdisciplinary approach 24 groups of 20 pigs each were fattened outdoors to examine and calculate the nutrient inputs and their distribution in soils in relation to several management strategies. Management strategies varied in diets, field crops to pigs, static or mobile installation units like huts, troughs, and sun shelters. Stocking rates were adapted to the regulations of the Bioland organic farming associations, which limit the nutrient input to a maximum nitrogen load of 112 kg ha -1 a-1 or 10 fattening pigs ha-1 a-1, respectively. The results were discussed with regard to the nutrient accumulation in soils and leaching of nitrate into groundwater. Recommendations in relation to management strategies and integration of outdoor pig fattening within crop rotation of an organic farming system were formulated. Nutrient accumulation and leaching can be kept to a well tolerated level by adapting nutrient inputs and optimising their distribution. Therefore, the amount of concentrate has to be limited. Fodder loss should be avoided and available field fodder has to be considered as a ratio of concentrate. The main conclusion of this approach: The results indicate that it is possible to integrate pig production within crop rotation without the risk of high nutrient losses by moving huts and troughs at short intervals and rationed paddocks at weekly intervals, which markedly homogenised the distribution of nutrients.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4446/4/Quintern_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Quintern, Michael    (2005) Integration of organic outdoor pig production within crop rotation.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4446/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>