<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of an agroforestry system for chicken production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Philipps, Lois</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Engel, Cindy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Because conventional production of chickens has gone further than any other animal production system towards complete control of the animal’s brief lives, development of effective silvo-poultry systems seems particularly necessary for these essentially woodland birds. The objective is to develop a production system that closely matches the physiological and behavioural needs of the animals being reared. For the example of chickens, this means trying to mimic a woodland/forest-clearing environment. By providing a wide range of trees, shrubs and herbs, it should be possible to provide shelter, nutrition and medicinal benefits for the birds. At the same time, the system needs to fulfil other functions in terms of biodiversity and community assets for the farm, together with profitable organic chicken production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8417/1/philipps_Agroforestry_chicken_production.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Philipps, Lois; Engel, Cindy and Wolfe, Martin    (2002) Development of an agroforestry system for chicken production.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 257-258.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8417/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>