<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Verschiedene Gründüngerpflanzen – Anbaueignung und&#xD;
Unkrautunterdrückung im Direktsaatsystem vor Winterweizen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stadler, Marina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zihlmann, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scherrer, Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jossi, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Streit, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a small-plot field trial 33 green manure plants (GM) were examined for their ability&#xD;
to suppress weeds in a no-tillage system. A roll-chopper was used to suppress the&#xD;
GMs before seeding winter wheat. The success of this organic method to control GMs&#xD;
was compared to the standard method using a non selective herbicide. Species of the&#xD;
group brassicaceae, monocotyles and plant mixtures covered the soil faster, produced&#xD;
more biomass and suppressed weeds more efficiently than species of the group&#xD;
legumes and dicotyles. In spring, weed infestation in all roll-chopper treatments&#xD;
always exceeded economic threshold values whereas in the herbicide treatment weed&#xD;
infestations remained below these values. Additionally, wheat yield and density was&#xD;
reduced in the roll-chopper treatment compared to the herbicide treatment. Application&#xD;
of the roll-chopper together with a suitable GM for Swiss growing conditions will have&#xD;
to be improved before its introduction for no tillage agriculture in organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14397/1/Stadler_14397.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stadler, Marina; Zihlmann, Urs; Scherrer, Caroline; Jossi, Werner and Streit, Bernhard    (2009) Verschiedene Gründüngerpflanzen – Anbaueignung und Unkrautunterdrückung im Direktsaatsystem vor Winterweizen.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14397/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>