<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Distribution chain effects on quality parameters of organically grown tomatoes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Raffo, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baiamonte, I</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nardo, N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nicoli, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paoletti, F</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to evaluate the effects of short, compared to medium or long distribution chains, on some quality parameters of organically grown fresh tomatoes, a post-harvest experiment was carried out by reproducing in the lab the most common temperature, relative humidity conditions and storage-transport times occurring in the real distribution chain of organic horticultural fresh products.&#xD;
Organically grown tomatoes of the cv. Nerina harvested at three different ripening stages (mature green, turning, red) were subjected to conditions corresponding to a short (1 day at room temperature), a medium (cold storage for 2 days, followed by ripening at room temperature) and a long distribution chain (cold storage for 6 or 9 days, followed by ripening at room temperature). In addition fruits harvested at the three different ripening stage were also subjected to optimal storage condition (8°C, turning and red tomatoes; 13°C green tomatoes, all at 95% R.H.) for 16 days.&#xD;
At the end of the post-harvest experiment fruits were analyzed for volatile aroma compounds, organic acids, ascorbic acid, soluble sugars, texture, phenolic compounds.&#xD;
Conditions of medium and long distribution chain (harvest at the green stage and cold storage-transport) did not have a significant detrimental effect when compared to short chain on the formation of some key tomato odorants, such as the lipid-derived aroma compounds (among which (3Z)-3-hexenal, hexanal) and the carotenoid-derived volatiles (among which damascenone, b-ionone). &#xD;
On the other hand, conditions of medium and long chain greatly inhibited the formation of other aroma compounds (such as 1-nitro-2-phenylethane and 2-isobutylthiazole, related to the amino acid metabolism), which showed markedly higher levels in vine ripened fruits (or at the end of the short chain experiment). &#xD;
Another significant effect was observed on firmness: fruits subjected to medium or long chain tended to show a reduced firmness when compared to vine ripened tomatoes, at harvest or at the end of the short chain.&#xD;
On the contrary biosynthesis of ascorbic acid was scarcely affected by the distribution chain conditions: green harvested tomatoes, subjected to cold storage and ripened at room temperature afterwards, were able to accumulate an amount of ascorbic acid similar to that observed in vine ripened fruits. &#xD;
&#xD;
Acknowledgement: The present study was performed within the project BIOVITA (W.P.3.1- Supply chain of horticultural products) funded by the Italian Ministry of Agriculture, Food and Forestry Policy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICT Prague Press</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Pulkrabova, Jana</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tomaniova, Monika</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kahl, Johannes</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hajšlová, Jana</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18979/1/abstract_Raffo.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Raffo, A; Baiamonte, I; Nardo, N; Nicoli, S and Paoletti, F    (2011) Distribution chain effects on quality parameters of organically grown tomatoes.   In: Pulkrabova, Jana; Tomaniova, Monika; Kahl, Johannes and Hajšlová, Jana (Eds.)  Book of Abstracts. First International Conference on Organic Food Quality and Health Research, ICT Prague Press, Prague, Czech Republic, p. 89.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18979/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>