<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmers' approaches to organic farming; motivations, barriers and different strategies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vartdal, Barbro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conversion to organic agriculture as a process of social adaptation was qualitatively analysed by the sociologists Barbro Vartdal and Arild Blekesaune during 1990-92. Altogether, 33 farmers were analysed, giving the sociologists interviews, written diaries or reports as material. The farmers participated in the "30 farm-project", conducted by the Norwegian Centre for Ecological Agriculture. The sociologists described three categories of eco-farmers, according to whether the farmer was cosmopolitically or locally orientated: The antroposopher,the ecosopher and the reformist. Their motivations of farming, conversion and mastering strategies as well as social barriers for conversion were described. It is argued that conversion is a social process as well as a process of agronomy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists (NJF)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Granstedt, Artur</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Koistinen, Riitta</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1994-03-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19309/1/Vartdal_and_L%C3%B8es_Mikkeli_NJF_1994.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vartdal, Barbro and Løes, Anne-Kristin    (1994) Farmers' approaches to organic farming; motivations, barriers and different strategies.   In: Granstedt, Artur and Koistinen, Riitta (Eds.)  Converting to organic agriculture. NJF-report 93, Appendix. Proceedings of NJF seminar 237, Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists (NJF), St Michel, Finland, NJF report, no. 93, pp. 48-61.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19309/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>