<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies for a diversified organic pork production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kongsted, A.G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claudi-Magnussen, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, B.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Possible reasons for the low market share of organic pork may be heavy price competition with conventional produced pork products combined with no or small distinctive characteristics in appearance and quality, both regarding eating quality (flavour, tenderness) and ethical quality (production methods). The overall aim of this study is to identify strategies for a diversified organic pork production with high credibility and superior eating quality based on pigs foraging in the cropping system, use of a traditional breed and no castration. Preliminary results indicate that the use of a traditional breed, the Danish Black-Spotted pig, might be a way to produce pork, which in appearance differ from conventional pork and at the same time improve the credibility of organic pig production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Proceedings of the Second Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), held at the 16th IFOAM Organic World Congres - in Cooperation with the Internationl Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Halberg, N.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Thommen, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hermansen, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Waarst, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lueck, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Caporali, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jensen, H.H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14772/1/14772.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14772/2/14772a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kongsted, A.G.; Claudi-Magnussen, C.; Hermansen, J.E. and Andersen, B.H.    (2008) Strategies for a diversified organic pork production.    In: Neuhoff, D.; Halberg, N.; Alföldi, T.; Lockeretz, W.; Thommen, A.; Rasmussen, I.; Hermansen, J.; Waarst, M.; Lueck, L.; Caporali, F.; Jensen, H.H.; Migliorini,  and Willer, H. (Eds.)   Cultivating the future based on science.  Proceedings of the Second Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), held at the 16th IFOAM Organic World Congres - in Cooperation with the Internationl Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), pp. 190-193.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14772/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>