<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung des Unkrautaufkommens bei unterschiedlicher&#xD;
Stoppelbearbeitung im Ausschnitt einer ökologischen&#xD;
Fruchtfolge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gruber, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A long-term experiment at the Experimental Station for Organic Farming&#xD;
Kleinhohenheim should determine effects of stubble tillage on weed density and weed&#xD;
communities. The treatments were stubble tillage by a chisel plough (10 cm), a&#xD;
modified skimmer plough (7 cm), a rotary hoe (5 cm) and a control, previous to&#xD;
primary tillage by a mouldboard plough in autumn. The results presented here refer to&#xD;
the weed density of dicotyledonous-annual plants, monocotyledonous plants and&#xD;
lucerne volunteers in the years 8 and 9 of the experiment, i.e. the first two years after&#xD;
perennial lucerne grass. There were no significant differences found between the&#xD;
treatments for weeds, volunteers and crop yield of winter wheat and oats. These&#xD;
results confirm and continue the observations of the years 1999-2003 in the long run.&#xD;
Stubble tillage had no visible effect on the density of annual weeds in a diverse, 8-year&#xD;
organic crop rotation with focus on cereals if a plough was used for primary tillage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14026/1/Gruber_14026.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gruber, Sabine and Claupein, Wilhelm    (2009) Entwicklung des Unkrautaufkommens bei unterschiedlicher Stoppelbearbeitung im Ausschnitt einer ökologischen Fruchtfolge.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14026/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>