<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Book Review: Rudolf Steiner - Alchemy of the Everyday</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>'Rudolf Steiner - Alchemy of the Everyday' presents an overview of Steiner’s life work. Steiner was a pioneer of New Age thinking. He had a prodigious appetite for work, and his output was prolific as well as diverse. He presented over 5105 lectures and he authored 354 books. Alchemy encapsulates Steiner’s oeuvre including architecture, furniture, art, painting, sculpture, dance, jewellery, typography, medicine, education, and agriculture. As the Foreword states: “Rudolf Steiner was one of the most influential - yet most controversial - reformers of the 20th century”. In the year before his untimely death, Steiner laid the foundations of biodynamic agriculture. 'Alchemy' is a timely retrospective coinciding with the one hundred and fiftieth anniversary of Steiner’s birth. The book accompanies a travelling exhibition, of the same name, curated by Germany’s Vitra Design Museum.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21865/7/21865.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2012) Book Review: Rudolf Steiner - Alchemy of the Everyday.   Journal of Organic Systems, 7 (2), pp. 61-63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21865/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>