<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The diversity of livestock systems and definition of animal welfare (2nd NAHWOA Workshop)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>content: &#xD;
Part A: Livestock in organic farming: role and research methodologies&#xD;
Part B: The diversity of organic livestock systems – Austria and Spain&#xD;
Part C: Organic livestock production standards&#xD;
Part D: Organic livestock production and animal welfare&#xD;
&#xD;
The theme of the 2nd NAHWOA Workshop was "Diversity of livestock systems and definition of animal welfare". The diversity of livestock systems within the European Conmmunity area has become particularly clear during the development of the common organic livestock production standards, in the form of EU Regulation 1804/ 1999. The Workshop heard several interesting papers on the subject, including an account of first-hand, field visit experience of the DEHESA farming system and of an olive farm with mixed livestock systems to utilise the by-products. In addition to a lively discussion during a session in the Workshop, the NAHWOA Working Group on organic standard development had a meeting to discuss the issue. These Proceedings include a combined report of all these discussions. This report is also submitted to the European Commission as an official NAHWOA statement on the present state of development of EU Regulation 1804/1999.&#xD;
&#xD;
precise content:&#xD;
Part A: Livestock in organic farming: role and research methodologies&#xD;
&#xD;
W. Lockeretz &amp; E. Boehncke: Agricultural systems research&#xD;
D. Younie:Integration of livestock into organic farming systems&#xD;
M. Vaarst: Methodology in animal health and livestock research in organic livestock production&#xD;
&#xD;
Part B: The diversity of organic livestock systems – Austria and Spain&#xD;
&#xD;
M. Eder, L. Kirne, and W. Zollitsch:Animal husbandry in alpine organic farming – regional diversity and critical obstacles in Austria&#xD;
J. M. Ameztoy: Organic animal husbandry conversion in Navarra, Spain&#xD;
R. García Trujillo: Organic livestock production in Spain&#xD;
R. García Trujillo and C.Mata: The Dehesa: an extensive livestock system in the Iberian Peninsula&#xD;
&#xD;
Part C: Organic livestock production standards&#xD;
&#xD;
O. Schmid:Comparison of European Organic Livestock Standards with national and international standards - problems of common standards development and future areas of interest&#xD;
O. Schmid: Appendix IV: Comparison of Organic Livestock Production Standards between the new EU Regulation Nr. 1804/1999, IFOAM Basic Standards of November 1998 and the new draft guidelines of Codex Alimentarius ALINORM 99/22A&#xD;
R. Keatinge, D. Gray, S. Milan Thamsborg, A. Martini, P. Plate: EU Regulation 1804/1999 - the implications of limiting allopathic treatment&#xD;
S. Padel and R. Keatinge: Discussion report: Discussion of the EU livestock regulation (1804/99) at the 2nd NAHWOA workshop in Cordoba, Spain 9-11/ 01/2000&#xD;
&#xD;
Part D: Organic livestock production and animal welfare&#xD;
&#xD;
H. Verhoog: Defining positive welfare and animal integrity&#xD;
G. van Putten: An ethological definition of animal welfare with special emphasis on pig behaviour&#xD;
H. Bartussek: How to measure animal welfare? The idea of an "Animal Needs Index" ANI-35L [Tiergerechtheitsindex TGI 35L]: a practical tool for assessing farm animal housing conditions on farm level in respect to animals´ well being and behavioural needs - Austrian experiences&#xD;
Torben Bennedsgaard and Stig Milan Thamsborg: Comparison of welfare assessment in organic dairy herds by the TGI200-protocol and a factor model based on clinical examinations and production parameters&#xD;
Vonne Lund: Is there a such a thing as "organic" animal welfare?&#xD;
S. M. Thamsborg, M. Hovi and T. Baars: Discussion report: What to do about animal welfare in organic farming? A report on the Animal Welfare Discussion at the 2nd NAHWOA Workshop</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Trujillo, R. Garcia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/874/1/hovi-2001-2ndNAHWOA-proceedings.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hovi, Malla and Trujillo, R. Garcia (Eds.)    (2000) The diversity of livestock systems and definition of animal welfare (2nd NAHWOA Workshop).    . Proceedings of NAHWOA - Network for Animal Health and Welfare in Organic Agriculture, Córdoba, Spain, 8-11 January, 2000.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/874/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>