<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pflanzenverträglichkeit von verschiedenen Schwefelpräparaten auf Braeburn bei Behandlungen mit dem Sprüher oder mit der Oberkronenberegnung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The apple variety Braeburn is very popular among the organic apple growers in South Tyrol. Braeburn brings high and regular yields and good prices at the north European fruit and vegetable market. Braeburn is quite susceptible to scab and mildew. To regulate this latter disease the organic orchardists use mainly sulphur products. Braeburn however is sensitive to sulphur treatments. Mainly during summer at high tem-peratures the leaves of Braeburn treated with sulphur develop a yellowish colour and necrotic spots. A field-trial was carried out for 2 years to investigate which sulphur formulations and application techniques give less phytotoxic problems to leaves and fruits of the apple variety Braeburn. The results show only small dif-ferences between the sulphur formulations and mixtures. The overhead irrigation system shows significantly less damaged leaves but there were no significant differences in the percentage of sunburned fruits.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9026/1/ecofruit_12th_40.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Casera, Claudio and Lardschneider, Ewald    (2006) Pflanzenverträglichkeit von verschiedenen Schwefelpräparaten auf Braeburn bei Behandlungen mit dem Sprüher oder mit der Oberkronenberegnung.  [Phytotoxicity of different sulphur products applied with the sprayer or with the overheat irrigation system on Braeburn apples.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 228-233.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9026/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>