<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Agriculture in the Czech Republic (Country Report 2011)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urban, Jiri</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Czech organic farming is continuously growing and has reached almost 12 % of the farmland acreage in the Czech Republic. The main driving force in the development of the organic farming in the Czech Republic are subsidies; which led to the fact that there is mainly grassland in the organic system (82,5 %). Concerning the organic plant production there is a significant increase in the organic viticulture (965 ha), the most important crops are cereals followed by fodder crops. The organic land burden in livestock units is very low (with beef cattle being the most numerous). The share of organic products on the Czech food market is still small (less than 1 %) compared to the developed EU countries and about a half of the sold goods was produced abroad. Organic food is sold mostly in retail chains, nowadays “farmer markets” and “box delivery systems” have become very popular. The Czech Ministry of Agriculture is since 2000 the key-player in the area of organic farming, it is responsible for regulation and supervision of the certifying control bodies and also for official controls in the organic sector (some of this activities are delegated to other bodies). Since 2004, the Czech Republic adopts Action Plans for the Development of Organic Farming (currently for the period of 2011-2015), a strategic document, which is approved by the government. The Czech Republic supports its organic farmers not only in the form of subsidies per ha but also for example in the form of promotion campaigns on organic food.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bayerische Landesanstalt für Landwirtschaft</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Wiesinger, Klaus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Cais, Kathrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-03-29</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20991/1/Urban_2012_Organic_Agriculture_in_the_Czech_Republic.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urban, Jiri    (2012) Organic Agriculture in the Czech Republic (Country Report 2011).   In: Wiesinger, Klaus and Cais, Kathrin (Eds.)  Angewandte Forschung und Beratung für den ökologischen Landbau in Bayern, Bayerische Landesanstalt für Landwirtschaft, Freising, Schriftenreihe der Bayerischen Landesanstalt für Landwirtschaft, no. 4/2012, pp. 169-178.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20991/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>