<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic cropping systems for higher and more stable cereal yields</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>"Organic cropping systems for higher and more stable cereal yields" is a 5- year Strategic Institute Programme from Research Council of Norway,  “Bioproduksjon og  foredling” led by Bioforsk Arable Crops Division in cooperation with The Norwegian University of Life Sciences (UMB), Bioforsk Organic Food and Farming Division, Bioforsk Plant Health and Protection Division, Bioforsk Grassland and Landscape Division and Hedmark University College. In addition scientists from Denmark, Finland, The Netherlands and China are involved. Of vital importance for future policy on the structure and development of organic farming in Norway is how and to what extent we can improve the level and stability of cereal yields in organic cash cropping systems with limited access to organic nutrient sources, without compromising the major goal of sustainability in organic farming. In this programme we will seek solutions to this task through a comprehensive agroecological analysis combined with component-oriented studies of the main bottlenecks in organic cereal production:1) poor soil structure; 2) insufficient nitrogen supply; 3) perennial weeds.&#xD;
The education of a PhD candidate in agroecology is included in the programme. International cooperation and broadening of the level of competency in this field of research will be focussed upon.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7052/1/RevSoknadjanuar2003.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    ØKOKORNSIP: Organic cropping systems for higher and more stable cereal yields.  [Økologiske dyrkingssystem for høgare og meir stabile kornavlingar.]   Runs 2003 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Eltun, Ragnar, Bioforsk Norwegian Institute of Agronomical and Environmental Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7052/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>