<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alternativen zur betäubungslosen Ferkelkastration: Verbraucherakzeptanz</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heid, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming there is an ongoing discussion on piglet castration without anaesthesia and possible alternatives to this practice due to animal welfare concerns. Consumer acceptance of alternatives to piglet castration without anaesthesia plays an important role in this discussion. This contribution examines organic consumers’ attitudes towards piglet castration without anaesthesia and the alternatives castration with anaesthesia and analgesia, immunocastration and fattening of entire males. Additionally, consumers’ willingness-to-pay for the alternatives is determined. The results show that animal welfare, food safety and health concerns influence consumers’ attitudes towards the alternatives. However, the individual perception of those aspects is quite varying. Thus, consumers’ opinions towards the alternatives are also different. Consumers’ perception of the alternatives is reflected in their willingness-to-pay. When implementing alternatives to piglet castration without anaesthesia the organic farming sector should address consumers’ concerns in an appropriate way in order to avoid misinformation and insecurity among consumers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17452/3/Heid_17452.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heid, Astrid and Hamm, Ulrich    (2011) Alternativen zur betäubungslosen Ferkelkastration: Verbraucherakzeptanz.  [Alternatives to piglet castration without anaesthesia: consumer acceptance.]      Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17452/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>