<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of new socio-political forces on land use, and on farm and landscape biodiversity in Bosnia and Herzegovina (study areas: Banja Luka and Derventa)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>DIMITRIJE, Markovic</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Socio-political forces during and after the war are main external factor affecting land use changes at farm and regional scales that are among the most important drivers of species diversity. The aim of this study is to analyze these changes and their impact on biodiversity in two municipalities in Bosnia and Herzegovina, one (Banja Luka) not directly, and other one (Derventa) directly affected by the war. To develop these analysis, statistical data referring to land use situation before and after the war were compared and on site investigation were performed. Interviews to farmer allowed us to investigate the farm organization and structure. Biodiversity at field level was assessed.Land-use changes occurred in both municipalities, mainly in Derventa, due to abandoned land. Present state of biodiversity was assessed indicating direct and indirect negative impact of war on biodiversity loss both at farm and municipality level</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7005/1/DimitrijeMarkovic05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>DIMITRIJE, Markovic   (2005) Influence of new socio-political forces on land use, and on farm and landscape biodiversity in Bosnia and Herzegovina (study areas: Banja Luka and Derventa).  [Influence des nouvelles forces socio-politiques sur l’utilisation des terres, l’exploitation et la biodiversité du paysage en Bosnie-et-Herzégovine (zones d’étude : Banja Luka and Derventa).]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 400. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7005/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>