<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pathogenicity in Verticillium on strawberry plants</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schubert, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Golldack, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwärzel, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lentzsch, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the most common strawberry cv. ’Elsanta’, Verticillium infection can lead to rapid wilt&#xD;
and even death of plants. It is known, that a dead plant can be located directly beside vital&#xD;
ones. In a survey of 8 fields in Brandenburg, Mecklenburg- Vorpommern, Sachsen-Anhalt&#xD;
and Sachsen, 432 genotypes of Verticillium dahliae Kleb. were isolated from wilted and&#xD;
even vital plants from 8 fields and classified by PCR-fingerprints. For strawberries, the&#xD;
genotypes can be classified as apathogenic, weakly and highly pathogenic according to&#xD;
the results of climate chamber experiments on strawberry transplants.&#xD;
At landscape scale, similarity analysis of the PCR fingerprints of 432 genotypes resulted in&#xD;
13 genetic subtypes. Several of these subtypes occurred at all fields, whereas 1 subtype&#xD;
was found in one location only. At field scale, 2 to 11 different subtypes per field were&#xD;
observed. Vital plants were colonised by up to 9 subtypes, wilted plants by up to 11&#xD;
subtypes. Population structure of Verticillium subtypes is different between vital and wilted&#xD;
plants, the same subtypes can occur in either plant group. In our plot experiments, wilt&#xD;
symptoms could be reduced by changing the Verticillium population structure in the plant.&#xD;
Inoculation of plants with a mixture of three Verticillium genotypes sustained plant vitality&#xD;
over a period of 15 months (WO 2007/051654).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13659/1/138-143.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schubert, P.; Golldack, J.; Schwärzel, H. and Lentzsch, P.    (2008) Pathogenicity in Verticillium on strawberry plants.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 138-143.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13659/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>