<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New approaches in biological control of apple scab</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Köhl, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Apple scab caused by Venturia inaequalis is a major disease in apple production. In&#xD;
organic farming scab control depends on the use of fungicides based on copper or&#xD;
sulphur. Since the use of copper will be restricted in the European Union and the use of&#xD;
sulphur often leads to insufficient control and phytotoxicity, alternative control measures&#xD;
are needed. The use of microbial antagonists may be an alternative to fungicides for scab&#xD;
control.&#xD;
Scab epidemics during summer are driven by conidia produced only on apple leaves. In&#xD;
this situation, antagonists present in the phyllosphere may interfere with conidia of the&#xD;
pathogen during sporulation or infection. Within the EU-funded project REPCO, more than&#xD;
hundred fungi were isolated from sporulating scab colonies and tested on apple seedlings&#xD;
for their potential to reduce sporulation of the pathogen. Since the aim of the study was to&#xD;
contribute to the development of a biocontrol product, only candidates were selected which&#xD;
fulfilled a range of additional criteria considering major constraints in development of&#xD;
biocontrol products. The best antagonists were applied under orchard conditions during&#xD;
two growing seasons. The antagonist H39 significantly reduced sporulation of V.&#xD;
inaequalis after most applications. However, in a few cases no effect was found.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13637/1/023-028.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Köhl, J.    (2008) New approaches in biological control of apple scab.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 23-28.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>