<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimizing crop loading of apples and pears - results 2004-2006 (foliar fertilizers, thinning)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pfeiffer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eis, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fieger-Metag, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Main topics of the research-project FuE 03OE088 of “Bundesprogramm Ökologischer&#xD;
Landbau” (30.04.2004-31.12.2006) were the testing of foliar fertilizers in organic apples&#xD;
and pears, optimizing lime sulphur for blossom thinning, looking for alternatives to lime&#xD;
sulphur for blossom thinning and looking at different combinations of thinning measures.&#xD;
Only the results of testing foliar fertilizers (carried out by KoGa Ahrweiler and OVB/ÖON&#xD;
Jork) and combinations of thinning measures (carried out by LVWO Weinsberg) are&#xD;
described in this article. Over three years only a small increase in yield was evaluated for&#xD;
the fertilizers Aminosol PS and Wuxal Ascofol (site Ahrweiler, apple variety ‘Elstar’). In&#xD;
Jork (apple variety ‘Holsteiner Cox’) yield could only be judged in 2005 and 2006. Wuxal&#xD;
Ascofol showed some advantage in comparison to the control. At pear variety ‘Conference’&#xD;
no clear tendencies could be seen, the control had the highest yield. In 2005 the fruitsetting&#xD;
of ‘Conference’ was very low because of bad conditions during blossom.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13741/1/324-329.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pfeiffer, B.; Eis, B.; Zimmer, J. and Fieger-Metag, N.    (2008) Optimizing crop loading of apples and pears - results 2004-2006 (foliar fertilizers, thinning).   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 324-329.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13741/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>