<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Risiken und Chancen der Stoffwechsel- und Eutergesundheit im Zeitraum der Trockenperiode und der Frühlaktation in ökologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krömker, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zinke, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paduch, Jan-Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bormann, Anke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abograra, Esmaiel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volling, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Drerup, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weiler, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weiß, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Becker, Mathias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spiekers, Hubert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mersch, Ferdinand</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schumacher, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Doris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a part of the study 'Health and performance of dairy cows in organic farming from an interdisciplinary point of view  13 an (intervention-) study on metabolic disorders and mastitis with regard to forage production, feeding management and husbandry practices' different udder health and metabolic variables were determined in 106 dairy farms in Germany between January 2008 and April 2010. The objective of this study was to evaluate udder health risks and metabolic risks in dry period and early lactation. Udder health and metabolic situation were similar to conventional dairy farms. Identified risks for metabolic health and udder health lay in the feeding area (homogenous feeding without a huge variation in body condition in lactation and dry period) and in the dry period therapy.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17619/3/Kr%C3%B6mker_17619.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krömker, Volker; Zinke, Claudia; Paduch, Jan-Hendrik; Bormann, Anke; Abograra, Esmaiel; March, Solveig; Brinkmann, Jan; Volling, Otto; Drerup, Christoph; Weiler, Martin; Weiß, Martin; Becker, Mathias; Spiekers, Hubert; Mersch, Ferdinand; Schumacher, Ulrich; Barth, Kerstin and Klocke, Doris    (2011) Risiken und Chancen der Stoffwechsel- und Eutergesundheit im Zeitraum der Trockenperiode und der Frühlaktation in ökologisch wirtschaftenden Milchviehbetrieben.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17619/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>