<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bestimmungsgründe für die Präferenz von Bio- und Low-Input-&#xD;
Lebensmitteln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Food quality has become an important topic in the food market. Thus, suppliers have&#xD;
started offering conventional products including additional quality attributes, such as&#xD;
“free from GMO” or “free from additives”. We analysed the preferences and buying&#xD;
behaviour regarding such conventional “low-input” products in competition with conventional&#xD;
and organic product alternatives in consumer choice experiments in Germany&#xD;
and Switzerland. In the experiments, we tested milk, yogurt and apples. The choice&#xD;
experiments were combined with face-to-face interviews in order to collect information&#xD;
about the participating consumers, which might explain the buying behaviour observed&#xD;
in the choice experiment. We found that low-input products rather compete with conventional&#xD;
than with organic products, because the low-input alternative was mainly&#xD;
chosen by consumers, who also in their everyday’s life buy the respective product in&#xD;
conventional quality. Furthermore, variances in the buying behaviour observed mainly&#xD;
depend on consumers’ attitudes of food quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14372/1/Stolz_14372.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stolz, Hanna and Stolze, Matthias    (2009) Bestimmungsgründe für die Präferenz von Bio- und Low-Input- Lebensmitteln.  [Determinants of preferences for organic and low-input food.]      Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, ETH Zürich, 11. - 13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14372/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>