<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleich von zwei Rinderrassen hinsichtlich ihrer Eignung zur&#xD;
Ökologischen Milchproduktion – Teilfrage: Tiergesundheit</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Dr. Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Franze, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to the rules of organic farming, prophylaxis shall be supported by selection&#xD;
of appropriate breeds. Nevertheless, today high yielding breeds predominate in organic&#xD;
dairy herds. Since 2004 the Institute of Organic Farming in Trenthorst compares&#xD;
two breeds under the same management conditions on its experimental farm. The&#xD;
evaluation of the data gained between March 2006 and March 2008 revealed a higher&#xD;
treatment rate in the milk orientated Holstein-Friesian cows compared to the German&#xD;
Red Pied, a local dual purpose breed. Although treatment of claw disorders were&#xD;
much more frequent in Holstein-Friesian cows, the lameness scoring carried out every&#xD;
fortnight did not show any difference between the two breeds (Chi2&#xD;
3=3.506, n. s.). In&#xD;
24 of 134 cases, cows needed support during calving but the frequency did not differ&#xD;
between the groups (Chi2&#xD;
2=0.125, n. s.). Due to the low cell frequency the reasons for&#xD;
culling could not be evaluated, yet. Even if a comparison of breeds has to take into&#xD;
account the genotype-environment-interactions, these first results show no clear&#xD;
advantage of an assumed robust breed under the conditions of our organic farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14009/1/Barth_14009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barth, Dr. Kerstin and Franze, Ulrike    (2009) Vergleich von zwei Rinderrassen hinsichtlich ihrer Eignung zur Ökologischen Milchproduktion – Teilfrage: Tiergesundheit.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14009/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>