<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Spaltenbodenreinigung in einem Rinderstall auf die Ammoniakemissionen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Retz, Stefanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Georg, Heiko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van den Weghe, Herman</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ammonia emissions from barns have a severe impact on the environment. Especially dairy cattle, kept in loose housing, contribute to the total emission of ammonia up to 50%. Soiled walking areas like slatted floors, are realised as one of the main sources of the emission. In this study, a special cleaning device was used in order to remove manure from a slatted floor in an organically run dairy barn. It was investigated how the combination of a rubber-scraper, mechanical star discharge rotors and high-pressure water nozzles affects the ammonia emission from the floor. Six concrete test elements (55cm x 62cm x 20cm) were cut out of the existing slatted floor in order to be able to separate them from other sources of ammonia emission in the barn. With a wet-chemistry method, the ammonia emitted from the slatted floor was analysed. Compared to untreated control slats, a reduction of the amount of manure weighted on the clean test elements up to 33.2% could be observed. However, no significant effect of the cleaning of the slats on the ammonia emission could be detected.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17381/3/Retz_17381.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Retz, Stefanie; Georg, Heiko and Van den Weghe, Herman    (2011) Einfluss der Spaltenbodenreinigung in einem Rinderstall auf die Ammoniakemissionen.       Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17381/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>