<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Systems in Organic Dairy Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oudshoorn, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Renes, Reint Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Boer, Imke</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to explore stakeholder perceptions of the&#xD;
contribution of an Automatic Milking System (AMS) to sustainable development of&#xD;
organic dairy production in Denmark and the Netherlands. In addition, reasons for&#xD;
the current difference in AMS use on organic dairy farms between both countries&#xD;
were explored. To answer above mentioned aims, farmers and advisors in both&#xD;
countries were interviewed using a focus group approach. Questions of the interviews&#xD;
were based on a literature review on sustainability issues affected by introduction of&#xD;
AMS. Participants expressed no moral problems regarding AMS use. They, however,&#xD;
pointed out uncertainty about the economic gain, difficulties with grazing,&#xD;
adaptation problems to technology, and image problems towards consumers. The&#xD;
latter results from a reduction in grazing time affecting both animal welfare and&#xD;
product quality. The participants did not recognize eutrophication, as result of high&#xD;
stocking density on farmstead lots, as a problem caused by AMS. The milk quality&#xD;
problem related to AMS use, although acknowledged as crucial towards consumers,&#xD;
was not prioritized very highly, especially not by the farmers in both countries. All&#xD;
groups were, however, unanimous in their perception of how important image was as&#xD;
far as the consumers are concerned. The perception analysis revealed that Dutch&#xD;
participants were more concerned about the economic payoff of AMS use, and&#xD;
showed more reluctance towards enlargement than Danish ones. In addition, they&#xD;
acknowledged the small-scale naturalness of organic production. These differences in&#xD;
perception could possibly explain observed differences in AMS use in organic dairy&#xD;
production between Denmark and the Netherlands.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Haynes, Richard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2666/1/2666.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oudshoorn, Frank; Renes, Reint Jan and de Boer, Imke   (2008) Systems in Organic Dairy Production.   Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Ethics, 2008 (21), pp. 205-228.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2666/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>