<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of colostrum type on serum gamma globulin concentration, growth and health of goat kids until three months</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Iepema, G.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Eekeren, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study the effect of three colostrum types; goat, cow and artificial colostrum, on serum gamma globulin concentration (GGC), growth and health of goat kids during the first three months of the rearing phase was measured. Thirty newborn goat kids were randomly assigned to three experimental groups; goat colostrum (GC), cow colostrum (CC) and artificial colostrum (AC). At 2, 28, 56 and 86 days serum GGC and live weight were measured. The three colostrum types were analysed on immunoglobulin G (IgG). Goat colostrum contained twice as much IgG as cow colostrum and artificial colostrum. At 2 and 28 days GC kids had a higher serum GGC than CC and AC kids. At 56 and 86 days no significant differences in serum GGC between the groups were found. No effect of colostrum type on daily weight gain was found.  Eight out of thirty goat kids under study suffered from health problems. Health problems and mortality were heavier among the AC kids. It can be concluded that for a successful passive transfer of immunity goat colostrum is necessary. When it is not possible to provide goat colostrum because of health reasons (disease transmission), cow colostrum is the best alternative. In that case good farm management is even more important.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11943/1/Iepema_11943_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Iepema, G.L. and van Eekeren, N.    (2008) Effect of colostrum type on serum gamma globulin concentration, growth and health of goat kids until three months.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11943/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>