<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Monitoring of total contents of copper in organically and&#xD;
conventionally managed soils. Part 1: Study plan and&#xD;
preliminary sampling of copper and other anthropogenic&#xD;
induced heavy metal contents in vineyard soils</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Riepert, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steindl, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eibach, Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maixner, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reichmuth, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strassemeyer, Jörn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strumpf, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project aims to develop a survey designed for the representative assessment of copper contents in vineyard soils. The method development for the sampling of adequate monitoring areas is based on a preliminary survey of load distribution as well as on exposure assessment on selected areas of some typical vinery sites in Rheinland-Pfalz, differently managed and with different use history. Additionally to the sampling of selected areas, which reflects the spectrum of the load situation in viticulture, chemical quantitative analysis of soil samples collected from areas of known mode of cultivation and history followed by biological standard tests will be conducted.&#xD;
Obtained findings will serve for further method development, for preselection of adequate monitoring areas and for first indications of hazard potential. The project is a prerequisite for the performance of the long-term study “Development of current data of effects of copper contents in organic soils in viticulture, pomiculture and hopculture on soil life in terms of the strategypaper concerning further copper application in agriculture, especially in organic farming.”</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Eugen Ulmer KG</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16806/1/belegexemplar_Cu_part1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Riepert, Frank; Steindl, Anna; Eibach, Rudolf; Maixner, Michael; Reichmuth, Christoph; Strassemeyer, Jörn and Strumpf, Thomas   (2010) Monitoring of total contents of copper in organically and conventionally managed soils. Part 1: Study plan and preliminary sampling of copper and other anthropogenic induced heavy metal contents in vineyard soils.  [Erhebung von Kupfergesamtgehalten in ökologisch und konventionell bewirtschafteten Böden. Teil 1: Erhebungsplan und Vorbeprobung von Kupfer und anderen anthropogen eingetragenen Schwermetallen in Weinbergsböden.]  Journal für Kulturpflanzen, 62 (2), pp. 42-50.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16806/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>