<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results from a three year testing project of new strawberry cultivars in Verticillium infested soils and under organic farming conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spornberger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weissinger, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steffek, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scheiblauer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jezik, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Altenburger, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stich, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As part of a research project 13 cultivars were planted in 2005 at 11 sites on 9 farms in 5&#xD;
different Austrian regions. The aim was to find new cultivars tolerant to soil-borne&#xD;
pathogens and leaf/fruit diseases, with high yield, winter hardness and good fruit quality, to&#xD;
serve as alternative to the highly susceptible cultivar ‘Elsanta’, regarding soil-borne&#xD;
diseases. Plant vigour and infestation with Verticillium dahliae and leaf diseases were&#xD;
evaluated in 2005 und 2006 at 7 sites and in 2007 at 3 sites.&#xD;
In addition, following parameters were assessed on 2 organically managed sites in 2006&#xD;
and 2007: marketable yield, percentage of different categories of unmarketable fruits and&#xD;
incidence of the blossom weevil. In 2006 fruit characteristics and consumer acceptance&#xD;
were studied.&#xD;
‘Elsanta’ showed the highest infestation with V. dahliae whereas ‘Salsa’, ‘Daroyal’ and&#xD;
‘Alice’ were most tolerant. ‘Dora’, ‘Eva’, ‘Queen Elisa’ and ‘Daroyal’ recorded significantly&#xD;
higher losses by the blossom weevil than ‘Alice’. ‘Alba’ and ‘Divine’ were the earliest&#xD;
cultivars in ripening time. Highest marketable yield per plant had the late ripening cultivars,&#xD;
particularly ‘Salsa’ and ‘Sonata’. Of all early ripening cultivars tested, ‘Elsanta’ showed the&#xD;
highest productivity, followed by 'Alba', ‘Darselect’, ‘Daroyal’ and ‘Eva’. Regarding fruit&#xD;
firmness, content of ascorbic acid, shelf life and appearance, ‘Alba’, ’Clery’, ‘Eva’ and&#xD;
‘Queen Elisa’ were most convincing. The best tasting cultivars were ‘Clery’, ‘Daroyal’ and&#xD;
‘Divine’.&#xD;
Summing up all the results, ‘Alba’, ‘Alice’ and ‘Salsa’ can be recommended for organic&#xD;
production, whereas ‘Clery’, ‘Daroyal’, ‘Darselect’, ‘Elsanta’, ‘Eva’, ‘Queen Elisa’ and&#xD;
‘Sonata’ are classified as suitable for only a limited extent. ‘Elsanta’, ‘Divine’, ‘Dora’ and&#xD;
‘Sonata’ are particularly unsuitable for growing in Verticillium infested soils. ‘Divine’, ‘Dora’,&#xD;
and ‘Record’ cannot be recommended for organic production at all.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13657/1/127-132.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spornberger, A.; Weissinger, H.; Steffek, R.; Scheiblauer, J.; Jezik, K.; Altenburger, J. and Stich, K.    (2008) Results from a three year testing project of new strawberry cultivars in Verticillium infested soils and under organic farming conditions.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 127-132.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13657/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>