<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of sampling and extraction on deoxynivalenol quantification</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hallier, Arnaud</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Celette, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>David, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Deoxynivalenol was extracted from wheat grain and quantified by GC-ECD. The quantification of deoxynivalenol can be critical, for example in certifying the amount of the mycotoxin in a lot and determining if this amount is over or under a fixed limit. Thus, an objective was to obtain representative samples to monitor DON quantification variability. We show that among the different steps of analysis the critical one is grain sampling. We also show that we were able to significantly improve the extraction rate without increasing the variability by using a longer extraction time with a magnetic agitator, and a grinding process which takes into account both the heterogeneous repartition of deoxynivalenol within wheat grains and different extraction rates according to the size of the flour powder particles. Thus, it could be of interest to use this methodology to determine if a lot is above or below a maximum limit because it enables the detection limit to be lowered, thereby simplifying the subsequent analysis.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18893/2/Hallier_et_al.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hallier, Arnaud; Celette, Florian and David, Christophe   (2011) Effects of sampling and extraction on deoxynivalenol quantification.   Food chemistry, 127, pp. 303-307.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18893/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>