<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erhalt ökologisch wertvoller Grünlandstandorte durch eine&#xD;
Integrierte Festbrennstoff- und Biogasproduktion aus Biomasse&#xD;
(IFBB-Verfahren)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richter, M.sc. Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuschnereit, M.sc. Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graß, Dr. Rüdiger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fricke, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wachendorf, Prof. Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a new utilisation concept for the conservation of ecologically valuable habitats the&#xD;
integrated generation of solid fuel and biogas from biomass (IFBB) was tested on five&#xD;
semi-natural grasslands from typical German mountain areas. Through hydrothermal&#xD;
conditioning and mechanical dehydration grassland silage was separated into a press&#xD;
cake and a press fluid. In anaerobic digestion experiments with press fluids methane&#xD;
yields of 304 to 522 normal litre per kg organic dry matter were obtained within 13&#xD;
days. The specific methane production was higher and went faster compared to the&#xD;
fermentation of the untreated grassland silage. Elemental analyses of the press cakes&#xD;
showed a significant reduction in compounds detrimental for combustion. The ash&#xD;
softening temperature and the lower heating value of the press cakes increased&#xD;
compared to the parent material. The conditioning at high temperatures (60°C and&#xD;
80°C) showed the best effects for a qualitative improvement of the press fluid as&#xD;
fermentation substrate and the press cake as solid fuel compared to the untreated&#xD;
grassland silage. The energy conversion efficiency of the IFBB procedure (52-62%)&#xD;
was higher compared to a conventional digestion of the whole crop silage (26%). In&#xD;
view of the results, the IFBB procedure is a promising utilisation alternative for areas&#xD;
managed under nature conservation standards, whose biomass is difficult to exploit.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14205/1/Richter_14205.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Richter, M.sc. Felix; Kuschnereit, M.sc. Sara; Graß, Dr. Rüdiger; Fricke, Dipl.-Ing. agr. Thomas and Wachendorf, Prof. Dr. Michael    (2009) Erhalt ökologisch wertvoller Grünlandstandorte durch eine Integrierte Festbrennstoff- und Biogasproduktion aus Biomasse (IFBB-Verfahren).       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14205/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>