<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving Compost Quality for Organic Vegetable production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>GALAL ELGHARABLY, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this research is to improve the quality of organic farm compost, in order to satisfy soil fertility status required for reasonable organic vegetable production. Field experimental trial has been conducted on ALHODA organic farm, Ismaillia Governorate, Egypt. This experiment was carried out during the summer of 2002 to study the effect of some plant and animal residues (crop residues, cow manure, chicken manure, bone meal and animal hoof) in addition to natural mineral sources (rock phosphate and orthoclase). All were piled, prepared in three different mixtures and composted for 6 months. Three treatments C1, C2 and C3 were composed of 40 % crop residues + 20 % chicken manure + 40 % cow manure (control), control + 500 kg rock phosphate + 300 kg orthoclase + 500 kg bone meal and control + 500 kg rock phosphate + 300 kg orthoclase + 200 kg animal hoof, respectively. Squash (c.v. Iskandrani) was used as a test crop in sandy soil to study the effect of these compost treatments on the plant yield and leaf nutrient concentrations as well as the nutrient contents of soil. During plant growth, effective microorganisms (EM culture) was sprayed on the plant leaf and soil as well, as a biofertilizer at a rate of 4 L / feddan separately to each treatment to enhance further composting in the soil. The experimental design of the field trial was completely randomized block design with 3 replicates, in order to facilitate the statistical analysis of the results. Data obtained revealed that treatment C3 (40 % crop residues + 20 % chicken manure + 40 % cow manure  + 500 kg rock phosphate + 300 kg orthoclase + 200 kg animal hoof) was the superior one. Also, EM proved significant results with all treatments; however, C3 + EM treatment recorded the highest squash yield among all treatments (8.12 tons/fed.). Bone meal and animal hoof significantly affected the NPK and micronutrient levels in compost, plant leaves and soil. Furthermore, they caused remarkable increases in both soil salinity and organic matter level in the soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6529/1/AhmedElgharably02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>GALAL ELGHARABLY, Ahmed   (2002) Improving Compost Quality for Organic Vegetable production.  [Amélioration de la qualité du compost pour la production biologique de cultures maraîchères.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Tesi Master of Science, no. 281. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6529/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>