<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Contaminants in manure - a problem for organic farming?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>McKinnon, Kirsty</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Serikstad, Grete Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eggen, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This work addresses possible ways in which animal manure might become contaminated by undesirable elements and how such manure might pose a risk to the health of soil organisms, animals, plants and humans. Research has shown that the pathways of organic compounds such as veterinary medicines and pesticides may be unpredictable and that undesirable elements can be transferred to the food chain. The basic principles of organic farming, in this case specially related to the principles of health, ecology and care, imply that special attentionshould be given to precaution and responsibility. These are key concerns in the management of organic farming. Taking these principles seriously, would mean a more restrictive practice on the use of animal manure from conventional farming. Through identifying which compounds might be present, their environmental properties and their residue levels in manure and environment, the authorities will be able to establish restricted practice based on knowledge.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24526/1/24526.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>McKinnon, Kirsty; Serikstad, Grete Lene and Eggen, T.    (2013) Contaminants in manure - a problem for organic farming?   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 51-52.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24526/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>