<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmer's Eye and Breeder's Eye - Fields of Knowledge Exchange as a Condition of a Participatory Breeding Approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Timmermann, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With the change to organic agriculture, the diversity of local conditions becomes more important. Local adapted varieties are necessary. But breeding&#xD;
for this demand is not profitable for a conventional breeding strategy. An alternative can be a participatory breeding approach (PPB). Evolved in the&#xD;
context of international development cooperation, this approach is increasingly discussed in the European context.&#xD;
Communication between farmers and breeders is a key issue in participatory breeding. Farmer`s and breeder`s eye have different perspectives on the&#xD;
plants and different knowledge gained through experience. Those perspectives and experiences need to be exchanged. As an outcome of the&#xD;
investigation of “The breeder`s eye” on the example of the crossbreeding of self-fertilizing cereals from a knowledge sociology perspective three&#xD;
levels of consciousness could be described: vegetational consciousness, generational consciousness and consciousness in hereditary flow&#xD;
(Timmermann, 2006). The framework of these three levels allows to understand the various levels of breeding behaviour and how the breeders learn&#xD;
and develop their breeding practices. Based on this results, fields of knowledge exchange between farmer and breeder, their limits and possibilities for&#xD;
further development can be worked out.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13108/1/FarmersBreedersEye.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Timmermann, Martin    (2007) Farmer's Eye and Breeder's Eye - Fields of Knowledge Exchange as a Condition of a Participatory Breeding Approach.       Poster at:   EUCARPIA Symposium, Wageningen (NL), 07.-09.11.2007.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13108/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>