<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Major problems of organic farming – experience transmission</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cudlinova, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sramek, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As a very particular agricultural system organic farming encounters many problems. Some of these problems are common to several countries where organic farming is applied. On that ground it might be useful to compare condition and levels of organic farming in more countries, find its common problems and thanks to experience transmission try to eliminate some of these problems preventively.&#xD;
Mutual comparison of organic farming in the Czech Republic with organic farming in Austria and actual conditions assessment provide to determine main problems of organic farming in both countries.&#xD;
Within the framework of analysis of organic farming several general problems of organic farming in both countries were defined, e. g. lower yields and higher costs per production unit or legislative restrictions. At the same time for the Czech republic were defined major problems related to agricultural and socioekonomic differences (e. g. dual characteristics of farm size, high share of imported bioproduction) and for Austria (high prices of bioproducts, lower rate of conversion to organic farming) and proposed suitable solutions based on experience of partnership country. If the number of partnership countries with differentially developed organic farming was broaden and there was defined common problems and aims for organic farming in general it might be a very important step for simplification and acceleration of its development.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21037/1/Moudry_-_organic_farming...2009_en-f_%282009_-_RumunskoI%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moudry, Jan (Jr.); Hartl, Wilfried; Cudlinova, Eva; Moudry, Jan; Konvalina, Petr and Sramek, Jan   (2009) Major problems of organic farming – experience transmission.   Lucrări Ştiinţifice, Seria Agronomie, 52 (2009), pp. 327-333.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21037/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>