<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Energetische Nutzung extensiver Grünlandflächen in Überschwemmungsgebieten von Fließgewässern im Rahmen des Verbundprojektes KLIMZUG Nordhessen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graß, Rüdiger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wachendorf, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to mitigate the negative impacts of increasing heavy rainfalls and flooding as an effect of climate change, the conservation and reintroduction of ecologically managed grassland in flood plains of rivers is a crucial step towards soil and water protection. However, an ecologically and economically viable utilisation of the biomass is necessary and could be provided by the conversion into electricity and solid fuel through the IFBB process. Within the joint interdisciplinary project KLIMZUG-Nordhessen, which develops structures and services to adapt to climate change, the yield and energy potential of three different grassland mixtures (a standard mixture, a diversity mixture and reed canary grass as monocrop) in floodplains was determined in a field experiment. In the first experimental year 2009 yields were highest in a standard mixture with 5 grass and 2 clover species (8.41 t DM ha-1 for the first cut on 01 July). Fertilizer application (100 kg N ha-1 as chicken manure) had no significant effect on yield increase. Methane yields of IFBB press fluids were highest in the standard mixture (331.5 LN kg-1 VS) and significantly lower in the two other mixtures. No significant differences were found between different fertilizer applications regarding methane yield.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17398/3/Richter_17398.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Richter, Felix; Graß, Rüdiger and Wachendorf, Michael    (2011) Energetische Nutzung extensiver Grünlandflächen in Überschwemmungsgebieten von Fließgewässern im Rahmen des Verbundprojektes KLIMZUG Nordhessen.  [Energy recovery from extensively managed grasslands in floodplains of rivers in the context of the joint research project KLIMZUG-Nordhessen.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17398/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>