<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The New Local: Linking Geographical Indications and Organics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Giovannucci, Daniele</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>What do Parmigiano cheese, Bordeaux, Idaho potatoes, Basmati rice, and Darjeeling tea have in common? As the concept of 'local' sourcing and marketing becomes more important, these Geographical Indications (GIs) or appellations are a potentially unique form of competitive advantage available even for small farmers and enterprises. A GI legally identifies and formally recognizes a good as originating in a delimited territory, or region where a noted quality, reputation or other characteristic of the good is essentially attributable to its geographical origin and/or the human or natural factors there.&#xD;
&#xD;
In many markets, organic certification, though valuable, may not offer the most appropriate way of safeguarding the actual provenance of local foods and conveying this to consumers in the marketplace. However, in more than a hundred nations, GIs are recognized as a unique expression of local agro-ecological and even cultural characteristics that have come to be valued as signals of high quality and local traditions. In many cases GIs can readily combine with organic certifications and thus provide a unique combination of assurance to consumers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13309/1/The_New_Local__Organics_and_Geographic_Indications_Daniele_Giovannucci_ITC_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Giovannucci, Daniele    (2007) The New Local: Linking Geographical Indications and Organics.       Paper at:   1st IFOAM International Conference on 'Marketing of Organic and Regional Values', Germany, August 26 - 28, 2007.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13309/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>