<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards a paradigm for the convergence of production, marketing and environmental protection in the field of the organic olive oil production chain- Conclusions from the BIOLMED project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ehaliotis, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinis, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Minotou, Ch</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The majority of innovations pioneered within/for the organic olive oil production (OOOP) chain may, and are, increasingly becoming, adopted by the conventional olive oil production chain, especially regarding cultivation, inputs related to plant/ecosystem protection and trade/promotion of specialized high quality products. Therefore the OOOP-chain may become a pioneering paradigm, for the implementation and convergence of agricultural production, marketing, sustainable rural development and environmental/biodiversity protection EU policies in the Mediterranean. Moreover, it appears that OOOP systems are increasingly becoming model systems for developing, applying and evaluating innovations that may have far more general applicability for Mediterranean agriculture. There is little divergence between conventional and organic production regarding water consumption and waste production, but the OOOP-chain has a lower impact as regards to soil erosion, desertification, pollution due chemicals and fertilizers (minimal), and effects on wildelife/vegetation biodiversity. Regarding pest and disease control, Bactrocera oleae is the most common pest problem, but effective means of control are available. On the contrary, Verticillium wilt is constantly expanding and, although not still a widespread problem, it is difficult to manage. Bottom-up demand for innovations, however, tends to underrate the need for innovations on common marketing priorities, trade policies, infrastructure and joint promotion strategies. Regarding “biopesticides” and “natural products”, approval protocols and legislation regarding synthetic inputs should also be fully applied to these products, to assure safe development of the OOOP sector. By working on innovations, differentiations, measures, policies and strategies regarding the organic olive oil production chain in the Mediterranean (OOOP) we realized that OOOP may have a much wider impact. By merging all major attributes of environmentally safe, sustainable agriculture, and becoming a key parameter of integrated rural development in the Mediterranean OOOP may serve as paradigm that may be tailored to apply to a much wider range of agricultural and agro-industrial activities. Features of OOPC in line with this view are discussed below</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic, Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19834/1/03_Ehaliotis_FULL.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ehaliotis, C; Martinis, A and Minotou, Ch    (2011) Towards a paradigm for the convergence of production, marketing and environmental protection in the field of the organic olive oil production chain- Conclusions from the BIOLMED project.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic, Drazen; Hashem, Yousry and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstract. International Conference on ORGANIC AGRICULTURE and AGRO-ECO TOURSIM in the Mediterranean, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19834/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>