<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diet type dictates the gut microbiota and the immune response against Yersinia ruckeri in rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ingerslev, Hans-Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strube, M. Lenz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Louise von Gersdorff</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalsgaard, Inger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boye, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, Lone</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigated the influence of the rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss) commensal intestinal microbiota in connection to an experimental Yersina ruckeri infection, the causative agent of enteric redmouth disease. One marine and one plant diet was administered to two different groups of rainbow trout. The plant-based diet gave rise to an intestinal microbiota dominated by the genera Streptococcus, Leuconostoc and Weissella from phylum Firmicutes whereas phylum Proteobacteria/Bacteroidetes/Actinobacteria dominated the community in the marine fed fish. In connection to the Y. ruckeri bath challenge there was no effect of the diet type on the cumulative survival, but the number of Y. ruckeri positive fish as measured by plate count and the number of fish with a ‘high’ number of reads belonging to genus Yersinia as measured by 16S rRNA next-generation sequencing was higher for marine diet fed fish. Furthermore, the two experimental groups of fish showed a differential immune response, where Y. ruckeri challenged marine fed fish had a higher transcription of IL-1β and MBL-2 relative to challenged plant diet fed fish. The data suggest that the plant diet gave rise to a prebiotic effect favouring the presence of bacterial taxons proving protective in connection to bath challenge by Y. ruckeri.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27356/7/27356.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ingerslev, Hans-Christian; Strube, M. Lenz; Jørgensen, Louise von Gersdorff; Dalsgaard, Inger; Boye, Mette and Madsen, Lone   (2014) Diet type dictates the gut microbiota and the immune response against Yersinia ruckeri in rainbow trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss).   Fish and Shellfish Immunology, 40 (2), pp. 624-633.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27356/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>