<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Potential des Anbaus von Saflor (Carthamus tinctorius L.) unter den Bedingungen des Ökologischen Landbaus in Mitteleuropa</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elfadl, Elfadl Yousif</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reinbrecht, Carsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Witzke-Ehbrecht, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Under organic farming conditions, twenty safflower genotypes were tested for genotype-by-environment interaction (GxE) and stability across four locations in Germany and Switzerland for seed yield and oil content.. ANOVA showed highly significant differences among the genotypes, locations and GxL interactions for yield and oil content. None of the genotypes had a significant regression coefficient or a mean square deviation from the regression coefficient, thereby all genotypes are considered stable for seed yield, whereas, BS-62929 and PI-5724755 were relatively the most stable for oil content.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3762/1/3762.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Elfadl, Elfadl Yousif; Reinbrecht, Carsten; von Witzke-Ehbrecht, Sabine and Claupein, Wilhelm    (2005) Potential des Anbaus von Saflor (Carthamus tinctorius L.) unter den Bedingungen des Ökologischen Landbaus in Mitteleuropa.  [Potentiality Of Safflower (Carthamus tinctorius L.) Cultivation Under Organic Farming Conditions in Central Europe.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3762/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>