<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Altering the composition of ruminant-derived foods for improved human health</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Shingfield, Kevin J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Viitala, Sirja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leskinen, Heidi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vilkki, Johanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nutritional regulation of milk and meat fatty acid composition has been the subject of&#xD;
intense research during the last few decades. Considerable progress has been made&#xD;
towards understanding the role of diet on enhancing the nutritional value of ruminantderived&#xD;
foods while more recent studies have attempted to elucidate the molecular&#xD;
mechanisms underlying the changes in milk and tissue lipid fatty acid composition in&#xD;
ruminants. Diet is the major environmental factor influencing the CLA content of&#xD;
ruminant milk whilst the effects of genotype, stage of lactation and parity are&#xD;
relatively minor (Palmquist el al. 2005). Concentrations of CLA in ruminant meat are&#xD;
dependent on diet, gender, slaughter weight and breed with evidence of variable&#xD;
enrichment between tissues.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18290/1/Shingfield.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Shingfield, Kevin J.; Viitala, Sirja; Leskinen, Heidi and Vilkki, Johanna    (2010) Altering the composition of ruminant-derived foods for improved human health.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18290/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>