<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Legehennen in einem mobilen Stallsystem - Auslaufnutzung und Flächenzustand -</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fürmetz, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keppler, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knierim, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deerberg, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The use of the free-range area by laying hens housed in a mobile system and the resulting condition of the range were investigated. The free-range was used very intensively. On an average of nine complete observation days 35 % of the birds (23 – 44 % means per day) were outside the house. The maximum of animals in the free range was 77 %. 75 % (60 – 95 %) of the hens outside the house stayed in an area of 20 m around the house. This led to deteriorated conditions of the range in these areas. By moving the mobile house regularly (after 2 weeks in summer and 6 weeks in winter) a destruction of the vegetation could be avoided, while after not moving the house for three months in winter a complementary seeding became necessary.&#xD;
We conclude that the use of mobile systems for poultry in conjunction with a regular change of position and sufficient area per animal can avoid destruction of the vegetation despite an intensive use of the free-range all year round.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3773/1/3773.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fürmetz, A.; Keppler, C.; Knierim, U.; Deerberg, F. and Heß, J.    (2005) Legehennen in einem mobilen Stallsystem - Auslaufnutzung und Flächenzustand -.  [Laying hens in a mobile housing system - Use and condition of the free-range area -.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3773/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>