<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biolandbau und Werte: Was ist Biobauern in Österreich wertvoll?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Plakolm, Gerhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fromm, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The research project "Organic Revision" is part of the 6th Framework Program of the EU and tries to support the European Commission improving the regulation 2092/91 about organic farming. As part of one work package organic farmers have been con-sulted about their ethical values concerning organic farming. This work has been done as whole in five countries. Here are presented the results of Austria only.&#xD;
Different focus groups discussed according to a guideline and filled in some question-naires. The mentioned values have been classified. Organic farmers are aware of their ethical values for their life and their profession. The ethic of farming, the social and ecological communities and the respect of others (e.g. lower developed countries) are important as well as the continuation of the own farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9523/1/9523_Plakolm_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Plakolm, Gerhard and Fromm, Elisabeth    (2007) Biolandbau und Werte: Was ist Biobauern in Österreich wertvoll?  [Organic Farming and values: What is valuable for Austrian Organic Farmers?]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9523/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>