<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Faba beans in diets for growing-finishing pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alaviuhkola, Timo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Siljander-Rasi, Hilkka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suomi, Kaija</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two experiments were carried out to study the effects of using the new faba bean (Vicia faba L.) cultivar Kontu as a domestic protein source for growing-finishing pigs.In Experiment 1,120 pigs were used with a body weight (BW)of 25–110 kg to study the effects of replacing 0, 25, 50, 75,and 100%of rapeseed meal with faba beans in barley +rapeseed meal based diets. Restrictedly fed grower and finisher diets contained 137–317 and 114–260 g kg–1 faba beans, respectively. A barley +soya bean meal based diet was included as a control. The replacement of rapeseed meal with faba beans exerted a quadratic effect on daily weight gain and on the feed conversion ratio of pigs in the growing period and during total fattening (P &lt;0.05).The growth rate of growing pigs declined when 75 or 100%of rapeseed meal was replaced with faba beans.In addition,the complete replacement of rapeseed meal with faba beans decreased feed consumption (P&lt;0.05).The best overall growth performance and feed conversion ratio were observed when 50% of rapeseed meal was replaced with faba beans. These pigs had a better feed conversion ratio than those fed a barley +soya bean based meal diet (P&lt;0.05).The Minolta L*value of the longissimus dorsi muscle decreased linearly (P&lt;0.01) with increasing dietary faba bean levels. This indicates that the meat became darker. Therefore, Experiment 2 was carried out with 20 pigs (25–107 kg BW)to study the effect of faba beans on the colour and ultimate pH of the meat. The pigs were fed barley +soya bean meal or barley + faba bean based diets (243 g kg–1 faba beans).The ultimate pH of the longissimus dorsi muscle was higher in pigs fed the faba bean diet (P=0.05),but meat colour did not differ between the treatments (P&gt;0.05).In conclusion,inclusion of over 200 g kg–1 of faba beans in barley + rapeseed meal based diets is not recommended for growing pigs because it may result in reduced growth performance. Faba beans may influence meat colour,but this phenomenon should be investigated further.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16755/1/partanen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Partanen, Kirsi; Alaviuhkola, Timo; Siljander-Rasi, Hilkka and Suomi, Kaija   (2003) Faba beans in diets for growing-finishing pigs.   Agricultural and Food Science in Finland, 12 (1), pp. 35-47.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16755/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>