<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sustainable apple breedings needs sustainable marketing and management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weber, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Apple breeding programmes are currently in the middle of transition in terms of&#xD;
ownership and management. Until now most of them were funded by the public.&#xD;
Breeding took place by traditional methods since decades in a very sustainable way&#xD;
to develop better apple varieties. Today, increasing loss of national boundaries and&#xD;
globalisation, less interest by national bodies and institutions and rising cost levels&#xD;
for high tech breeding methods entire programmes are nowadays urged to look for&#xD;
new sustainable co- or self-financing business models in order to continue their&#xD;
work. The paper explains through financial calculations how risk can be split by all&#xD;
partners and how the supply chain can be developed further into a value chain by&#xD;
using a collective royalty system on trees and fruit, to add value to all market&#xD;
participants and to support the breeding efforts and to become sustainable through&#xD;
profitability. A leading shift of mindset requires the involvement of variety managers&#xD;
and companies who are coaching the whole process of introduction.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13700/1/232-237.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weber, M.    (2008) Sustainable apple breedings needs sustainable marketing and management.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 232-237.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13700/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>