<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Poliennal results on soil N management and maize N nutrition by green manuring</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Benincasa, Dr Paolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tosti, Dr Giacomo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boldrini, Dr Arianna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tei, Prof Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guiducci, Prof Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Several field trials were carried out in 5 years in Central Italy to study the effect of green manuring on soil N management and N availability for grain maize as a succeeding crop. Hairy vetch, field bean, rapeseed and barley were grown in autumn-winter as pure crops or mixed in leg-non leg couples. Maize was sown in early spring just after green manure incorporation. The amount of N supplied by green manures, as well as the maize N uptake and the estimated N effect (i.e. the N taken up by maize that actually derives from green manure N) depended on species used, but with a high between-year variability. The N effect at harvest over 3 years was found to depend on the amount of incorporated biomass (DW) and its N content (N%) according to a multiple linear regression (Neff = -3.9*DW + 47.8*N%, R2 = 73%).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11581/1/Benincasa_11581_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Benincasa, Dr Paolo; Tosti, Dr Giacomo; Boldrini, Dr Arianna; Tei, Prof Francesco and Guiducci, Prof Marcello    (2008) Poliennal results on soil N management and maize N nutrition by green manuring.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11581/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>