<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Is it easy for producers to market organic beef meat ? The case of BioBourgogne viande (France),</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sans, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Fontguyon, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sylvander, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Le Floc’h, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Auersalmi, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This contribution aims to present the results of a French case-study analysis - BioBourgogne&#xD;
Viande - carried up by members of three research teams in the framework of the European&#xD;
Program OMIaRD (Organic Marketing Initiatives and Rural Development)1. This overall project&#xD;
examine all aspects of organic products marketing in Europe in order to develop strategies that&#xD;
both satisfy environmentally and ethically conscious consumers, support the development of new&#xD;
jobs and improve incomes in rural communities. The project focuses on the impact of what we&#xD;
name Organic Marketing Initiative (O.M.I) on rural development, especially in Less Favoured&#xD;
Areas (L.F.A). An OMI is an organisation of actors (privately or co-operatively owned) involving&#xD;
participation of organic producers which aims to improve the strategic marketing position of the&#xD;
products by adding value to the raw product through processing or marketing. In order to&#xD;
improve knowledge of success factors (in social and economic terms) of O.M.I, 67 narrative&#xD;
case-study analysis were firstly carried up in 40 European regions, with a special attention in selection process (examination of highly diverse OMIs, in different geographical, cultural, agroecological&#xD;
and political contexts). Then, researchers implemented a comparative in-depth case&#xD;
study analysis involving 4 selected O.M.I located in Austria, France, Italy and the United&#xD;
Kingdom and based on interviews of internal, external and interface stakeholders.&#xD;
In a first part, after a brief description of the region where the O.M.I is located, we present the&#xD;
main features of the development of BioBourgogne Viande, from its origins to the present day. In&#xD;
a second part, the motivations, cohesion and competencies are analysed in the structure of a&#xD;
SWOT (opportunities, threats, strengths and weaknesses), identifying organisational learning&#xD;
processes through the past ten years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6730/1/Paper_SAFO_version_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sans, P.; de Fontguyon, G.; Sylvander, B.; Le Floc’h, A.; Auersalmi, M. and Schmid, O.    (2003) Is it easy for producers to market organic beef meat ? The case of BioBourgogne viande (France),.       Speech at:   Workshop SAFO : Socioeconomics aspects of animal health and food safety in organic farming systems,  Florence, Italie, 2003/09/05.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6730/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>