<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sarapatka, Borivoj</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Urban , Jiri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cizkova, Stanislava</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hejduk, Stanislav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hradil, Radomil</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jurcik , Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leibl, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matlova, Vera</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Plisek, Bedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pokorny, Eduard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rozsypal, Roman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sedlo, Jiri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skerik, Josef</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sonkova , Romana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Travnicek, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vanek, Dusan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pinschof, Anton</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The “Organic Agriculture” (OA) book provides anyone interested in this type of farming with a practically focused textbook. The book gives a basic summary of work covering all relevant themes on which the most competent authors, coordinated by Czech experts - Borivoj Šarapatka and Jirí Urban, provide definitive contributions valid not only within the Czech Republic. The book is recommended for practical farming but also as a textbook for teachers and students. The real value of the book is in the fact that it has been compiled by a number of OA specialists and institutions focusing on this area of agriculture - to meet the demand for a comprehensive publication. The book includes chapters on the history and present status of OA in Europe, the legal status of organic agriculture methods (in accordance with European Council Regulation (EC) No. 834/2007 and Commission Regulation No. 889/2008), the environmental effects of OA, plant production, soil, plant nutrition and fertilization, cultivation of crops, weed control, permanent grassland, organic fruit and vegetable-growing, organic viticulture and wine-making, animal husbandry and animal breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IAEI</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sarapatka, Borivoj</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Urban, Jiri</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20519/1/Ucebnice_AJ.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sarapatka, Borivoj; Urban , Jiri; Cizkova, Stanislava; Hejduk, Stanislav; Hradil, Radomil; Jurcik , Josef; Leibl, Martin; Matlova, Vera; Moudry, Jan; Plisek, Bedrich; Pokorny, Eduard; Rozsypal, Roman; Sedlo, Jiri; Skerik, Josef; Sonkova , Romana; Travnicek, Petr; Vanek, Dusan and Pinschof, Anton    (2009) Organic Agriculture.     IAEI, Prague, Czech Republic.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20519/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>