<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Approaches for field assessment of resistance to leaf pathogens in spring barley&#xD;
varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinnschmidt, H.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hovmøller, M.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Østergård, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The resistance of spring barley varieties to powdery mildew, leaf rust, leaf scald and net blotch was characterized by using results from inoculated small-plot nurseries and larger survey plots subject to natural infection. The experiments were conducted in different environments. Both trial types often yielded complementary results with respect to the ranking of varieties suggesting that a recommended variety characterization should include both naturally infected survey-type trials and nursery trials in which the most relevant pathogen isolates and/or isolate mixtures or populations are used for inoculation. Average and median values of the diseased leaf area of a variety were highly correlated with each other and with the genotype main effect determined by joint regression analysis, whereas maximum diseased leaf area was poorly correlated with them. Statistics based on absolute disease severity values were highly correlated with the corresponding statistics derived from relative values. It is suggested that one should use at least two parameters to characterize the disease resistance of a variety, a parameter indicating the overall resistance level and a parameter indicating the potential susceptibility and/or resistance instability of a variety. For practical purposes, the genotype median and maximum, respectively, may represent these, although statistically more appropriate parameters do exist.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Verlag, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8203/1/8203.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pinnschmidt, H.O.; Hovmøller, M.S. and Østergård, H.   (2006) Approaches for field assessment of resistance to leaf pathogens in spring barley varieties.   Plant Breeding, 125, pp. 105-113.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8203/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>