<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von Einstrahlungsintensität, Stickstoffangebot, Düngungsverfahren und Hornkieselapplikation auf den Nitrat-, Ascorbinsäure- und Glucosinolatgehalt bei Salatrauke (Eruca sativa)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Athmann, Miriam</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blasco, Irene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Effects of nitrogen supply (high / low), fertilizer type (biodynamic / organic / mineral) and application of the biodynamic horn silica preparation on nitrate, ascorbic acid and glucosinolate contents of rocket (Eruca sativa L.) were studied under conditions of full sunlight (100% photosynthetically active radiation PAR) and shading (55% PAR). Nitrate contents increased in response to shading and under conditions of full sunlight also in response to high nitrogen supply and mineral fertilization. Ascorbic acid contents were significantly higher with low nitrogen supply, biodynamic and organic fertilization, horn silica application and under conditions of low nitrogen supply with full sunlight. Glucosinolate contents were significantly increased by low nitrogen supply, full sunlight (in combination with biodynamic fertilization) as well as biodynamic and organic fertilization (under conditions of full sunlight).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17722/3/Athmann_17722.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Athmann, Miriam; Blasco, Irene and Köpke, Ulrich    (2011) Einfluss von Einstrahlungsintensität, Stickstoffangebot, Düngungsverfahren und Hornkieselapplikation auf den Nitrat-, Ascorbinsäure- und Glucosinolatgehalt bei Salatrauke (Eruca sativa).  [Effects of radiation intensity, nitrogen supply, fertilizer type and horn silica application on nitrate, ascorbic acid and glucosinolate content in rocket (Eruca sativa).]      Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17722/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>