<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In vitro screening of six anthelmintic plant products against larval Haemonchus contortus with a modified methyl-thiazolyl-tetrazolium reduction assay</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hördegen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cabaret, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hertzberg, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langhans, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Because of the increasing anthelmintic resistance and the impact of conventional anthelmintics on the environment, it is important to look for alternative strategies against gastrointestinal nematodes. Phytotherapy could be one of the major options to control these pathologies. Extracts or ingredients of six different plant species were tested against exsheathed infective larvae of Haemonchus contortus using a modified methyl-thiazolyltetrazolium (MTT) reduction assay. Pyrantel tartrate was used as reference anthelmintic. Bromelain, the enzyme complex of the stem of Ananas comosus (Bromeliaceae), the ethanolic extracts of seeds of Azadirachta indica (Meliaceae), Caesalpinia crista (Caesalpiniaceae) and Vernonia anthelmintica (Asteraceae), and the ethanolic extracts of the whole plant of Fumaria parviﬂora (Papaveraceae) and of the fruit of Embelia ribes (Myrsinaceae) showed an anthelmintic efficacy of up to 93%, relative to pyrantel tartrate. Based on these results obtained with larval Haemonchus contortus, the modified MTT reduction assay could be a possible method for testing plant products with anthelmintic properties.&#xD;
© 2006 Elsevier Ireland Ltd. All rights reserved.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13306/1/hoerdegen-etal-2006-J_Ethnopharmacol..pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hördegen, P.; Cabaret, J.; Hertzberg, H.; Langhans, W. and Maurer, V.   (2006) In vitro screening of six anthelmintic plant products against larval Haemonchus contortus with a modified methyl-thiazolyl-tetrazolium reduction assay.   Journal of Ethnopharmacology (108), pp. 85-89.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13306/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>