<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Issues of sustainable food production in Latvia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Melece, Ligita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Romanova, Dina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The article presents main results of the first in Latvia study addressing the issues of the development of Latvia’s sustainable food&#xD;
production. For detailed research two main themes for Latvia’s agri-food sector’s sustainability were chosen: 1) the issues related to&#xD;
further development of the organic farming and processing; where the special attention has been paid to organic milk processing; and&#xD;
obtaining of organic pigmeat and beef in different Latvia’s regions; 2) quality and environment management systems enforcement -&#xD;
mandatory and voluntary and the trends of implementation of the international management standards (ISO 9001, ISO 22000;&#xD;
HACCP DS 3027:2002; ISO 14001). The publications, legal documents and databases of Latvia’s governmental and nongovernmental&#xD;
institutions were used as materials and the qualitative and quantitative research methods were applied for this empirical&#xD;
research. The assessment of present situation and the proposals for further development has been given.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18615/1/LM_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Melece, Ligita and Romanova, Dina   (2007) Issues of sustainable food production in Latvia.   Economics and Rural Development, 3 (2), pp. 16-21.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18615/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>