<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Saatgut-Testmethoden für Falschen Mehltau an Feldsalat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schärer, Hansjakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Penzkofer, Lena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reents, Hansjürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brändle, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Peronospora valerianellae is one of the most important pathogens of corn salad. It is&#xD;
seedborne and besides seed treatments there is no possibility to control the disease.&#xD;
The wash-off-test and the grow-out-test are currently in use to test seed lots for the&#xD;
presence of the pathogen. Despite these test methods, there are still seed lots that&#xD;
show infected plants during production of corn salad. This indicates that a low&#xD;
infection rate of a seed lot (&lt; 0.25% - 1%) may lead to serious problems in grower’s&#xD;
production units. To allow an improved identification of seed lots with low infection&#xD;
rate, a specific PCR-based detection method for P. valerianellae was developed.&#xD;
Three test methods were compared for their efficacy to detect contaminated seed lots.&#xD;
Six out of seven seed lots not showing contamination in the standard grow-out test&#xD;
were identified as contaminated. With an extended grow-out test, it was possible to&#xD;
confirm these results from the PCR-test. The PCR based test for P.valerianellae on&#xD;
seed offers the possibility to detect the pathogen below the actual detection limits.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14490/1/Sch%C3%A4rer_14490.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14490/2/Poster_Feldsalat_schaerer_wisstagung2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schärer, Hansjakob; Penzkofer, Lena; Reents, Hansjürgen and Brändle, Frank    (2009) Saatgut-Testmethoden für Falschen Mehltau an Feldsalat.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14490/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>