<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Süßholz (Glycyrrhiza glabra) - Extrakt zur Regulierung von Falschem Mehltau im Öko-Gemüseanbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmitt, Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scherf, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schuster, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gärber, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marx, Peggy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Idczak, Elke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rupp, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leinhos, Gabriele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konstantinidou-Doltsinis†, Stavroula</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A raw extract of licorice (Glycyrrhiza glabra) was tested against downy mildew in vegetables under semi-commercial conditions. In two greenhouse trials in cucumber, efficacies of ca. 70% were achieved (3% extract concentration) in either 7 or 10-11 day application intervals. Under open field conditions, weekly treatments resulted in ca. 2 week retardation of disease. In open field trials in lettuce, efficacies after weekly application of 5% G. glabra extract were variable, depending on disease pressure. In contrast, on lettuce seedlings in climate chambers, the extract reduced disease incidence of Bremia lactucae by 66 to 100%. In onion, applications of the extract at 6% concentration failed to control Peronospora destructor, despite of high efficacies under controlled conditions in the greenhouse. Overall, the G. glabra raw extract was highly effective in protected vegetables. Under field conditions low efficacies were most likely due to reduced rain fastness or UV-stability.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17759/3/Schmitt_17759.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmitt, Annegret; Scherf, Andrea; Schuster, Christina; Gärber, Ute; Marx, Peggy; Idczak, Elke; Rupp, Jochen; Leinhos, Gabriele and Konstantinidou-Doltsinis†, Stavroula    (2011) Süßholz (Glycyrrhiza glabra) - Extrakt zur Regulierung von Falschem Mehltau im Öko-Gemüseanbau.  [Licorice (Glyzyrrhiza glabra) extract for control of downy mildew in organic vegetable production.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17759/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>