<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production and marketing of organic fruits and vegetables in Morocco</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>EL MALOUI, Hamid</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Morocco</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic agriculture in Morocco is still in its infancy. In absence of domestic market, the whole production is exported towards the European market.  Moroccan organic exports of fruits and vegetables are growing sharply. Yet, the exported quantity is still limited. The late establishment of national standards, the lack of public support, the absence of local market and the inadequate marketing structure are the main hindrances of organic production development in the Kingdom. The aim of this study is to identify the opportunities and constraints facing the organic production and marketing, to provide an understanding of the limitations of the existing production system and exports’ strategies, and to suggest how these limitations can be overcome and marketing process of organic horticultural products can be improved. This study was based upon a survey conducted in Morocco and Europe. Interviews were drawn from the whole spectrum of those involved in the production, marketing and assistance of Moroccan organic horticultural products: producers, exporters, processors, importers, public and private institutions.Results show that the sector avails of great potential in terms of production adequacy and diversity, which provides stakeholders various opportunities in the coming years. Yet, there exists a series of weaknesses, which limit the producers’ ability to take full advantage from these potentialities. Public institutions are still far from fully supporting the organic sector, whilst, farmers’ associations and NGO’s are making many efforts for the sector development. Results have allowed to set up the main actions that should be undertaken for the promotion of the sector, the responsibility of the involved actors, and the 'actions’ time scale feasibility</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6472/1/HamidMalaoui02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>EL MALOUI, Hamid   (2002) Production and marketing of organic fruits and vegetables in Morocco.  [Production et commercialisation de fruits et légumes biologiques au Maroc.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 277. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6472/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>