<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bekämpfung von Fusarien mit antifungalen Pflanzenprodukten&#xD;
und deren Effekte auf den Mykotoxin-Gehalt von Weizen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, Dr. Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hecker, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jenny, Evelyne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwab, Fabienne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wettstein, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogelgsang, Dr. Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fusarium graminearum (FG) is the most prevalent Fusarium Head Blight (FHB)&#xD;
fungus in Switzerland. In conventional agriculture, fungicides are used to reduce the&#xD;
risk of FHB infection and mycotoxin contamination of wheat. As an alternative for&#xD;
organic wheat production, we examined plant-based products that showed antifungal&#xD;
effects from our previous late blight field trials. In bioassays, the effect of these&#xD;
antifungal plant preparations (APP) was screened against FG. In 2006 and 2008, the&#xD;
most active APP, Rheum palmatum, Frangula alnus and preparations of Galla&#xD;
chinensis as well as a plant substance (PSX), were used as FHB control agents in&#xD;
field trials with artificial FG infections. In both years, FG incidence and deoxynivalenol&#xD;
content were significantly reduced by the APP. In 2006, the reduction was in the same&#xD;
dimension as applications with Pronto Plus®, a fungicide mixture of tebuconazole and&#xD;
spiroxamine.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14704/1/Forrer_14704.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Forrer, Dr. Hans-Rudolf; Hecker, Andreas; Jenny, Evelyne; Schwab, Fabienne; Wettstein, Felix and Vogelgsang, Dr. Susanne    (2009) Bekämpfung von Fusarien mit antifungalen Pflanzenprodukten und deren Effekte auf den Mykotoxin-Gehalt von Weizen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14704/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>