<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evolutionary breeding of wheat for low input systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Prof Martin S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hinchsliffe, Miss Kay S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clarke, Dr Sarah M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Dr Hannah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haigh, Miss Zoe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Snape, Prof John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fish, Dr Leslie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Genetically diverse Composite Cross Populations (CCPs) may be useful in environmentally variable low-input systems as an alternative to pure varieties. They are formed by assembling seed stocks with diverse evolutionary origins, recombining these stocks by hybridisation, bulking the F1 progeny, and subsequent natural selection of the progeny in suc-cessive natural cropping environments. CCPs derived from either 10 high yielding parents (YCCPs), 12 high quality parents (QCCPs), or all 22 parents (YQCCPs), were grown at four sites (2 organic, 2 conventional) in the UK. The YCCPs out yielded the QCCPs, which had higher protein concentrations and Hagberg falling numbers. Although the CCPs performed within the range of the parents, they often performed better than the mean of the parents.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7450/2/denmark_conference_06_wheat_breeding_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7450/3/7450.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wolfe, Prof Martin S.; Hinchsliffe, Miss Kay S.; Clarke, Dr Sarah M; Jones, Dr Hannah; Haigh, Miss Zoe; Snape, Prof John and Fish, Dr Leslie    (2006) Evolutionary breeding of wheat for low input systems.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7450/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>