<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>UPSCALING THE UPLANDS: ASSESSMENT OF OPPORTUNITIES FOR UPLAND RICE-BASED ORGANIC FARMING IN SELECTED COMMUNITIES IN CAMARINES SUR, PHILIPPINES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CRUZ, JOSEPHINE</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This project aimed to develop agricultural systems that will optimize  utilization and value of  upland areas by using them for organic agriculture to provide food and livelihood opportunities in the community. The project sites were the rolling and mountainous areas of Barangay Antipolo in Baao and   Duran in Nabua, Camarines Sur, Philippines. Participatory Resource Appraisal was used to gather data for the Situational Analysis which characterized the production system of the sites. Thirty one farmers participated which were organized into an association. Capability development activities were conducted in Baao and Nabua: Training on Organic Fertilizer Production and Training on Organic Upland Rice Production. Agricultural inputs, like vegetable seeds, upland rice seed, molasses and vermicast  for  organic fertilizer production and knapsack sprayer were provided. The project had three components:  Organic Vegetable Production where 3.25 hectares of land were grown with various vegetables and farmers gained  $2,095.54 income; Organic Upland Rice Production where 16.75 hectares of land were planted with various rice varieties achieving about $4,627.32 income;  Organic Fertilizer Production which produced concoctions and vermicompost used as natural fertilizers in their farms. To access relevant services and ensure sustainability of the project, linkages were fostered with Department of Agriculture, Philippine Rice Institute, academe and Local Government Units. The project was able to identify good practices and establish mechanisms which show the sustainability of upland organic farming as a source of livelihood and as a way of good life.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24479/7/24479.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CRUZ, JOSEPHINE    (2014) UPSCALING THE UPLANDS: ASSESSMENT OF OPPORTUNITIES FOR UPLAND RICE-BASED ORGANIC FARMING IN SELECTED COMMUNITIES IN CAMARINES SUR, PHILIPPINES.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24479/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>