<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Formation of canker lesions on stems and black scurf on tubers in experimentally inoculated potato plants by isolates of AG2-1, AG3 and AG5 of Rhizoctonia solani: a pilot study and literature review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lehtonen, Mari J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wilson, Paula S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ahvenniemi, Paavo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valkonen, Jari P.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Development of black scurf on potato tubers (cv. Nicola) was compared in plants inoculated with isolates of Rhizoctonia solani of three anastomosis groups (AG2-1, AG3 and AG5) which occur in potato crops in Finland. All isolates induced stem canker lesions but only isolates of AG3 formed efficiently black scurf on progeny tubers. Among the AG2-1 and AG5 isolates tested, only one AG2-1 isolate formed a few sclerotia on 13.5 % of the progeny tubers in one experiment. The data indicate that isolates of AG3 differ from those of AG2-1 and AG5 in having a higher ability to form sclerotia on tubers. Therefore, while AG2-1 and AG5 isolates have a broader host range, AG3 is more efficient in producing black scurf, which provides this anastomosis group with more efficient means of dissemination on seed potatoes. These differences probably explain the predominance of AG3 (98.9 % of isolates) in potato crops in Finland and other northern potato production areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16976/1/lehtonen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lehtonen, Mari J.; Wilson, Paula S.; Ahvenniemi, Paavo and Valkonen, Jari P.T.   (2009) Formation of canker lesions on stems and black scurf on tubers in experimentally inoculated potato plants by isolates of AG2-1, AG3 and AG5 of Rhizoctonia solani: a pilot study and literature review.   Agricultural and Food Science, 18 (3-4), pp. 223-233.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16976/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>