<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrate leaching in grazed grasslands of different composition and age</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vinther, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a field experiment at Research Centre Foulum a suction cup technique was used to investigate nitrate leaching from grassland depending on composition (grass-clover or perennial ryegrass), management (grazing or cutting) and age of the swards. In 1997-2001 was investigated the successive nitrate leaching from 4-7 year old grazed grass-clover and ryegrass with cut plots of similar age and spring barley as reference. In 2000-2001 the simultaneous nitrate leaching from newly established swards, swards grazed for 1 and 7 years and swards cut for 7 years was investigated. In the newly established swards nitrate leaching from grass-clover and ryegrass were similar but at increasing sward age nitrate leaching from the fertilized ryegrass increased dramatically compared to a constant low level from the unfertilized grass-clover. Apparently, the clover component of grass-clover was able to equalize differences in soil nitrogen availability in swards of different age. The results of N2 fixation studies in swards of different age in 2001 will be used in the interpretation of the nitrate leaching data.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>European Grassland Federation</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/160/1/cfp404.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J. and Vinther, F.P.    (2002) Nitrate leaching in grazed grasslands of different composition and age.    In:      MULTI-FUNCTION GRASSLANDS – Quality Forages, Animal Products and Landscapes .  European Grassland Federation, pp. 682-683.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/160/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>