<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung von pfluglosen Anbauverfahren im ökologischen Landbau unter Anwendung verschiedener Hofdüngerformen und biologisch-dynamischer Präparate</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Berner, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frei, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a long-term field trial (November 2002-2011), located in Frick near Basle (Switzerland), the influence of reduced tillage on soil fertility and yield is studied in a crop rotation under organic farming conditions. Here, we describe the field experiment and present results of the first year. The three factors examined, soil tillage, manure type and biodynamic preparations are implemented in a fully factorised experimental setup. The experimental field manifested a high homogeneity for the parameters pH, soil organic carbon (Corg), dehydrogenase activity and microbial biomass.&#xD;
Wheat yield in the first experimental year was 16% higher in ploughed plots than in the plots with reduced tillage (p &lt; 0.001). Plots fertilised with slurry manifested 5 % (p &lt; 0.001) higher wheat yields than plots manured with compost. Yield of the following oat/clover intercrop was somewhat higher in reduced tilled plots than in ploughed plots, but not statistically significant. Long-term effects need to be evaluated.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3569/1/3569.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Berner, Alfred; Frei, Robert and Mäder, Paul    (2005) Entwicklung von pfluglosen Anbauverfahren im ökologischen Landbau unter Anwendung verschiedener Hofdüngerformen und biologisch-dynamischer Präparate.  [Development of reduced tillage systems in organic farm using different manure types and biodynamic preparations.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3569/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>