<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biogramm und Qualitätskennzahl</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Velimirov, Alberta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The quality assessment and comparison of differently cultivated products still represents a problem. On the one hand “quality” comprises many, mostly target group oriented aspects, necessitating the application of relevant methods, on the other hand the interpretation of diviating results is not easy or suitable to corroborate cultivation dependent quality aspects systematically. &#xD;
Some scientists have already tried to tackle that problem and developed quality indices by integratig different quality parameters (BREDA 1973, HUBER et al. 1988, SCHULZ &amp; KÖPKE 1997).&#xD;
The aim of this presentation is to reach a grafic and numeric interpretation of results obtained from different methods. Although organic quality research corresponds to the holistic background of organic agriculture, no adequate basis for the interpretation of integrative results has been defined. Therefore in this presentation only holistic methods have been used  to achieve  a connection of systemic results. The quality aspects taste (sensory evaluation), nutritional quality (food preference test), shelf life (decomposition test) and energy status (P-value determination) have been investigated. The grafic presentations has been copied from HOFFMANN (1997). &#xD;
The test products (carrots, beeet root, apples) came from organic and conventional producers of the same region.  The results of interdisciplinary projects have been summarised and compared (VELIMIROV et al. 1995, VELIMIROV et al. 2000, VELIMIROV 2001).&#xD;
It could be shown, that the presentation of the 4 data sets used as the corner points of a rhombus („biogram“) and as the basis for the calculation to a single value („quality count“) enable a balance between differing results and corresponds to a more general quality concept. &#xD;
The attempt to maintain an eco-systemic approach throughout the organic production system including the presentation of quality results is meant to draw attention to the interpretation and representation of holistic quality results.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universität für Bodenkultur Wien - Institut für Ökologischen Landbau</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2083/1/Velimirov-2003-biogramm_quality-count.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Velimirov, Alberta    (2003) Biogramm und Qualitätskennzahl.  [Biogram and Quality Count as Suitable Indicators of Product Quality.]  In: Freyer, Bernhard (Ed.)  Beiträge zur 7. Wissenschaftstagung zum Ökologischen Landbau: Ökologischer Landbau der Zukunft, Universität für Bodenkultur Wien - Institut für Ökologischen Landbau.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2083/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>