<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FAIR3-CT96-1794 Organic and in-conversion land area, holdings, livestock and crop production in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Foster, Carolyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this report is to provide an up-to-date overview of the organic and inconversion land area, number of holdings, livestock and crop production in all EU member states plus the Czech Republic, Norway and Switzerland from 1993 to 1998. The report traces the growth and development of organic farming in general and as part of policy measures to support organic farming and updates the data presented in Foster and Lampkin (1999). This report is one of several aiming to assess ex post the impact of EU and other policy measures on organic farming as part of the project ”Effects of the CAP Reform and possible further developments on organic farming in the EU” (FAIR 3-CT96 1794). The general objective of the project is to provide an assessment of the impact of the 1992 CAP Reform on organic farming and thus contribute to a better understanding of the effects that current EU policies have on this sub-sector. 1993 was chosen as the starting point from which to present the data as it represents the year in which most EU member states implemented Council Regulation (EEC) No. 2092/91 defining organic crop production in statutory terms. It was also the first year in which the CAP Reform of 1992 began to have an impact on organic farming, in particular through support under the agri-environment programme (Council Regulation (EEC) No. 2078/92).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2000-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10830/1/European_organic_farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Foster, Carolyn and Lampkin, Nicolas         (2000) FAIR3-CT96-1794 Organic and in-conversion land area, holdings, livestock and crop production in Europe.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10830/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>