<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consequences of including adapted white clover in northern European grassland: transfer and deposition of nitrogen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gylfadóttir, Thórey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Helgadóttir, Áslaug</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The interspecific transfer of nitrogen (N) between white clover (Trifolium repens) and smooth meadow grass (Poa pratensis) in legume-based grasslands was assessed under North European field conditions using 15N individual plant leaf labelling. On average 50% of N in the grass was transferred from the white clover and about 6% of N in white clover was transferred from the grass. This corresponds to 2.5 and 0.3 g N m-2 being transferred over the growing season between the two species respectively and demonstrates that a significant part of the total N of the grass is coming through interspecific transfer. The majority of the 15N transferred was within a period of 20 days at relatively low soil temperatures. This implies that there is a need for a new focus on direct transfer pathways or exudation and transfer of organic N sources. Rhizodeposition in the top 10 cm of the soil was found to be 2.98 g N m-2 on average over the growing season for the grass and white clover mixture. Inclusion of adapted white clover varieties in the low-input grassland systems of northern Europe will lead to a substantial contribution of N.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11466/1/11466.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gylfadóttir, Thórey; Helgadóttir, Áslaug and Høgh-Jensen, Henning   (2007) Consequences of including adapted white clover in northern European grassland: transfer and deposition of nitrogen.   Plant and Soil, 297, pp. 93-104.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11466/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>