<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diversidade de Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) em plantas aromáticas (Apiaceae) como sítios de sobrevivência e reprodução em sistema agroecológico.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lixa, Alice T</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Campos, Juliana M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Resende, André L S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Silva, Joice C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almeida, Maxwell M T B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Menezes, Elen L Aguiar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Studies show that Apiaceae may provide concentrated vital resources for predator insects,stimulating their abundance, diversity and persistence in agricultural systems, thereby increasing their effi ciency as biological control agents. Among the predatory insects, Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) on many different species both as larvae and adults, complementing their diet with pollen and/or nectar. This&#xD;
study aimed to determine the diversity and relative abundance of Coccinellidae species visiting plants&#xD;
of Anethum graveolens (dill), Coriandrum sativum (coriander) and Foeniculum vulgare (sweet fennel)&#xD;
(all Apiaceae), particularly in their blooming seasons, and to evaluate the potential of these aromatic species for providing the resources for survivorship and reproduction of coccinelids. Coccinellids were collected by removal of samplings from September to October, 2007. Besides one unidentifi ed species of Chilocorinae, five species of Coccinellinae were collected: Coleomegilla maculata DeGeer, Coleomegilla quadrifasciata (Schönherr), Cycloneda sanguinea (L.), Eriopis connexa (Germar) and Hippodamia convergens Guérin-Meneville. Dill provided a signifi cant increase in the abundance of coccinellids as compared to coriander and sweet fennel. These aromatic species were used by coccinellids as survival and reproduction sites, providing food resources (pollen and/or prey), shelter for larvae, pupae and adults, and mating and oviposition sites as well.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21994/1/Lixa_Diversidade.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lixa, Alice T ; Campos, Juliana M ; Resende, André L S ; Silva, Joice C ; Almeida, Maxwell M T B  and Menezes, Elen L Aguiar   (2010) Diversidade de Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) em plantas aromáticas (Apiaceae) como sítios de sobrevivência e reprodução em sistema agroecológico.  [Diversity of Coccinellidae (Coleoptera) using aromatic plants (Apiaceae) as survival and reproduction sites in agroecological system.]  Neotropical Entomology, 39 (03), pp. 354-359.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21994/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>