<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A review of knowledge of the potential impacts of GMOs on organic agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dale, Phillip</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clarke, Belinda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fontes, Eliana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martin, Wolfe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pearce, Bruce</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Welsh, James</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic movement believes that organic agriculture, by its nature, cannot involve the use of genetically modified organisms (GMOs).  This has been incorporated into EU regulations which state that there is no place in organic agriculture for GMOs.  The aim in this review is to consider the ways in which the use of GMOs in agriculture in the UK and internationally might impact on organic farming.  It does not address the controversy about the rights or wrongs of GMO’s per se.  The subjects covered are based on a set of questions raised at the beginning of the study.  The review is based primarily on evidence from peer-reviewed literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
The report is based on a number of themes, as follows:&#xD;
•	Fate of DNA in soil&#xD;
•	Fate of DNA in livestock feed and possible impact of GM feed&#xD;
•	Fate of DNA in slurry, manure, compost and mulch&#xD;
•	Impact of herbicide tolerant crops&#xD;
•	Impact of pest and disease resistant crops&#xD;
•	Safety of promoters&#xD;
•	DNA transfer in pollen and seeds&#xD;
•	Horizontal gene transfer&#xD;
•	Impact of scale&#xD;
The report’s Executive Summary includes summaries of the findings on each of these themes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6843/1/6843.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dale, Phillip; Clarke, Belinda; Fontes, Eliana; Martin, Wolfe; Pearce, Bruce and Welsh, James         (2001) A review of knowledge of the potential impacts of GMOs on organic agriculture.    John Innes Centre.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6843/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>