<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EHEC – kein spezifisches Problem nachhaltiger Landwirtschaft&#xD;
- [EHEC – A problem not specific to sustainable agriculture] [La EHEC – no es un problema específico de la agricultura sostenible] - [EHEC – Non è un problema specifi-co dell’agricoltura biologica] - [ECEH n’est pas un problème dû à l’agriculture durable] - [EHEC – nem speciálisan a fenntartható mezőgazdaság gondja] - [ECEH n’est pas un problème dû à l’agriculture durable]</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Landau, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koller, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Notz, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forster, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>DEUTSCH &#xD;
Über den EHEC-Erreger, der in Deutschland zu über dreissig tragischen Todesfällen geführt hat, ist viel spekuliert worden. Unterdessen konnten die Verbreitungswege nahezu aufgeklärt werden, während die Entstehung des Krankheitserregers noch weitgehend unklar ist.&#xD;
Im Zusammenhang mit dem EHEC-Ausbruch wurde auch die Frage erörtert, ob bestimmte Landwirtschaftsmethoden (zum Beispiel gemischte Betriebe mit Tierhaltung und Pflanzenbau oder die organische Düngung von Gemüse) oder ob gewisse Hygienisierungsmethoden für frische, konsumfähige Produkte(wie zum Beispiel die Verwendung von schonenden, weniger Rückstände verursachenden organischen Säuren) das Risiko erhöhen könnten.&#xD;
Diese Dokumentation geht nicht auf die aktuellen Fälle von EHEC in Norddeutschland ein, sondern liefert an diesem Beispiel Hintergrundinformationen zur Frage, wie nachhaltige, in Kreisläufen arbeitende Landwirtschaftsmethoden mit vom Tier auf den Menschen übertragbare Krankheitserreger (Zoonosen) umgehen.&#xD;
ENGLISH &#xD;
There has been much speculation about the pathogenic EHEC bacterial strain that has tragically claimed the lives of more than 30 people so far in Germany. Meanwhile, the transmission pathways have for the most part been identified. The origin of the pathogen, however, is largely unclear.&#xD;
In the context of the EHEC outbreak there have been debates as to whether certain agriculturalmethods (e.g. mixed holdings including both livestock and crop production, or the use of organic fertilizers for vegetable production) or certain sanitization methods for fresh consumable products (such as the use of organic acids, a mild treatment that leaves fewer residues) may increase the risk of infection.&#xD;
This document does not address the current epidemiological situation of the outbreak in northern Germany. Its purpose is rather to provide background information on the question of how sustainable agricultural methods based on nutrient cycling deal with pathogens that can be transmitted from animals to humans (zoonoses).&#xD;
CASTELLANO&#xD;
Mucho se ha especulado sobre la bacteria patógena Escherichia coli enterohemorrágica (ECEH), que ha ocasionado más de treinta muertes trágicas en Alemania. Hasta ahora casi se ha podido esclarecer la via de su propagación, mientras que sigue estando poco claro como ha aparecido el agente patógeno.&#xD;
Con el brote de la ECEH se ha cuestionado si determinadas prácticas agrícolas (por ejemplo, mantener explotaciones mixtas con ganado y cultivos, o la fertilización orgánica de los vegetales) o si los métodos de higiene para productos frescos, listos para el consumo (como por ejemplo, el uso de ácidos orgánicos menos agresivos y con menor riesgo de dejar residudos), pudieran incrementar los riesgos.&#xD;
Esta documento no se refiere sólo a los casos actuales de ECEH en el norte de Alemania, sino que proporciona, información básica de fondo, aprovechando este ejemplo, sobre como los métodos de producción agraria de ciclos cerrados con animales evitan forma sostenible que los patógenos generadores de enfermedades contagiosas (zoonosis) trasmisibles al ser humano.&#xD;
ITALIANO&#xD;
A proposito dell’insorgenza di EHEC è stata sollevata la questione se determinati metodi agricoli (per esempio aziende miste con allevamento di animali e produzione vegetale o la concimazione organica di ortaggi) oppure se determinati metodi di igienizzazione per pro-dotti freschi adatti al consumo (come per esempio l’impiego di acidi organici che provocano meno residui) possano aumentare i rischi.&#xD;
La presente documentazione non entra nei particolari degli attuali casi di EHEC nella Ger-mania settentrionale bensì fornisce informazioni d’approfondimento su come i me-todi agri-coli sostenibili basati sui cicli degli elementi nutritivi trattano la questione degli agenti pato-geni trasmissibili dagli animali all’uomo (zoonosi).&#xD;
HUNGARIAN&#xD;
Sok a spekuláció az EHEC kórokozót illetően, amely Németországban harmincnál is több tragikus halálesethez vezetett. Időközben a terjedés útját már csaknem teljesen felderítették, míg a kórokozó létrejöttéről még szinte semmit sem tudunk. &#xD;
Az EHEC fertőzés kitörése kapcsán az a kérdés is felmerült, hogy bizonyos mezőgazdasági módszerek (pl. a vegyes üzemek, melyek egyaránt foglalkoznak növénytermesztéssel és állattenyésztéssel, vagy a zöldségek szerves trágyázása), ill. a friss, fogyasztásra kész termékek egyes fertőtlenítési módszerei (így pl. a kímélőbb, kevesebb hulladékot eredményező szerves savak alkalmazása) nem növelhetik-e a kockázatot. &#xD;
A jelen tanulmány nem a Németország északi részén kialakult aktuális EHEC esetekkel foglalkozik, hanem háttér-információval szolgál arról, hogy a körforgásos működésű, fenntartható mezőgazdasági módszerek milyen kapcsolatban lehetnek az állatról emberre terjedő betegségekkel, az ún. zoonózisokkal. &#xD;
FRANCAIS&#xD;
ECEH n’est pas un problème dû à l’agriculture durable</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-06-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/17/fibl-2011-ehec-deutsch.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/10/fibl-2011-ehec-english.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/13/fibl-2011-ehec-spanish.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/24/fibl-2011-ehec-italiano.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/27/fibl-2011-ehec-hungarian.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18904/30/fibl-2011-ehec-francais.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niggli, U. ; Gattinger, A.; Kretzschmar, U.; Landau, B.; Koller, M.; Klocke, P.; Notz, C.  and Forster, J.     (2011) EHEC – kein spezifisches Problem nachhaltiger Landwirtschaft - [EHEC – A problem not specific to sustainable agriculture] [La EHEC – no es un problema específico de la agricultura sostenible] - [EHEC – Non è un problema specifi-co dell’agricoltura biologica] - [ECEH n’est pas un problème dû à l’agriculture durable] - [EHEC – nem speciálisan a fenntartható mezőgazdaság gondja] - [ECEH n’est pas un problème dû à l’agriculture durable].   FiBL - Research Institute of Organic Agriculture / Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau , Frick.   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18904/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>