<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Stickstoffflüsse im System Boden-Pflanze nach einer Grünlanderneuerung mit eingeschobener Ackerzwischennutzung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmeer, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An Experiment to examine the nitrogen fluxes after ploughing up and resowing grassland was conducted on the organic experimental station “Lindhof” in northern Germany. The trial was implemented on a uniform grassland site (since 1993) focussing on the factors grassland resowing, fertilisation with organic cattle slurry (0/230 kg ha-1) and year of renovation (2005, 2006, 2008). The factor grassland resowing further involved the following treatments: 1. undisturbed control, 2. ploughing up and resowing grassland in late summer, 3. ploughing up of grassland in autumn followed by winter wheat and grassland resowing the year after, 4. ploughing up of grassland in spring followed by spring wheat and grassland resowing the year after. Ploughing up in autumn induced increased nitrate leaching. Inserted wheat cultivation led to higher leaching in the second winter. N-yields of the newly sown grassland did not exceed those of the undisturbed control due to a low content of white clover in newly established grassland.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17609/3/Loges_17609.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmeer, Maria; Loges, Ralf and Taube, Friedhelm    (2011) Stickstoffflüsse im System Boden-Pflanze nach einer Grünlanderneuerung mit eingeschobener Ackerzwischennutzung.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17609/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>