<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biological profitability of maize inoculation with selected rhizosphere micro organisms (Pseudomonas fluorescens and Glomus intraradices) under Water Deficit Stress</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aghaalikhani, Dr. Majid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ehteshami, Dr. Seyyed Mohammad Reza</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Irrigation and drainage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This research focused on evaluating the usefulness of an arbuscular mycorrhizal fungus (Glomus intraradices) and a plant growth-promoting rhizobacterium (Pseudomonas fluorescens) to maize growth under water deficit stress. Field experiment was conducted at Soil and water research institute, Karaj Station, Iran, during 2006 growing season.  Biological positive effects of the micro organisms  on plant growth, nutrient uptake, grain yield and yield components in maize plants was recorded in the treatment receiving mixed inoculums of G. intraradices  and P. fluorescens.  Maize shoot  P content, grain yield, yield components, harvest index, grain N and P, soil available P, root colonization percentage and water use efficiency increased significantly with the G. intraradices inoculation and P. fluorescens, alone or in combination under water deficit stress.  The highest profitability was observed in the combined treatment of inoculation with G. intraradices and P. fluorescens, which synergistically increased plant growth compared with other treatments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11833/1/Aghaalikhani_11833_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aghaalikhani, Dr. Majid and Ehteshami, Dr. Seyyed Mohammad Reza    (2008) Biological profitability of maize inoculation with selected rhizosphere micro organisms (Pseudomonas fluorescens and Glomus intraradices) under Water Deficit Stress.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11833/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>