<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Methodology for Sustainability Evaluation in Organic Farming under Colombian Conditions: a Proposal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Escobar, C.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Espinosa, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Malagon, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zuluaga, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The lack of specific methodologies to evaluate and monitor the impact of agricultural activities on the-biotic, abiotic and socio-economic environment constitutes a technical - scientific barrier for the development and improvement of Organic Agriculture in Colombia.&#xD;
The proposed methodology consists of:  &#xD;
Step 1: Gathering of information on the organic production system by means of surveys and interviews with farmers.  &#xD;
Step 2: Characterisation and description of the production system.  &#xD;
Step 3: Qualification and quantification of the production system.  &#xD;
Step 4: Identification and evaluation of environmental quality indicators and creation of diagrams &#xD;
Step 5: Interpretation of results.&#xD;
This proposal is a first approach for a complete evaluation of any organic production system by means of using indicators that define environmental quality. The proposal is flexible to modification according to the specific conditions of each system, region or country.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4339/4/Escobar_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Escobar, C.A.; Espinosa, A.; Malagon, R. and Zuluaga, A.    (2005) Methodology for Sustainability Evaluation in Organic Farming under Colombian Conditions: a Proposal.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4339/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>