<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Europe: Current Statistics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schaack, Diana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlatter, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lernoud, Julia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this article, key area and operator data about organic farming in Europe and the European Union are presented. &#xD;
&gt; In Europe, 11.2 million hectares were under organic agricultural management, constituting 2.2 percent of the agricultural area. Compared with 2003 (6.3 million hectares), the organic land has almost doubled. In 2012, the area increased by 0.63 million hectares or six percent.&#xD;
&gt; In the countries of the European Union, there were almost 10 million hectares in 2012, constituting 5.6 percent of the agricultural land. Compared with 2003 (5.7 million&#xD;
hectares), the organic land increased by 75 percent. In 2012, the area increased by 0.54 million hectares or six percent.&#xD;
&gt; The country with the largest organic agricultural area is Spain (1.6 million hectares), followed by Italy (1.2 million hectares), Germany and France (both slightly over 1&#xD;
million hectares).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FiBL and IFOAM</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-02-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25255/1/Willer-et-al-2014-2014-03-05-online.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga; Schaack, Diana; Schlatter, Bernhard and Lernoud, Julia    (2014) Europe: Current Statistics.    In:   Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM) (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends 2014 [online version].  FiBL and IFOAM, Frick and Bonn, pp. 200-207.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25255/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>