<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Suitability of leguminous cover crop pollens as food source for the green lacewing Chrysoperla externa (Hagen) (Neuroptera: Chrysopidae).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Venzon, Madelaine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rosado, Maria C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Euzébio, Denise E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Souza, Brígida</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schoereder, José H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Diversification of crops with species that provide suitable pollen for predators may reduce pest population on crops by enhancing predator effectiveness. In this paper we evaluated the suitability of leguminous cover crop pollens to the predatory green lacewing Chrysoperla externa (Hagen). The predator is commonly found in coffee agroecosystems and the plant species tested were pigeon pea and sunn hemp, which are used in organic coffee systems. Newly emerged females and males of C. externa were reared on diets containing pollen of pigeon pea, sunn hemp, or castor bean, used as a control. The reproductive success of C. externa was evaluated when females fed the pollen species and when honey was added to the diets, to verify the predator need for an extra carbohydrate source. Similar intrinsic growth rates were found for females fed on pigeon pea pollen and on sunn hemp pollen but these rates increased significantly when honey was added to the diets. Females fed with pigeon pea pollen plus honey and with sunn hemp pollen plus honey had higher intrinsic growth rates than those fed with castor bean pollen plus honey. Females fed on castor bean pollen only or on honey only, did not oviposit. Leguminous pollen species were equally suitable for C. externa especially when they were complemented with honey. The results suggest that to successfully enhance predator effectiveness, organic coffee plantation should be diversified with plant providing pollen in combination with plant providing nectar.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22722/1/venzon_Suitability.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Venzon, Madelaine ; Rosado, Maria C. ; Euzébio, Denise E. ; Souza, Brígida  and Schoereder, José H.    (2006) Suitability of leguminous cover crop pollens as food source for the green lacewing Chrysoperla externa (Hagen) (Neuroptera: Chrysopidae).  [Adequação do pólen de leguminosas utilizadas em adubação verde como fonte de alimento para Chrysoperla externa (Hagen) (Neuroptera: Chrysopidae).]  Neotropical Entomology, 35 (3), pp. 371-376.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22722/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>