<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biofortification of food chain with selenium</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seppänen, Mervi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kontturi, Juha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartikainen, Helinä</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Selenium (Se) is an essential micronutrient for humans and animals which is circulated&#xD;
to food chain via crop plants. Agronomic biofortification with Se is used in areas where&#xD;
the soil Se content is low and Se deficiency causes health problems. Brassica species&#xD;
are efficient in accumulation of soil Se and therefore an attractive choice of species for&#xD;
biofortification. Se uptake and translocation was studied in B. rapa and B. napus in&#xD;
field experiments applied with 0, 6 or 20 mg Se ha-1 as Na2SeO4 and foliar sprays of&#xD;
30 mg Se ha-1 as Na2SeO4 or Na2SeO3. In addition, a HPLC-ICP-MS based method to&#xD;
identify and quantify organic Se-compounds in seeds and meals was developed. High&#xD;
concentration of Se accumulated in seeds (1.89 μg g-1) and after oil extraction Se&#xD;
remained mainly in the meal fraction (1.34 μg g-1). Foliar spray of Na2SeO4 was most&#xD;
efficient in increasing the meal Se concentration. Selenium specification studies&#xD;
revealed that 68-82 % of Se was in a form of valuable selenomethionine (SeMet).&#xD;
Other Se-compounds were not detected. At rosette stage, Brassica plants had taken&#xD;
up 30-40% of applied Se but the translocation to seeds was low. The results show that&#xD;
agronomic biofortification with Se can improve the nutritive quality of Brassica meal&#xD;
due to high accumulation of SeMet and its stability during processing. The strategy to&#xD;
improve the efficiency of agronomic biofortification with Se in Brassica is discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18292/1/seppanen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seppänen, Mervi; Kontturi, Juha and Hartikainen, Helinä    (2010) Biofortification of food chain with selenium.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18292/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>