<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of band-steaming on microbial activity and abundance in organic farming soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elsgaard, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elmholt, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Martin Heide</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Band-steaming of arable soil at 80–90 °C kill off weed seeds prior to crop establishment which allows an extensive intra-row weed control. Here we evaluated the side-effects of in situ band-steaming on soil respiration, enzyme activities, and numbers of culturable bacteria and fungi in an organic field soil. The results showed that mechanical disturbance created by band-steaming could be neglected as a mediator of microbial changes. Also, soil pH and water content was unaffected by band-steaming. Effects of band-steaming on in situ soil respiration and basal respiration, respectively, were insignificant or slightly stimulatory (P &lt; 0.05). Fluorescein diacetate hydrolysis and arylsulfatase activity were significantly (P &lt; 0.001) inhibited by 25 and 38%, respectively, and only showed weak recovery during 90 days after band-steaming. Bacterial colony-forming units increased after soil steaming whereas the number of fungal propagules was reduced by 50% (P &lt; 0.001). This reduction persisted at a level of 38% after 90 days (P &lt; 0.001). Evaluated in relation natural environmental stresses, band-steaming showed ecologically tolerable short-term effects, but with weaker recovery potential and therefore possible long-term effects. However, band-steaming affects only a minor volume of the plough layer (&lt;10%) and long-term effects may be minimal due to annual tillage (mixing) of the soil. In conclusion, the side-effects on soil microbiology may not disqualify band-steaming as an option in organic farming systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17300/1/Agriculture_Ecosystems_and_Environment_2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Elsgaard, Lars; Elmholt, Susanne and Jørgensen, Martin Heide   (2010) Effects of band-steaming on microbial activity and abundance in organic farming soil.   Agriculture, Ecosystems &amp; Environment, 137 (3-4), pp. 223-230.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17300/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>