<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung des Gemengeanbaus mit Körnerleguminosen sowie der Standraumzuteilung und der Saatstärke auf Kornertrag und Kornproteingehalt von Winterweizen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hof, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtke, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rauber, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In stockless organic farms it is difficult to produce winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) with high protein content. The objective of this study was to evaluate the effects of intercropping of (i) winter wheat with either winter field bean (Vicia faba L.) or winter pea (Pisum sativum L.), (ii) the spatial arrangement (mixed, row or row-strip intercrop) and (iii) the seeding rate of the wheat (100 or 20 %) on yield formation and grain protein content. Monocropped wheat planted at a seeding rate of 20 % significantly out-yielded monocropped wheat at 100 % seeding rate because of a more efficient use of the mineral nitrogen (N) in soil. A gradient in the spatial and temporal use of mineral soil N by the wheat was found. N was available in particular from deeper soil layers during the grain filling phase in row strip intercrop trials, resulting in a higher grain protein content of the wheat. Monocropped wheat achieved mean protein content levels of 9,9 and 9,4 % at two different sites and protein content increased significantly in mixture (mean: 12,8 and 11,4 %). The highest protein content of 15,4 % was achieved with the row strip intercrop of field bean.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3548/1/3548.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hof, C.; Schmidtke, K. and Rauber, R.    (2005) Wirkung des Gemengeanbaus mit Körnerleguminosen sowie der Standraumzuteilung und der Saatstärke auf Kornertrag und Kornproteingehalt von Winterweizen.  [Effects of intercropping, spatial arrangement and seeding rate on grain yield and grain protein content of winter wheat.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3548/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>