<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>State of the art review - On healthy growth initiatives in the mid-scale values-based chain of organic food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kvam, Gunn-Turid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjørkhaug, Hilde</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the paper is to present results from a review of successful mid-scale organic values-based chains, where characteristics of such chains and their strategies for growth are in focus. The work is part of an EU-project, Healthy Growth, where ten European countries participate. Results are based on reviewed research in each participating country and a general review of research on successful chains. Results show that successful mid-scale values-based chains are characterized by an emphasis on diverse values and product qualities, they emphasize personal relationships between chain actors, are based on a diversity of consciously chosen sale channels both direct and indirect and utilize a variety of communication channels/means to communicate values and product qualities to consumers. They also employ a diversity of organizational forms/structures, where different forms of producer organizations are common in the majority of chains.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-04-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27675/7/27675.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kvam, Gunn-Turid and Bjørkhaug, Hilde    (2014) State of the art review - On healthy growth initiatives in the mid-scale values-based chain of organic food.       Paper at:   IFSA 2014, Berlin, Germany, 1-4 April 2014.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27675/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>