<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) on yield,growth and nutrient contents in organically growing raspberry</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Orhan, Emine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Esitken, Ahmet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ercisli, Sezai</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Turan, Metin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sahin, Fikrettin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During 2003 and 2005, plant growth promoting effects of two Bacillus strains OSU-142 (N2-fixing) and M3 (N2-fixing and phosphate&#xD;
solubilizing) were tested alone or in combinations on organically grown primocane fruiting raspberry (cv. Heritage) plants in terms of yield,&#xD;
growth, nutrient composition of leaves and variation of soil nutrient element composition in the province of Erzurum, Turkey. The results showed&#xD;
that Bacillus M3 treatment stimulated plant growth and resulted in significant yield increase. Inoculation of raspberry plant roots and rhizosphere&#xD;
with M3 and/or OSU-142 + M3, significantly increased yield (33.9% and 74.9%), cane length (13.6% and 15.0%), number of cluster per cane&#xD;
(25.4% and 28.7%) and number of berries per cane (25.1% and 36.0%) compared with the control, respectively. In addition, N, P and Ca contents of&#xD;
raspberry leaves with OSU-142 + M3 treatment, and Fe and Mn contents of the leaves of raspberry with M3 and OSU-142 + M3 applications&#xD;
significantly improved under organic growing conditions. Bacterial applications also significantly effected soil total N, available P, K, Ca, Mg, Fe,&#xD;
Mn, Zn contents and pH. Available P contents in soil was determined to be increased from 1.55 kg P2O5/da at the beginning of the study to&#xD;
2.83 kg P2O5/da by OSU-142, to 5.36 kg P2O5/da by M3 and to 4.71 kg P2O5/da by OSU-142 + M3 treatments. The results of this study suggest&#xD;
that Bacillus M3 alone or in combination with Bacillus OSU-142 have the potential to increase the yield, growth and nutrition of raspberry plant&#xD;
under organic growing conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006-09-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18587/1/ahududuscientia.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Orhan, Emine; Esitken, Ahmet; Ercisli, Sezai; Turan, Metin and Sahin, Fikrettin   (2006) Effects of plant growth promoting rhizobacteria (PGPR) on yield,growth and nutrient contents in organically growing raspberry.   Scientia Horticulturae, 111 (2006), pp. 38-43.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18587/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>