<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Characteristics of spring barley varieties for organic farming. Nutrient acquisition and crop performance</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Dr. Niels Erik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, Senior scientist Ingrid Kaag</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berntsen, Scientist Jørgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It appears that the growth of barley seedlings during spring is restricted by moderate internal deficiency of phosphorus (P) and potassium (K) in most cases. This agrees with the well-known increases of growth and grain yields if P and K fertilizer placement is used in spring barley growing.&#xD;
&#xD;
It is also evident from our earlier work that barley cultivars may differ in the P acquisition from soil (Gahoonia and Nielsen, 2004; Gahoonia and Nielsen, 2003). The existence of cereal varieties differing in the efficiency in P uptake from soil suggests that more nutrient efficient varieties can be identified among the existing varieties.&#xD;
&#xD;
The aim of this work was to study differences between selected barley cultivars in their soil-P and soil-K acquisition to find indication of moderate P and K deficiency in spring barley seedling grown under organic farming conditions at various soil fertility levels.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1453/1/BAR-OF-NEN-O3-paper1.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nielsen, Dr. Niels Erik; Thomsen, Senior scientist Ingrid Kaag and Berntsen, Scientist Jørgen    (2003) Characteristics of spring barley varieties for organic farming. Nutrient acquisition and crop performance.  [Næringsstofoptagelse og afgrøde-performance.]   Working paper, Department of Agricultural Sciences, The Royal Veterinary and Agricultural University.   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1453/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>