<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 8. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LowInputBreeds Consortium,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This has been a busy time for partners of the project, although much of the recent work has involved preparing reports rather than activities that might be of interest to a wider audience. We would like to thank all partners for their cooperation in submitting reports and responding to queries – more or less on time, despite the relatively short notice given for these tasks.&#xD;
Partners have also been preparing technical notes; presenting findings from some of our research to give guidance directly to the industry – more can be read about these on page 14 of this newsletter. Again thank you to all contributors.&#xD;
At the time of writing, we are approaching our 3rd Symposium (see page 14 for details) held in August in conjunction with the 64th Annual Meeting of the European Federation of Animal Science (EAAP, www.eaap2013.org), giving us the opportunity to present findings and make our work accessible to a much wider audience than in the past. Other FP7 projects are also holding satellite meetings at the conference - hence an excellent opportunity to accommodate other findings as we approach the later stages of our project.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2013-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24648/1/LowInputBreeds-Newsletter-no-8-2013.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LowInputBreeds Consortium,     (2013) Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 8. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24648/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>