<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Controlling root flies with exclusion fences?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Siekmann, Gitta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hommes, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Protecting crops with insect fences is currently being considered as an alternative to row cover netting and synthetic insecticides. Previous studies reported efficacies of such fences with 50-90 % reduction in crop damage by root flies. We conducted trials with a 1.70 m fence over two years to monitor carrot rust fly (Psila rosae) in carrots and cabbage root fly (Delia radicum)  in radish. There was a significant reduction in cabbage root fly damage in fenced plots whereas no such effect could be found with carrot rust fly. The structure of the overhang at the top of the fence and the mobility of this particular species may be important elements to consider in fence design. The length of the overhang also seemed to be important for cabbage root fly (Delia radicum) control, as a statistically significant treatment effect was observed only when the overhang was 35 cm long. Using radish as a test crop, the fences reduced damage by 55 % in the second year of the trial. The population size of overwintering cabbage root flies was also an important factor, as the number of flies in the year that the fence was effective was lower than in the previous year.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9072/1/Fence_IOBC_Organic_eprints.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Siekmann, Gitta and Hommes, Martin         (2005) Controlling root flies with exclusion fences?    Biologische Bundesanstalt für Land- und Forstwirtschaft, Institut für Pflanzenschutz im Gartenbau.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9072/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>