<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of the users value of salts against apple scab and powdery mildew for fruit production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Creemers, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Laer, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Van Mechelen, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vorstermans, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hauke, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The research was aimed at finding anti resistance strategies for Integrated fruit growing.&#xD;
As the salts tested may be approvable for organic farming, the trial results are also of&#xD;
value for the development of scab an mildew control strategies for organic fruit growing. As&#xD;
new fungicides are mainly unisite action fungicides, the problem of fungicide resistance&#xD;
development is becoming more important every year. Combining chemical fungicides,&#xD;
which is the best anti-resistance strategy, is not always possible or recommended in the&#xD;
case when the number of available chemical fungicides are limited or a reduction in&#xD;
fungicide use is asked for. Therefore the use of salts as an anti-resistance strategy was&#xD;
looked upon. The salts evaluated were K(HCO3), KH2PO3, KHPO4 and K2SiO3. When&#xD;
using these salts as an anti-resistance strategy the efficacy obtained when spraying the&#xD;
compounds alone was often to low to be used in rotation with chemical fungicides. Only&#xD;
with K(HCO3)2 a good efficacy can be observed in some years. The variation in efficacy&#xD;
with K(HCO3)2 observed is higher for powdery mildew. K(HCO3)2 can be considered as a&#xD;
ideal product for scab control in organic orchards at moments of low infection risk.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13648/1/076-081.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Creemers, P.; Van Laer, S.; Van Mechelen, A.; Vorstermans, B. and Hauke, K.    (2008) Evaluation of the users value of salts against apple scab and powdery mildew for fruit production.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 76-81.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13648/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>