<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming Research Support and Research Priorities in the European Union</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gonzálvez, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlueter, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slabe, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Support for Organic Farming focused research has increased significantly in successive EU research funding frameworks. This is in line with constantly increasing consumer demand for organic foods over the last 20 years, which has accelerated again over the last 2 years in many European countries, including new member states. &#xD;
Under the 7th Framework Programme (FP7), the expected new increase of funds for organic farming could significantly decrease, even below the levels made available under the 5th Framework Programme (FP5). Most of the project topics listed focus on the development of methods for economic analyses of Organic Farming and/or follow a very “reductionist” one problem - one potential solution approach.&#xD;
On the other side, as there is no clear instruments to establish priorities in research programmes at European level. The IFOAM EU Group has developed a consultation process to set  organic farming sector priorities, which could be used as a model to set research priorities in the future. &#xD;
This paper also presents  a first assessment of the EU support to organic farming research, reviewing main achievements in organic food production systems research and proposing some changes in the current 7th Framework Programme.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9899/1/gonzalvez-etal-2007-research-eu.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gonzálvez, V.; Schmid, O.; Schlueter, M. and Slabe, A.    (2007) Organic Farming Research Support and Research Priorities in the European Union.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9899/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>