<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluß der Preisentwicklung von Einzelfuttermitteln in den Jahren&#xD;
2005, 2007 und 2008 auf den Preis von 100% Bio-&#xD;
Legehennen-Alleinfutter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Deerberg, Dr. Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keppler, Christiane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knierim, Prof. Dr. Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Keil, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four layer-mash rations based on 100% agricultural feedstuffs of organic origin and&#xD;
with different levels of energy content were tested at the University of Kassel some&#xD;
years ago. Now it is to investigate the influence of different parts of the feedstuffs in&#xD;
the composition of the rations on the cost of the 100% layer-mash in three years with&#xD;
different costs for the feedstuffs. It is obvious to see, that the price of protein sources&#xD;
like soy-products or some oil cakes (sesame) and the grain legumes ascended about&#xD;
100% from 2005 to 2008. Layer mash with the highest energy level is in all years the&#xD;
most expensive variant. The facts due to concern, that regarding to actual price trends&#xD;
of organic protein sources, it is favourable to reduce energy content of layer mash,&#xD;
leaving static tradition and act sparingly with organic feedstuff resources.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14162/1/Deerberg_14162.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Deerberg, Dr. Friedhelm; Keppler, Christiane; Knierim, Prof. Dr. Ute and Keil, Joachim    (2009) Einfluß der Preisentwicklung von Einzelfuttermitteln in den Jahren 2005, 2007 und 2008 auf den Preis von 100% Bio- Legehennen-Alleinfutter.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14162/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>