<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kaolin clay, a new method for protecting plants against the peach aphid Myzus persicae Sulzer by creating a mineral barrier</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>GARCIN, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The peach aphid Myzus persicae Sulzer is one of the major pests found on peach trees. The CTIFL has been running tests since 2005 to assess the efficacy of Surround® WP, a product containing kaolin that is applied either at the time of leaf fall to prevent winter egg-laying or in the spring to prevent the establishment of fundatrices. The period of application and the production system (organic or conventional) were tested, allowing a comparison with chemical aphicides. The clay product used at leaf fall reduced winter egg-laying by about 50%. Autumn application of Surround® alone was not sufficient to control aphid colonies in the spring, but it could be used as part of a supervised control strategy, combined with the application of mineral oils in late winter.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15470/1/17-Garcin.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>GARCIN, A.    (2009) Kaolin clay, a new method for protecting plants against the peach aphid Myzus persicae Sulzer by creating a mineral barrier.  [L’argile kaolinite, une nouvelle méthode de lutte par barrière minérale protectrice contre le puceron vert du pêcher Myzus persicae Sulz.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 107-113.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15470/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>