<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>OrgTrace – No Difference in Levels of Bioactive Compounds  found in Crops from Selected Organic and Conventional Cultivation Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Knuthsen, Pia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Soeltoft, Malene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, Kristian Holst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bysted, Anette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, Katja H</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen , John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halekoh, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of the present study was to compare the  content of selected bioactive compounds in organically and conventionally grown crops, and to evaluate if the ability of the crops to synthesize selected secondary metabolites was systematically affected by growth systems across different growth years as well as soil types. &#xD;
The results showed that contents of neither polyacetylenes and carotenoids in carrots, flavonoids in onions, nor phenolic acids in carrots and potatoes were significantly influenced by growth system. Thus it could not be concluded that the organically grown crops had higher contents of bioactive compounds than the conventionally grown. This indicates that giving preference to organic products because they contain more bioactive components is doubtfull. However, there are many other reasons for the consumer to choose organic food products, including: no pesticide residues in foods, animal welfare, and environmental protection.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19815/3/19815.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Knuthsen, Pia; Soeltoft, Malene; Laursen, Kristian Holst; Bysted, Anette; Madsen, Katja H; Nielsen , John; Halekoh, Ulrich and Husted, Søren    (2011) OrgTrace – No Difference in Levels of Bioactive Compounds found in Crops from Selected Organic and Conventional Cultivation Systems.   In:     Proceedings of the First International Conference on Organic Food Quality and Health Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19815/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>