<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Catch crops have little effect on P and K availability of depleted soils</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Stoumann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Niels Erik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It is a well-known fact that catch crops have a significant effect on availability and loss of soil inorganic nitrogen (Thorup-Kristensen et al., 2003) and recently marked effects on soil inorganic sulphur dynamics have also been shown (Eriksen and Thorup-Kristensen 2002; Eriksen et al., 2004).&#xD;
&#xD;
However, we know much less about the effect of catch crops on phosphorous (P) and potassium (K) mobilisation and availability for the next crop. After several years of organic cash crop production, e.g. vegetables and cereals, yield levels may gradually be limited by soil P and K availability, depending on the initial status at conversion to organic production principles. This is particularly the case during the establishment phase of certain vegetable cultures with a limited rooting system (e.g. lettuce, leeks, onions).&#xD;
&#xD;
Therefore, it has often been hypothesized that certain catch crops are capable of increasing the availability of P and K when the soil status becomes low.&#xD;
&#xD;
In the VegCatch subproject 'Catch crops as a tool for increasing P bioavailability in soils' we have therefore studied the ability of different catch crop species to mobilise and take up P and K from soils of low availability, as well as the ability of the catch crops deliver P and K to the subsequent main crop.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6165/1/6165.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Lars Stoumann; Pedersen, Anders; Magid, Jakob and Nielsen, Niels Erik   (2005) Catch crops have little effect on P and K availability of depleted soils.  [Efterafgrøder har ringe effekt på P og K forsyningen på udpint lerjord.]  DARCOFenews.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6165/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>