<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innere Qualität von Bioobst</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
Only few data, from samples of trials situated at only one site are available to answer the question above.&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Consumers, retailers, producers and scientists, for different reasons are very interested at the question whether organically grown fruit tastes better and is heathier. Very little comparative data are available.&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
To analyse and compare different parameters of inner fruit quality (sensorial and health-related) from conventional and organic commercial fruit production.&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
In a field study including 10 commercial orchards that form 5 comparison pairs (conv./org) at 5 different sites in all important fruit growing regions of Switzerland fruit samples of cultivar Golden Delicous were picked and analysed. We measured: sensorial score, standard fruit quality (sugar, firmness, acidity); mineral content, content of polyphenols, vitamins, nutritional fibres. We also applied holistic methods such as picture forming methods, feeding preference tests with rats, self degradation tests. Since 2004 we also test the potential of the so called Gas Discharge Visualisation method (GDV; Kirlian Photography).&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
Regularly we found increased contents of polyphenols in organic fruit (10-20 % more). In half of the cases, sensory scores were better for organic fruit, case-wise also fibres and phosphorus content were higher in organic fruit. A “Vitality”-Index, derived from the picture forming method, was well in line with the standard quality and revealed repeatedly up to 60 % higher scores for organic fruit.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Innere Qualität von Bioobst.  [Inner Quality of Organic Fruit.]   Runs 1997 - 2009.      Project Leader(s): Weibel, Franco, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6289/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>