<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innovative design and management to boost functional biodiversity of organic orchards : the ECOORCHARD project</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Warlop, Francois</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Penvern, Servane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herz, Annette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Porcel, Mario</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tchamitchian, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Orchards are perennial cultures, and, especially in organic fruit production it is essential to design and manage orchards in a way which favours beneficials such as insect predators and parasitoids over pests and diseases. As landscape-dominating crops their management affects overall biodiversity in the agricultural landscape. Increasing plant biodiversity and habitats in such a way that beneficials are favoured is called Functional Agro-Biodiversity (FAB). The value of FAB for reducing pesticide use in fruit production is generally acknowledged, and many growers try to increase it. However, they lack situation-specific information about how to drive and assess biodiversity to optimize FAB. &#xD;
ECOORCHARD is therefore combining several approaches: &#xD;
(i) identifying and sharing innovative methods already implemented by fruit growers to increase FAB in EU countries ; &#xD;
(ii) assessing simple methods for farmers to monitor FAB ; &#xD;
(iii) quantifying the effect of FAB-boosting flower strips.&#xD;
The different on-farm sites, scientific trials and a web-based stakeholder platform to collect and share information are important elements to bring the collected experiences and scientific results very directly to the organic fruit growers.&#xD;
Interviews already started in 2015 with advisors and growers will provide useful information on  original practices and methods used in orchard, to be shared during workshops with farmers for empowerment. &#xD;
ECOORCHARD aims to develop appropriate functional biodiversity practices for users’ needs and thus will identify and assess innovative techniques in terms of effectiveness and implementation conditions , carry out classical field experiments, on-farm and multi-site trials and collective workshops involving farmers, researchers and advisory services.&#xD;
More on : http://coreorganicplus.org/research-projects/ecoorchard</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-06-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28921/7/28921.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Warlop, Francois; Penvern, Servane; Weibel, Franco; Herz, Annette; Porcel, Mario; Tchamitchian, Marc and Sigsgaard, Lene    (2015) Innovative design and management to boost functional biodiversity of organic orchards : the ECOORCHARD project.       Poster at:   INNOHORT 2015, Avignon, 8-12 June 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28921/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>