<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rhizospheric changes of fungal and bacterial communities in relation to soil health of multi-generation apple orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Caputo, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nicoletti , F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De Luca Picione , F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manici, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study focused on changes of rhizosphere microbial communities in apple trees in long-term replanted orchards of Central Europe, aiming at developing cropping practices to mitigate replant problems. It started from the evidence of a previous study which showed that a slight modification&#xD;
of root-colonizing fungal communities was responsible for a great increase of plant growth in soil samples which had previously been subjected to a gamma-irradiation cycle (25 kGy for 8 h), as compared to that observed in the corresponding untreated native soils.&#xD;
The study was performed on rhizospheric soil from nine multi-generation apple orchards after a plant growth assay with M9 rootstock plantlets. PCR-DGGE analysis of soil DNA was performed to evaluate fungal and bacterial communities in fallow and replanted soils, as well as corresponding&#xD;
gamma-irradiated samples. Findings showed that rhizospheric fungal and bacterial communities within apple orchards did not differ according to their position within the orchard; while, they showed a shift in the gamma-irradiated soils. Pseudomonas fluorescens, Pseudomonas tolasii, Pseudomonas spp. and Novosphingobium spp. were the bacteria which were mainly attributed to this change. A shifting in composition of Fusarium communities toward F. oxysporum and F. equiseti resulted the most linked to the changes at rhizosphere level after re-colonization; to the contrary, F. venenatum and F. venaceum, Truncatella sp. and Gibellulopsis sp., only occurred in native soils. Findings of this study suggest that disturbance events such as a gamma-irradiation can&#xD;
modify microbial communities in long-term apple orchards thus allowing a soil re-colonization suitable to increase soil suppressiveness.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28774/1/Biological_Control_Caputo%20et%20al.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Caputo, F.; Nicoletti , F.; De Luca Picione , F.  and Manici, L.   (2015) Rhizospheric changes of fungal and bacterial communities in relation to soil health of multi-generation apple orchards.   Biological Control, 88, pp. 8-17.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28774/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>