<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality beef with efficient suckler cow production</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To keep Finnish beef production equivalent to consumption, one has to raise carcass weights and increase the number of suckler cows. At the moment, approximately 40% of the 55,000 suckler cow quota is unused, and less than 10% of beef comes from beef-breed animals. The share of organically produced beef is some 2% of the total production. Thus, suckler cow production is a branch of livestock production which may be increased without quotas. In addition, the demand for its products exceeds the domestic supply. Suckler cow production as such and organic suckler cow production, in particular, is a form of livestock farming especially accepted and valued by consumers. &#xD;
&#xD;
The low interest of producers in suckler cow production is mainly due to its low profitability. The reasons for it are partly a result of harsh natural conditions, partly from unfavourable production structure and a lack of know-how. Suckler cow farms need clear unprejudiced production strategy models in order to ensure efficient and profitable production. &#xD;
&#xD;
The aims of the project are to seek new efficient and profitable production strategies for suckler cow production, to produce information so as to develop suckler cow producers' professional skills, to support the safeguarding of Finnish beef production, to increase the supply of quality beef, organic beef and lamb meat, and to improve the possibilities to utilise the Finnish suckler cow premium quota to the full. &#xD;
&#xD;
This study includes four subcategories: production strategies, feeding strategies, buildings and economics. In production strategies, the effects of different strategy choices to input use and the output achieved by it are studied. The feeding section of the project will focus on the study of forages typical to organic production. In field studies, forage mixes suitable for Finnish natural conditions are sought. In feeding studies, optimal production models for beef carcasses and economical feeding strategies for suckler cows are examined. In grazing studies, possibilities to intensify pasture utilisation with mixed grazing of suckler cows and sheep are sought. In the building section, the functional solutions of large suckler cowsheds are planned and evaluated. The economic return of production is reviewed with profit margin and model calculations, and on the basis of data of actual suckler cow farms. The profitability of investments is calculated by real option method, and calculation forms are developed for advisor use to facilitate planning. &#xD;
&#xD;
The results of the study will be published in scientific and professional journals. A central aim is to produce material for a new edition of a manual on suckler cow production and tools for advice. The results will also benefit the planning of support policies.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Emolehmähanke: Quality beef with efficient suckler cow production.  [Laatulihaa tehokkaalla emolehmätuotannolla.]   Runs 2003 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Heikkilä, Anna-Maija, MTT Agrifood Research Finland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5674/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>