<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reben an verschiedenen Standorten sind unterschiedlich anfällig gegen falschen Mehltau und unterscheiden sich in der Expression von Krankheits-Verteidigungs-Genen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thürig, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Slaughter, Ana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marouf, Elaheh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mauch-Mani, Brigitte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The influence of site on resistance of grapevine (cv. Chasselas) to Plasmopara viticola was evaluated. Grapevine leaves from three vineyards in the region of Lake Neuchâtel (Switzerland) were tested for their susceptibility to P. viticola in the lab in five successive years (2004-2008), and the expression levels of four selected defense-related genes (Glucanase, Lipoxygenase 9, 9-cis epoxycarotenoid dioxygenase, Stilbene synthase) were studied in one year. In all five years of examination, differences between sites were substantial, with plants from site HAU being much less susceptible to P. viticola than plants from site AUV. Susceptibility of plants from a third site varied from year to year. Differences in susceptibility were mirrored in the constitutive expression pattern of four defence-related genes, with samples from the HAU site clearly separated from samples of the other two sites in redundancy analysis.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17701/2/Tamm_17701.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thürig, Barbara; Slaughter, Ana; Marouf, Elaheh; Mauch-Mani, Brigitte and Tamm, Lucius    (2011) Reben an verschiedenen Standorten sind unterschiedlich anfällig gegen falschen Mehltau und unterscheiden sich in der Expression von Krankheits-Verteidigungs-Genen.  [Site-specific field resistance of grapevine to Plasmopara viticola correlates to altered gene expression.]      Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17701/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>