<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A COMPARISON OF SELECTED MILK INDICATORS IN&#xD;
ORGANIC HERDS WITH CONVENTIONAL HERD AS REFERENCE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hanuš, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vorlíček, Zdeněk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sojková, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rozsypal, Roman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vyletělová, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roubal, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genčurová, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pozdíšek, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Landová, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a historical sense, current organic farming is an old-new&#xD;
alternative under changed world conditions. Organic dairying&#xD;
(O) is an alternative of friendly use of the environment in&#xD;
time of presupposed global climate changes. Potential impact&#xD;
of organic farming on raw cow-milk quality, composition and&#xD;
properties, as conpared to conventional milk production (C),&#xD;
were evaluatedin this paper on the basis of selectedm ilk indicators&#xD;
(MIs). Total solids, whey volume, pH of milk fermentation&#xD;
ability (FAM-pH), FAM streptococci, FAM noble lactic acid&#xD;
bacteria, I and Cu were higher in C milk (P&lt;0.05). The alcohol stability (AS), titration acidity, curd firmness (CF), FAM titration acidity (FAM-T), Ca, P, Mg, K and Fe were higher in O milk (P&lt;0.05). No differences( P&gt;0.05) were observed in pH, rennet coagulation time, curd quality, FAM lactobacilli and streptococci/lactobacilli, Na, Mn and Zn. In general, the differences were a little more advantageous for O milk from both technological and nutritional point of view, particularly because of AS (0.46&lt;0.58ml , C vs. O) , CF (1.88&gt;1 .81m m), FAM-T (27.3&lt; 33.8ml of 0.25mol . l ' rNaOH. I00ml r )F, AM-pH ( 5.1 &gt; 4.6 ) , Ca (1172 &lt; l257 mg.kg-1)P, ( 950 &lt; l004 mg. kg-1) and Mg 107.4&lt;ll2.0mg.kg{) results. Organic milk can also produce better environment for yoghurt fermentation. Nevertheless, the results obtained should not be overestimated as both sources produced milk of good quality. Additional results are&#xD;
needed to prove organic milk benefits.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21322/1/Str%C3%A1nky_z_FOLIA_2008_3_4_small.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hanuš, O.; Vorlíček, Zdeněk; Sojková, K.; Rozsypal, Roman; Vyletělová, Marie; Roubal, P.; Genčurová, V.; Pozdíšek, J. and Landová, H.   (2008) A COMPARISON OF SELECTED MILK INDICATORS IN ORGANIC HERDS WITH CONVENTIONAL HERD AS REFERENCE.   Folia Veterinaria, 52 (3-4), pp. 155-159.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21322/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>