<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Use of farm grown cereal/protein mixes by lactating dairy cows in a winter diet</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>COQUIL, X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>TROMMENSCHLAGER, J-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BAZARD, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DESPRES, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DELABY, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We compared the use of three farm grown cereal/protein mixes (oat/fava bean, barley/lupin, triticale/pea), that were used to complement lactating dairy cow diets based on hay consisting of alfalfa/orchard grass and perennial grassland. The trial took place in 2007 at the INRA experimental station of Mirecourt, where an organic mixed-crop dairy system is being prototyped. The experiment was carried out in a Latin square with three groups of eight cows (50% Holstein, 50% Montbéliarde). The cows were fed 4 kg/cow/day of one of the three cereal/protein mixes, 8 kg DM/cow/day of alfalfa/orchardgrass hay, and permanent grassland hay ad libitum. The three diets were indicative of the animals’ needs. Diets had no significant effect on milk production (20.3 kg/cow/d) and milk fat content (41.3 g/kg). However, dairy cows fed with the oat/fababean mix had a significantly lower protein content in their milk. This is the result of: (i) a nitrogen surplus in relation to energy, and (ii) a lower starch content compared to the two other diets. Therefore, in organic mixed-crop dairy systems with forages that are rich in nitrogen, the choice to cultivate mixtures of cereal/pulses and the composition of these mixtures must be primarily based on their agronomic interest and not on their zootechnical one since they are not essential to a balanced animal diet.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15474/1/21-Coquil.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>COQUIL, X. ; TROMMENSCHLAGER, J-M. ; BAZARD, C. ; DESPRES, S.  and DELABY, L.    (2009) Use of farm grown cereal/protein mixes by lactating dairy cows in a winter diet.  [Valorisation par les vaches laitières de mélanges céréales/protéagineux fermiers dans une ration hivernale.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 145-149.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15474/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>