<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Hygienic quality of head lettuce: Effects of organic and mineral fertilizers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wießner, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thiel, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krämer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The hygienic quality of head lettuce (Lactuca sativa L.) was investigated after different fertilizer treatments (fresh farmyard manure, composted farmyard manure, stinging nettle extract and calcium ammonium nitrate) in a 2-year field experiment with two trials per year, respectively. For assessment of the hygienic quality the total aerobic bacterial counts, Enterobacteriaceae, coliform bacteria, Escherichia coli and Salmonella were investigated in soil, fertilizer and lettuce samples. Plants were washed with running tap water before analysis. The total aerobic bacterial count, as well as the levels of Enterobacteriaceae and coliform bacteria tended to be slightly higher (not significant) after organic compared to mineral fertilization. No Salmonella was detected in any soil, fertilizer or lettuce sample, while E. coli was randomly detected in low concentrations independent from fertilizer treatment. No higher risk of bacterial contamination due to the use of organic fertilizers was indicated.&#xD;
(c) Elsevier</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18933/1/JFCO1634_Wiesner_et_al._2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wießner, S.; Thiel, B.; Krämer, J. and Köpke, U.   (2009) Hygienic quality of head lettuce: Effects of organic and mineral fertilizers.   Food Control, 20, pp. 881-886.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18933/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>