<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Possible agents for organic seed treatment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Radics, László</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ertsey, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The quality of seed is the basis of successful organic plant production. Since seed treatment with synthetic chemicals is not allowed in organic farming, it is important to find alternative methods for seed treatment instead of that process. The goal of our research was to find methods that retain good quality of organic seed and assure high field emergence. The experiment consisted of two parts. In the first part, the effects of the chosen materials on germination green pea (Pisum sativum L.) seeds was measured. In the second part, the effect of the chosen materials on the seed-borne fungi Ascochyta sp., and Fusarium moniliforme on corn seed was observed. The chosen methods were warm water, Biokál, Alginit and Vetozán -permitted fertilisers and conditioners in organic farming in Hungary - and oil of thyme. Effects on germination ability were observed in the laboratory and in the field according to international rules (ISTA 2003). The ‘Poisoned agar plate’ method was used to determine the effect of chosen materials on seed-borne fungi. According to our present results, Biokál enhanced germination and thyme oil gave the best inhibition on fungi.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4448/4/radics-ertsy-2005-seed-final.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Radics, László and Ertsey, Anna    (2005) Possible agents for organic seed treatment.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4448/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>