<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Simulated nitrogen leaching, nitrogen mass field balances and their correlation on four farms in south-western Finland during the period 2000-2005</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rankinen, Katri</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salo, Tapio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Granlund, Kirsti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rita, Hannu</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nitrogen (N) gross balance is one of the indicators designed for following developments in agriculture in the European Union. A nutrient surplus occurs when the quantity of a nutrient applied in fertilizers is greater than that removed during harvest. In this study the usefulness of N balance in studying the fate of N and controlling N leaching from agricultural fields in south-western Finland was evaluated. To estimate N leaching in 2000–2005 the mathematical, process-based model COUP was applied to twelve fields representing four agricultural production sectors. The fields represented conventional cereal production, organic cereal production and both conventional cattle and pig husbandry. Simulated N leaching was lowest from cereal production fields with a low N balance. Higher N leaching from pig and cattle production farms might be reduced by decreasing the N balance but also by applying manure in spring instead of autumn. Both N balance and simulated N leaching from organic farm were relatively high compared to low N application rate to the fields. N balance appears to be a rather useful indicator of N leaching over longer periods of time. In the short term, N leaching depends mainly on precipitation and on cultivation practices, like timing and amount of fertilizer application. Statistical evaluation indicated significant positive correlation between calculated N balance and simulated N leaching, especially when supported by constant values of precipitation and N mineralization rate. Decrease of N balance by 1 kg ha–1yr–1 decreased N leaching by 0.3 kg ha–1yr–1. High positive N balances are conducive to abundant accumulation of residual N in soil and consequently to a high risk of N leaching during rainy seasons.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16899/1/rankinen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rankinen, Katri; Salo, Tapio; Granlund, Kirsti and Rita, Hannu   (2007) Simulated nitrogen leaching, nitrogen mass field balances and their correlation on four farms in south-western Finland during the period 2000-2005.   Agricultural and Food Science, 16 (4), pp. 387-406.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16899/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>