<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Growth, competitive strength and herbage quality of herbs in multispecies leys</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Herbs are established in many organic grasslands due to  expected beneficially properties of nutritive value and biodiversity. However, knowledge about grassland herbs is limited. Three mixtures were therefore established at different grazing/cutting management and slurry application. The competitiveness of the species varied very much. Plantain (Plantago lanceolata) and lucerne (Medicargo sativa) competed best under cutting, opposite chicory (Cichorium intybus) that competed best under grazing. Caraway (Carum carvi), burnet (Poterium sanguisorba) and lotus (Lotus coniculatus) had a relative low competitiveness. Slurry application did not affect the proportion of non-leguminous herbs. The nutritive value differed very much. Caraway had the highest and plantain the lowest value, as judged by in vitro organic matter digestibility (IVOMD) and content of NDF, ADF and ADL. Under cutting, the annual yields of the three mixtures were similar.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20624/4/20624.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Søegaard, K.; Eriksen, J. and Askegaard, M.   (2012) Growth, competitive strength and herbage quality of herbs in multispecies leys.   Grass and Forage Science,  , p. 1.    [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20624/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>