<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil GHG fluxes under organic &amp; non-organic agriculture compared: First results from measurements taken in the DOK-Experiment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skinner, Colin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buol, Amanda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fliessbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil management induces nitrous oxide (N2O) and methane (CH4) emissions that account for around 40% of agriculture's direct greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions globally. Nitrous oxide is formed in the soil through a multitude of aerobic and anaerobic microbial processes with broadly varying shares and rates depending on atmospheric and site-specific conditions. Generally, N2O fluxes show a high spatial and temporal variability. A robust finding is that lower nitrogen application rates are associated with lower nitrous oxide emissions.&#xD;
Organic farming systems provide multiple environmental benefits; they foster inter alia agriculture’s mitigation potential concerning climate change. Skinner et al. (2014) evaluated with Meta-Analysis the available global dataset from field measurements comparing organic with non-organic (with synthetic fertilisers and herbicides) agricultural management. They found with high significance that area-scaled nitrous oxide emissions from organically managed soils are 497 ± 160 kg ha-1 a-1 CO2-eq. lower than under non-organic management. Meta-Regression indicated that the main driver of N2O emissions under non-organic farming was N-input, whereas for organic farming concentrations of total soil N and soil organic C (SOC) were responsible. This can be explained by the high bioavailability of synthetic fertiliser and the retarded mineralisation of the N inputs in organic systems; a decoupling in time of N input and consumption. &#xD;
Since August 2012 soil GHG fluxes, N2O, CH4 and CO2, are being sampled in the DOK experiment at Therwil CH. This farming system comparison trial of organic and non-organic treatments was established in 1978. The good documentation of crop management and inputs will be of advantage, e.g. for the endeavour to close knowledge gaps concerning N fluxes and pools in soils under organic management. We present first results from measurements in a winter wheat crop (second vegetation phase) and in a grass-clover corn crop-sequence, as timelines of the gas fluxes underlined with corresponding variables, as well as cumulated values with tested significance of differences.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>BGS Geschäftsstelle</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-02-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25754/1/Poster-BGS-Changings-improved-fin.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Skinner, Colin; Buol, Amanda; Gattinger, Andreas; Fliessbach, Andreas and Mäder, Paul    (2014) Soil GHG fluxes under organic &amp; non-organic agriculture compared: First results from measurements taken in the DOK-Experiment.   In:     BGS Jahrestagung – Böden und ihre Rolle im Ökosystem besser verstehen: Eine systemische Betrachtung, BGS Geschäftsstelle, CH-Changins.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25754/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>