<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kartoffeln mit Zusatznutzen – Antioxidative Kapazität und Erträge&#xD;
ausgewählter blau- und rotfleischiger Kartoffelsorten im ökologischen&#xD;
und integrierten Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hüsing, Bianka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herrmann, M. E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trautz, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hillebrand, Silke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schliephake, Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winterhalter, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a three year research project a representative spectrum of coloured potato varieties&#xD;
were cultivated and tested in detail regarding yield potential and the influence of production&#xD;
systems (organic/integrated). The varying anthocyanin content as well as the&#xD;
antioxidant capacity of the types used were analysed to determine their potential&#xD;
health benefits. Types with a particularly high content undergo further tests to show&#xD;
the influence of the manner of preparation (boiling, steaming, frying) and determine&#xD;
their use for the processing industry. The cultivation of high yield blue types can be an&#xD;
alternative to the cultivation of yellow fleshed high yield types in organic or integrated&#xD;
operating farm companies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14059/1/H%C3%BCsing_14059.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hüsing, Bianka; Herrmann, M. E.; Trautz, Dieter; Hillebrand, Silke; Schliephake, Ulrike and Winterhalter, Peter    (2009) Kartoffeln mit Zusatznutzen – Antioxidative Kapazität und Erträge ausgewählter blau- und rotfleischiger Kartoffelsorten im ökologischen und integrierten Landbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14059/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>