<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Nutzung der Esparsette (Onobrychis viciifolia) im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bücking, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Field trials with four sainfoin cultivars as well as lucerne were carried out on two sites in southern Northrhine - Westphalia from 2003 to 2005. The objective of the experi-ments was to gain experience with the organic cultivation of sainfoin, an old fodder legume known for low yields but a high feeding value, particularly for horses. Crop development, dry matter yield and hay quality were determined. Crop dm yield on a loess soil site with a total lime content of 3207 mg kg-1 was very low (about 1t ha-1) in 2005. Dry matter yield on a loess soil site rich in lime (total lime content = 13974 mg kg-1) was comparatively high in 2004 (first cut: = 7.5 t ha-1), but decreased in 2005 (first cut: 1.6 t ha-1) mainly due to increasing weed infestation. Dry matter yield of sainfoin cv. Visnowsky was always lower compared with Lucerne, while digestable energy content tended to be higher in sainfoin. Sainfoin production may be an interest-ing option for organic horse fodder production, if soils are rich in lime and if weed pressure is manageable.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9630/1/9630_Neuhoff_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Neuhoff, Daniel and Bücking, Katrin    (2007) Untersuchungen zur Nutzung der Esparsette (Onobrychis viciifolia) im Ökologischen Landbau.  [Potential of Sainfoin Production (Onobrychis viciifolia) in Organic Agriculture.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9630/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>