<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Umweltverträgliche Freilandhaltung von Mastschweinen im Ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Outdoor pig fattening can lead to environmental impact due to high nutrients loads and local hot spots of nutrient inputs. In a project fattening pigs were kept outside to assess the input of nutrients (nitrogen, phosphorus and potassium) and nutrient distribution under various management conditions (reducing the daily supply with concentrate by offering field fodder and allocation of the area with field fodder). Finally, huts and troughs were shifted to provide better conditions for the distribution of faeces.&#xD;
With a concentrate diet that contributed to 80 % to the calculated requirements, the nutrient input corresponded with the regulations of the organic farming associations and the EEC-Regulation. A daily ration of concentrate according to the requirements during the finishing period lead to increased nutrient inputs of N and P. Fodder losses due to too small sized pellets and unsuitable troughs increased nutrient losses around the troughs. Due to shifting the equipment (huts, feeding and watering troughs), partial nutrient accumulations in these areas decreased significantly. Dividing the paddock increased the activity of the pigs at this area. More faeces were placed in the paddock and nutrients were distributed in a more uniform way. &#xD;
Results indicate that optimising the management of fattening pigs in outdoor systems can contribute to a high degree to reduce nutrient losses to an acceptable level.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3790/1/3790.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brandt, Michael and Sundrum, Albert    (2004) Umweltverträgliche Freilandhaltung von Mastschweinen im Ökologischen Landbau.  [Environmental sustainable outdoor pig fattening in organic farming.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel, pp. 1-4.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3790/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>