<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The sustainable livelihoods approach: A frame for furthering our understanding of organic farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oelofse, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The rapid development of organic agriculture on a global scale has led to an increased inclusion of producers in developing and transitional countries in the organic food chain. In order to enhance the theoretical frame for the analysis and understanding of the impact that inclusion in the organic food chain has on producers and their families, an analysis was conducted of the use of the Sustainable Livelihoods Approach (SLA). The SLA provides a holistic and integrative approach which researchers can use as the overriding frame for their research. The application of the approach is recommended as it enables us to maintain important elements of the sustainability vision, yet emphasises that a number of assets influence farmers’ livelihoods and it maintains the focus on salience, legitimacy, and credibility in the research.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11662/1/Oelofse_11662_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oelofse, M. and Høgh-Jensen, H.    (2008) The sustainable livelihoods approach: A frame for furthering our understanding of organic farming systems.       Paper at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11662/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>