<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Is there any certification of public organic procurement in iPOPY countries?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On 24 June 1991, the Council of the European Union adopted Regulation (EEC) No 2092/91 on organic production of agricultural products and indications referring thereto&#xD;
on agricultural products and foodstuffs. As well as defining the required method of production of crops and livestock they also regulate labelling, processing, marketing, import and inspection. The research project iPOPY compares and analyses procedures for certification of food-serving outlets within its participating countries&#xD;
(Norway, Denmark, Finland and Italy) using Germany as a reference. While Denmark chooses government agencies to carry out the inspection and certification, Italy, Finland, Norway and Germany choose a state-supervised private system. With the exception of Italy all have a national organic label. Currently only Germany has publicly adopted a standard organic certification programme for the out of home sector. Of the countries analysed, Norway has the most similar system, whereas Denmark and Finland offer operators defined categories of organic use. Though Italy leads in organic use in schools there appears to be no national or other verification system in operation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-06-19</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17453/1/2009_CS_AKL_s57-66.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strassner, Carola and Løes, Anne-Kristin    (2009) Is there any certification of public organic procurement in iPOPY countries?   In:     Proceedings of the Workshop on Organic Public Catering, pp. 57-66.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17453/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>