<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The influence of farm and herd factors on the health status of organic dairy cattle under low concentrate feeding considering an assessment-tool for siterelated breeding</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Selle, Margret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spengler Neff, Anet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reiber, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valle Zárate, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objectives of this study were to examine influences of farm and herd factors on the health status of Swiss organic dairy cattle and to evaluate if an existing estimation tool is suitable to express impacts of not-site-related breeding on herd health and reproduction indicators in 72 organic dairy farms with low concentrate feeding. Farm and herd factors were body condition scores, milk recording data, and farm management characteristics. Data from an existing estimation tool to describe farm and cow ‘types’ and the site-relatedness of breeding was also included. Health status was assesses by herd means of calving interval, fat-to-protein ratio, somatic cell score, veterinary treatments, culling rate, and number of lactation. A relation between the site-relatedness of cow type and calving interval was found. Further factors influencing the herd health status were mainly related to feeding. Also cow type factors had an effect, which is why strategies for improving animal health should include both feeding and breeding practices and consider sight-relatedness of breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27936/1/Selle%202012%20-%20Farm%20%2B%20herd%20factors%20animal%20health%20site-relatedness.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27936/7/Pr%C3%A4sentationSELLE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Selle, Margret; Ivemeyer, Silvia; Spengler Neff, Anet; Reiber, Christoph and Valle Zárate, Anne    (2012) The influence of farm and herd factors on the health status of organic dairy cattle under low concentrate feeding considering an assessment-tool for siterelated breeding.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries, vTI Agriculture and Forestry Research, Special Issue, no. 362 , pp. 324-330.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27936/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>