<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kraut- und Knollenfäule im Kartoffelanbau - ist im ökologischen&#xD;
Anbau eine wirksame Bekämpfung ohne Kupfer möglich?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dorn, Brigitte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Musa, Tomke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krebs, Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fried, Padruot</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In laboratory, growth chamber, micro-plot and small-plot field trials, 53 copper-free&#xD;
preparations (CFPs) were examined for their potential to control potato late blight&#xD;
(PLB) caused by Phytophthora infestans (PI). In-vitro, 43% of the CFP inhibited the&#xD;
germination of sporangia or the mycelial growth of the pathogen completely. In growth&#xD;
chamber trials, 21% of them reduced PI foliar blight of tomato seedlings by at least&#xD;
80%. In contrast, in small-plot field trials with potatoes under practice like applications,&#xD;
none of the CFPs sufficiently controlled the disease. Even in micro-plot field trials with&#xD;
applications twice a week the efficacies did not exceed 60%. With in-vitro tests we&#xD;
showed that the reason for the insufficient performance of the CFPs was due to their&#xD;
lack of persistence and rainfastness. However, applications of copper fungicides with&#xD;
low rates according to the decision support system Bio-PhytoPRE resulted in a good&#xD;
control of late blight. We recommend using this strategy until CFPs are developed for&#xD;
practise application.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14095/1/Dorn_14095.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dorn, Brigitte; Musa, Tomke; Krebs, Heinz; Fried, Padruot and Forrer, Hans-Rudolf    (2009) Kraut- und Knollenfäule im Kartoffelanbau - ist im ökologischen Anbau eine wirksame Bekämpfung ohne Kupfer möglich?       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14095/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>