<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Implications of genotype and amino acid sup-ply on pork quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Acosta Aragon, Dr. Yunior</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulze-Langenhorst, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bütfering, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henning, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stalljohann, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An experiment was conducted to evaluate the effect of different feeding regimes and genotypes on growth performance, carcass characteristics, composition and eating quality of pork under organic framework conditions. 198 individually housed pigs of 4 genotypes were allocated to three dietary treatments. Feeding regimes differed in relation to the supply of limiting amino acids (AA). The genotypes used were Pi x (DL x DE); Du x DL, Pi x German Swabian Hall (Pi x SH) and pure SH breed.&#xD;
While Pi x (DL x DE) pigs showed the highest carcass yields, pigs of the genotype Du x DL achieved higher values in dlwg and in meat composition compared to the other genotypes. &#xD;
Performance traits were significantly influenced by the feeding regime. Lean meat percentage and area of M.l.d. were significantly lower when a diet reduced in limited amino acids compared to the control treat-ment was fed. Backfat thickness was not influenced by the feeding regime. However, intramuscular fat content clearly increased when a diet without AA supplementation was fed.&#xD;
The results indicate that the limited availability of high quality feedstuffs in organic farming does not impair but improve the preconditions to produce pork of high eating quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7347/1/7347_QLIF_Pork_Quality.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert; Acosta Aragon, Dr. Yunior; Schulze-Langenhorst, C.; Bütfering, L.; Henning, M. and Stalljohann, G.    (2006) Implications of genotype and amino acid sup-ply on pork quality.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7347/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>