<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nachhaltige Fruchtfolgesysteme für den biologischen Energiepflanzenanbau in Österreich</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hrbek, Regina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amon, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Biogas production is a key technology for sustainable use of biomass from agricultural production. An optimisation of biogas production from energy crops should not confine to the consideration of the biogas process. To assure a durable success, cropping of energy plants has to be designed according to the principles of sustainable crop rota-tions. Only in site-adapted and ecologically balanced crop rotation systems, energy crop production is meaningful. The general aim of this study was to develope site-adapted crop rotation systems including energy crops as main and catch crops. &#xD;
Study regions were chosen to represent large regions of Austria. To include a great share of the crop species relevant for Austria, sites from the dry region (NUTS III region „Weinviertel”), the transition zone (NUTS III region „Mostviertel-Eisenwurzen, Northern part“) and the Northern Alps (NUTS III region „Mostviertel-Eisenwurzen, Southern part) were chosen.&#xD;
 Altogether, three different categories of model crop rotations were designed:&#xD;
1.	Typical regional model crop rotations&#xD;
2.	Crop rotations for energy crop production (I) with the aim of optimising methane hectare yields considering ethical and economic guidelines&#xD;
3.	Crop rotations for energy crop production (II) with the aim of maximal methane hectare yields &#xD;
The methane hectare yields in organic crop rotations I amounted to around 830 to 1700 Nm3 ha-1 a-1. Crop rotations II yielded around 2430 to 3650 Nm3 ha-1 a-1. Highest values were achieved on farms with a great share of energetically used fodder crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9395/1/9395_Hrbek_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hrbek, Regina; Freyer, Bernhard; Amon, Thomas and Friedel, Jürgen K.    (2007) Nachhaltige Fruchtfolgesysteme für den biologischen Energiepflanzenanbau in Österreich.  [Sustainable crop rotations for organic energy crop production in Austria.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9395/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>