<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Produktionsaufbau und Qualitätssicherung für Bio-Jungbäume und Bio-Jungreben</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently no reliable modern growing methods for high quality plantlets are available for organic fruit tree and grapevine nurseries, suitable for Swiss conditions. Such methods need to be developed. &#xD;
&#xD;
Since 2005 organic fruit and wine producers have to use plantlets from organic nurseries. Currently, prices for these plants are higher and their external quality is lower than that of conventional plants. Therefore organic growers and nurseries have expressed their urgent demand for improved production techniques to reach an “as-conventional” quality of the organic plantlets.&#xD;
&#xD;
As part of the project on-farm research trials are carried out on: &#xD;
i) different fertilization concepts; &#xD;
ii) substitution of ramification-hormones (manual methods or natural substances); &#xD;
iii) use of mycorrhiza; specific soil bacteria; &#xD;
iv) optimization and innovation of plant protection; methods to improve weed control; and between-row management (cover plants);&#xD;
v) tests on rootstock production; vi) elaboration of quality criteria for organic tree and grapevine plantlets &#xD;
Regular consultation and follow-op of organic tree nurseries are carried out.&#xD;
&#xD;
Results&#xD;
-Fertilization with high levels of nitrogen in the spring did not result in the best quality trees.&#xD;
-Firsts results with soil bacteria products show that it might be possible to work with less nitrogen fertilization.&#xD;
-Use of foliar fertilizers did not improve tree quality.&#xD;
- So far, the best substitute of ramification hormones is the mechanical method (Pleuzen).&#xD;
- Soil management control between rows: Covering the soil with organic material (China straw) or with plastic foil (Mypex) and sowing with annual legumes or Phacelia represent practical possibilities.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Organic fruit tree and grapevine nurseries: Produktionsaufbau und Qualitätssicherung für Bio-Jungbäume und Bio-Jungreben.  [Establishment and quality assurance of organic fruit tree and grapevine nurseries.]   Runs 2002 - 2008.      Project Leader(s): Suter, Francisco; Weibel, Franco and Tschabold, Jean-Luc, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6208/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>