<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming as A Development Strategy: Who are Interested and Who are not?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Much evidence shows that implementation of organic farming (OF) increases productivity in the Global South, and that&#xD;
it will be possible to feed a growing world population with food produced in OF systems. OF is explored, analysed and&#xD;
discussed in relation to the principles of Ecology, Health, Care and Fairness as enunciated by IFOAM, as a developmental strategy.&#xD;
Major financial powers are involved in the agro-related industries. A number of civil society-based organisations point to the major negative side effects of the trade with and use of agro-chemical products environmentally and in the further deepening of the gaps between rich and poor. The MDGs target the environmental sustainability explicitly, and OF is regarded as being a relevant strategy to meet many goals. A global development strategy is needed that explicitly includes future generations, ecosystems, biodiversity and plant and animal species threatened by eradication.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CCSE</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16791/1/16791.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vaarst, Mette   (2010) Organic Farming as A Development Strategy: Who are Interested and Who are not?   Journal of Sustainable Development, 3 (1), pp. 38-50.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16791/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>