<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Concentrations of soil potassium after long-term organic dairy production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Øgaard, Anne Falk</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On five long-term organic dairy farms aiming at self-sufficiency with nutrients, soil concentrations of ammonium-acetate lactate extractable potassium (K-AL) and acid-soluble K was measured twice in topsoil (0-20 cm) and subsoil (20-40 cm) over periods of 6-14 years. Organic management had occurred for &gt;9 years at the second sampling. On average there were most probably field level K-deficits. Even so, topsoil K-AL concentrations were medium high (65-155 mg K kg–1 soil), and did not decrease during the study period. However, for three farms, topsoil K-AL was approaching a minimum level determined by soil texture, where further decrease is slow. Subsoil K-AL concentrations were generally low (&lt;65). The soils were mostly light-textured, and reserves of K-releasing soil minerals (illite) were low, never exceeding 6% of the mineral particles &lt;2 mm diameter. Topsoil acid-soluble K concentrations were low (&lt;300 mg K kg–1 soil) on two farms, medium (300–800) on three farms and decreased significantly on one farm. Cation-exchange capacity increased on two farms. This may indicate increased amount of expanded clay minerals caused by K-depletion. On self-sufficient organic dairy farms, purchased nutrients will be required by low soil nutrient reserves to avoid seriously decreased yields and quality of crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Channel View Publications</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Jules, Pretty</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5244/1/jas_010_%28loesogaard%29.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Løes, Anne-Kristin and Øgaard, Anne Falk   (2003) Concentrations of soil potassium after long-term organic dairy production.   International Journal of Agricultural Sustainability, 1 (1), pp. 14-29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5244/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>