<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>„Ökologische Modernisierung“ durch Biologischen Landbau in Österreich?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schermer, Dr. Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Europe</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is finding increasingly widespread acceptance. The paper tries to examine whether the growth of organic farming is also connected with a transformation of economy and society under the heading of “ecological modernisation”. We use the example of Austria which is the EU-country with the highest percentage of organic farm area. The results of a survey undertaken in the frame of the EU-Project „Further Development of Organic Farming Policy in Europe, with Particular Emphasis on EU Enlargement“, EU-CEE-OFP are interpreted along the grid of ecological modernisation (GIBBS, 2000). The analysis suggests that the impact of organic farming was so far moderate and only towards a weak form. However there is a certain future potential in the combination of organic with regional development.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3341/1/3341.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schermer, Dr. Markus    (2005) „Ökologische Modernisierung“ durch Biologischen Landbau in Österreich?  [Ecological modernisation by organic farming in Austria?]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3341/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>