<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Produktionskosten von ökologischem Rindfleisch in ausgewählten Ländern &#xD;
der erweiterten Europäischen Union</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Dr Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deblitz, Dr Claus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The comparison of production costs in selected West and East European countries will give a first idea of possible international trade relationships in the organic beef sector. Via selection of typical farms in five countries, it can be shown that there are lower production costs in the Czech Republic. Nevertheless they are not as pronounced as it could have been expected. Differences in labour productivity are supposed to be the main reason for that. On the other hand the prices for organic beef are much higher in the West European countries, so that for East European farmers and processors a production and export incentive does exist. But for the time being, the organic processing sector is almost completely missing. The establishment of a processing sector in these countries will need time, so that reactions on West European markets at the moment are not very likely.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3400/1/3400.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zander, Dr Katrin and Deblitz, Dr Claus    (2005) Produktionskosten von ökologischem Rindfleisch in ausgewählten Ländern der erweiterten Europäischen Union.  [Production Costs of Organic Beef in selected countries of the Enlarged European Union.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3400/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>