<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of distribution of quebracho extracts on experimental Haemonchus contortus infections in goats</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>V., Paolini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., Prevot</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ph., Dorchies</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H., Hoste</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effects of tannins on adult populations of Haemonchus contortus, Trichostrongylus colubriformis and Teladorsagia circumcincta&#xD;
in goats are characterised mainly by a decrease in egg excretion without any significant changes in worm number. In contrast,&#xD;
the impact of tannins on T. colubriformis or T. circumcincta third-stage larvae (L3) is associated with a significant reduction in worm&#xD;
establishment. The objective of the present study was to examine the effects of quebracho extract tannins on H. contortus L3. The&#xD;
consequences of consumption of sainfoin hay were also examined.&#xD;
Twenty-one naı¨ve kids were divided into three experimental groups. Group Q received quebracho extract and group S received&#xD;
sainfoin hay from days D3 to D5. Group C remained as an infected control group. All kids received 1500 L3 H. contortus on D0, D1&#xD;
and D2. On D18, post-infection, the kids were slaughtered and the worm populations compared in the different groups. Compared&#xD;
to the control values, the worm counts decreased, respectively, by 33% and 38% in groups Q and S but the differences were not significant.&#xD;
No differences were found in pathophysiological measurements between the three groups. The results confirm differences in&#xD;
tannin effect according to nematode species but not parasitic stage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6991/1/VETJOURNAL.PDF</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>V., Paolini; F., Prevot; Ph., Dorchies and H., Hoste    (2002) Effects of distribution of quebracho extracts on experimental Haemonchus contortus infections in goats.   In:     The Veterinary Journal (170), pp. 260-263.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6991/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>