<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of apple scab by curative applications of biocontrol agents</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kunz, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mögel, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hinze, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volk, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic apple growing protective applications with copper, sulphur or lime sulphur are&#xD;
used for apple scab control. Protective applications have to be repeated when new leaves&#xD;
unfold. The timing of protective sprays depends on the weather forecast. If forecasted&#xD;
infection conditions fail to appear, treatments were for nothing. With curative control&#xD;
agents available, the number of treatments could be reduced. In greenhouse trials we&#xD;
tested control agents for their protective and curative efficiency against apple scab after&#xD;
artificial inoculation of potted apple trees. Applications were done 2 hours before&#xD;
inoculation, 5 hours after inoculation on wet leaves, 5 hours after inoculation during&#xD;
simulated rainfall or 24 hours after inoculation on wet or dry leaves. The optimal time of&#xD;
application differed between the preparations tested. Vitisan and OmniProtect had their&#xD;
highest activity when sprayed curative 24 hours after inoculation. Combinations were&#xD;
found, which revealed a high efficiency against apple scab from 2h before to 24 hours after&#xD;
inoculation. In a field trial apple scab was effectively controlled by curative applications of&#xD;
OmniProtect.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13645/1/062-067.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kunz, S.; Mögel, G.; Hinze, M. and Volk, F.    (2008) Control of apple scab by curative applications of biocontrol agents.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 62-67.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13645/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>