<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>On-Farm Risikoanalysen zur Entwicklung von&#xD;
Kontrollmaßnahmen bei Kreuzkraut-Arten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Suter, Dr. Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Dr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Poisonous Senecio species occur in grasslands of various countries. Their further&#xD;
spread into farmland must be prevented, but efficient methods for their control are&#xD;
often lacking, especially under organic farming. We propose on-farm surveys&#xD;
designed as case-control studies to assess the risk for the occurrence of such species&#xD;
and present results of a study on S. aquaticus. Following a case-control design, 72&#xD;
plots were evaluated for their botanical composition, half the plots contained S.&#xD;
aquaticus. For all the plots, the soil nutrients and the details of management practice,&#xD;
such as type and intensity of management and fertiliser application, were recorded&#xD;
from the farmer. There was a high risk for occurrence of S. aquaticus with low nitrogen&#xD;
fertilisation, with a decrease of management intensity in the preceding 15 years, high&#xD;
inclination, and gaps in the sward. For the long-term control of S. aquaticus, we&#xD;
suggest promoting dense swards and preventing sward damage as much as possible.&#xD;
This paper demonstrates the great power of case-control studies in on-farm research.&#xD;
The design allows thorough statistical testing using generalised linear models and&#xD;
provides reliable results in relatively short time. Various questions can be linked to the&#xD;
management practice on farms and over a wide range of environmental conditions.&#xD;
Such data can hardly be obtained from small plot experiments.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14023/1/Suter_14023.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Suter, Dr. Matthias and Lüscher, Dr. Andreas    (2009) On-Farm Risikoanalysen zur Entwicklung von Kontrollmaßnahmen bei Kreuzkraut-Arten.  [On-farm risk-assessment supports the control of Senecio species.]      Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14023/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>