<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bekämpfung des Schneeschimmels (Microdochium majus) bei Winterweizen mit Naturstoffen – vom Labor ins Feld</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vogelgsang, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bänziger, Irene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krebs, Heinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Legro, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sanchez-Sava, Victor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Forrer, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The fungal pathogen Microdochium majus, causing snow mould, seedling blight or foot rot results in severe yield losses in small grain cereals. There are few options to control this pathogen in organic production. In this study, aqueous extracts and powders from the botanicals chamomile, meadowsweet, thyme and Chinese galls were tested in vitro against M. majus conidia germination and mycelial growth. Subsequently, powders of three chosen botanicals were tested for their effect on emergence of M. majus infected wheat seedlings from soil in climate chambers. Furthermore, seed treatments with warm water, a commercialised bacterial product and one chosen botanical were tested in a field experiment throughout three consecutive years. Of the botanicals tested, Chinese galls showed the highest efficacy in controlling M. majus, reducing conidia germination and mycelial growth by up to 97 and 100 %, respectively. In the growth chamber, an application with Chinese galls compared with the control treatment increased total seedling emergence by up to 57 %. In the field, yield increase through Chinese galls, the bacterial product and the warm water treatment compared with the control was 19, 10 and 37 %, respectively. This study demonstrated the potential of Chinese galls to control M. majus in wheat.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21458/1/21458_Vogelgsang.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vogelgsang, Susanne; Bänziger, Irene; Krebs, Heinz; Legro, Robert; Sanchez-Sava, Victor and Forrer, Hans-Rudolf    (2013) Bekämpfung des Schneeschimmels (Microdochium majus) bei Winterweizen mit Naturstoffen – vom Labor ins Feld.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21458/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>