<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Environmental and economic benefit of new fungus-tolerant grape varieties and their usability for different training systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schwab, A. L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knott, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schottdorf, W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Five selected new fungus-tolerant vitis vinifera L. grape varieties from different German grape breeders were tested over a periode of five years under cool climatic conditions with a special taxation of environmental and economical benefits  for different training systems. REGENT, RONDO, JOHANNITER and Gf 48-12 obtained a better wine quality ranking than PINOT NOIR  and  SILVANER, respectively, and can be recommended for sustainable viticulture to reduce fungicide applications. The new fungus-tolerant varieties are usable for most training systems depending on the expected yield and wine quality. A reduced pesticide application lowers the plant protection costs and increase the financial  benefits of the winegrowers.  The reduction in working time and costs depends on the climatic conditions of the annual season. In average, the saved costs range between 400 to 1000 €/ha  and year, especially at steep slopes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2066/1/2066-schwab-a-et-al-2001-tolerance-eco.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schwab, A. L.; Knott, R. and Schottdorf, W.    (2001) Environmental and economic benefit of new fungus-tolerant grape varieties and their usability for different training systems.  [Benefice écologique et économique de nouveaux cepages tolerant aux maladies fongiques et leur emploi dans différents systèmes de conduite.]  In:     Proceedings of the 12th GESCO congress 2001 in Montpellier, France, I, pp. 201-204.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2066/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>