<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ethical Consideration in Livestock Breeding</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The first LowInputBreeds Symposium was organised by the LowInputBreeds project partners Wageningen UR Livestock Research and the Danish Centre for Bioethics and Risk Assessment of the University (CeBRA) of Copenhagen in cooperation with ECO AB, the European Consortium for Organic Animal Breeding.&#xD;
The aim of the symposium was to discuss the plans and progress in LowInputBreeds in an early stage of the EU-project with stakeholders. For the symposium farmers and policy workers from governmental and non-governmental organisations were invited. Special attention was paid to possible ethical issues in organic and free range systems of livestock production as considered by the LowInputBreeds project. CeBRA had arranged for facilitators and a structure to discuss in species specific workshops these ethical issues.&#xD;
The proceedings of the symposium contain abstracts of the plenary and species specific presentations, links to the presentations and reports on the workshops per species.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Leenstra, Ferry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Klint Jensen, Karsten</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Butler, Gillian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Baker, Brian</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Maurer, Veronika</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22524/1/leenstra-etal-2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leenstra, Ferry; Klint Jensen, Karsten; Butler, Gillian; Baker, Brian; Willer, Helga and Maurer, Veronika (Eds.)    (2012) Ethical Consideration in Livestock Breeding.   Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick, Switzerland.  Proceedings of First LowInputBreeds Symposium, Wageningen, The Netherlands, 15-16 March 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22524/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>