<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impediments to plant health in table grape production in southeastern France</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>REYNAUD, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At the La Tapy Experimental Station in southeastern France, a plot of table grapes is managed according to the principles of organic farming in order to study potential technical impediments of this growing system compared to another plot that is managed according to the principles of sustainable agriculture. Muscat de Hambourg, the variety common to these two plots, is used as a reference for the different observations. Results are primarily related to the impact of pest management efficiency on vine quality. The qualitative requirement that powdery mildew be absent on table grapes is difficult to fulfil in the case of organic farming, even with several different treatments and frequent applications. Botrytis management is related to climatic conditions; disease prevention is therefore essential. Small populations of grapeberry moths (Lobesia botrana) and the absence of grape bud moths (Eupoecilia ambiguella) on those plots, as well as the efficacy of specific treatments, even in the context of biological control, using products containing Bacillus thuringiensis, led to either none or negligible damage on the two observed plots. Monitoring of grape leaf hopper populations (Empoasca vitis) revealed that there was no increase in the larva population. The stable level of auxiliaries on this plot partially explains the low incidence of Empoasca vitis.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15469/1/16-Reynaud.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>REYNAUD, C.    (2009) Impediments to plant health in table grape production in southeastern France.  [Les verrous phytosanitaires en production de raisin de table dans le Sud-est de la France.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 101-106.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15469/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>