<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farming across the years: temporal and spatial dimensions of learning organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seppänen, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koskimies, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming, it is generally accepted that a long-term perspective spanning across the&#xD;
years is necessary for the sustainability of organic field management. This paper analyzes the&#xD;
crossing over of annual boundaries during an organic inspection in an attempt to show how&#xD;
the long-term perspective is learnt in the practical organic vegetable farming. Within the&#xD;
speech turns that refer across the years, two main topics emerged. The first is the nutrient&#xD;
management, which was connected with plant growth and environmental regulations. The&#xD;
second is the sequence of crop rotation, appearing both as a list, detached from the fields, and&#xD;
as a temporal process of the fields. A weed problem, caused by couch grass, was repeatedly&#xD;
referred to by the farmer. It was not addressed at all from the several years’ perspective. The&#xD;
results suggest that the nutrient issue within the administrative rules heavily impacts on&#xD;
organic farming. This leaves other important issues concerning production, such as the longterm&#xD;
weed management, with little emphasis. Reasons for this are discussed in the context of&#xD;
the sustainability of environment and production. Crossing over temporal boundaries is linked&#xD;
with many other boundaries.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17584/1/sepp%C3%A4nen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seppänen, L. and Koskimies, H.    (2002) Farming across the years: temporal and spatial dimensions of learning organic farming.       Paper at:   Farming and rural systems research and extension - local identities and globalisation : 4th European IFSA symposium, Florence, Italy.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17584/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>