<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proceedings of the seminar Environmental friendly food production system: requirements for plant breeding and seed production</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>General objective of the seminar ENVIRFOOD is to bring together plant breeders, seed producers, specialists of variety testing of Baltic countries (Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania) and organic agriculture experts from EU for facilitation the exchange of knowledge and expertise between conventional and organic plant breeding, variety testing, seed production and food processing in order to provide successful implementation of EU regulations 2092/91, 1257/1999 and 1452/2003 in the Baltic States. Participants from nine states took part in the seminar. With experience in the breeding of new varieties, their evaluation and seed production for organic management system introduced experts from Germany, Denmark, the Netherlands and Italy. Sector specialists gathered information and analysed current situation in the Baltic States and compared it with situation in others European countries. &#xD;
Proceeding book covers current problems and future prospects regarding to organic plant breeding, variety testing and seed production, and organic farming in general in the Baltic States and in the old EU States. This book will address for researchers, students, practical agriculturists and functionaries who are conncted with problems of organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>NGO "Aleksandra Pelēča lasītava" at Dižstende:State Stende Plant Breeding Station</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Belicka, Ina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Viklante, Mara</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Arbidans, Maris</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5190/1/ENVIRFOOD_2005.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Belicka, Ina; Viklante, Mara and Arbidans, Maris (Eds.)    (2005) Proceedings of the seminar Environmental friendly food production system: requirements for plant breeding and seed production.   NGO "Aleksandra Pelēča lasītava" at Dižstende:State Stende Plant Breeding Station.  Proceedings of Environmental friendly food production system: requirements for plant breeding and seed production (ENVIRFOOD) FP-2003-SSA-1-007003, Talsi, Latvia, May 31-June 3, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5190/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>