<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Life Cycle Assessment of Conventional and Organic Farming in the DOC trial</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nemecek, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gunst, Lucie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaillard, Gérard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The environmental impacts of the conventional and organic farming systems practised in the DOC trial (organic-dynamic, organic and conventional farming) have been assessed by the SALCA life cycle assessment method. Both organic farming systems were more favourable for the environment in all investigated impacts per area unit. When analysed per product unit, clear advantages of organic farming were found for ecotoxicity and the use of mineral resources, while energy use and eutrophication were similar to conventional farming. Reducing fertilisation by 50% led to lower or equal environmental impacts for all systems, depending on the impact category and the functional unit. The analysis of single crops revealed large differences that are partly counterbalanced by other crops in the crop rotation. The eco-efficiency of organic potato production in particular should be improved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4458/3/Nemecek_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nemecek, Thomas; Dubois, David; Gunst, Lucie and Gaillard, Gérard    (2005) Life Cycle Assessment of Conventional and Organic Farming in the DOC trial.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4458/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>