<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entomological and functional role of floral strips in an organic apple orchard: Hymenopteran parasitoids as a case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dib, Hazem</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Libourel, Gilles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Warlop, François</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Habitat manipulation techniques improve the availability of resources required by natural enemies to increase their effectiveness. This study focused on the effects of floral strips on Hymenopteran parasitoid presence. The experiments were conducted during spring 2007 in one organic low-input apple orchard located in south-eastern France. The density and the diversity of parasitic wasps collected from sown floral strips were higher than those from mown plants. The family of parasitic wasps of Braconidae was strongly dominant, followed by Mymaridae and Pteromalidae. By studying 26 flowering species, the greatest diversity and density of parasitic wasps were collected from Potentilla reptans, Achillea millefolium, Trifolium repens and Torilis arvensis. In terms of the early flowering plants, the most important results were observed in Euphorbia helioscopia, Senecio vulgaris and Veronica persica. To give an idea of the functional role of these plants, we studied the parasitic wasps of the diapausing larvae (cocoon) of codling moth Cydia pomonella. We recorded three emerged species: Ascogaster quadridentata, Pristomerus vulnerator and the hyperparasite Perilampus fulvicornis. However, none of these species have been observed on the 26 studied plants. Hence, this result may be suggesting that the studied plants do not have a functional role concerning these parasitoids. These studies may be advantageous for biological control programs in order to select flowering plant species attracting parasitic wasps specific to fruit pests.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-02-18</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21388/1/Dib_et_al_2012_floral_strips_%26_hymenopteran_parasitoids.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dib, Hazem; Libourel, Gilles and Warlop, François   (2012) Entomological and functional role of floral strips in an organic apple orchard: Hymenopteran parasitoids as a case study.   Journal of Insect Conservation, 16 (2), pp. 315-318.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21388/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>