<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends 2012</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Latin America</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2012 documents recent developments in global organic agriculture. “The World of Organic Agriculture 2012“ includes contributions from representatives of the organic sector from throughout the world and provides comprehensive organic farming statistics that cover surface area under organic management, numbers of farms and specific information about land use in organic systems. The book also contains information on the global market for organic food, the latest developments in organic certification, standards and regulations and insights into current status and emerging trends for organic agriculture by geographical region. In addition, the volume contains a number of country reports: Australia, Azerbaijan, Benin, Bulgaria, Canada, Ethiopia, Germany, Iran, Pacific Islands, Peru, Thailand, Turkey, and the United States. “The World of Organic Agriculture“ is published by the Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and the International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM). The project is financially supported by the International Trade Centre (ITC), the Swiss State Secretariat for Economic Affairs (SECO) and Nürnberg Messe, the organisers of the BioFach World Organic Trade Fair.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-02-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25208/1/1581-organic-world-2012.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25208/7/fibl-ifoam-2012-world-of-organic-chinese-s.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/png</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25208/14/world-orgnaic-2012.jpg</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25208/19/agence-bio-2013-CC2012_Chap2_Monde.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)      (2012) The World of Organic Agriculture. Statistics and Emerging Trends 2012.   13 edition. The World of Organic Agriculture . Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL) and International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM), Frick and Bonn .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25208/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>