<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation and registration of plant protection inputs for organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Speiser, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmers may only use those plant protection products which are listed in Annex II B of the ‘Organic Regulation’ 2092/91 and also registered for use at national level. At present, new compounds may only be listed in Reg. 2092/91, if they do not come into direct contact with the crop (although in perennial crops, contact outside the growing season of the edible parts is possible), which is a major obstacle for progress. The EU-funded ORGANIC INPUTS EVALUATION project aims at making Reg. 2092/91 more flexible with regard to new products, while safeguarding the principles of organic farming. Registra-tion under the ‘Pesticide Directive’ 91/414 represents a considerable financial hurdle. The REBECA project will propose registration requirements which are better adapted for biological control agents, plant extracts and other low-risk products. The aim is to accelerate registration and make it more cost-effective, without compromises to the level of safety.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7637/1/Speiser_Tamm_Schmid_2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Speiser, B.; Tamm, L. and Schmid, O.    (2006) Evaluation and registration of plant protection inputs for organic farming.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7637/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>