<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Studies on preventive strategies and alternative treatments against roundworm in organic pig production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borgsteede, Fred H.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaasenbeek, Cor P.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Krimpen, M.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spoolder, H. A. M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thamsborg, S.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vermeer, Herman M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic and many ‘low input’ production standards for pigs require outdoor access, and as a consequence expose the animals to a wide range of potential endo- and ectoparasite infection sources. Conventional anthelmintics are used to control parasitic infections, but their preventive use is banned by the organic standards. The present paper investigates the potential of prevention of infection through better hygiene. Attempts were made to break the infection cycle through thorough pen cleaning 10 weeks after the pigs had been introduced to the pen. Although pen fouling can be reduced, the level of roundworm (Ascaris&#xD;
suum) infection was not reduced. Regular deworming with conventional medication is still required in addition to good hygiene.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19931/1/NJAS94.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borgsteede, Fred H.M.; Gaasenbeek, Cor P.A.; van Krimpen, M.M.; Maurer, Veronika; Mejer, Helena; Spoolder, H. A. M.; Thamsborg, S.M. and Vermeer, Herman M.   (2011) Studies on preventive strategies and alternative treatments against roundworm in organic pig production systems.   NJAS - Wageningen Journal of Life Sciences, 58, pp. 173-176.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19931/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>