<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Expert perspectives on the future of the organic food market: results of a Pan-European Delphi study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Padel, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Foster, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Midmore, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A Delphi Inquiry was carried out to assess the prospect and conditions affecting the overall growth in the European Market for organic products in the coming decade, and to provide support for research. Countries were classified as established, growing and emerging, according to the state of development of their organic market. The survey confirmed the importance of factors influencing the development of the organic food market: the supply base, the role of supermarkets as sales channels and of government support. Organic Producer Initiatives were seen as important in securing a fair deal for organic producers but managerial capacity and professionalism are key challenges for such organizations.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hopkins, A</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11001/1/expert_perspectives_on_the_future_of_the_organic_food_market_results_of_a_pan-european_delphi_study.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Padel, S; Foster, C and Midmore, P    (2004) Expert perspectives on the future of the organic food market: results of a Pan-European Delphi study.   In: Hopkins, A (Ed.)  Organic farming: science and practice for profitable livestock and cropping. Occasional Symposium of the British Grassland Society (37), pp. 39-42.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11001/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>