<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>„Nationale Evaluation der Ökomassnahmen, Bereich Biodiversität“ - Erfolgskontrolle  des ökologischen Ausgleichs hinsichtlich Biodiversität</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Evaluation of different semi-natural habitats in three different landscapes. Effects on different faunal and floral indicator groups.&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
•	Evaluation of different semi-natural habitats on different faunal and floral indicator groups. &#xD;
•	Assessment of key factors altering community of target indicator groups in relation to the landscape. &#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
Three case studies in three different landscapes were performed in order to analyse communities of several arthropod groups (spiders, carabids, butterflies, grasshoppers).  FiBL has focussed on the epigeic fauna (carabids).&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
Ecological compensation areas have altered and partly enhanced carabid communities in all three landscapes. Wildflower strips, hedges and low-input grassland had greatly enhanced carabid. No beneficial effects were found in grassland of high stem trees. Species diversity and abundance of specialized species (stenotopic and microclimatic specilalized) were positively influenced  in all three landscapes. Endangered species were found to be enhanced directly, but they occurred most abundant and partly exclusively in ecological compensation areas. EEffects of ecological compensation areas were altered by several site and anthropogenic factors (age, history, botanical aspects) and finally also by landscape factors (e.g. distance to forest).</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    „Nationale Evaluation der Ökomassnahmen, Bereich Biodiversität“ - Erfolgskontrolle des ökologischen Ausgleichs hinsichtlich Biodiversität.  [Evaluation of biodiversity in ecological compensation areas.]   Runs 1999 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Pfiffner, Lukas and Luka, Henryk, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6342/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>