<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pregled razvoja i obilježja ekološke poljoprivrede u Republici Hrvatskoj</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Petljak, Kristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the last decade, an ever increasing interest of both foreign and domestic academic and general public for organic agriculture can be observed. Organic agriculture, as a new agricultural production system, enables full utilization of farming potentials while satisfying social and economic needs and preserving natural ecosystem and environment. Act on Organic Production of Agricultural Products and Foodstuffs provides an elementary strategic frame for agricultural production development in Republic of Croatia. This article gives an overview of organic agriculture legislation in Croatia and detailed analysis of development periods of organic agriculture. Special emphasis is put on structure of organic production which highlights data on organic plant and animal production in Croatia. The paper provides a comparison between levels of organic agriculture development in the world (with the special emphasis on Europe) and in Croatia, as well as the overview of main obstacles towards more significant development of organic agriculture in Republic of Croatia.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16763/2/16763.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Petljak, Kristina   (2011) Pregled razvoja i obilježja ekološke poljoprivrede u Republici Hrvatskoj.  [Review of development and characteristics of organic agriculture in Croatia.]  Ekonomski vjesnik, 24 (2), pp. 382-396.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16763/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>