<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>From niche to volume with integrity and trust. Case study Fact sheet. Ekodar - Slovenia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borec, Andreja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prišenk, Jernej</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The “Ekodar” organic beef label was established in 2009 by the Šaleška Valley agricultural cooperative. Currently, 76 producers/farmers label their products with the Ekodar brand, which speaks to a onnection of trust between consumers. The meat is available in eleven large producers and retailers, such as Mercator, two organic shops, two agricultural co’ops, as well as online, and delivery is available in twelve cities throughout Slovenia. Marketing and distribution is done via the central umbrella of the Šaleška Valley (owner of the brand) agricultural cooperative. The special characteristic f the “Ekodar” brand is its QR code, which allows consumers to trace the origins of their meat. In using a smart phone to scan QR codes on packaging before purchase, consumers can receive full information about their meat’s farm location, the size of the farm, and the size of the cattle herd on the farm. The main (key) actor of the brand, the Šaleška Valley agricultural cooperative, usually describes the business logic of the food chain before inviting new actors to cooperate. Internally, business plans have been questioned, especially during the first two years of the Ekodar brand’s existence, as there were difficulties involved in promoting it on the market (i.e., they were selling organic beef under the conventional price). Strategic decisions are usually made by the Šaleška Valley agricultural cooperative. The company’s board is mainly concerned with the economic matters. We did not witness internal or external criticisms of the company’s modes of management and governance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28838/7/28838.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borec, Andreja and Prišenk, Jernej    (2015) From niche to volume with integrity and trust. Case study Fact sheet. Ekodar - Slovenia.   University of Maribor, Faculty of Agriculture and Life Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28838/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>