<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Residual effects of previous crops on soil respiration, nitrogen mineralisation and N2O emission</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vinther, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Models for simulating nitrogen leaching are often based on simulations of a number of individual processes in the soil, such as turnover of organic matter, nitrogen mineralisation and immobilisation, nitrification, denitrification etc. It has been found that the models used under Danish conditions (DAISY and/or FASSET) have some limitations especially concerning the turnover of organic matter with implications on e.g. soil respiration. Therefore, the models are being modified and for calibration of the model measurements of in situ soil respiration using a portable CO2-analyser, nitrogen mineralization using a field incubation technique and N2O emission using a static chamber method, were carried out during the growing season 2001. The measurements were carried out on bare soil but with different previous crops in 2000 representing two cropping systems with different input of organic matter. Results are summarised in the table below.&#xD;
&#xD;
Previous crop	        Soil respiration   N mineralisation     N2O emission&#xD;
                         kg CO2-C ha-1	      kg N ha-1	         kg N ha-1&#xD;
Grass-clover	             4109	          91	            2.7&#xD;
Pea-barley/grass 	     4268	          93	            3.3&#xD;
Pea-barley	             4320	          90	            2.6&#xD;
Winter wheat	             3435	          70	            2.6</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1816/1/Abstract_Finn_Vinther_Denmark.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vinther, F.P. and Olesen, J.E.    (2001) Residual effects of previous crops on soil respiration, nitrogen mineralisation and N2O emission.   In:     Abstracts of Cost Action 627 meeting: Carbon Storage in European Grasslands., p. 30.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1816/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>