<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Social development: organic horticulture in São Paulo, Brazil.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Abreu, L.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Networks and ownership</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is increasingly considered a viable alternative model for the design of a new rural society in Brazil, one that is able to make sense of the global economy. Organic farming is increasingly considered as a possible alternative model to design a new rural society in Brazil and making sense in global economy. Farmers in São Paulo have set up collectives, based on new relationships with institutions and urban consumers, in three Brazilian metropolis. The starting point for the research presented here therefore, was the hypothesis that organic farming is a social strategy, committed to creating spaces for agricultural production in order to rebuild rural communities. The research uses an institutional framework to investigate modes of organization, and the dynamic of economic and social relations. Secondly, the authors characterize the process of organic farming as social development in Ibiúna territory, and identify contingent economic and environmental interactions. Thirdly, the authors analyse the evolution of organizational forms through various initiatives to aid production, certification and distribution, and show how stakeholders can select and marginalize farmers. Finally, the paper outlines those elements of social organic development that act as a template for the renewal of farmer associations, and discusses available strategies to reduce the risk inherent in sustaining alternative avenues for organic sector development.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CABI</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5598/1/614BE039.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bellon, S. and de Abreu, L.S.    (2004) Social development: organic horticulture in São Paulo, Brazil.   In:     Book of abstracts, CABI.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5598/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>