<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Economics of Hot Water Dipping</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>P., Maxin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>K., Klopp</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Hot water dipping is an appropriate method to protect apples against spoilage&#xD;
caused by gloeosporium rot. Tests on the varieties Topaz and Ingrid Marie at the&#xD;
OVB Jork (Germany) have demonstrated an effective reduction of spoilage from&#xD;
between 80% and 92% in charges by an infection rate of 40%. The result of an&#xD;
intensive R&amp;D process between 2002 and 2003 is the development of a praxis-tested&#xD;
big box (300 kg) dipping station. With the first Bio Dipping systems now on the&#xD;
market it has now been possible to analyse the economics of this process.&#xD;
The costs of the systems per apple farm have been calculated from the fixed capital&#xD;
costs for the system itself (including maintenance costs) and from the variable costs&#xD;
based on an average crop of 250 t gloeosporium-sensitive varieties, which would be&#xD;
treated with this process every season. The Return on Investment depends largely&#xD;
on the effectiveness of the process in reducing spoilage and on the level of infection&#xD;
within the crop, assuming that losses occur in storage. Based on an average&#xD;
effectivity of 85% and an infection rate of 10% it has been possible to calculate an&#xD;
amortisation within eight years. Higher levels of infection and a consistent effectivity&#xD;
of 85% shorten this time span significantly.&#xD;
The attractions of the hot water dipping process are in the opinion of the research&#xD;
team at the OVB Jork not merely economically convincing in terms of ROI. By&#xD;
reducing the levels of spoilage throughout the entire supply chain, it is for the first&#xD;
time possible to make a significant development in the sustainable quality&#xD;
management of organic apples, providing clear benefits for both consumer, trade and&#xD;
the grower.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14077/1/14_Maxin_75_78.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>P., Maxin and K., Klopp    (2004) Economics of Hot Water Dipping.  [Zur Wirtschaftlichkeit des Heißwasserverfahrens.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 75-78.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14077/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>