<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Managing Soil Quality: Challenges in Modern Agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil quality is a concept that allows soil functions to be related to specific purposes. Previous books on soil quality have emphasized descriptive aspects, by focusing on e.g. soil quality indicators, indexing, and minimum data sets. This book takes a management oriented approach by identifying key issues in soil quality and management options to enhance the sustainability of modern agriculture. Topics covered include major plant nutrients (N, P, K), soil acidity, soil organic matter, soil biodiversity, soil compaction, erosion, pesticides and urban waste. Also included are in-depth treatments of the soil quality concept, its history, and its applicability in research and in developed and developing societies. The book will be of significant interest to post-graduate students and researchers in agronomy and in soil, crop and environmental sciences, and to stakeholders involved in issues related to land use and agricultural development.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>CABI Publishing, Wallingford, UK</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Schjønning, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Elmholt, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Christensen, B.T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1511/2/A4659_Schjonning_Chap01.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schjønning, P.; Elmholt, S. and Christensen, B.T. (Eds.)      (2004) Managing Soil Quality: Challenges in Modern Agriculture.     CABI Publishing, Wallingford, UK.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1511/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>