<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innovative Mechanization of Garlic in Vessalico (North Italy)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Peruzzi, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raffaelli, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fontanelli, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frasconi, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lulli, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ginanni, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Vessalico is a small village close to Imperia (Liguria region), where garlic is a typical crop. The garlic of Vessalico is a product that is very appreciated being one of the most traditional and top quality food in Italy. The division of Agricultural Machinery and Farm Mechanization of the Department of Agronomy and Agroecosystem Management and the CIRAA “E. Avanzi” of the University of Pisa, in collaboration with the Agriculture and Civil Defence department of the Liguria Region and the cooperative of farmers “A Resta”, carried out a trial aimed to study the possibility of introducing a mechanization chain in order to solve the main agronomic problems of the garlic cultivation in this area, such as sowing, weed control and harvesting, thus improving garlic yield and quality. Ordinary organic garlic crop management was compared with an innovative system in which physical weed control was carried out using a rolling harrow, two flame weeding machines and a precision hoe. The innovative treatments increased whole plant and bulbs dry weight of about 38 and 78% respectively, and reduced weed biomass at harvest up to 77%.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12298/1/Peruzzi_12298_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Peruzzi, A.; Raffaelli, M.; Fontanelli, M.; Frasconi, C.; Lulli, L. and Ginanni, M.    (2008) Innovative Mechanization of Garlic in Vessalico (North Italy).       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12298/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>