<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Controlling broad-leaved dock (Rumex obtusifolius) in grass clover mixtures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van Eekeren, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fehér, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smeding, Frans</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prins, Udo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jansonius, PieterJans</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This article describes three experiments on the control of broad-leaved dock. Experiment 1: Dock seeds were ensiled in grass silages of different dry matter percentages; 23, 34 and 60% respectively. All silages showed a decline of seed vitality in time. Grass clover with dock seeds should be ensiled at a low dry matter percentage or remain in the silage bin for a longer period than 8 weeks. Experiment 2: In a potassium fertilisation trial on grass clover the development of dock was followed. After two years of potassium fertilisation, the number of dock and the root mass was not significant different between the fertilised and the unfertilised plots. It is concluded that potassium fertilisation at a low potassium status does not positively influence the dock development. Experiment 3: In a resown grass clover, dock seedlings were cut at three frequencies; 2, 4 and 6 weeks. After 3 months the number of seedlings had decreased the same in all treatments. However the root biomass of the seedlings was significantly affected. It is concluded that frequent cutting has a negative effect on root biomass but should be practised for a longer period than 12 weeks to have an effect on seedling numbers.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Lloveras, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gonazalez-Rodriguez, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vasquez-Yanez, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pinero, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Santamaria, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Oleaamd, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Poblaciones, M.L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8622/1/1783.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van Eekeren, Nick; Fehér, L.; Smeding, Frans; Prins, Udo and Jansonius, PieterJans    (2006) Controlling broad-leaved dock (Rumex obtusifolius) in grass clover mixtures.   In: Lloveras, J.; Gonazalez-Rodriguez, A.; Vasquez-Yanez, O.; Pinero, J.; Santamaria, O.; Oleaamd, L. and Poblaciones, M.L. (Eds.)  Sustainable grassland, 11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8622/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>