<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer Reaction to the «Flavour Group Concept» to introduce Scab Resistant Apple Varieties into the Market. «Variety-Teams» as a Further Development of the Concept</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leder, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A tool to ease the market introduction of scab resistant apple varieties in supermarkets, is the socalled&#xD;
«Flavour Group Concept (FGC; Weibel and Grab, 2000) that has been developed by FiBL&#xD;
and «Coop» (second biggest supermarket retailer of Switzerland) already in 1995. The FGC is providing&#xD;
to the buyers additional information on the specific flavour direction of that "unknown" apple&#xD;
cultivar in front of them (mild to sweet; spicy-tart; predominantly tart). In 2002 a consumer behaviour&#xD;
study was undertaken by «IHA/GfK-Switzerland» Institute to evaluate the consumer response to the&#xD;
FGC.&#xD;
The results reveal that 36 % of the persons interviewed at the point of sale considered additional&#xD;
information on the flavour direction of the apple cultivars as «important» and 40 % as «very important&#xD;
». Information on flavour direction was considered as the second important information at the&#xD;
shelf (59 % score), compared to the general presentation of the apples with 78 % score. On basis of&#xD;
these positive results, Coop introduced the FGC also for conventional apples. One year later, also&#xD;
the biggest supermarket retailer of Switzerland «Migros»introduced a FGC for organic and conventional&#xD;
apples.&#xD;
To develop further the FGC, in the year 2002, a consortium of the supermarket chain Coop-&#xD;
Switzerland, organic apple growers, retailers and FiBL experts joined together in a so-called «Variety&#xD;
Team». There, in contrast to Variety Clubs, the focus is not a particular variety but the active&#xD;
creation and promotion of an attractive assortment of scab resistant apple varieties in a well coordinated&#xD;
and thus for growers and retailers most efficient way. Investments and risks are evenly&#xD;
shared between the Team Partners. The first cultivar promoted is «Ecolette».</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14537/1/36_Weibel_196_201.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, Franco and Leder, Alfred    (2004) Consumer Reaction to the «Flavour Group Concept» to introduce Scab Resistant Apple Varieties into the Market. «Variety-Teams» as a Further Development of the Concept.  [Konsumenten-Reaktion auf das «Geschmacksgruppen-Konzepte» zur Markteinführung schorfresistenter Apfelsorten. «Sorten-Teams» als weitere Entwicklungsstufe des Konzepts.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 196-201.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14537/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>