<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Apple scab control with grapefruit seed extract: no alternative to chemical fungicides</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spitaler, Renate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marschall, Klaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zidorn, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zelger, Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stuppner, Hermann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The growth inhibiting effect of four commercially available grapefruit seed extracts&#xD;
on the causal organism of apple scab  Venturia inaequalis was tested. Germination of&#xD;
the conidia of Venturia inaequalis was pronouncedly inhibited by all tested extracts.&#xD;
The commercial products were analyzed by high pressure liquid chromatography and&#xD;
thin layer chromatography. All samples contained at least one preserving agent.&#xD;
These substances were identified as either benzethonium chloride, benzalkonium&#xD;
chloride, methyl parabene or propyl parabene. Freshly prepared extracts from seeds&#xD;
of grapefruits (Citrus paradisi) did not inhibit the germination of Venturia inaequalis. It&#xD;
was therefore concluded that the antifungal effect of grapefruit seed extracts is&#xD;
caused by the added preservatives.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14543/1/39_Kelderer_208_211.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spitaler, Renate; Marschall, Klaus; Zidorn, Christian; Kelderer, Markus; Zelger, Roland and Stuppner, Hermann    (2004) Apple scab control with grapefruit seed extract: no alternative to chemical fungicides.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 208-211.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14543/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>