<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality of organically grown protein crops in Norway for livestock concentrates – limited N and S supplementation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Britt I. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prestløkken, Egil</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of organic farming husbandry, is to be entirely based on an organically produced diet. Shortage of organically produced protein crops for production of concentrates supplying the European market, and a contemporary ban on the use of fishmeal for ruminants in the EU has lead to an increased need for organically produced feedstuffs for production of concentrates in Norwegian organic husbandry. Pea is the most common cultivated protein-rich crop in organic agriculture in Norway. For ruminants, peas has a low bypass protein content compared to common protein supplements such as rape meal and soybean meal. Other high-protein crops with complementary properties are therefore needed to meet the demand in feed quality for ruminants, pigs and poultry. Oilseed crops, which are rich in both fat and protein, will become of considerable interest if problems related to their cultivation are solved. Currently, our experience with oilseed crops in organic agriculture is limited. In a four year research project "Organic protein feed and edible oil from oilseed crops" this experience will be extended and the feed quality of organically grown protein crops like rape, turnip rape and camelina will be evaluated. The project will provide knowledge about the rumen degradability of protein, starch and NDF (neutral detergent fibre) and intestine digestibility of protein and starch in organically grown protein-rich crops necessary for the production of concentrates with an optimal feed quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12238/1/Henrikesen_12238_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Henriksen, Britt I. F. and Prestløkken, Egil    (2008) Quality of organically grown protein crops in Norway for livestock concentrates – limited N and S supplementation.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12238/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>