<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The development of an international curriculum on organic farming in China</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pugliese, Massimo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gullino, M. Lodovica</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project “Organic farming: social, ethical, economical, scientific and technical aspects in a global perspective” was founded by European Commission within the framework of Asia Link programme. The specific objective was the development of a curriculum on organic farming suitable to the Chinese educational framework, and the development of relevant learning and teaching tools supporting the implementation of the developed curriculum within the Chinese partners’ institutions. It consisted of four major components: seminars, visits abroad, PhD student mobility and summer schools. The developed curriculum consist of six major components for a total of 30 credits: a core course on organic farming  (8 credits); four specific courses in biological system management of pests, diseases and weeds, soil quality management, organic animal production, and food quality and food safety (20 credits); and approximately 2 credits for experimental learning on farms. Direct target groups of the project activities were professors and associate professors, postgraduate and graduate students. The project indirectly addressed also private and public industries, non-governmental and governmental organisations. The project lasted 24 months, starting from December 2005.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12616/1/Pugliese_12616_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pugliese, Massimo and Gullino, M. Lodovica    (2008) The development of an international curriculum on organic farming in China.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12616/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>