<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of burying and removing dead leaves from the ground on the development of scab epidemics in an apple organic orchard.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gomez, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brun, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chauffour, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Le Vallée, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rolland, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ascospores produced on scabbed leaves in the leaf litter constitute the primary&#xD;
inoculum causing scab infections in apple orchards during the year. The trial, carried&#xD;
out in a commercial organic orchard, permitted to evaluate the effects of the&#xD;
removal of dead leaves located on the inter-row supplemented by the ploughing in of&#xD;
the leaves left on the row, on the development of scab epidemics. From the first&#xD;
recorded contamination to harvest time, lesions on leaves and fruits were counted to&#xD;
determine reduction in disease incidence and severity, compared with the untreated&#xD;
plots. Disease severity as a function of the distance from the untreated plot was also&#xD;
observed, to evaluate the spore dispersal gradient within the orchard. The results&#xD;
show that the ploughing in and the removal of the litter reduced disease incidence by&#xD;
62% on leaves, and by almost 82% on fruits to harvest. Moreover, measurements of&#xD;
the dispersal gradient show that the spores do not disperse, or little, beyond 20m of&#xD;
the untreated zone.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14541/1/39_1_Gomez_212_212.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gomez, C.; Brun, L.; Chauffour, D.; de Le Vallée, D. and Rolland, E.    (2004) Effects of burying and removing dead leaves from the ground on the development of scab epidemics in an apple organic orchard.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, p. 212.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14541/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>