<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sorption and fractionation of dissolved organic matter and associated phosphorus in agricultural soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gjettermann, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Styczen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borggaard, O.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, H.C.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Molibility of dissolved organic matter (DOM) strongly affects the export of nitrogen (N) and phosphorus (P) from oils to surface waters. To study the sorption an mobility of dissolved organic C and P (DOC, DOP) in soil, the pH-dependent sorption of DOM to samples from Ap, EB, and Bt horizons from a Danish agircultural Humic Hapludult was investigated and a kinetic model applicable in field-scale model tested. Sorption experiments of 1 to 72 h duration were conducted at two pH levels (pH 5.0 and 7.0) and six initial DOC concentrtions (0-4.7 mmol L-1). Most sorption/desorption occurred during the first few hours. Dissolved organic carbon and DOP sorption decreased strongly with increased pH and desorption dominated at pH 7, especially for DOC. Due to fractionation during DOM sorption/desorption at DOC concentrations up to 2 mmol L-1, the solution fraction of DOM was enriched in P indicating preferred leaching of DOP. The kinetics of sorption was expressed as a function of how far the solution DOC or DOP concentrations deviate from "equilibrium". The model was able to simulate the kinetics of DOC and DOP sorption/desorption at all concentrations investigated and at both pH levels making it useful for incorporation in field-scale models for quantifying DOC and DOP dynamics.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21007/4/21007.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gjettermann, B.; Styczen, M.; Hansen, S.; Borggaard, O.K. and Hansen, H.C.B.   (2007) Sorption and fractionation of dissolved organic matter and associated phosphorus in agricultural soil.   Journal of Environmental Quality , 36 (3), pp. 753-763.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21007/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>