<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aggressivität von Fusarium avenaceum, Fusarium solani f. sp pisi und Mycosphaerella pinodes auf Wintererbsen (Pisum sativum L.) unter kontrollierten Bedingungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Šišić, Adnan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bacanovic, Jelena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Climate change scenarios exhibit a definite warming trend (Schröter et al. 2005), and it will have an impact on crop management strategies. Increase in winter precipitation and higher temperatures favour soil borne pathogens and can lead to an increase in survival rate and to more rapid population buildup (Chakraborty et al. 2000). In recent years, one of the main reasons for declining production of summer pea in organic farming in Germany are foot and root rot pathogens (Pflughöft 2008). On the other hand, predicted increase in winter temperatures is expected to favour winter pea over summer pea varieties. The hope is also, that winter peas are less susceptible to root rot as summer peas. However, few data are available. The present study was carried out to evaluate the susceptibility of winter pea variety EFB 33 against different isolates of Fusarium avenaceum, Fusarium solani f. sp pisi and Mycosphaerella pinodes under controlled conditions in sterile sand. Three weeks after sowing and inoculation, disease symptoms were assessed and plant growth parameters measured. All of the tested pathogens caused root discoloration and development of disease symptoms on pea seedlings. F. avenaceum was the most aggressive pathogen causing severe wilting symptoms and highest reduction in fresh weight of pea. No significant differenceses in aggressivness between F. solani and M. pinodes were observed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21418/1/Sisic_etal_Wintererbsen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Šišić, Adnan; Bacanovic, Jelena ; Bruns, Christian and Finckh, Maria R.    (2013) Aggressivität von Fusarium avenaceum, Fusarium solani f. sp pisi und Mycosphaerella pinodes auf Wintererbsen (Pisum sativum L.) unter kontrollierten Bedingungen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21418/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>