<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of landscape agricultural intensification and management on weed species richness in the edges of dryland cereal fields.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Romero, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chamorro, Lourdes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blanco-Moreno, José Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Armengot, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jose María, Laura</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sans, Francesc Xavier</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An extensive survey of weed vegetation was conducted in the crop edges of 180 organic and conventional dryland cereal fields in nine localities of NE Iberian Peninsula to assess the effect of landscape agricultural intensification and management on weed diversity. &#xD;
This preliminary results show that averaged weed species richness per edge (alpha-diversity) and floristic homogeneity among edges are higher in organic than conventional fields. Only in conventionally managed fields, elevated landscape intensification is associated to higher weed alpha-diversities and floristic homogeneity among crop edges.&#xD;
The expression of high-quality weed flora is higher in organic than in conventional crop edges but, conversely, it is only sensitive to landscape intensification in organic fields, being clearly favoured in low-intensified landscapes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12302/1/Romero_12302_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Romero, Albert; Chamorro, Lourdes; Blanco-Moreno, José Manuel; Armengot, Laura; Jose María, Laura and Sans, Francesc Xavier    (2008) Effects of landscape agricultural intensification and management on weed species richness in the edges of dryland cereal fields.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12302/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>