<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A participatory approach to variety trials for organic systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Clarke, Dr Sarah M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hinchsliffe, Miss Kay E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haigh, Miss Zoe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Dr Hannah</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pearce, Dr Bruce</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfe, Prof Martin S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, Dr Jane</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A participatory research methodology was used to compare the performance of UK wheat varieties under organic conditions. Plots of three breadmaking winter wheat varieties (Hereward, Solstice and Xi19) and a mixture (1:1:1) of the varieties were grown at 19 UK farms in two seasons (2003/04 and 2004/05). Meas-urements were taken of growth habit, yield and grain quality. Grain yields in both seasons showed significant site by variety interactions, although the variation among sites was greater than among varieties in both instances. Wheat grown at Western sites was significantly shorter and higher-yielding than that grown at Eastern sites in 2003/04 but significantly taller in 2004/05. As with grain yield, greater variation among site than variety was found in the Hagberg Falling Number and protein concentra-tion results in both seasons. The results from the two years of trials illustrate the variability of organic systems and the difficulty in selecting a single variety suitable for organic farms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7444/1/denmark_congress_agronomic_PC_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7444/2/7444.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Clarke, Dr Sarah M.; Hinchsliffe, Miss Kay E.; Haigh, Miss Zoe; Jones, Dr Hannah; Pearce, Dr Bruce; Wolfe, Prof Martin S and Thomas, Dr Jane    (2006) A participatory approach to variety trials for organic systems.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7444/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>