<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The future of organic grassland farming in mountainous regions of Central Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wachendorf, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pötsch, Erich M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>8 % of the total EU population lives in mountainous areas which represent a particularly important eco-region in Central Europe. Because of ecological, climatic and economic reasons an increasing pressure is imposed upon agriculture. Hence in large parts of European mountainous&#xD;
areas drastic changes in agricultural structure and land use systems can be observed in terms of emigration and land abandonment. Due to disadvantaged production conditions, and the high ecological sensitivity, organic farming is an important option for a sound regional development. In alpine regions organic farming does not proceed in a homogeneous way. One essential reason for that could be seen in the differences of national and regional “traditions and orientations” and supporting tools. For a positive development it is necessary to work on further integration of organic farming in regional development concepts (e.g. organic regions) and on the development of the “quality leadership” through cross-regional production, marketing and merchandising concepts. Undisputedly, further positive development of organic farming in mountainous regions depends on ongoing financial, research and advisory support.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organising Committee of the 16th Symposium of the EGF 2011 and Agricultural Research and Education Centre (AREC) Raumberg-Gumpenstein 8952 Irdning, Austria</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-08-29</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19338/1/The_future_of_organic_grassland_farming_in_mountainous_regions_of_Central_Europe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinwidder, Andreas; Schneider, Manuel; Wachendorf, Michael; Starz, Walter and Pötsch, Erich M.    (2011) The future of organic grassland farming in mountainous regions of Central Europe.   In:     Grassland Farming and Land Management Systems in Mountainous Regions. Proceedings of the 16th Symposium of the European Grassland Federation, Organising Committee of the 16th Symposium of the EGF 2011 and Agricultural Research and Education Centre (AREC) Raumberg-Gumpenstein 8952 Irdning, Austria , Grassland Science in Europe, no. 16, pp. 286-296.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19338/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>