<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agroecology Education and Research: An Academic Platform for Organic Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Francis, Dr. Charles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Breland, Dr. Tor Arvid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lieblein, Dr. Geir</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moulton, Mr. Mike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salomonsson, Dr. Lennart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geber, Dr. Ulrika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langer, Dr. Vibeke</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sriskandarajah, Dr. N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Porter, Dr. John</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Helenius, Dr. Juha</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agroecology education and research programs are gaining prominence in universities. This emerging field provides an appropriate and convenient platform for bringing organic farming into academia. Agroecology deals with complex systems, uncertainty, and the future. Examples from organic farming and local food systems often provide valuable examples of applications of the principles of ecology in designing a sustainable agriculture. The agroecology MSc program in the NOVA network is a successful example of how organic farming can be brought into university programs, and how interdisciplinary education and research can tap into a regional faculty in agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7275/1/Organic_DK6.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7275/2/7275_Francis.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Francis, Dr. Charles; Breland, Dr. Tor Arvid; Lieblein, Dr. Geir; Moulton, Mr. Mike; Salomonsson, Dr. Lennart; Geber, Dr. Ulrika; Langer, Dr. Vibeke; Sriskandarajah, Dr. N.; Porter, Dr. John and Helenius, Dr. Juha    (2006) Agroecology Education and Research: An Academic Platform for Organic Farming.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7275/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>