<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zur Zuchtstrategie in Schweizer Bio-Braunviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bapst, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bieber, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haas, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A survey on 1000 organic dairy cattle farms was done to obtain information on the state of breeding affairs in Switzerland. The response of 60% of returned questionnaires was very high. Milk performance data were average for organic as well as for traditionally managed farms. The farmers weighted functional traits to be very important in breeding.&#xD;
The bulls used on organic farms were compared with the bulls used on traditional farms. A total of 25067 organic and 28003 traditional matings of Swiss Braunvieh was analysed. The comparison of breeding values of the sires showed that in the scope of selection strategies the functional traits were not as important. It is concluded that organic farmers persecute an organic breeding strategy but in the particular mating it is not implemented.&#xD;
On one hand the chosen organic breeding strategy has to be reconsidered and on the other hand there seems to be a backlog in consulting and sensitizing the farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3612/1/3612.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bapst, B.; Bieber, A. and Haas, E.    (2005) Untersuchungen zur Zuchtstrategie in Schweizer Bio-Braunviehbetrieben.  [Analysis of breeding strategies on Swiss organic Braunvieh-farms.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3612/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>