<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Copper replacement in organic viticulture - state of the art in legislation and research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Berkelmann-Löhnertz, Beate</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In European viticulture, downy mildew (Plasmopara viticola (Berk. &amp; Curt.) Berl. &amp; de Toni) is one of the most dangerous diseases affecting grapes, causing significant damage and severe decreases of product quality.&#xD;
European organic viticulture is predominantly based on copper applications to control this disease. Due to environmental problems incurred by copper applications, the European Commission decided to limit the use of certain copper products in organic viticulture. This should be achieved by the year 2002 (cf. EC 1488/97). Therefore, the Commission recommends testing alternative strategies in downy mildew control in line with EC 2092/91.&#xD;
In the last decade, specific actions were realized to investigate, apply and support alternative control measures. These are based on microbial antagonists, plant extracts and inorganic, naturally occurring compounds. Studies on modes of action should help to characterize markers indicating effective resistance inducers.&#xD;
Apart From the introduction of newly developed control agents, field trials focused on copper reduction strategies and new products with extremely low copper concentrations. Nevertheless, a multidisciplinary approach is highly recommended in order to help solving one of the major problems of organic viticulture.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14611/1/berkelmann_123.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Berkelmann-Löhnertz, Beate    (2002) Copper replacement in organic viticulture - state of the art in legislation and research.  [Ersatz von Kupferspritzungen im ökologischen Weinbau - Stand in Wissenschaft und Gesetzgebung.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing and Viticulture. Proceedings to the Conference from 4th to 7th Feb. 2002 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 123-126.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14611/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>