<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrating maize and triticale in grass/clover based dairy systems:  examining yields and autumn soil nitrate levels</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinxterhuis, Ina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boer, H. de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eekeren, N. van</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stienezen, M.W.J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To establish N-efficient crop rotations with perennial ryegrass/white clover, maize and triticale, a 9-year field experiment was executed on an organic experimental farm in the Netherlands. Crop rotations with different levels of slurry (dairy effluent from the free-stall barn, average dry matter content of 7%) application were tested for dry matter (DM) yield, N yield, soil mineral N in autumn, soil organic matter and soil organic N. Maize cropping and slurry application both increased annual DM yield. However, the second year of grass/ clover following maize, maize itself and slurry applications each resulted in higher soil mineral N in autumn, increasing the risk of nitrate leaching losses. A rotation of 4 years of grass/clover, 2 years of maize and 1 year of triticale resulted in relatively high average annual DM production (12 t DM/ha/year) for Dutch conditions, with a higher potential N leaching loss in 2 out of 7 years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26765/1/2816.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pinxterhuis, Ina; Boer, H. de; Eekeren, N. van and Stienezen, M.W.J.    (2013) Integrating maize and triticale in grass/clover based dairy systems: examining yields and autumn soil nitrate levels.   In:     Proceedings of the New Zealand Grassland Association, 75, pp. 251-256.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26765/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>