<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimising the production and utilisation of forage for organic livestock (CTE0202)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keatinge, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On most organic farms in the UK, forages are fundamental to the application of organic farming practices, particularly where dairy cattle, beef cattle and/or sheep are the major enterprises. Methods used for the production, conservation and utilisation of these forage resources have a major influence on the productivity, efficiency and overall sustainability of organic farms. Forage management and utilisation also have a pivotal role in the maintenance of animal health and in the minimisation of environmental impacts associated with livestock farming.&#xD;
Specific objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
1. Extrapolating from published data, to review the requirements for energy and protein across the production cycle for organic milk, beef, lamb, pig and poultry production.&#xD;
&#xD;
2. To predict the likelihood of meeting all or a minimum proportion of these requirements from a range of organically produced forages.&#xD;
&#xD;
3. To examine the potential to adjust management or production system to achieve a better balance of nutrient supply and demand&#xD;
&#xD;
4. To consider likely contribution from alternative forages, and protein sources, as home-grown feeds&#xD;
&#xD;
5. To assess likely effects on animal health and product quality&#xD;
&#xD;
6. To develop a database model to predict the potential output and benefits for organic farmers of implementing different options and strategies for forage production and utilisation &#xD;
&#xD;
7. To determine the environmental losses and gains at each stage of production and utilisation&#xD;
&#xD;
8. To provide specific guidelines for use by farmers, advisers and policymakers to maximise efficiency in the production and utilisation of forages within a range of organic livestock production systems.&#xD;
Overall, this body of work has indicated that a number of gaps in current knowledge exist such as: the particular suitability of diverse plants and animal genotypes for forage-based organic systems, methods for determining the nutritive value of organically produced forages, trace element nutrition of organic livestock and specific weed and pest control measures in organic crop production.&#xD;
Further dissemination of the outputs from this study, drawn from the five separate work packages in which the work was conducted, will help underpin the sustainability of the organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6705/1/OF0328_Report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Keatinge, R         (2004) Optimising the production and utilisation of forage for organic livestock (CTE0202).    ADAS Consulting Ltd, Redesdale.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6705/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>