<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bolivia's local organic market and how it might be affected by the new national organic legislation 3525/06</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zschocke, Arnd</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Bolivia</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The booming demand for organic products leads to high growth rates in this sector, especially in exporting countries. This study investigates how organic legislation in Latin American countries, which is intended to support the export sector, can also influence the local market. This is done through a case study for Bolivia, its new law 3525/06 and its national market for organic products. The general situation in Bolivia is described briefly, the new law is analyzed, and an analysis of the national market for organic products is presented. The results are that the new law is very progressive and allows easier access to organic certification for the internal market. Nevertheless, the local organic market is still a very small niche market and completely unregulated, but there is potential for growth if the implementation of the law is accompanied by a broad publicity campaign aimed at the consumers and support and education for farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14958/1/14958.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zschocke, Arnd   (2008) Bolivia's local organic market and how it might be affected by the new national organic legislation 3525/06.    Masters thesis, University of Kassel, Department of Development Economics, Migration and Agricultural Policy.  .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14958/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>