<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Catch Crops in Organic Farming Systems without Livestock Husbandry - Simulations with the DAISY model</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Torsten</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Lars Stoumann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper presents simulations of the soil-plant-atmosphere model DAISY based on an organic crop rotation with incorporation of different catch crops following pea as a leguminous cash crop. Special emphasise was put on the simulation of N-mineralisation/-immobilisation and of soil microbial biomass N. The DAISY model was able to simulate soil mineral N and soil microbial biomass N after soil incorporation of catch crop plant residues to some extend. Several processes need further attention and may be integrated into the DAISY model: (1) soil tillage induced mobilisation of organic material including considerable amounts of organic N, (2) winter killing of sensitive plant species and varieties, (3) decomposition of plant residues at the soil surface as occurring after winter killing, (4) decomposition of easily decomposable plant residues at low temperatures, (5) soil microbial residues as an organic pool temporarily protected against turnover. Furthermore, reliable criteria for the subdivision of green plant residues into an easily decomposable pool and a more recalcitrant pool have to be developed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7886/2/7886.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Müller, Torsten; Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Magid, Jakob; Jensen, Lars Stoumann and Hansen, Søren   (2006) Catch Crops in Organic Farming Systems without Livestock Husbandry - Simulations with the DAISY model.   Ecological Modelling, 191, pp. 538-544.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7886/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>