<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einsatz der Mikroverkapselungsverfahren in der Ökolebensmittelverarbeitung&#xD;
am Beispiel von mikroverkapselten Probiotika</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aminoforoughi, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ploeger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Microencapsulation is a technique by which sensitive ingredients are entrapted in thin&#xD;
polymeric matrix or coats. Microcapsule contents or „core“ materials are generally&#xD;
protected from adverse environmental conditions. Microencapsulation in the food&#xD;
industry can be used by every class of food ingredient. The microencapsulation of&#xD;
probiotics, the live microbial food supplements, is developing since the past decade.&#xD;
However many promised positive effects of probiotics are not yet proved scientifically.&#xD;
Furthermore research on the effects of the probiotic bacteria and the microencapsulation&#xD;
techniques is needed. This work aimed at just observing the adverse effects of the&#xD;
microencapsulation techniques (e.g. by probiotics). Due to this, there is a great need&#xD;
of regulation according to the European Regulation on organic production (EEC) No&#xD;
2092/1991 (834/2007).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14176/1/Aminforoughi_14176.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aminoforoughi, M.; Kahl, J. and Ploeger, A.    (2009) Einsatz der Mikroverkapselungsverfahren in der Ökolebensmittelverarbeitung am Beispiel von mikroverkapselten Probiotika.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14176/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>