<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Need for protein supplementation in the diet of growing dairy bulls fed total mixed ration based on moderate digestible grass silage and barley</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huuskonen, Arto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Khalili, Hannele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Joki-Tokola, Erkki</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of the present experiment was to study the need for the protein supplementation in the diet of growing dairy bulls (initial live weight 272 ± 28.5 kg and final live weight 666 ± 31.2 kg, on average) fed total mixed ration based on moderate digestible grass silage and barley. The experiment comprised 24 Finnish Ayrshire bulls and 8 Holstein-Friesian bulls and included four treatments. The control diet (C) consisted of moderate digestible (653 g digestible organic matter in dry matter (DM) grass silage (450 g kg-1 DM), barley grain (275) and barley fibre (275) without protein supplementation. Three isonitrogenous experimental diets included also extra protein, i.e. (1) rapeseed meal (RSM) (supplementation 530 g DM per animal day-1), (2) wet distillers’ solubles (WDS) (600 g) and (3) a mixture of barley protein (90% of fresh weight) and wet distillers’ solubles (10) (BPWDS) (480 g). In all isonitrogenous diets the crude protein content of concentrate increased from 137 to 150 g kg-1 DM (9%) compared with the C diet. All bulls were fed total mixed ration ad libitum. The energy content of all diets was 11.6 MJ kg-1 DM. The live weight gain of the bulls tended to be higher with the BPWDS diet than with the C diet (C 1214 vs. BPWDS 1301 g d-1; p = 0.10), but the treatments had no significant effect on carcass gain, feed conversion or slaughter parameters. Only the BPWDS diet differed significantly from the C diet in DM (C 9.69 vs. BPWDS 10.38 kg DM d-1; p &lt; 0.01) and energy intake (C 112.4 vs. BPWDS 120.3 MJ d-1; p &lt; 0.05). The apparent organic matter digestibility (OMD) was 5% higher in the BPWDS diet than in the C diet (p &lt; 0.001), but the RSM and WDS diets did not differ from the C diet in OMD. The results indicate that the supply of protein in dairy bulls is most probably adequate with moderate digestible, well-preserved grass silage and barley-based concentrates when intake of digestible organic matter is high enough to support microbial protein synthesis in the rumen.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16892/1/huuskonen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huuskonen, Arto; Khalili, Hannele and Joki-Tokola, Erkki   (2008) Need for protein supplementation in the diet of growing dairy bulls fed total mixed ration based on moderate digestible grass silage and barley.   Agricultural and Food Science, 17 (2), pp. 109-120.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16892/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>