<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Bio-Economy Concept and Knowledge Base in a Public Goods and Farmer Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Levidov, Les</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently an industrial perspective dominates the EU policy framework for a European bio-economy. The Commission’s proposal on the bio-economy emphasises greater resource-efficiency, largely within an industrial perspective on global economic competitiveness, benefiting capital-intensive industries at higher levels of the value chain. However a responsible bio-economy must initially address the sustainable use of resources. Many farmers are not only commodity producers but also providers of quality food and managers of the eco-system. A public goods-oriented bio-economy emphasises agro-ecological methods, organic and low (external) input farming systems, ecosystem services, social innovation in multi-stakeholder collective practices&#xD;
and joint production of knowledge. The potential of farmers and SMEs to contribute to innovation must be fully recognised. This approach recognises the importance of&#xD;
local knowledge enhancing local capabilities, while also accommodating diversity and complexity. Therefore the bio-economy concept should have a much broader scope&#xD;
than the dominant one in European Commission innovation policy. Socio-economic research is needed to inform strategies, pathways and stakeholder cooperation towards&#xD;
sustainability goals.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20942/1/SCHMID_BAE_2012_10770-18316-1-PB.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, Otto; Padel, Susanne and Levidov, Les   (2012) The Bio-Economy Concept and Knowledge Base in a Public Goods and Farmer Perspective.   Bio-based and Applied Economics, 1 (1), pp. 47-63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20942/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>