<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Non-midical control of parasitic worms in pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roepstroff, Allan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Generally there is a higher prevalence of intestinal parasites in organic pigs compared to conventional indoor pigs. It may be possible to reduce infection levels by ensuring that new animals are parasite free, using a moderate stocking rate, co-grazing cows and sows, using noserings, altering feed composition and feeding the pigs predatious fungi. In addition, paddock rotation is recommended in order to remove the pigs from the infectious parasite stages (eggs and larvae). Resent results show that the free-living larvae of the nodular worm do not survive for long on pasture. Overall, the nodular worm is considered to be less of a problem than other parsites. Eggs from the large round worm and especially the whipworm can take long to become infective but may in return  survive several years in the soil. It seems as if ploughing may reduce the transmission of whipworm considerably, whereas the effect on the large round worm is not as strong. The large differences between the three parasites mean that control strategies may have to be designed according to the parasites present in a given herd.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3230/1/Non_medical_parasite_control.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mejer, Helena and Roepstroff, Allan   (2003) Non-midical control of parasitic worms in pigs.   DARCOFenews.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3230/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>