<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Roughages for Growing Pigs, with Emphasis on Chemical composition, Ingestion and Faecal Digestibility</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carlson, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lærke, H.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poulsen, H.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, Henry</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2 experiments, 10 gilts (30 kg initial liveweight) were given a basal diet with fresh or frozen/thawed clover-grass, clover-grass silage or whole-crop pea-barley silage. The faecal digestibility of gross energy (GE), DM, organic matter (OM), dietary fibre (DF) and CP were measured. The 3 roughages, leaves and stems of clover-grass and the basal diets were also tested for in vitro OM digestibility. Roughage intake was similar in both experiments and the average proportion of roughage ingested was 18-19% of DM. There were no differences between fresh and frozen/thawed clover-grass nutrient digestibility values. Glucose (cellulose) and xylose were the main constituents of the non-starch polysaccharides (NSP) in the roughages, with whole-crop pea-barley silage having the highest content. The faecal digestibility of NSP was significantly lower for diets based on whole-crop pea-barley silage than clover-grass silage. In both experiments, the GE, DM, OM and CP digestibility did not differ. Clover-grass leaves had higher in vitro OM digestibility than the stems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>1999</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20923/4/20923.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Carlson, D.; Lærke, H.N.; Poulsen, H.D. and Jørgensen, Henry   (1999) Roughages for Growing Pigs, with Emphasis on Chemical composition, Ingestion and Faecal Digestibility.   Acta Agriculturæ Scandinavica. Section A, Animal Science, 49, pp. 129-136.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20923/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>