<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ancient Wheat Species Can Extend Biodiversity of Cultivated&#xD;
Crops</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Wheat genetic resources may be grown in organic farming systems or in less favourable areas for bread wheat species. Characteristics of hulled wheat species (23 varieties of einkorn, emmer wheat, spelt wheat) were studied and evaluated within a two-year trial period (which was executed on certified organic fields) and they were compared to characteristics of landraces and modern bread wheat varieties. The main aim of our study was to evaluate the potential uses of genetic resources of wheat in organic farming. The hulled wheat species were resistant to mildew and brown rust. Their grains were less contaminated with DON than the grains of the control varieties. The grain yield rate was reduced. Per hectare crude protein yield was higher in spelt and emmer wheat species than in the control varieties. High protein proportion in grain was an important advantage of the hulled wheat species. Spelt wheat is suitable for production of products similar to bread wheat (they have similar technological qualities). Einkorn and emmer wheat contain worse-quality gluten and therefore are suitable for the production of unyeasty products, that is pasta, mush, traditional unyeasty bread, etc.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20763/1/SRE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Moudry, Jan; Konvalina, Petr; Stehno, Zdenek; Capouchova, Ivana and Moudry, Jan (Jr.)   (2011) Ancient Wheat Species Can Extend Biodiversity of Cultivated Crops.   Scientific Research and Essay, 6 (20), pp. 4273-4280.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20763/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>