<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 1. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LowInputBreeds Consortium,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Welcome to the first issue of the newsletter of the project&#xD;
LowInputBreeds “Development of integrated livestock&#xD;
breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European&#xD;
organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production”. This&#xD;
newsletter aims to keep you up-to-date on progress of the&#xD;
LowInputBreeds project. In this issue we introduce the&#xD;
project, and we report on recent LowInputBreeds meetings&#xD;
and subproject activities.&#xD;
For all those that attend BioFach, the World Organic Trade&#xD;
Fair in Nuremberg, Germany, we recommend that you&#xD;
come to the session ‘Management and breeding for organic&#xD;
plant and livestock production systems’, to take place on&#xD;
Friday, February 19, 2010. At this workshop, the EU projects&#xD;
QLIF, LowInputBreeds and NUE Crops will be presented&#xD;
and discussed with the audience.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24641/1/LowInputBreeds-Newsletter-no-1-2009.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LowInputBreeds Consortium,     (2009) Newsletter of the LowInputBreeds project. Issue 1. EU project LowInputBreeds - Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.   Newcastle University and Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24641/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>