<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>What do we (need to) know about low-susceptibility of codling moth against Cydia pomonella granulovirus (CpGV)!</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jehle, Johannes A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sayed, Samy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wahl-Ermel, Britta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2005, the first codling moth (CM) populations with a reduced susceptibility to Cydia pomonella granulovirus&#xD;
(CpGV) products have been observed. This phenomenon might be an indicator of an emerging resistance of&#xD;
CM to CpGV. This paper summarizes some aspects of CM CpGV interaction and discusses potential&#xD;
mechanisms in the host virus interaction, which could contribute to the observed low susceptibility. In order to&#xD;
develop and implement successful resistance management strategies, much more knowledge about the&#xD;
plasticity of CM CpGV interaction and the diversity of CM populations is essential.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13757/1/ecofruit_12th_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jehle, Johannes A.; Sayed, Samy and Wahl-Ermel, Britta    (2006) What do we (need to) know about low-susceptibility of codling moth against Cydia pomonella granulovirus (CpGV)!  [Was wir über die Minderempfindlichkeit des Apfelwicklers gegenüber dem Cydia pomonella Granulovirus (CpGV) wissen (müssen)!]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 14-24.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13757/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>