<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Understanding Entrepreneurial Skills in the Farm Context</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Strategic orientations on farms are becoming more diverse: in addition to those who focus on cost-effectiveness in conventional primary production, many farmers add value to their agricultural products through processing, direct sales and niche-products, or diversify their activities into non-agricultural businesses. This development indicates that farmers are taking the initiative and pursuing ways to develop their businesses. Obviously, this development implies the need for entrepreneurial skills.&#xD;
&#xD;
In this study entrepreneurial skills are understood as the skills of recognizing and realizing business opportunities, networking and utilizing contacts, as well as creating and evaluating a business strategy. Are these skills relevant in the farm context? Do farmers consider these skills important?&#xD;
&#xD;
How do they assess themselves regarding these skills? How do farmers explain the development of these skills? What could be done to enhance the development of these skills? &#xD;
&#xD;
This book’s aim is to answer these questions with the help of a detailed analysis of qualitative interviews with farmers in six European countries. The book reports the results from the main study of the EU-funded research project ´Developing Entrepreneurial Skills of Farmers` (ESoF).&#xD;
&#xD;
Both organic and conventional farmers were intereviewed.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, CH-Frick</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Vesala, Kari Mikko</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jarkko, Pyysiäinen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13278/1/Versalapyysiaetinen-2008-esof-oe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vesala, Kari Mikko and Jarkko, Pyysiäinen (Eds.)      (2008) Understanding Entrepreneurial Skills in the Farm Context.     Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, CH-Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13278/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>