<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchung zu Veränderungen der Lebensmittelqualität&#xD;
durch Vitaminierung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Geier, Dr. Uwe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buchmann, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Strube, Dr. Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 1991, European Union law prescribes minimum vitamin contents in foods for&#xD;
babies and small children. The prescribed level of vitamin contents requires supplementation&#xD;
by synthetic or isolated vitamins. Such supplementation with synthetic or&#xD;
isolated substances contrasts sharply with the principles of organic farming. Experiments&#xD;
were carried out to investigate the effect of supplemented vitamins on food&#xD;
quality. These included investigation of the addition of thiamin (vitamin B1) to flour of&#xD;
rice and spelt and L-ascorbic acid (vitamin C) to juices of carrot and apple. A set of&#xD;
different complementary research methods was used. Fluorescence excitation&#xD;
spectroscopy distinguished the treatments of carrot juice significantly. The picture&#xD;
forming methods found effects of the added vitamins in both juices; these effects are&#xD;
interpreted as a reduction of quality. Observation of formative forces revealed a reduction&#xD;
of quality in all samples with vitamin supplements.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14450/1/Geier_14450.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Geier, Dr. Uwe; Buchmann, Markus and Strube, Dr. Jürgen    (2009) Untersuchung zu Veränderungen der Lebensmittelqualität durch Vitaminierung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14450/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>