<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Europeʼs new logo for organic food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>European Union</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The European Commission introduced a compulsory new logo for organic food on 1 July 2010. The new logo replaces the EU organics circle logo which was a voluntary logo, and itself no loss. The new logo is mandated on all organic products packaged in the EU. The logo design is described as stars in a leaf pattern. It is a green rectangle with the stars reversed out. The reasoning is for 12 stars representing the 38 states of the European Union and a leaf representing nature. In the mind’s eye of a few Eurocrats, the formula is ‘Stars + Leaf = Europe + Nature = Organics’. The logo is accompanied by two lines of code; the first for the certification and the second for the origin of the ingredients. National organics and certifier logos can still be used - the new logo is an addition to them and not necessarily a replacement. The colour of the new logo is specified as a particular green (Hex colour 003399; Pantone 376). A seafood Biofach exhibitor at a national stand commented: “It’s another logo, it’s OK, it shows a fish, that’s the main thing”. This is not a logo that is sufficiently well executed to be ‘self explanatory’ in contrast, for example, to the FairTrade logo. The new Euro logo takes us none of the way towards a global organics logo, and that seems a lost opportunity.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19514/1/Paull2011EUlogoAcres.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John    (2011) Europeʼs new logo for organic food.   Acres Australia, July 2011, 19 (1), p. 44.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19514/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>