<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organische Düngung intensiv genutzten Dauergrünlandes im&#xD;
Vergleich mit Mineraldüngung - Ergebnisse eines 22 jährigen&#xD;
Versuches auf Wiese und Mähweide.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elsäßer, PD Dr. Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kunz, Dipl.Ing.(FH) Hans-Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a 22-year-old experiment in Southwest Germany, the effects of different fertilization&#xD;
systems (organic and mineral fertilizers) on permanent grassland were investigated.&#xD;
The effects were investigated under cutting and mown pasture with two grazing&#xD;
periods per year. The experiment had 8 fertilizer treatments and 3 replications, the&#xD;
size of field plots were 25 m2 in area. Dry matter (DM) yields and mineral contents in&#xD;
soil and forage (P, K) were measured. The botanical composition was investigated&#xD;
each second year. Maximum DM yields were obtained by mineral NPK fertilization and&#xD;
a treatment called ‘alternating fertilizer’, with yearly alternating use of farmyard&#xD;
manure, liquid manure and mineral NPK. The application of composted farmyard&#xD;
manure reduced DM yields. The additional application of stone-meal and metallurgical&#xD;
lime to slurry did not increase the effects of untreated slurry on yield. Fertilization with&#xD;
slurry increased the proportions of grasses, whereas farmyard manure increased&#xD;
forbs. The proportion of legumes was increased by PK and by fertilization with slurry&#xD;
with lime.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14539/1/Elsaesser_14539.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Elsäßer, PD Dr. Martin and Kunz, Dipl.Ing.(FH) Hans-Georg    (2009) Organische Düngung intensiv genutzten Dauergrünlandes im Vergleich mit Mineraldüngung - Ergebnisse eines 22 jährigen Versuches auf Wiese und Mähweide.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14539/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>