<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of a nature conservation standard for enhancing biodiversity and marketing in organic farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stein-Bachinger, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gottwald, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dräger de Teran, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rühs, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract&#xD;
Organic farms are proven to yield highly beneficial environmental services for nature. But an appreciation of these services by consumers is nearly non-existent. Furthermore the state does not offer sufficient financial support in this field. This has led to the situa-tion that many farms, due to economic constraints, cannot tap their nature conservation potential, even though the will to do so is very high. It is hoped that through the devel-opment of a nature conservation standard for organic farms connected with nature con-servation advisory services and rewarding farmers for facilitating environmental services by marketing organic+biodiversity products, farmers will experience a higher added value. At the same time consumers who purchase these products will be exposed to more information about organic products and their nature conservation effects.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24165/1/24165_ISOFAR_Stein-Bachinger%20et%20al_2014_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stein-Bachinger, Karin; Gottwald, Frank; Dräger de Teran, Tanja and Rühs, Michael    (2014) Development of a nature conservation standard for enhancing biodiversity and marketing in organic farming systems.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 2, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 543-546.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24165/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>