<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Traps for Lygus rugulipennis and Anthonomus rubi: preliminary results from Softpest Multitrap activities in Latvia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ralle, Baiba</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cross, Jerry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hall, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trandem, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baroffio, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fountain, Michelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wibe, Atle</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There is a lack of appropriate plant protection methods against strawberry blossom weevil (SBW) not only in organic plantations, but also in plantations, where IPM is used. European tarnished plant bug (ETPB) is not currently recognized as a pest in Latvian strawberry plantations, because the visual defects made by bugs are not important for Latvian consumers.&#xD;
Cross vane bucket traps and sticky stake traps were the most effective for trapping SBW in Latvia. These traps, where the lure was positioned at the top of cross vanes, were also the most effective for capturing ETPB.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>NJF Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists and University of Copenhagen</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Jensen, Birgit</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Trandem, Nina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Parikka, Päivi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Svensson, Birgitta</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-11-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25579/7/Ralle%20et%20al.%20-%20Softpest%20Multitrap%20for%20NJF465.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ralle, Baiba; Cross, Jerry; Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin; Hall, David; Trandem, Nina; Sigsgaard, Lene; Baroffio, Catherine; Fountain, Michelle and Wibe, Atle    (2013) Traps for Lygus rugulipennis and Anthonomus rubi: preliminary results from Softpest Multitrap activities in Latvia.   In: Sigsgaard, Lene; Jensen, Birgit; Trandem, Nina; Parikka, Päivi and Svensson, Birgitta (Eds.)  NJF seminar 465 IPM in Nordic and Baltic berry crops.Copenhagen, Denmark 12-13 November, 2013, NJF Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists and University of Copenhagen, 9 (8), NJF report, pp. 17-18.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25579/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>