<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erfahrungswissenschaftliche Evaluierung von 7 ökologischen&#xD;
Milchviehbetrieben mit überdurchschnittlich guten Zellzahlen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zipp, Frau Katherina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kusche, Dipl Ing Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baars, Prof Dr Ton</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The maintenance of udder health is one of the biggest problems in organic dairy&#xD;
farming. Therefore, it was the aim to explore the experience of successful farming&#xD;
experts to evaluate their individual complex solutions for mastitis ans somatic cell&#xD;
count problems. 7 organic dairy farmers in Baden-Württemberg/Germany were selected,&#xD;
who achieved an above-average low somatic cell count. Qualitative steeredquestion&#xD;
interviews and the observation of two milkings were used to investigate their&#xD;
knowledge and insight and their practical daily actions. The results were clustered in&#xD;
the following areas: milk analysis, animal health and therapy, animal husbandry and&#xD;
hygiene in the barn, milking machine, milking management and hygiene, feeding,&#xD;
raising of calves, breeding, stress/calmness/welfare and animal-human-relationship.&#xD;
Although all farms had average good somatic cell counts, they could be divideded in&#xD;
two types, differing in management, biography, experience and modernity of barn and&#xD;
milking-parlor. The results indicate that there are individual solutions achieving a low&#xD;
somatic cell count, but it is important that these fit to the farm methods. Furthermore&#xD;
some commonalities between the farmers were noticed, which can be starting-point&#xD;
for improvements in farms with poor udder health.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14109/1/Zipp_14109.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zipp, Frau Katherina; Kusche, Dipl Ing Daniel and Baars, Prof Dr Ton    (2009) Erfahrungswissenschaftliche Evaluierung von 7 ökologischen Milchviehbetrieben mit überdurchschnittlich guten Zellzahlen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14109/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>