<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The volatile compounds in lamb fat are affected by the time of grazing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vasta, Valentina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ventura, Valentina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luciano, Guiseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andronico, Valeria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pagano, Renato</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scerra, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biondi, Luisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arvondo, Marcella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priolo, Alessandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study was designed to assess whether different grazing managements affect the appearance of organic volatile compounds (VOC) in lamb fat. Forty-two lambs were divided into four groups: 9 lambs were restricted in stall and fed concentrate (S group); 12 lambs grazed from 9 am to 5 pm (8 h group); 10 lambs grazed from 9 am to 1 pm (4hAM group) and 11 lambs grazed from 1 pm to 5 pm (4hPM group). After 72 days on feed the animals were slaughtered and the perirenal fat subjected to SPME-GC/MS analysis of VOC; the data were analyzed by stepwise discriminant analysis. The 6-methyl-2-heptanone and furanone, 2,5-dimethyl, 4-hydroxy-3(2H) allowed discrimination between the 4hAM and the 4hPM animals. These are the first results indicating that the time of the day in which the animals are allowed to graze affects the appearance of VOC in lamb fat.&#xD;
This paper was written in the framework of the LowInputBreeds project: “Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production”. The LowInputBreeds project unites 21 partners from Europe and further afield and will develop integrated breeding and management strategies to tackle the issue of improved animal health and food quality. It will run until 2014 and is co-funded by the European Union’s Seventh Framework Programme for Research and Technological Development.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Vasta, Valentina; Ventura, Valentina; Luciano, Guiseppe; Andronico, Valeria ; Pagano, Renato ; Scerra, Manuel ; Biondi, Luisa; Arvondo, Marcella and Priolo, Alessandro   (2012) The volatile compounds in lamb fat are affected by the time of grazing.   Meat Science, Available online 17 September 2011, Online, ---.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19573/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>