<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nanofasern als neuartige Träger für flüchtige Signalstoffe zur&#xD;
biotechnischen Regulierung von Schadinsekten im integrierten&#xD;
und ökologischen Landbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hein, Dr. Detlef F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hummel, Prof. Hans E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vilcinskas, Prof. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Greiner, Prof. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wendorff, Prof. Joachim H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dersch, Dr. Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hellmann, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Breuer, Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Beer, Dr. Holger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schroer, Dr. Sibylle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kratt, Dr. Armin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kleeberg, Dr. Hubertus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulze, Dr. Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wahl, Ferdinand</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Using nanofibers as dispensers for pheromones and kairomones in plant protection for&#xD;
disrupting insect chemical communication is a novel approach aiming at popularizing&#xD;
this technique in organic and integrated plant production. Expected advantages of the&#xD;
nanofibers are highly controlled spatiotemporal release rates of pheromones /&#xD;
kairomones, improved climatic stability, and mechanized application. Dispenser types&#xD;
used so far show deficiencies in one or more of these requirements. Mechanical&#xD;
application of pheromones is a new approach to reduce the costs of manual labour&#xD;
and therefore the environmentally compatible, highly specific and efficient technique of&#xD;
mating disruption may become an alternative to the use of synthetic pesticides in&#xD;
integrated pest management. The nanofibers are highly elastic, which prevents breakoff&#xD;
of smaller pieces, and polymers used are biocompatible. Due to the scale of&#xD;
nanofibers the mass input both for pheromones and for polymeric nanofibers is very&#xD;
low. Major environmental benefits are high control specificity, very low concentrations&#xD;
of residues and reduced risk of development towards insect resistance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14105/1/Hein_14105.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hein, Dr. Detlef F.; Leithold, Prof. Günter; Hummel, Prof. Hans E.; Vilcinskas, Prof. Andreas; Greiner, Prof. Andreas; Wendorff, Prof. Joachim H.; Dersch, Dr. Roland; Hellmann, Christoph; Breuer, Dr. Michael; Beer, Dr. Holger; Schroer, Dr. Sibylle; Kratt, Dr. Armin; Kleeberg, Dr. Hubertus; Schulze, Dr. Christian and Wahl, Ferdinand    (2009) Nanofasern als neuartige Träger für flüchtige Signalstoffe zur biotechnischen Regulierung von Schadinsekten im integrierten und ökologischen Landbau.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14105/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>