<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of Organic Source of Nutrients on Growth and Yield Parameters of Tomato</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>V, Alex Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>V, Krishnasamy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming of vegetables are aiming for domestic market and export. Studies were undertaken at the Department of Seed Science and Technology, Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, Coimbatore in tomato cv PKM 1 to fix optimum organic technologies for maximizing yield and quality. Recommended dose of  150 : 100 : 50, N : P : K kg ha-1 was applied in the farm of urea single super phosphate and murate of potash for inorganic treatment and in the form of vermicompost, coircompost, FYM alone and their combinations for the organic treatments at the nitrogen equivalent basis. Foliar spray of panchakavya 3 per cent, herbal leaf extract 5 per cent were given on vegetative, flowering and fruiting stages. The results showed that among the organic sources, FYM + vermicompost + panchakavya and FYM + vermicompost + HLE(Herbal Leaf Extract) performed better than other organics in yield parameter. The highest fruit weight of 39.2 g was noticed in FYM + Vermicompost + Panchakavya. The highest fruit yield was registered in inorganic treatment (26.9 t) followed by FYM + Vermicompost + Panchakavya treatment (24.6 t).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9370/1/9370.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>V, Alex Albert and V, Krishnasamy   (2004) Evaluation of Organic Source of Nutrients on Growth and Yield Parameters of Tomato.   Thesis, Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, Coimbatore, INDIA., Department of Seed Science and Technology.  .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9370/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>