<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Das Potential umstellungsbereiter Betriebe in Norwegen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Koesling, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ebbesvik, Martha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lien, Gudbrand</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flaten, Ola</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valle, Paul Steinar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>About eighteen percent of the conventional dairy and cash crop farmers in Norway are considering to, and four percent are planning to convert to organic farming during the next five years. These two farmer groups can be considered as the potential for conversion to organic farming in Norway. In a questionnaire survey, this group rated attitudes on organic and conventional farming more similar to organic farmers than other conventional farmers did. For farmers considering or planning to convert, additional organic farming payments, organic farming laws and regulations and price premiums for organic products were more important sources of risk than for other conventional farmers. Most of these mentioned factors are influenced by agricultural policies, which thus represent an important factor for farmers‘ decision regarding the conversion to organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Kassel University Press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3573/1/3573.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Koesling, Matthias; Ebbesvik, Martha; Lien, Gudbrand; Flaten, Ola and Valle, Paul Steinar    (2005) Das Potential umstellungsbereiter Betriebe in Norwegen.  [The potential for conversion to organic farming in Norway.]  In: Heß, J. and Rahmann, G. (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Kassel University Press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3573/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>