<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Analysis of organic and conventional beetroot juice assortment in Warsaw shops and consumer sensory evaluation of selected products</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>KAZIMIERCZAK, RENATA</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>JABŁOŃSKA , PAULINA</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>REMBIAŁKOWSKA, EWA</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic food is produced in accordance with strictly defined rules, established by the European Union legislation. Thanks to this is considered to be safer and healthier than produced conventionally. Many studies show that organic products, especially vegetables, fruits and preserves contained more dry matter, vitamin C, vitamin B group, total sugar, indispensable amino acids and mineral compounds. At the same time organic plant products usually have been in general better evaluated in terms of taste and smell than conventional food. The aim of this study was to analyze the assortment of beetroot juice from organic and conventional stores in Warsaw, Poland and consumer sensory evaluation of selected products. Analysis of the products was carried out in grocery stores taking into account the size of usable floor space - large-and small area, and due to the specific origin of the range of products - organic and conventional food stores. The results showed that the market of beetroot juices were diverse - organic producers juices were available mainly in specialist organic stores, and conventional juices were available in all the analyzed places. Consumer sensory evaluation, which was conducted among the students, showed that consumers did not have a explicit preference for the taste, smell, color and consistency of beet juice, due to the origin of the product.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24040/1/24040_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>KAZIMIERCZAK, RENATA; JABŁOŃSKA , PAULINA and REMBIAŁKOWSKA, EWA    (2014) Analysis of organic and conventional beetroot juice assortment in Warsaw shops and consumer sensory evaluation of selected products.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 917-920.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24040/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>