<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of pollen beetle in organic farming with plant protecting&#xD;
agents</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Humphrys, Clay</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jossi, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pollen beetle (Meligethes spp.) is a major yield-limiting factor in organic oilseed&#xD;
production. Currently there are no effective methods available to control this beetle in&#xD;
organic agriculture. From 2006 to 2008 work was carried out at Agroscope ARTReckenholz&#xD;
to find suitable organically compatible plant protecting agents which are&#xD;
effective against the beetle. A partial reduction in beetle infestation was observed&#xD;
when liquid manure, lavender oil and rapeseed oil was applied. Dusting agents such&#xD;
as ash and substances containing silicate (stone meal) were very efficient, almost&#xD;
completely removing the beetle after application. However, beetle infestation&#xD;
increased again after one or two days following application. Dusting substances in&#xD;
combination with pine oil and rapeseed oil produced the best results with an effective&#xD;
period of action of up to five days. The addition of vegetable oil is assumed to improve&#xD;
the adhesiveness of these agents. None of the methods showed any significant&#xD;
effects on oilseed yield. Practical use will require further tests and investigations into&#xD;
economic feasibility and application technology.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14463/1/Humphrys_14463.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Humphrys, Clay and Jossi, Werner    (2009) Control of pollen beetle in organic farming with plant protecting agents.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14463/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>