<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Collation and dissemination of information on the performance of vegetable and cereal varieties under organic and non-organic conditions (COSI)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Description&#xD;
&#xD;
The objective of this research project is to collate and disseminate information relating to the performance of varieties under organic conditions and to facilitate the use of a knowledge transfer centre by producers and seed suppliers. The website will list all vegetable and cereal varieties available as organic seed and include performance data in organic and non-organic conditions where this is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
The research will collate and disseminate published data on variety performance under UK conditions as well as making the latest variety trials data carried out in the UK rapidly and easilly available for organic producers. It will also group varieties that have similar performance characteristics together for key crops. This will support organic producers searching for appropriate varieties grown from organic seed.&#xD;
&#xD;
The above information will be made accessible to the organic sector via the internet website: www.cosi.org.uk Centre of Organic Seed Information (COSI). The Centre will be used as a resource to disseminate research findings, such as variety trials and a value judgement of grower experience (derived from SA questionnaires) to insure effective technology transfer. A simple search tool on COSI will enable users to search for performance data by variety.&#xD;
&#xD;
COSI will also communicate any standards changes relating to organic seed and will include updates from the four seed working groups that were established by the Soil Association in 2000. In addition latest news and information from existing research projects will be posted on the site, including information on seed treatments and organic seed production techniques. The site will also direct users to the latest legislation in all seed related areas including seed legislation, phytosanitary requirements and latest organic legislation.&#xD;
&#xD;
COSI will be supported by a telephone helpline, run by staff experienced in issues relating to organic seed, that will be able to assist the organic sector in accessing and understanding the information on variety performance trials and standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
The research meets a number of recommendations made within the Governments Organic Action Plan including:&#xD;
- organic feed and seed production should be encouraged&#xD;
- standards development towards consumer expectations,&#xD;
- R&amp;D contracts should include clear strategy for technology transfer&#xD;
&#xD;
It will also be of great help to certification bodies and producers searching for varieties with particular performance charactersitics. &#xD;
&#xD;
Objective&#xD;
1. To collate, and disseminate organic and non-organic performance information in UK coditions for vegetable and cereal varieties available as organic seed.&#xD;
&#xD;
2.To maintain constant contact with research organisations carrying out organic variety trials on an annual basis and insure that results are collated in a speedy and user friendly manor. Organisations that the project will work with include Duchy College, Welsh College of Horticulture, HRI, HDRA and Elm Farm Research Centre.&#xD;
&#xD;
3. To facilitate, collate and disseminate UK wide exchange of data from producers on how varieties have performed under their conditions using a standardised but uniform scoring system.&#xD;
&#xD;
4. To develop a fully functional Centre of Organic Seed Information accessible over the phone through a telephone support service and via the internet at www.COSI.org.uk. The centre will be used as a vehicle to find up to date variety performance data and latest variety trials, keep up to date with news on organic seed, find out about changing standards and learn about producers experiences with different varieties grown from organic seed. The centre will be the definitve knowledge transfer tool for all organic seed and variety related information and will be used widely by non organic farmers and growers searching for independent variety performance data.&#xD;
&#xD;
5. To group varieties on COSI, with similar performance characteristics.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Collation and dissemination of information on the performance of vegetable and cereal varieties under organic and non-organic conditions (COSI).    Runs 2004 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Unspecified, , National Institute for Agricultural Botany.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6708/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>