<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>COMPARISON OF TWO CHICKEN GENOTYPES ORGANICALLY REARED: OXIDATIVE STABILITY AND OTHER QUALITATIVE TRAITS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CASTELLINI, prof C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DAL BOSCO, dr A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MUGNAI, dr C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>PEDRAZZOLI, dr M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of genotype on the oxidative stability and other qualitative traits of chicken meat was studied. Two groups of 200 chicks (Ross 205 and Kabir) were reared according to the organic farming system. At 81 d of age 20 birds per group were slaughtered and after refrigeration (24 h at 4°C) of the carcasses, Pectoralis major muscles were excised for analyses.Samples were analysed after 0, 24, 48, 72 and 96 hours of storage at 4°C under continuous fluorescent illumination (2300 lux). The analyses concerned the chemical composition and the shear force (only at time 0) and the progress of several traits as pH, CIELAB values, Thiobarbituric Acid Reactive Substances (TBARS), panel test and fatty acid composition (at 0 and after 96 h). Genotype greatly affected the physico-chemical characteristics and the sensory evaluation. The meat from Ross chickens showed high TBARS values, perhaps due to selection for growth rate that reduced their adaptability to greater space allowance and to poorer environmental conditions; these higher TBARS values were also negatively correlated to lightness and yellowness. The initial level of TBARS affected the oxidative stability of breast meat during storage. The amount of TBARS showed significantly negative relationship with the sensory evaluation; breast meat of Kabir had higher scores for liking when the level of malondialdehyde was less than 2.5 mg kg-1.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Avenue media, Bologna Italy</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Scipioni, prof R</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9328/1/Castellini_IJAS_01-06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CASTELLINI, prof C; DAL BOSCO, dr A; MUGNAI, dr C and PEDRAZZOLI, dr M   (2006) COMPARISON OF TWO CHICKEN GENOTYPES ORGANICALLY REARED: OXIDATIVE STABILITY AND OTHER QUALITATIVE TRAITS.   Italian journal animal science (5), pp. 29-42.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9328/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>