<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss unterschiedlicher Bewirtschaftungsverfahren auf&#xD;
P-Formen und P-Dynamik im Boden</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Keller, Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bünemann, Else K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of cropping systems on soil phosphorus (P) forms and P dynamics was&#xD;
studied. The systems were a biodynamic (DYN), a bioorganic (BIO), a conventional&#xD;
(CON), a stockless system (MIN) and an unfertilized control (NON). These cropping&#xD;
systems are part of the DOK field trial in Therwil near Basel. The systems differed in&#xD;
fertilization and plant protection. The P budgets over 30 years were negative except&#xD;
for CON and increased in the order: NON &lt; DYN &lt; ORG &lt; MIN &lt; CON. A sequential&#xD;
P extraction scheme was used to characterize the P forms in soil samples from 2007&#xD;
and 1977 (before the start of the trial). Labile inorganic P (Pi) forms differed significantly&#xD;
between cropping systems. Organic P forms (Po) and stable Pi forms were not&#xD;
affected by the cropping systems apart from Po in concentrated HCl extract. The&#xD;
comparison between P forms in the soils of 2007 and 1977 revealed depletion in labile&#xD;
Pi forms in all systems. The changes were related to the P budget. Po changes were&#xD;
small and thus most of Po appears to be strongly stabilized in the soil.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14255/1/Keller_14255.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Keller, Martina; Oberson, Astrid; Frossard, Emmanuel; Mäder, Paul; Mayer, Jochen and Bünemann, Else K.    (2009) Einfluss unterschiedlicher Bewirtschaftungsverfahren auf P-Formen und P-Dynamik im Boden.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14255/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>