<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirken sich Auslauf- und Einstreumanagement auf den Wurmbefall&#xD;
von Legehennen aus?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amsler, Zivile</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perler, Erika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of our experiments was to investigate the transmission and infectivity of the&#xD;
two main helminth parasites of poultry (Ascaridia galli and Heterakis gallinarum) under&#xD;
different run and litter management regimes. In experiment (a) two stocking rates were&#xD;
simulated in outdoor runs and the effect of a simple management practice (mowing)&#xD;
on helminth transmission was studied during two subsequent flocks. Stocking rate&#xD;
seemed not to change helminth transmission patterns and repeated mowing of runs&#xD;
did not reduce helminth infections. Lower stocking rates led to a substantial improvement&#xD;
of the run vegetation. In experiment (b) two litter management regimes (replace&#xD;
or add litter material) were compared to unmanaged litter with regard to parasitological&#xD;
parameters and water content of the litter. The regimes had no significant effect on&#xD;
water content or on parasitological parameters. These results suggest that positive&#xD;
effects of run and litter management regimes on helminth infections of laying hens are&#xD;
often overestimated in practice.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14106/1/Maurer_14106.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Maurer, Veronika; Amsler, Zivile; Perler, Erika and Heckendorn, Felix    (2009) Wirken sich Auslauf- und Einstreumanagement auf den Wurmbefall von Legehennen aus?       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14106/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>