<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Compound-Specific δ15N and δ13C Analyses of Amino Acids for Potential Discrimination between Organically and Conventionally Grown Wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paolini, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ziller, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, K.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Husted, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Camin, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We present a study deploying compound-specific nitrogen and carbon isotope analysis of amino acids to discriminate between organically and conventionally grown plants. We focused on grain samples of common wheat and durum wheat grown using synthetic nitrogen fertilizers, animal manures, or green manures from nitrogen-fixing legumes. The&#xD;
measurement of amino acid δ15N and δ13C values, after protein hydrolysis and derivatization, was carried out using gas chromatography−combustion−isotope ratio mass spectrometry (GC-C-IRMS). Our results demonstrated that δ13C of glutamic acid and glutamine in particular, but also the combination of δ15N and δ13C of 10 amino acids, can improve the discrimination between conventional and organic wheat compared to stable isotope bulk tissue analysis. We concluded that compound-specific stable isotope analysis of amino acids represents a novel analytical tool with the potential to support and improve the certification&#xD;
and control procedures in the organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/29077/1/29077.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paolini, M.; Ziller, L.; Laursen, K.H.; Husted, S. and Camin, F.   (2015) Compound-Specific δ15N and δ13C Analyses of Amino Acids for Potential Discrimination between Organically and Conventionally Grown Wheat.        [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/29077/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>