<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of the apple sawfly Hoplocampa testudinea Klug in organic fruit growing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, P:</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rank, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bathon, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The best application technique and application data for the treatments with Quassia extract against the apple sawfly Hoplocampa testudinea Klug were tested. The spraying solution was distributed best on the receptacle of the blossom – the place where the sawfly larvae feed before the enter the blossom – when the treatment was effecttuated at fading blossom with a high amount of water (about 500 l/ha/mTh). The addition of T/S forte, a wetting agent, could also improve the efficacy of Quassia treatments in a lower dose. Thus, it is recommended to apply in fading blossom with addi-tion of T/S forte and high amounts of water to obtain the best effect. If the conditions for applica-tions are good and the infestation is not too high, the normally recommended dose of 6 g/ha/mTh can even be reduced.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8806/1/ecofruit_12th_4.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.; Zimmer, J.; Maxin, P:; Rank, H.; Bathon, H. and Zebitz, C.P.W.    (2006) Control of the apple sawfly Hoplocampa testudinea Klug in organic fruit growing.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 25-29.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8806/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>