<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Extractability of slurry and fertilizer phopshorus in soil after repeated freezing</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Soinne, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peltovuori, Tommi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The potential effects of freezing on phosphorus (P) chemistry in Finnish soils are not well known. We studied the effects of multiple freeze-thaw cycles on soil P chemistry in a laboratory incubation experiment with one organic and one mineral surface soil. The soils were incubated at +5°C or at alternating +5/–20°C temperatures for 24 weeks, either without amendment or amended with pig slurry or with commercial compound fertilizer (NPK 20–3–9). After incubation, the soils were analyzed for water-soluble reactive and unreactive P, and acid ammonium acetate soluble P (PAAA). Freezing and thawing of soils during the incubation had no significant effect on any of the water-soluble P fractions or PAAA. The outcome was most likely a consequence of the good P status of the soils, which masked the gentle effects of freezing. According to these results, the time of soil sampling (fall vs. spring) has no effect on P test results on soils with a good P status. Concentrations of soluble P after incubation were roughly twice as high in the slurry treatments than in the fertilizer treatments, demonstrating potentially better long-term availability of slurry P.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16823/1/soinne.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Soinne, Helena and Peltovuori, Tommi   (2005) Extractability of slurry and fertilizer phopshorus in soil after repeated freezing.   Agricultural and Food Science, 14 (2), pp. 181-188.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16823/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>