<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of different management strategies on soil quality&#xD;
of citrus orchards in Southern Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Canali, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Emanuela, Di Bartolomeo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alessandra, Trinchera</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luigi, Nisini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fabio, Tittarelli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Francesco, Intrigliolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giancarlo, Roccuzzo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maria Luisa, Calabretta</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Twenty-six soil samples were collected from 13 paired orchards (organically vs. conventionally managed)&#xD;
homogeneous for age, rootstock and cultivars, belonging to the Eastern Sicily Organic Citrus&#xD;
farm Network. The soil quality was evaluated by chemical and biochemical indicators. The total&#xD;
organic C, humification parameters and isoelectric focusing of extracted organic matter were measured&#xD;
to quantify the size of relevant soil C pools. In addition, C turnover was evaluated by determining&#xD;
microbial C mineralization, C microbial biomass and by calculating the mineralization and metabolic&#xD;
quotient (qCO2). The results obtained demonstrated that organic citrus soils were characterized by a&#xD;
general increase in all the organic matter pools, which means a greater C supply for soil metabolic&#xD;
processes. This observed trend did not directly influence the organic matter turnover, indicating that&#xD;
the organic approach could act as a soil C-sink. The soil microflora of organically managed soils&#xD;
showed an improved efficiency in use of energy and organic resources, corresponding to an increased&#xD;
ability of soils under organic management to sustain biological productivity in the long term.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28208/1/Soil%20Use%20and%20Management%20_%20survey%20of%20citrus%20orchards.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Canali, Stefano; Emanuela, Di Bartolomeo; Alessandra, Trinchera; Luigi, Nisini; Fabio, Tittarelli; Francesco, Intrigliolo; Giancarlo, Roccuzzo and Maria Luisa, Calabretta    (2009) Effect of different management strategies on soil quality of citrus orchards in Southern Italy.   In:     Soil Use and Management, 25, pp. 34-42.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28208/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>