<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORGANIC FARMING INTEGRITY IN MAIZE CULTIVATION IN SPAIN</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bello, Dr A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Porcuna, Dr J. L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fabeiro, Dra C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonz치lvez, Mr V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Although now Genetically Modified Organism (GMO) maize varieties (Zea mays L. ) are legal in all EU Member States, Spain was the first European Union (EU) country where this type of varieties were cultivated, since 1998. Currently the Spanish Ministry of Agriculture, Fish and Food (MAPA), estimate ca. 12 % of the total conventional maize area was sown last year 2006 with these varieties. In the last five years 9 organic maize contamination cases have been report by 3 different EU organic certification bodies in Navarra, Arag칩n and Catalu침a. But no actions to search sources of contamination, lessons to develop an improved coexistence regulation, were taken. Organic farmers never received any compensation for their losses. This paper analyse existing information, research studies and also interviews and visits to organic farms with maize, concluding that organic maize integrity is still not granted in Spain.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>European Comission JOint Research Centre. Institute for Prospective Technological Studies. Luxembourg: Office for Official Publications of the European Communities 2007</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Stein, Dr. A. J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rodriguez-Cerezo, Dr. E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12909/1/034-Bello-Organic_as1.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bello, Dr A; Porcuna, Dr J. L.; Fabeiro, Dra C. and Gonz치lvez, Mr V.    (2007) ORGANIC FARMING INTEGRITY IN MAIZE CULTIVATION IN SPAIN.   In: Stein, Dr. A. J. and Rodriguez-Cerezo, Dr. E. (Eds.)  Third International Conference on Coexistence between Genetically Modified (GM) and non-GM based Agricultural Supply Chains Book of abstracts, European Comission JOint Research Centre. Institute for Prospective Technological Studies. Luxembourg: Office for Official Publications of the European Communities 2007, pp. 373-374.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12909/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>