<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>100 % organic ration works for organic table birds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Woodward, Lawrence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>O'Brien, Josie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Poultry researcher Josie O’Brien and Lawrence Woodward present some results from a series of EFRC trials that are questioning the need for the conventional feed derogation in organic poultry production.&#xD;
Currently the use of up to twenty percent of non-organic components is allowed in the feed ration of organically certified table birds.  Although this derogation is supposed to be removed in August 2005, there is mounting pressure to allow it to continue in some form. The derogation was introduced due to concerns that without it the bird’s nutritional needs could not be met by certified organic sources alone and therefore their health, welfare and growth would be compromised.&#xD;
The primary concern relates to amino acid levels and in particular methionine. There was and still remains a perception that the ingredients generally used by the sector to supply methionine do not have a suitable organic substitute; or at least one that is easily accessible at a reasonable price. &#xD;
This trial revealed no overall health or growth or welfare issues when comparing the two rations, contrary to suggestions that there might be due to the assumed nutritional inadequacy of the one hundred percent organic ration. &#xD;
Since the end of this trial we have undertaken further work that is confirming these findings.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elm Farm Research Centre</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4185/1/4185.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Woodward, Lawrence and O'Brien, Josie    (2005) 100 % organic ration works for organic table birds.   Elm Farm Research Centre Bulletin, 2005 (76), pp. 8-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4185/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>