<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmer Family Learning Groups for Community Development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tibasiima, Thaddeo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nalunga, Jane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dissing, Aage</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dissing, Inge Lis</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The approach which is owned by everybody who uses it.&#xD;
&#xD;
Farmer Family Learning Groups are groups of farmer families, who together define their needs and goals in relation to their own future development, both as individuals, families and as a group - and then they help each other to reach the goals. The groups form strong networks and help each other, and help the entire local community. &#xD;
&#xD;
Organic farming is practiced in ways which are contextual specific and dependent on the environment, wherever it is being practiced. Forming farmer groups using this approach is likewise contextual specific and entirely determined by the needs and wishes and agreements within the group of families who in the first place decided to form a group for conscious and goal directed development in their households and local community.&#xD;
&#xD;
The beauty of the approach – like many other empowering group approaches – is its flexibility and at the same time strong and clear foundation on values like respect, trust, equality, common learning, building up human and social capital and knowledge which is relevant and meaningful to each participant and learner, as well as probably the most important value: ownership. &#xD;
&#xD;
Contact to the authors and further information can be obtained through the web pages of SATNET, NOGAMU and OD.  &#xD;
Tell me and I will forget&#xD;
Show me and I will remember&#xD;
Involve me and I will understand&#xD;
Step back and I will act</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>NOGAMU SATNET ORGANIC DENMARK</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-08-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19341/4/19341.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vaarst, Mette; Tibasiima, Thaddeo; Nalunga, Jane; Dissing, Aage and Dissing, Inge Lis    (2011) Farmer Family Learning Groups for Community Development.   1 edition.  NOGAMU SATNET ORGANIC DENMARK, Kampala, Uganda.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19341/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>