<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ROBUSTFISH: NEW POSSIBILITIES FOR GROWTH AND ROBUSTNESS IN ORGANIC AQUACULTURE</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jokumsen, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høglund, Erik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lund, Ivar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, Lone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Lars-Flemming</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Max</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Thorkild</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Villy J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Erling P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Aquaculture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of Robustfish project is to answer the following research questions: (1) Is it possible to select robust rainbow trout fry early in development before they enter the more cost intensive steps in the production cycle? (2) Does sustainable (non-fish based) dietary lipid sources affect stress resilience and immune-competence of the fry? (3) Related to (1) and (2): Is improved resistance to RTFS achieved? (4) How will the market respond to a significant increase in production of organic trout, i.e. consumer preferences and competiveness by companies in the value chain?&#xD;
&#xD;
RobustFish will strengthen the development of Danish organic trout production. In this respect the robustness of the fry to diseases is crucial, i.a. RTFS. The robustness of the fry seems to be related to larval developmental rate and to the dietary content of specific Ω-3 fatty acids (HUFAs). Stress and RTFS challenge tests will be performed to investigate if these two factors can be included in strategies to increase the robustness of the fry. Further, the effect of water treatments on health and welfare using approved agents (Pedersen et al., 2013) is tested. RobustFish will create growth – based on organic principles and in a balance between environment, ethics and economy. The efforts will also aim at improving the productivity of the conventional trout farming by a lower prevalence of RTFS, reduced medication and lower environmental impact. Connected to these efforts RobustFish also will provide needed knowledge about market conditions and consumer attitudes, including the competitive effect of increased production (Nielsen et al., 2007). Mapping the existing types of organic aquaculture products in European markets will pave the way for product development and increased market share.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27821/12/27821.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27821/2/EAS-2014_besk%C3%A5ret.jpg</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jokumsen, Alfred ; Høglund, Erik; Lund, Ivar; Madsen, Lone; Pedersen, Lars-Flemming; Nielsen, Max; Nielsen, Thorkild; Larsen, Villy J.  and Larsen, Erling P.    (2014) ROBUSTFISH: NEW POSSIBILITIES FOR GROWTH AND ROBUSTNESS IN ORGANIC AQUACULTURE.       Poster at:   Aquaculture Europe 2014, San Sebastian, Spain, 14-17 October 2014.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27821/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>