<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cultural sustainability of Finnish food system: Young consumers' approach</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>• Discourse represented competent SD jargon&#xD;
• Critical stance visible towards SD and organic food&#xD;
• Economic reason connected as ruling entity with law,&#xD;
science, politics, moral and education&#xD;
• Only economically feasible and innovative solutions&#xD;
accepted&#xD;
• Evidence based political decisions and public&#xD;
organization of activities such as organic school food&#xD;
expected&#xD;
• Alignment with reasonable individual practical effort&#xD;
• Moral demand for SD and organic food addressed to&#xD;
wealthier people and given up by less well-off people&#xD;
• Cynicism visible in the situation of perceived&#xD;
sustainability threat and disbelief in individuals’ effort,&#xD;
‘fairness’, lack of caring for one self and others&#xD;
&#xD;
• Young peoples’ discourse indicated their high level&#xD;
education, intellectual and moral quality, in age conformity&#xD;
• Focus on every-day practices seemed virtuous as&#xD;
commitment to improvement of ‘basic needs’ – paper,&#xD;
electricity, public traffic, even food&#xD;
• Some difficulties with practices reported (recycling, snacks)&#xD;
• Leads easily to virtues and vices and strength of will&#xD;
• Interestingly, context dependent organic food use reported&#xD;
(in summer cottage) and structural change as vitamin D&#xD;
addition into organic milk suggested&#xD;
• Three things disturb this positive image: the lack things of&#xD;
higher personal interest, additional examples of personal&#xD;
commitment and suggestions for structural changes&#xD;
• Tendency to emphasis on political decisions based on&#xD;
scientific evidence and fair sharing of costs/labour&#xD;
• How much more can we expect of them in terms of cultural&#xD;
sustainability compared with what we expect of ourselves?</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Helsinki, Ruralia Institute</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Teaching resource</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16834/1/ESRS_Minna_Mikkola.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkola, Minna    (2009) Cultural sustainability of Finnish food system: Young consumers' approach.   University of Helsinki, Ruralia Institute, http://www.helsinki.fi/ruralia/julkaisut/pdf/ESRS_Minna_Mikkola.pdf.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16834/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>