<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control of fruit flies pest on guava fruit by using organic insecticide</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kardinan, Agus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Guava fruit (Psidium guajava) is a mainstay commodity in Bogor and Bogor district is a supplier of guava into surrounding towns. In Bogor, population of guava fruit is around 160,000  trees that reaches an area of about 800 ha and scattered in several places, including in the Village of Kencana, Sukadamai, Mekarwangi and Sukaresmi that reaches an area of about 80 ha with a population of about sixteen thousand trees. Production during the harvest reaches 15 tones per ha at each harvest, and the harvest can be done every three days. Nevertheless, one of the obstacles limiting factor in the production is a matter of losing the results, both quantitatively by falling fruit, as well as qualitatively by rotten fruit  caused by infestation of fruit flies (Bactrocera spp) with a strike rate that can reach about 75 %.&#xD;
So far, control measure that has been done is by synthetic insecticide spraying, wrapping fruits, fencing garden with nets nearly as high as 3 meters to deter pest fruit flies not to attack guava fruit. Such control measures  is relatively expensive, also cause problems with insecticide residues in fruits and environments that adversely affect human health and the environment. A technique control that is considered environmentally friendly is to use an organic insecticide made from plants, such as basil plant (Ocimum spp) and Tea tree (Melaleuca bracteata).&#xD;
Essential oil obtained from distillation of basil and tea tree leaves contain methyl eugenol (C12H24O2) which is acting as attractant for fruit flies.  Fruit flies will try to consume methyl eugenol before matting.  Methyl eugenol consumed is as a compound to result sex pheromone in fruit flies body to attract their couple, therefore fruit flies will try to reach methyl eugenol as far as 100 m to 1,000 m.  By locating methyl eugenol in the trap, then fruit flies will be trapped.  This technique is considered as environmentally friendly technique, hence can be applied in organic farming practice.   &#xD;
The use of organic insecticides derived from the distillation of basil  (Ocimum spp) and tea tree (Melaleuca bracteata) leaves containing methyl eugenol (C12H24O2) is very effective to control  fruit flies in guava orchard, so that it is able to decrease pest attack and consequently increase farmers income.  Since organic insecticide is considered environmentally friendly, therefore it can be applied in organic farming practice.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23314/1/23314%20CONTROL%20OF%20FRUIT%20FLIES%20PEST-turkey-revised_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kardinan, Agus    (2014) Control of fruit flies pest on guava fruit by using organic insecticide.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 675-678.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23314/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>