<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pflanzenselektion durch freilebende Rinder in südbolivianischen&#xD;
Bergwäldern</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marquardt, Svenja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Beck, Dr. Stephan G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Encinas, Felix D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Dr. Andrea C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzer, Prof. Dr. Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alzérreca, Dr. Humberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the present research was to study the plant species selected by freeranging&#xD;
cattle in southern Bolivian subtropical mountain forests. The cattle were followed&#xD;
from May to November 2005 during 4-5 days/month in two study sites. The number&#xD;
of bites on the different plant species were recorded every 6 min. during 1 min. of&#xD;
actual observation. Additionally, plant availability was measured. The selection and&#xD;
availability data were ranked, giving rank number 1 to the most frequently selected&#xD;
plant species. Basing on this ranking system, species were categorized into four&#xD;
categories. Overall, 447 plant species were found in the study sites, whereof 364 were&#xD;
observed to be selected by the cattle. A low number of species (15, including indetermined&#xD;
leaf litter) made up the major part of plant selection (about 60%) and were&#xD;
classified as “main forage plants”, with the grass Ichnanthus pallens being the most&#xD;
selected plant species. Sixteen species were classified as “preferred”, 20 as “least&#xD;
preferred” and 121 as “neutral”.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14332/1/Marquardt_14332.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Marquardt, Svenja; Beck, Dr. Stephan G.; Encinas, Felix D.; Mayer, Dr. Andrea C.; Kreuzer, Prof. Dr. Michael and Alzérreca, Dr. Humberto    (2009) Pflanzenselektion durch freilebende Rinder in südbolivianischen Bergwäldern.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14332/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>