<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How to measure and regulate localness?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There are two main forces that work against the local, globalisation and functional differentiation. Localness as such is not a basic principle of organic agriculture, but the concerns for localness are connected to two ethical concerns, functional integrity and ecological justice, which are expressed in the organic principles. The problem of delocalisation is not simply a question of spatial distance but of associated consequences such as externalities, commodification, unfair trade, lack of transparency and breakdown of local food systems. Therefore, it is not easy to measure and regulate localness. Simple distance measures do not directly address these consequences, and more sofisticated measures are difficult to implement. One way to regulate is to add a "localness label" on the products and leave the choice, and the responsibility, with the consumers. Another way to regulate localness is to address the consequences associated with distance in the organic standards, where complex and varied issues can be handled, but then precautionary concerns need to be addressed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8318/1/Alroe_and_Kjeldsen-How_to_measure_and_regulate_localness.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alrøe, Hugo F. and Kjeldsen, Chris    (2006) How to measure and regulate localness?       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8318/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>