<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Institutional consumers' views of GHG emission reduction by optional milk systems within sustainability frame</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkola, Minna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Risku-Norja, Helmi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>An on-going study examines how Green House Gas (GHG) emission information could be&#xD;
used to support consumption driven changes in production, leading to reduction of GHG emissions in&#xD;
agriculture. This paper presents a pre-study, looking for discursive grounds by which institutional&#xD;
consumers make choices when confronted with the knowledge of GHG emission characteristics of five&#xD;
optional milk systems. The milk systems to be compared in terms of agricultural GHG emissions were&#xD;
(Option I) conventional milk system based on imported soy protein feed, (Option II) conventional milk&#xD;
system using domestic protein source and (Option III) organic milk system, as well as vegetable milk&#xD;
systems based on (Option IV) imported soy and (Option V) domestic oat. The discursive turn to these&#xD;
optional milk systems was taken by five catering information professionals, who tried to respond to the&#xD;
idea of catering for sustainability. The results revealed four different discourses, with variable ability to&#xD;
make use of emission information when systemic change is to be approached in everyday productive&#xD;
activities. Regarding emission information, the least sensitive discourse was the one of modernization,&#xD;
emphasising the use of conventional, cheap products. Sustainability and ecological modernization&#xD;
discourses exhibited most imaginative and novel solutions in productive activities. Bioregionalism&#xD;
discourse joined other discourses connecting them with the idea of domestic production. The&#xD;
discourses identified in this pre-study were, however, very fine-grained and intermingled, offering&#xD;
rather lean support for novel choices. Additionally the market position of organic milk suffered due to&#xD;
emission information, stressing heavily the reliability of environmental information as a ‘change agent’&#xD;
on the market.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA SAD</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17572/1/mikkola.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkola, Minna and Risku-Norja, Helmi    (2008) Institutional consumers' views of GHG emission reduction by optional milk systems within sustainability frame.       Paper at:   Empowerment of the rural actors: a renewal of the farming systems perspective : 8th European IFSA symposium, Clermont Ferrand, France, 6-10 July 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17572/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>