<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Four years of experience with the control of plum rust in organic production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häseli, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plum rust Tranzschelia pruni spinosa is an important disease and at present, no fungicide is registered&#xD;
for the organic agriculture in Switzerland. The efficacy of different fungicides potentially suitable&#xD;
for organic production and the susceptibility of different plum varieties against plum rust was&#xD;
tested during four years in different field trials in Switzerland.&#xD;
With the seven tested varieties only Top and Elena showed a clearly higher tolerance.&#xD;
With four to five treatments in the main infection period mid of June to mid of July the following results&#xD;
were obtained: Pandorra (Fennel oil) and Trilogy (Azadirachtin-free Neemoil) did not obtain a&#xD;
sufficient effect. Very high significant effects of about 80 % could be obtained with lime sulphur,&#xD;
Thiovit (wettable sulphur) and somewhat less with Serenade (Bacillus subtilis).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14456/1/23_Haeseli_115_121.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häseli, Andreas    (2004) Four years of experience with the control of plum rust in organic production.  [Vierjährige Versuchserfahrungen zur Regulierung des Zwetschgenrostes.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 115-121.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14456/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>