<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Möglichkeiten der Bekämpfung des Falschen Mehltaus an&#xD;
Gurke (Pseudoperonospora cubensis) mit alternativen&#xD;
Präparaten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nowak, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Konstantinidou-Doltsinis, Dr. Stavroula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seddon, Dr. Barrie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmitt, Dr. Annegret</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic cucumber production the infection with downy mildew (Pseudoperonospora&#xD;
cubensis) is one of the major problems. Use of biological control agents based on&#xD;
plant extracts and antagonistic micro organisms may be one possibility to control the&#xD;
disease.&#xD;
Plant extracts from Salvia officinalis and a plant belonging to the family Fabaceae&#xD;
(P1), as well as cultures of Brevibacillus brevis showed, in bioassays on potted&#xD;
cucumber plants, high potential to control the disease with efficacies between 55%&#xD;
and 100%. For S. officinalis extract the efficacy was close to 100% even at a&#xD;
concentration of 0.1325%. Initial trials under commercial growing conditions showed&#xD;
that the control of P. cubensis is better in protected than in open field production. In&#xD;
order to optimise the efficacy of the preparations for use in commercial cucumber&#xD;
production, further investigations on the mode of action, the active ingredients etc. are&#xD;
under way.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14653/1/Nowak_14653.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nowak, Andrea; Konstantinidou-Doltsinis, Dr. Stavroula; Seddon, Dr. Barrie and Schmitt, Dr. Annegret    (2009) Möglichkeiten der Bekämpfung des Falschen Mehltaus an Gurke (Pseudoperonospora cubensis) mit alternativen Präparaten.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14653/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>