<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>GM and non-GM supply chains: Their CO-EXistence and TRAceability</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Co-Extra aims at&#xD;
- developing comprehensive tools and methodologies and integrate them along with existing ones into embedded decision-support systems aimed at enabling co-existence between GM and non GM (conventional and organic) crops;&#xD;
- tracing of genetically modified organism (GMO) materials and derived products, along the food and feed chains;&#xD;
- anticipating the future expansion of GMOs in both quantitative as well as qualitative terms.&#xD;
&#xD;
Co-Extra will study and validate biological containment methods and model supply chain organisations and provide practical tools and methods for implementing co-existence. In parallel, Co-Extra will design and integrate GMO detection tools, develop sampling plans, and elaborate new techniques to meet the challenges raised by increased demands for cost effective multiplex methods to detect as yet unapproved or unexamined GMOs and by e.g. stacked genes. Co-Extra will also study and propose the most appropriate information structure, content and flow management for ensuring reliable and cost-effective documentary traceability.All of the methods and tools that will be studied and developed will be assessed not only from the technical point of view but also with regard to economic and legal aspects. In parallel, to promote harmonisation of co-existence and traceability practices around the world, Co-Extra will survey the GMO-related legal regimes and practices that exist in and beyond the EU.Stakeholders will be involved in the project from the start through the dialogue platform, editorial offices, focus groups, national relays, etc. Co-Extra outcomes will contribute to reinforcing consumers’ confidence in labelling claims and therefore EU products at large. By helping economic stakeholders to meet consumers’ requirements for reliable choices, Co-Extra will improve European competitiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
Co-Extra outcomes will be proposed to standardisation after validation. Dissemination activities will largely benefit from the strong commitment of the European Network of GMO Laboratories.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EU-COEXTRA: GM and non-GM supply chains: Their CO-EXistence and TRAceability.  [EU-Projekt zur Rückverfolgbarkeit und Koexistenz.]   Runs 2002 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Stolze, Matthias, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6226/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>