<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving knowledge of pest and weed control in organic crop production in Wales</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frost, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>1.1 ADAS Pwllpeiran were commissioned by the Farming Connect Organic Development Centre to compile information on pest and weed control and to hold workshops that will be valuable for the development of organic horticulture in Wales.&#xD;
1.2 The project started on 1st October 2002, and three Welsh Organic Grower Workshops were held in 2002 / 2003 at Aberystwyth, Northop and Llanarthne.&#xD;
1.3 The first workshop was held at the Llanbadarn Campus at University of Wales, Aberystwyth with a farm visit to Blaencamel, Cilcennin. There were fifteen delegates including growers, Farming Connect facilitators and researchers.&#xD;
1.4 The second workshop was held at the Welsh College of Horticulture, Northop, Mold, 22 January, 2003. There were seven delegates including growers, consultants, 1 Farming Connect Facilitator and 2 students.&#xD;
1.5 The third workshop was held at the National Botanic Garden of Wales, Llanarthne, Carmarthen. There were 28 delegates, 25 growers and three researchers / consultants.&#xD;
1.6 Technical information has been prepared on ‘Pest and Disease Control in Horticultural Crops’ and ‘Weed Control in Horticultural Crops’ for organic growers. The format for publication will be decided by Organic Centre Wales.&#xD;
1.7 The workshops identified 9 areas for action: composting, management of specific pests and diseases, making information on mechanical weed control more available, developing top and soft fruit growing, promoting health benefits of organic food, promoting marketing, support for horticultural businesses, monitoring effects of climate change, collection of information on the performance of organic seed varieties, the need&#xD;
for high quality alternatives to peat based growing media, and a greater focus on nonfood&#xD;
crops.&#xD;
1.8 Priorities and action points have been developed for each of these areas and it is proposed that these should be incorporated into a draft Action Plan for Organic Horticulture in Wales.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10834/1/pest_and_weed_control.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Frost, David         (2003) Improving knowledge of pest and weed control in organic crop production in Wales.    Organic Centre Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10834/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>