<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evaluation of 14 Old Unsprayed Apple Varieties</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kühn, Birka Falk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pedersen, Hanne Lindhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The performance of 14 old apple varieties planted in three experimental plots was evaluated over four or five seasons. The yield and fruit size were recorded on conventionally grown trees. The level of disease and pests on trees and fruits was estimated in an organically grown unsprayed plot, and the eating quality was evaluated in an unsprayed experimental plot. Large differences in yield and fruit size were found between varieties. It was demonstrated that Holsteiner Cox was the only variety that combined high yield, good fruit size and good eating quality with an acceptably low susceptibility to disease. Most varieties had poor eating quality.  ‘Holsteiner Cox’ had a medium susceptibility to canker and powdery mildew, while susceptibility to apple scab varied between the years. The investigation showed that old varieties seemed to be as susceptible to disease as newer commercially grown varieties. Of the 14 varieties only Holsteiner Cox was of interest for organic growing.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/132/1/Evaluation_af_14_old_Unsprayed_Apple_Varieties.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kühn, Birka Falk and Pedersen, Hanne Lindhard   (2003) Evaluation of 14 Old Unsprayed Apple Varieties.   Biological Agriculture &amp; Horticulture, 20 (4), pp. 301-310.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/132/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>