<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökologischer Anbau von Äpfeln ohne den Einsatz von Pflanzenschutzmitteln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Geipel, Karlheinz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreckl, Wolfgang</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plant protection is still a burning issue in organic apple production. Insufficient strategies lead to minor quali-ties and immense profit cuts. To thwart these problems and to support organic apple production a program has been started to test a new cultivation system for apple farming. Preconditions for the profitability of the new method are a high yield of premium quality apples comparable to those reached in conventional farming. Main components of the new cultivation system are a foil canopy to prevent fungal infections and lateral net-tings for protection against animal pests and to allow the application of beneficial organisms. To meet the top claims of organic production no chemical plant protection is performed and EU regulations are regarded. The program funded by the Bavarian State Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry started in 2002. First results show the practicability of the new cultivation system for organic apple production but also deficiencies still to be solved.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8842/1/ecofruit_12th_24.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Geipel, Karlheinz and Kreckl, Wolfgang    (2006) Ökologischer Anbau von Äpfeln ohne den Einsatz von Pflanzenschutzmitteln.  [Organic apple farming without pesticide application.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Weinsberg, Germany, pp. 133-137.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8842/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>