<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of Young Children (3-6 years) on Organic Food Consumption in their Families</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haberkorn, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Our interest was to analyse families with young children (3-6 years) to understand their consumption patterns of organic foods. To understand the influence of children on organic food consumption, as well as the role and impact of kindergarten, we studied the attitudes, habits and behaviour of 24 mothers and one couple through qualitative interviews. We found that children positively influence the consumption of organic food in the families, and that organic foods served in kindergartens is highly accepted by the parents. Five consumer types were identified based on the criteria of motivation, knowledge and economic aspects. Three conflict fields influencing the decision making process for organic food. Consumption of organic products is not a linear development process but can change in different life periods.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12130/2/Freyer_12130_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Freyer, B. and Haberkorn, A.    (2008) Influence of Young Children (3-6 years) on Organic Food Consumption in their Families.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12130/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>