<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Migration und Ausbreitung der Kirschfruchtfliege innerhalb von Obstanlagen – Möglichkeit der biologischen Bodenbehandlung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wyss, Eric</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The European cherry fruit fly (Rhagoletis cerasi) is the only pest insect which makes a&#xD;
insecticide treatment of cherry fruit necessary. With regard of residue free cherries a biocontrol&#xD;
method for R. cerasi by soil applications seems attractive. However, soil treatments can only be&#xD;
effective if the migration of flies is low. In order to examine the potential of soil treatments and to&#xD;
understand the dispersal behaviour of R. cerasi in orchards, experiments using nettings to cover the&#xD;
soil were conducted. The experiments were arranged in commercial, organically managed orchards. The nettings reduced fruit infestation by 90%. In addition, it was shown that the flies move only very short distances (less than 5 m) within orchards. Thus, soil treatments are an interesting strategy to control R. cerasi in extensively managed orchards.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20263/1/B_2009_12KifliMigrationDgaaE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia and Wyss, Eric   (2009) Migration und Ausbreitung der Kirschfruchtfliege innerhalb von Obstanlagen – Möglichkeit der biologischen Bodenbehandlung.   Mitteilungen der deutschen Gesellschaft für allgemeine und angewandte Entomologie, 17, pp. 247-248.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20263/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>