<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SIMULATING WINTER WHEAT YIELD AND NITROGEN LEACHING FROM ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL CROP ROTATIONS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Doltra, Jordi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ølsen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lægdsmand, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This work evaluates the effects of growing a green manure crop or a legume crop in winter wheat yield and on nitrate leaching, in an irrigated crop rotation. Results are also compared with a conventional cropping system. Simulations with the field version of the FASSET model (Berntsen et al., 2003) were done to evaluate the performance of the model to predict winter wheat dry matter yield. The simulated leaching from the different cropping systems was evaluated during the rotation period.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Università degli Studi di Torino; Università degli Studi di Milano</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Grignani, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Acutis, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Zavattaro, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bechini, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Bertora, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Marino Gallina, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sacco, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-06-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16153/2/16153.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Doltra, Jordi; Ølsen, Jørgen E. and Lægdsmand, Mette    (2009) SIMULATING WINTER WHEAT YIELD AND NITROGEN LEACHING FROM ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL CROP ROTATIONS.   In: Grignani, C.; Acutis, M.; Zavattaro, L.; Bechini, L.; Bertora, C.; Marino Gallina, P. and Sacco, D. (Eds.)  Proceedings of the 16th Nitrogen Workshop: Connecting different scales of nitrogen use in agriculture, Università degli Studi di Torino; Università degli Studi di Milano, Turin, (Italy), pp. 519-520.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16153/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>