<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Action research program on the innovations of the Organic economy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Touret, Claire</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Scaling up, the organic farming is more and more faced with competitiveness price trends which lead through pressures and tensions to production systems that neglect the environmental and social issues. Therefore biological farmers are forced to wonder about their economic organization model. What model will make it possible to optimize costs without affecting the best practices in social and environmental fields? To contribute to the discussion, the FNAB leads an action research program, where the producers endorse researchers' role. They developed their research question and the linked issues, and then questioned researchers about the main concepts that would help them. In a next step, they built together a theoretical model allowing them to analyze their own organizations with regard to their ambition of a new organic economic model. Interdependence and diversity are at the heart of this new food-processing governance, which is the main purpose of the program. This model was validated by 13 open discussions with organic farmers economic organizations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26781/1/Touret_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Touret, Claire   (2013) Action research program on the innovations of the Organic economy.  [Recherche action sur les innovations de lՎconomie Bio.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 185-197.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26781/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>