<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ergebnisse zur saisonalen Low-Input Vollweidehaltung von&#xD;
Milchkühen im österreichischen Berggebiet</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Dr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Starz, DI Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Podstatzky, Dr. Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirner, Dr. Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pötsch, Doz. Dr. Erich M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gallnböck, Ing. Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a research project six dairy farms (5 organic, 1 low input) in mountainous regions of&#xD;
Austria were supervised in converting to a seasonal low-input dairy production system&#xD;
based on grazing. Within an observation period of three years (October 1st, 2004 –&#xD;
September 30th, 2007) a strict annual cycle in milk production and reproduction could&#xD;
be implemented on two farms only. In average a pasture proportion of 42 % (26–61&#xD;
%) of the total feeding ration per year could be determined, depending on the farm&#xD;
specific conditions and the implementation level of this low input strategy. On four&#xD;
farms, which fed low amounts of supplemental feeds, a pasture proportion of 50 % of&#xD;
the total feeding ration was realized. With an input of only 470 kg DM concentrate (8&#xD;
% of DM intake) per cow and year a milk performance of 5.837 kg with 4.1 % fat and&#xD;
3.3 % protein was achieved. The results clearly indicate that the full grazing strategy&#xD;
with seasonal calving is feasible in Austria for animal health reasons. The project&#xD;
farms realized an average value of 0.29 Euro of payments free of direct charge per kg&#xD;
milk and 1.640 Euro per cow.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13898/1/Steinwidder_13898.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinwidder, Dr. Andreas; Starz, DI Walter; Podstatzky, Dr. Leopold; Kirner, Dr. Leopold; Pötsch, Doz. Dr. Erich M.; Pfister, Rupert and Gallnböck, Ing. Markus    (2009) Ergebnisse zur saisonalen Low-Input Vollweidehaltung von Milchkühen im österreichischen Berggebiet.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13898/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>