<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of organic olive cultivation and its importance for the sustainability in the Mediterranean</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Migliorini, P</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Olive is the most extensively cultivated fruit crop in the world counting 9,2 million hectares of area harvested in 2009: 8,3 million are in the Mediterranean countries. This paper explain why the development of organic olive cultivation (5% of the total olive cultivation) can increase the sustainability of the Mediterranean. Regarding the ecological aspects, organic farming has benefits on landscape, biodiversity soil, water and air. Regarding economic sustainability organic olive oil production can be viable if the correct marketing channel is found. Regarding social sustainability, the olive oil consumption have a positive impact on health related to Mediterranean diet effects.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic, Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19832/1/01_Migliorini_FULL.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Migliorini, P    (2011) Development of organic olive cultivation and its importance for the sustainability in the Mediterranean.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic, Drazen; Hashem, Yousry and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstract. International Conference on ORGANIC AGRICULTURE and AGRO-ECO TOURSIM in the Mediterranean, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19832/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>