<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>THE INVESTIGATION OF CROP WEEDINESS IN THE CROP ROTATION OF&#xD;
ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEM</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ausmane , M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaile, Z.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Melngalvis, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Field experiments were conducted during the period of 2004 – 2006 at the Research and&#xD;
Study Farm „Vecauce”. The aim of the investigation was to establish the weediness’ dynamics of&#xD;
crops in a six-field crop rotation of an organic farming system. The field was certified as being&#xD;
organic. Crop rotation: 1. triticale/ rye (for green manure in spring), 2. oil radish (for green&#xD;
manure)/ rye (for green manure in autumn), 3. potatoes, 4. oats, 5. vetch-oats mix (for green forage)&#xD;
with an undersown mixture of red clover and timothy, 6. red clover and timothy. Conventional soil&#xD;
tillage was done according to the requirements of the crops. The weeds were counted two times&#xD;
during the vegetation period of crops: at the early development stages of crops (for instance, at the tillering of cereals) and before the crop harvesting. The composition of weed flora comprised from&#xD;
59 species in the crops’ stands. The annual dicotyledonus were dominating groups of the weed&#xD;
flora. The most abundant weeds were lambsquarters (Chenopodium album L.), quackgrass&#xD;
(Elytrigia repens (L.) Nevski), common yellow rocket (Barbarea vulgaris R. Br.p.p.). The&#xD;
significantly smaller amount of weeds among crop rotation links was observed in the link rye/ oil&#xD;
radish/ rye – potatoes – oats. Much worse suppression of weeds was obtained in the crop rotation&#xD;
link red clover and timothy – triticale/ rye – oil radish/ rye. The number of weeds in the fields of&#xD;
crop rotation in the organic farming system is dependent on the cultivated crops, the succession of&#xD;
crops in the crop rotation links and crop cultivation technologies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18608/1/AgrVestis-Nr10-25-31.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ausmane , M.; Gaile, Z. and Melngalvis, I.   (2008) THE INVESTIGATION OF CROP WEEDINESS IN THE CROP ROTATION OF ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEM.   Latvian Journal of Agronomy, No.10, pp. 25-31.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18608/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>