<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The LowInputBreeds project has four main objectives:&#xD;
- To develop and evaluate innovative breeding concepts to deliver genotypes with ‘robustness’ and quality traits required under ‘low input’ conditions.&#xD;
- To integrate the use of improved genotypes with innovative management approaches. These will focus on issues where breeding or management innovations alone are unlikely to provide satisfactory solutions e.g. mastitis and parasite control.&#xD;
- To identify the potential economic, environmental and ethical impacts of the project’s results. The project needs&#xD;
to ensure that the results are in line with society’s different needs, priorities and consumer expectations.&#xD;
- To establish an effi cient training and dissemination programme aimed at rapid application of project results in organic and ‘low input’ livestock farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18497/1/maurer-2010-poster-lowinputbreedsbioforschungstag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    LowInputBreeds: Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production.    Runs 2009 - 2014.      Project Leader(s): Maurer, Veronika and Bulter, Gillian, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland and Newcastle University, UK.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18497/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>