<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Learning in context – improved nutrient management in arable cropping systems through participatory research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wivstad, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Naetterlund, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Participatory research (PR) provides opportunities to build knowledge relevant to site-specific farms conditions. This study used a PR approach to develop nutrient management strategies in stockless organic farming. A thorough problem identification process was carried out and the problem prioritised was how to combine preceding crop effects with fertilisation strategy in crop rotations. On-farm fertiliser (biogas digestion residues, chicken manure and meat-bone meal) experiments were conducted in spring wheat and winter rapeseed. Significant yield responses were achieved in spring wheat, up to 1200 kg ha-1, and they were higher than in rapeseed. The implications of the results for nutrient management at crop rotation level are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11864/1/11864.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wivstad, Maria and Naetterlund, Henrik    (2008) Learning in context – improved nutrient management in arable cropping systems through participatory research.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11864/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>