<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Melon varieties evaluation for organic horticulture in Extremadura (Spain)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sánchez-Giraldez, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De la Cuadra, Celia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ramos, María</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The correct selection of the variety is a fundamental principle in the organic production systems, in order to get a good adaptation and reduce the use of external inputs. So that, enough biodiversity is available to provide the market with horticultural crop varieties selected and developed under organic cultivation management. As part of a larger project, where several species have been on-farm evaluated using participatory evaluation methodologies, this survey shows the first year grown results of 17th melon varieties grown under open field conditions with an intermediate production cycle in the local area of La Jara del Romeral in the province of Caceres, the region of Extremadura located at the west of Spain.&#xD;
Variety groups evaluated include piel de sapo, yellow,rochet and tarifeño types of commercial and traditional varieties, some of them coming from several Spanish Gene Banks. In that case, characterization according to Biodiversity International and UPOV descriptors has been done to be added to the agronomic evaluation. Parameters of productivity, rusticity, resistances and commercial qualities have been observed(ºBRIX, conservation, caliber, productive period…).&#xD;
A tasting taste has been done in order to get sensorial evaluation parameters. The results show the great facility of this specie to being grown under organic cultivation management in our conditions. A group of 7-8 varieties stand out by its general behavior regarding all the observed parameters (both commercial and traditional varieties). It is important to enhance the good results of the traditional varieties regarding quality and sensorial good properties to which only a few of the commercial varieties have achieved a good valorization.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18535/1/MRamos_melons_%5BModo_de_compatibilidad%5D.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sánchez-Giraldez, Helena; De la Cuadra, Celia and Ramos, María    (2011) Melon varieties evaluation for organic horticulture in Extremadura (Spain).       Poster at:   International Horticulture Congress, Lisbon, August 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18535/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>