<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Differences in receptivity to gastrointestinal infections with&#xD;
nematodes in dairy ewes: Influence of age and of the&#xD;
level of milk production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>H., Hoste</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>A.C., Rulie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., Prevot</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>J.P., Bergeaud</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., Grisez</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., De La Farge</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>P., Jacquiet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>P., Dorchies</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Resistance to anthelmintics in populations of gastrointestinal nematodes is a major concern in small ruminants. One solution&#xD;
to limit the spread of anthelmintic resistance is to apply treatments selectively by targeting the most susceptible animals within&#xD;
a flock. In dairy goats, previous studies have shown that, within a flock, goats in first lactation and those with high level of milk&#xD;
production were highly receptive to nematode infections. These results provided the rationale for targeted treatments. In dairy&#xD;
ewes, such epidemiological information on possible factors modulating the susceptibility to parasitism were still lacking. The&#xD;
objective of the current study was therefore to examine differences in the level of parasite infection and in the pathophysiological&#xD;
consequences in dairy ewes, depending on the age or on the level of milk production. In three farms, parasite egg excretion, and the&#xD;
serum concentrations of pepsinogen and inorganic phosphate were compared on one hand between primiparous and multiparous&#xD;
ewes; on the other hand, between ewes with the highest and the lowest level of milk production, within a cohort of 3–5-year&#xD;
old animals. Overall, the results did not indicate significant differences for both either the parasitological or pathophysiological&#xD;
measurements depending on the level of milk production. In contrast, significant differences were found according to age,&#xD;
indicating higher levels of infections in the primiparous ewes than in the multiparous ones and suggesting that this category of&#xD;
animals represents a particular parasitic risk within a flock.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6968/1/paysbask.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>H., Hoste; A.C., Rulie; F., Prevot; J.P., Bergeaud; C., Grisez; F., De La Farge; P., Jacquiet and P., Dorchies   (2005) Differences in receptivity to gastrointestinal infections with nematodes in dairy ewes: Influence of age and of the level of milk production.   Small Ruminant Research.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6968/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>