<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of liquid manure application method on weed control in spring cereals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Injection of liquid manure (slurry)into the soil is an alternative to the traditional surface application. By the injection method,it is possible to place nutrients closer to the crop sown, thus offering the crop a competitive advantage over weeds. This study compares the response in crop yield, weed density and weed biomass to injection vs. surface application of liquid manure through three growing seasons in barley and oats. The manure applications were combined with treatments of weed harrowing or herbicide&#xD;
spraying or no treatment at all. The levels of weed control and crop yield obtained by harrowing and herbicides were larger when slurry was injected compared with surface application. Without any weed control treatments,the injection method decreased the ﬁnal weed biomass in barley. The in ﬂuence of nutrient injection on yield and weed control seemed to be modulated by the time of emergence and the early growth rate of the crop relative to weeds. Thus, because of its early root growth and development, barley responded more quickly to the injection treatment than oats. Consequently, barley became a more competitive crop.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>European Weed Research Society</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1784/1/Influence_of_liquid_manure.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, K.   (2002) Influence of liquid manure application method on weed control in spring cereals.   Weed Research (42), pp. 287-298.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1784/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>