<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Water discharge and nutrient leaching from organic mixed crop rotation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seuri, Pentti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuisma, Miia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Water discharge and nutrient leaching studies were conducted in an experimental field under organic farming practice for 20 years. The water discharge measurements cover five years out of a six-year crop rotation. The water discharge for the whole year was 1520 m³/ha (=152 mm). More than 2/3 of the total discharge occurred in April-May. The total precipitation for the whole year was 680 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
The total amount of N in the drainage runoff was 11.5 kg/ha and the flow-weighted average content 7.5 mg/l. The total amount of P in the drainage runoff was 48 g/ha and the flow-weighted average content 0.031 mg/l. 85 % of the total P was dissolved reactive phosphorus (DPR).&#xD;
&#xD;
Some preliminary correlation between N leaching and N management was observed, i.e. higher N concentrations in drainage water were found on green fallow after autumn ploughing compared to first-year grass or spring cereal. Variation in the P concentration of the drainage water between the plots seems to be correlated to soil P status rather than P management.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Tamm, Toomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pietola, Liisa</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8968/1/ymparisto.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seuri, Pentti and Kuisma, Miia    (2006) Water discharge and nutrient leaching from organic mixed crop rotation.   In: Tamm, Toomas and Pietola, Liisa (Eds.)  NJF Report, Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists, 2 (5), pp. 41-46.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8968/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>