<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of different soil preparation techniques on organically grown strawberries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leona, Brockamp</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eis, Birgit</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>From June 2005 till June 2007 different soil preparation techniques like chiselling and advance sowing of medicinal plants and green manuring were proofed for their influence on reducing plant losses of strawberries caused by root diseases like Phytophthora species and Verticillium dahliae. The variants were combined with potted plants and Frigos. The experiment took place on an organic fruit farm near Stuttgart, Germany, with the strawberry variety ´Elsanta´.&#xD;
Focused on root diseases, habit and yield chiselling combined with Frigos and green manuring combined with potted plants showed the best results. Generally the marketable yield was often below yields from conventional cultivation.&#xD;
This project is granted by Bundesprogramm Ökologischer Landbau (BÖL, FKZ 03OE087: 2004-2006, FKZ 06OE221: 2007-2009). It includes also experiments about cutting techniques at raspberries, plant protection at black- and gooseberries and weed control at blueberries and black currants. The part of weed control is carried out by ÖON Jork (Germany).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13662/1/148-151.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leona, Brockamp and Eis, Birgit    (2008) Influence of different soil preparation techniques on organically grown strawberries.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 148-151.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13662/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>