<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Minder en Anders Bemesten; resultaten van een vierjarig project over innovatieve bemesting.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>van der Burgt, Geert-Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Timmermans, Bart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Staps, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this report a summary is given from several experiments during three years at four farms. This summary focuses on yield; mineral balances and product quality are sometimes described. The overall soil quality descriptions can only be found in the complete reports which can be found in the reference list. &#xD;
This project aimed at reduced manure applications in an adapted fertilization strategy in several farm types, realizing:&#xD;
•	Equal or higher yields&#xD;
•	Improvement of product quality&#xD;
•	Maintenance or improvement of sustainable soil fertility.&#xD;
The results of the experiments at four farms are:&#xD;
•	At Joost van Strien’s farm it has been shown clear that the use of cut-and-carry fertilizers is a good option. The fertilizing value is as good as or better than manure, and the mineral content (N. P. K) is more in accordance with crop uptake than in case of manure. Next step to assess is the consequence at farm level when striving towards 100% own nitrogen supply by means of cut-and-carry fertilizers.&#xD;
•	At Jan en Hans Rozendaal’s farm the need for manure in the courgette crop is reduced by introducing grassclover as pre-crop. The nitrogen release out of this pre-crop is a bit delayed, so in the beginning of the season some additional fast-acting nitrogen fertilizer is still needed. This system, with the crop on small beds, has shown to work for courgettes but not for cabbage.&#xD;
•	At Jan van Lierop’s farm the two components of nitrogen dynamics have been explored: long term nitrogen release by means of soil organic matter, short term by means of specific fertilizer applications. A good mix of these two components is needed, but this is possibly not enough to cope the nutrient balance challenges. More changes might be needed such as choice of manure, introduction of catch crops and a less intensive production system.&#xD;
•	At Gerard Lanting’s farm the experiments have shown that in case of a sufficient basic soil fertility the additionally requested manure is lower than what is recommended normally. In a scenario study with changes in crops and manure strategy it is shown that a reduced manure input can be realized without yield reduction&#xD;
&#xD;
At the end of this report a list of conclusions is given, showing that there is a wide range of means needed and possible to create a substantial increase in nutrient use efficiency.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Louis Bolk Instituut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21702/1/2010-032_LbP_Minder_en_Anders_Bemesten_4_jaar.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>van der Burgt, Geert-Jan; Timmermans, Bart and Staps, S.         (2012) Minder en Anders Bemesten; resultaten van een vierjarig project over innovatieve bemesting.  [Less and adapted fertilizers: results of a 4-year project on innovative fertilizer strategies.]   Louis Bolk Instituut, 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21702/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>