<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Sorte auf den Rohproteingehalt und auf die Gehalte der Aminosäuren Cystein, Methionin und Lysin in ökologisch angebauten Futtererbsen und Ackerbohnen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lietzow, Julika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Peas and field beans as feeds for monogastric animals in organic farming have a high feeding quality particularly in consideration of protein content and amino acid profile.&#xD;
Beside this the native contents of crude protein and amino acids cystine, methionine and lysine in organic peas and field beans vary considerably related to genetic and environmental factors.&#xD;
20 peas and 12 field beans cultivars from different locations in Germany were selected to analyse the variance of the factor variety on contents of protein and amino acids. Significant effects of variety in peas were noticed on crude protein and methionine while cysteine and lysine were not or only marginally influenced. In field beans only crude protein was affected by variety. In both crops a weak positive correlation between crude protein and amino acids were observed.&#xD;
Increasing crude protein content by selection of varieties can lead to a decrease of protein quality in terms of amino acid profile.&#xD;
For calculating the diet of organic livestock it may be helpful to analyse and communicate in addition to crude nutrients the content of amino acids in feedstuffs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21471/1/21471_Lietzow.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lietzow, Julika; Aulrich, Karen and Böhm, Herwart    (2013) Einfluss der Sorte auf den Rohproteingehalt und auf die Gehalte der Aminosäuren Cystein, Methionin und Lysin in ökologisch angebauten Futtererbsen und Ackerbohnen.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21471/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>