<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Value Added Grains for Local and Regional Food Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kissing Kucek, Lisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baker, Brian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dyck, Elizabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dawson, Julie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Benscher, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Davis, Mike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kutka, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perry, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roth, Greg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Russell, June</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zwinger, Steve</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sorrells, Mark</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Small grains provide numerous benefits for organic farming systems. However, because they have relatively low value and require special equipment, many organic farming systems do not integrate them. Heritage varieities of ommon wheat (Triticum aestivum ssp. Aestivum) and its antecedents spelt (Triticum aestivum, ssp. spelta), emmer (Triticum turgidum subsp. dicoccum) and einkorn (Triticum monococcum) are the subject of a project that looks at their viability.  Preliminary results of variety trials show that organic farmers have several promising small grain options. Improved management and appropriate equipment are barriers to adoption that the project aims to overcome. Viability will depend on overcoming marketing as well as production obstacles.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24148/1/24148-Kucekal-2014_01_09-1_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kissing Kucek, Lisa; Baker, Brian; Dyck, Elizabeth; Dawson, Julie; Benscher, David; Davis, Mike; Kutka, Frank; Perry, Robert; Roth, Greg; Russell, June; Zwinger, Steve and Sorrells, Mark    (2014) Value Added Grains for Local and Regional Food Systems.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1183-1186.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24148/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>