<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A SURVEY OF ORGANIC AGRICULTURAL SECTOR IN THE WORLD IN &#xD;
COMPARISON WITH THE EUROPEAN UNION AND TURKEY PRACTICES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>ARSLAN, Kılıç Fehmi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karaca, Ahmet Ali</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As public became more aware of the possible hazardous effects of the conventional &#xD;
farming products, organic agriculture practices have been increasingly spreading all &#xD;
over the world. &#xD;
 Since the 1980’s, organic agriculture has been an important topic in the research &#xD;
agenda of the scientists active in various fields from science to biology or even &#xD;
economics. &#xD;
 Economic Unions have been increasingly important in the last decade, in which one of &#xD;
them is the European Union (EU) being the most integrated of all. It is an enlarging &#xD;
body that has achieved considerable degree of economic integration. The EU is &#xD;
considered to be important for Turkey. The EU has a supporting role in agricultural &#xD;
policy. Organical agriculture, which is considered to have an important role in EU &#xD;
economics, became more important issue between Turkey and EU relations, due to &#xD;
Turkey’s agriculture potential. &#xD;
 Organic agriculture started in Turkey through the demand from foreign countries in &#xD;
1990’s. Due to the lack of information sharing on organic agriculture, organic &#xD;
agriculture sector in Turkey was not aware of its potential. It is one of the factors that &#xD;
affects organic farming sector negatively. By creating the body which enables data &#xD;
sharing system by more number of people and significant support by organic agriculture &#xD;
sides would lead the sector to benefit from the existing potential. Organic agriculture &#xD;
market in Turkey will have a chance to compete with other world organic agriculture &#xD;
markets. Organic agriculture’s products are healthy for consumers. On the other hand &#xD;
what is also argued within this thesis is organic agriculture’s beneficial effects on the &#xD;
nature.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23361/1/K%C4%B1l%C4%B1%C3%A7%20Fehmi%20Arslan.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>ARSLAN, Kılıç Fehmi and Karaca, Ahmet Ali   (2009) A SURVEY OF ORGANIC AGRICULTURAL SECTOR IN THE WORLD IN COMPARISON WITH THE EUROPEAN UNION AND TURKEY PRACTICES.    Masters thesis, MARMARA UNİVERSİTESİ, AVRUPA BİRLİĞİ ENSTİTÜSÜ .  .   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23361/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>