<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reducing russeting of organically grown Elstar to increase quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jong, P.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van der Maas, M. P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sales organisations indicated that opportunities for organic apples sales can increase&#xD;
when quality increases, in particular reducing the amount of russeting.&#xD;
The use of copper is probably the most important factor for russeting. Therefore a worst&#xD;
case scheme was compared with a scheme with reduced copper application. Furthermore,&#xD;
there was a particular interest in the effects on russeting of potassium bicarbonate&#xD;
(Armicarb) because this product might be an important element in a copper free fungicide&#xD;
scheme. Application of Armicarb was investigated on wet or dry canopy and effects of two&#xD;
different dosages were studied. All the schemes were compared with a worst case organic&#xD;
fungicide scheme with copper. The experiment was done on two year old Elstar trees&#xD;
because Elstar is the most important organically grown cultivar in the Netherlands. Effects&#xD;
of the schedules on russet and scab control were evaluated. At harvest no effects were&#xD;
found on scab. Between the different schemes with copper no differences were found in&#xD;
amount of russet. Only the highest dosage of Armicarb (10 kg/ha) and the schedules with&#xD;
Armicarb on a wet canopy gave more russet compared with the worst case scheme. Also&#xD;
effects on fruit rot were evaluated.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13643/1/054-058.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jong, P.F. and van der Maas, M. P.    (2008) Reducing russeting of organically grown Elstar to increase quality.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 54-58.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13643/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>