<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer Willingness-To-Pay for Different Organic Certification Logos in Turkey</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Karahan Uysal, Ö</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Janssen, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miran, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abay, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boyaci, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Using data from focus group discussions with consumers and a choice experimentconducted in some of Turkey’s major cities, this study investigates whetherTurkish consumers prefer certain organic labelling schemes over others attemptsand to elicit their willingness to pay (WTP) for different organic certificationlogos. Although the level of awareness regarding organic certification logos waslow, consumers’ perceptions of the logos were generally positive. The results ofthe random parameter logit models indicated a positive WTP for the presence ofone of the three tested certification body logos in addition to the mandatorygovernmental logo. Given the low level of certification logo awareness, theconclusion is that both purchasing decisions and perceptions regarding logoswere affected by subjective criteria. Both the government and certification bodiesshould develop measures to increase consumer awareness of their logos and formconsumer perceptions and attitudes regarding the quality of the certificationimplied by the logo.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22563/1/22563.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Karahan Uysal, Ö; Janssen, M.; Miran, B.; Abay, C.; Boyaci, M. and Hamm, U.   (2012) Consumer Willingness-To-Pay for Different Organic Certification Logos in Turkey.   Revista de cercetare [i interven]ie social\, 39, pp. 154-175.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22563/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>