<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of an Organic Table Grape Production and Market in Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Häseli, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tschabold, J.-L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suter, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, F.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In Switzerland there is an increasing consumer demand for residue-free, organic table&#xD;
grapes. The organic cultivation of table grapes, however, is very delicate in humid climates&#xD;
and experience to advice organic growers is still lacking. The goal of our project that has&#xD;
started in 2004 is to develop and establish a cultivation system for organic table grapes&#xD;
under Swiss climatic and economic conditions with a high yield security and fulfilling the&#xD;
high quality demands of the market. Preliminary results: Interesting cultivars to produce&#xD;
are e.g. Fanny, Lilla, Palatina. However they are disease susceptible and must be&#xD;
produced under a rain roof. Better suited cultivars still need to be found. Consumer&#xD;
acceptance for organic table grapes produced in Switzerland is very positive. However&#xD;
changes towards new cultivars and lower production costs are necessary. Spray programs&#xD;
to achieve sufficient disease protection and no spray blotch seem to be realizable, mainly&#xD;
for production under rain roof.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13664/1/155-159.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Häseli, A.; Tschabold, J.-L.; Suter, F. and Weibel, F.P.    (2008) Development of an Organic Table Grape Production and Market in Switzerland.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 155-159.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13664/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>