<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of silage botanical composition on ruminal biohydrogenation and transfer of fatty acids to milk in dairy cows</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Adler, Steffen A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, S.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thuen, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gustavsson, A.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Harstad, O.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinshamn, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ruminal biohydrogenation and transfer of fatty acids (FA) to milk were determined for 4 silages with different botanical compositions using 4 multiparous Norwegian Red dairy cows [(mean ± SD) 118 ± 40.9 d in milk, 22.5 ± 2.72 kg of milk/d, 631 ± 3.3 kg of body weight, 3.3 ± 0.40 points on body condition score at the start of the experiment] fitted with rumen cannulas. Treatments consisted of 4 experimental silages: a mix of the first and third cut of organically managed short-term grassland with timothy (Phleum pratense L.) and red clover (Trifolium pratense L.; 2 yr old; ORG-SG); organically managed long-term grassland with a high proportion of unsown species (6 yr old; ORG-LG); conventionally managed ley with perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.; CON-PR); and conventionally managed ley with timothy (CON-TI). The herbages were cut, wilted, and preserved with additive in round bales and fed at 0.90 of ad libitum intake. A barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) concentrate constituted 300 g/kg of dry matter of the total feed offered. A Latin square design (4 × 4) with 3-wk periods and the last week in each period used for sampling was implemented. Omasal flows of FA were measured using Yb acetate, Cr-EDTA, and the indigestible neutral detergent fiber fraction as indigestible markers. The composition of FA was analyzed in feed, omasal digesta, and milk. Compared with ORG-LG, ORG-SG had a higher herbage proportion of red clover (0.36 vs. 0.01) and lower proportions of timothy (0.42 vs. 0.18), smooth meadowgrass (Poa pratensis L.), meadow fescue (Festuca pratensis Huds.), white clover (Trifolium repens L.), dandelion (Taraxacum spp.), and creeping buttercup (Ranunculus repens L.). The silages were well preserved. The concentration of neutral detergent fiber was higher and the concentration of Kjeldahl-N was lower for CON-TI than for the other silages. Silage type had no effect on dry matter intake, but milk yield was lower for CON-TI than for the other silages. Apparent biohydrogenation of C18:3n-3 was lower for ORG-SG (932 g/kg) than for ORG-LG (956 g/kg), CON-PR (959 g/kg), and CON-TI (958 g/kg). Compared with the grass-based silages, ORG-SG and ORG-LG resulted in higher omasal flows of C18:1 trans FA and higher milk fat proportions of C18:1 trans FA and C18:2 cis-9,trans-11. Apparent recovery of C18:3n-3 in milk was higher for ORG-SG (61 g/kg) than for ORG-LG (33 g/kg), CON-PR (34 g/kg), and CON-TI (38 g/kg), and milk fat proportion of C18:3n-3 was higher for ORG-SG than for CON-TI. Milk fat proportions of C16:0 were lower for ORG-SG and ORG-LG compared with those for CON-PR and CON-TI. It was concluded that high proportions of red clover and other dicotyledons in the silages affected ruminal biohydrogenation and increased milk fat proportions of beneficial FA.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23129/1/Adler%20et%20al%202013%20Silage%20bot%20comp%20ruminal%20biohydrogenation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Adler, Steffen A.; Jensen, S.K.; Thuen, E.; Gustavsson, A.-M.; Harstad, O.M. and Steinshamn, H.   (2013) Effect of silage botanical composition on ruminal biohydrogenation and transfer of fatty acids to milk in dairy cows.   Journal of Dairy Science, 96 (2), pp. 1135-1147.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23129/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>