<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dynamics of mineral nitrogen, water-soluble carbon and potential nitrification in band-steamed arable soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elsgaard, Lars</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Steaming of narrow soil bands prior to sowing is a new technique that reduces the need for intra-row weeding in herbicide-free row crops. However, the steam treatment may eliminate both weed seeds and non-target soil organisms, thereby affecting the nutrient cycling in the soil. This study tested the effect of band-steaming on N and C dynamics in a sandy loam soil that was steamed in situ to&#xD;
maximal temperatures of 70–90°C using a prototype bandsteamer. Soil samples (0–5 cm depth) were collected during 90 days from band-steamed soil, undisturbed control soil, and control soil treated just mechanically with the bandsteamer. In the steamed soil, ammonium concentrations&#xD;
increased from 1.1 to 20.3 μg NH4+-N g−1 dry weight&#xD;
during 28 days. This coincided with an immediate and&#xD;
persistent inhibition of potential nitrification (33–61%&#xD;
inhibition during 90 days). Assays of the temperature&#xD;
response of potential nitrification confirmed the temperature sensitivity and showed an optimum temperature of&#xD;
27.1°C and a temperature coefficient (Q10) of 1.9. The&#xD;
effects of band-steaming on concentrations of nitrate and&#xD;
water-soluble carbon were divergent and stimulatory,&#xD;
respectively, but generally not statistically significant.&#xD;
Mechanical effects of band-steaming were negligible. The&#xD;
observed ammonium surplus could be of agronomic benefit&#xD;
and should be evaluated in integrated studies of the effects&#xD;
of band-steaming on crop growth and plant N uptake.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18005/1/18005.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Elsgaard, Lars   (2010) Dynamics of mineral nitrogen, water-soluble carbon and potential nitrification in band-steamed arable soil.   Biology and Fertility of Soils.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18005/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>