<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Inputs Evaluation</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this Concerted Action is to develop recommendations for harmonized and standardised procedures for evaluation of Plant Protection Products (PPP) and Fertilizers and Soil Conditioners (F&amp;SC) authorised for use in organic agriculture according to EEC 2092/91, Annex II. The project consists of 6 workpackages (WPs) with 5 workshops. WP1 is for coordination and project management. Inventories on curent implementation of Annex II and evaluation procedures in the participating countries will be elaborated in WP2 (PPP) and WP3 (F&amp;SC). Standardised procedures for evaluation of PPP and F&amp;SC will be elaborated in WP4 &amp; WP5. Recommendations on evaluation procedures for PPP and F&amp;SC plus research needs and dissemination will be discussed in WP6. This Concerted Action provides a discussion forum questions related to the evaluation of PPP or F&amp;SC for organic farming. Institution engaged in this area are kindly invited to participate in the discussions (please »contact us).&#xD;
Involved organisations, project partners:&#xD;
•	Danish Agricultural Research Centre for Organic Farming (DARCOF), Denmark&#xD;
•	Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Switzerland&#xD;
•	EcoS Consultancy, United Kingdom&#xD;
•	Istituto Sperimentale per le Nutrizione delle Piante (ISNP), Italy&#xD;
•	Associazione Italiana per l'Agricultura Biologica (AIAB), Italy&#xD;
•	Louis Bolk Instituut (LBI), The Netherlands&#xD;
•	Soil Association, United Kingdom&#xD;
•	Ludwig Boltzmann Institut for Biological Agriculture, Austria&#xD;
•	Austria Bio Garantie / InfoXgen, Austria&#xD;
•	Associação Portuguesa de Agricultura Biologica (Agrobio), Portugal&#xD;
•	Universität Kassel, Germany&#xD;
•	Danish Plant Directorate, Denmark</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Organic Inputs Evaluation: Organic Inputs Evaluation.  [Harmonised and Standardised procedures for evaluation of plant protection products, fertilizers and soil conditioners for use in organic agriculture.]   Runs 2003 - 2005.      Project Leader(s): Speiser, Bernhard, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6013/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>