<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>How do farmers research and learn? The example of organic farmers’ experiments and innovations: A research concept</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kummer, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ninio, Racheli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leitgeb, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogl, Christian Reinhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Experimenting, adapting and innovating are central features of farmers’ activities all over the world. Farmers hold valuable knowledge about their environment, they actively do experiments, and have their own research traditions. The development of organic farming systems is continually evolving through the experiments and innovations of organic farmers. So far, there has been little attempt to study the nature, characteristics, and factors associated with the experimental processes of farmers in a systematic, comprehensive way. A current research project investigates learning processes of organic farmers in Austria, Cuba and Israel through researching the multifaceted experiments they conduct and the innovations they obtain as possible results. This paper presents the research concept of the project.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12226/1/12226.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kummer, Susanne; Ninio, Racheli; Leitgeb, Friedrich and Vogl, Christian Reinhard    (2008) How do farmers research and learn? The example of organic farmers’ experiments and innovations: A research concept.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12226/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>