<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biologische Bekämpfung von Drahtwürmern mit entomopathogenen Pilzen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eckard, Sonja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ansari, Minshad Ali</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schweizer, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Butt, Tariq M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grabenweger, Giselher</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigated the virulence of three European isolates of the entomopathogenic fungus (EPF) Metarhizium anisopliae against three wireworm species which are important pests of arable crops and vegetables in Europe: Agriotes lineatus, A. obscurus and A. sputator. In laboratory experiments, up to 90 % of the wireworms were killed by the fungus, depending on the fungal isolate and the wireworm species. Speed of kill was generally low with first wireworms showing unambiguous signs of fungal disease after two to three weeks. Maximum mortality rates were reached after six to eight weeks post inoculation. The next steps of this investigation will be to determine the most suitable fungal isolate and the validation of the laboratory results under greenhouse and field conditions. The aim of the study is to develop an easily applicable formulation with the most effective EPF isolate as the main active ingredient. In addition, applications of the EPF will be combined with entomoparasitic nematodes (EPNs) and repellent semiochemicals. Possible synergistic interactions between EPFs and EPNs or repellents may contribute significantly to improved biological control of wireworms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21438/1/21438_Eckard.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eckard, Sonja; Ansari, Minshad Ali; Schweizer, Christian; Butt, Tariq M. and Grabenweger, Giselher    (2013) Biologische Bekämpfung von Drahtwürmern mit entomopathogenen Pilzen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21438/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>