<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Coordination of European Transnational Research in Organic Food and Farming (CORE Organic)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project Coordination of European Transnational Research in Organic Food and Farming (CORE Organic) is a European Concerted Action, funded as Coordination Action of the 6th Framework Research Programme (6FP) of the European Union. The project will run from 2004-2007. The overall objective of CORE Organic is to enhance quality, relevance and utilisation of resources in European research in organic food and farming and to establish a joint pool of at least 3 million € per year for Transnational research in organic food and farming by the end of the project.&#xD;
&#xD;
In its full perspective organic farming may offer a solution to a number of difficulties that are experienced in connection with the common agricultural policy (CAP), where a sustainable development of agriculture, environment and the rural districts are seen as key policy objectives. However, in order to make full use of the perspectives in organic farming a comprehensive European research effort is needed. The public European Research and Development effort in organic food and farming is characterised by small research communities; often scattered and fragmented both geographically and institutionally. This produces a need for gathering the dispersed expertise to a critical mass for keeping and increasing the competitive quality and relevance. CORE Organic is a 3-year Coordination Action in organic food and farming, initially comprising 11 partners, but open to include all countries with a national research programme for research in organic food and farming. The overall objective of CORE Organic is to gather the critical mass and enhance quality, relevance and utilisation of resources in European research in organic food and farming. It is the goal to have established a joint pool of at least 3 million € per year by the end of the project. This will be accomplished by implementation through four objectives:&#xD;
1. Increased exchange of information and establishment of a common open web based archive&#xD;
2. Coordination of existing research and integration of knowledge&#xD;
3. Sharing and developing best practice for evaluating organic research&#xD;
4. Identification and coordination of future research&#xD;
&#xD;
Through objective one and two a common Internet portal for exchange of information, and common databases for participant countries will be built up, a thorough description of the current situation in participating states and the institutions in organic farming research will be produced, and mapping and analysis of existing research programmes, activities and facilities will be carried out. The result of the two first objectives will be the identification of barriers, gaps and possibilities for increased cooperation, as well as identification of new research areas suitable for cooperation, and the development of training schemes for research personnel and experts.&#xD;
Objective three will focus on the joint development of best practice of evaluation and quality assurance in new research areas within organic food and farming. A set of criteria, as well as a list of excellent experts, for evaluation of projects and programmes, will be developed.&#xD;
Under objective four a list of prioritised research topics and plans for future coordination will be developed and a range of procedures for Transnational funding will be agreed. Two joint funding collaborations will be created, including a joint funding collaboration with a pool of at least 3 million € per year in the last year of the project.&#xD;
CORE Organic will initiate the coordination and joint funding of future research in organic food and farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4847/1/Annex_I_CORE_Organic.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    CORE Organic: Coordination of European Transnational Research in Organic Food and Farming (CORE Organic).    Runs 2004 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Kristensen, Dr. Erik Steen, Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming (DARCOF).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4847/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>