<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Eight years of organic farming at Pwllpeiran – livestock production and the financial performance of organic upland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frost, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>McLean, Barbara M L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Evans, D Eifion</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. Established for 8 years, this project evaluates the practicalities of organic beef and sheep production on an upland farm in an ESA. Grassland productivity, stocking rates and animal performance are closely related to seasonal variations in the clover content of the small area of improved land. Improving sales have been offset by increasing input costs. Subsidy payments assist financial performance, but ESA prescriptions effectively prevent increased production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8419/1/frost_organic_farming_Pwllpeiran.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Frost, David; McLean, Barbara M L and Evans, D Eifion    (2002) Eight years of organic farming at Pwllpeiran – livestock production and the financial performance of organic upland.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 259-262.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8419/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>