<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>compost-based nursery substrates: effect of peat substitution on organic melon seedlings</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tittarelli, Fabio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rea, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Verrastro, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pascual, J.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Canali, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ceglie, F.G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trinchera, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rivera, C.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Greenhouses and coverings</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A bovine manure compost (BMC) and a green compost (GC) were evaluated as components of substrates in partial substitution of peat for organic melon seedlings production. Treatments, differentiated on the basis of the volume percentage of the two analysed composts, were compared to the control (a mixture of peat, coconut fibre and perlite). In order to respect the guidelines of organic production, all the treatments were fertilised, at the beginning of the trial, with guano. Compost-based substrates were analysed for physical, physicochemical and chemical parameters (bulk density, porosity, pH, EC, nutrients content etc.). Even though significant differences were observed, recorded values were in the range of acceptability for growing media. In terms of performance, seedling growth in treatments containing 30% and 50% of composts was significantly higher than in control.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Tittarelli, Fabio; Rea, E.; Verrastro, V.; Pascual, J.A.; Canali, S.; Ceglie, F.G.; Trinchera, A. and Rivera, C.M.   (2009) compost-based nursery substrates: effect of peat substitution on organic melon seedlings.   Compost Science &amp; Utilization, 17 (4), pp. 220-228.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19012/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>