<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Spider (Araneae) Species Activity, Crop Type and Management Factors in an Extensive Plot Trial</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eyre, Dr M.D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Shotton, Mr P.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Prof C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Spider species activity in five crop types, with organic and conventional fertility and crop protection management, was assessed using pitfall traps in 2005. Significant differences in activity between crop types were seen with 16 species, with 14 most active in grass/clover and 12 least active in vegetable plots. Within crops there were 20 significant responses to fertility, with 16 more active in conventional plots. Crop protection management produced four significant models, with three preferences for organic management. Small linyphiid species showed a distinct preference for the densest vegetation on conventionally fertilised plots, whilst the larger lycosid species were more active on the more open organic plots. In general, there was more activity in conventionally managed crops, in contrast to other reports.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11479/1/Eyre_11479_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eyre, Dr M.D.; Shotton, Mr P.N. and Leifert, Prof C.    (2008) Spider (Araneae) Species Activity, Crop Type and Management Factors in an Extensive Plot Trial.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11479/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>