<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer preferences for additional ethical attributes of organic food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper examines the relevance of additional ethical attributes of organic food for consumers’ purchase decisions. By means of an Information-Display-Matrix (IDM) and an accompanying consumer survey, the information acquisition behaviour of consumers regarding seven additional ethical attributes and the product price of organic food was investigated in five European countries. The ethical attributes, ‘animal welfare’, ‘regional production’ and ‘fair prices to farmers’ turned out to be the most important. The results also show that the vast majority of consumers of organic food was willing to pay higher prices for organic products with additional ethical attributes. Contrasting the results with those from direct inquiry by means of a ‘single source approach’ revealed considerable differences between both methods, particularly regarding the preferences for the product price relative to some of the ethical attributes. This may serve as evidence for higher external validity of the IDM with respect to social desirability bias.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2010-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17046/1/FQAP_Zander_Hamm_2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zander, Katrin and Hamm, Ulrich   (2010) Consumer preferences for additional ethical attributes of organic food.   Food quality and preference, 21 (5), pp. 495-503.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17046/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>