<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Koproduktion von Wissen in der Entwicklung des Biolandbaus -&#xD;
Einflüsse von Marginalisierung, Anerkennung und Markt</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aeberhard, Andrea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rist, PD Dr. Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The empirical analysis of the historical development of transdisciplinary co-production&#xD;
of knowledge (CPK) in organic agriculture (OA) in Switzerland has revealed three&#xD;
distinct phases. The initial phase shows various characteristics of transdisciplinary&#xD;
CPK and a high importance of experiential knowledge. The 2nd and 3rd phases involve&#xD;
an in-creasing segregation of farmers’, extension agents’, and scientists’ knowledge,&#xD;
caused by internal and external impacts, i.e. foundation of independent research&#xD;
institutions, changes in agriculture policy, and new market strategies. These&#xD;
developments strikingly represent an ambiguous trend: the growing societal and&#xD;
political recognition of OA and the increasing market, which are positive&#xD;
achievements, are associated by a gradual loss of very precious forms of CPK. A&#xD;
successful re-establishment of CPK processes and re-integration of experiential&#xD;
knowledge would help to resolve this dilemma and thus improve future research in OA&#xD;
and sustainability research in general.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14377/1/Aeberhard_14377.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aeberhard, Andrea and Rist, PD Dr. Stephan    (2009) Koproduktion von Wissen in der Entwicklung des Biolandbaus - Einflüsse von Marginalisierung, Anerkennung und Markt.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14377/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>