<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Diverse swards and mob grazing for dairy farm productivity: A UK case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leach, Katharine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palomo, Gonzalo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Waterfield, William</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zaralis, Konstantinos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper presents first year results of one participatory case study carried out as part of EU FP7 funded SOLID project (Sustainable Organic and Low Input Dairying) on an organic dairy farm managed with diverse swards and mob grazing in Britain. Mob grazing is a livestock management strategy consisting of high stocking density for a short time to remove forage rapidly due to high grazing pressure and then removing livestock to allow grass recovery. On the farm this is combined with a diverse sward, paying particular consideration to soil fertility. First results indicate that there was more available herbage in front of the cows, especially in the summer months, than could be expected from rotational grazing with shorter rest periods. Differences between the diverse and standard mixture measure in one field were not as marked as expected. Further measurements during the coming grazing season will be carried out.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23553/1/23553%20Leach%20etal-diverse%20swards_final%20V03_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leach, Katharine; Palomo, Gonzalo; Waterfield, William; Zaralis, Konstantinos and Padel, Susanne    (2014) Diverse swards and mob grazing for dairy farm productivity: A UK case study.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1155-1158.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23553/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>