<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Content of Selected Antioxidant Compounds in Bell Pepper Varieties from Organic and Conventional Cultivation Before and After Freezing Process</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hallmann, Dr. Ewelina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rembiałkowska, Prof. Ewa</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sweet bell pepper is one of the best sources of ascorbic acid and a fair source of carotenoids in human diets. The levels of vitamin C are very variable and may be affected by maturity, genotype and processing. Vegetable freezing is one of the most efficient and adequate preservation methods. Organic fresh vegetables contained more bioactive compounds than conventional ones. Two bell pepper cultivars (Roberta and Ożarowska) have been selected for analysis. Vegetables were cultivated on organic and conventional farms in Poland. Ripe bell peppers have been collected in the same week of ripening and were chemically analyzed twice: fresh before freezing and after six month of storage in -20°C. Vitamin C content, carotenoids also the total flavonols content have been determined in fruits. Organically produced bell peppers contained significantly more vitamin C and lutein than conventionally grown fruits. Processing with aid of freezing considerably decreases the content of the bioactive compounds in red bell peppers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12516/1/Hallmann_12516_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hallmann, Dr. Ewelina and Rembiałkowska, Prof. Ewa    (2008) The Content of Selected Antioxidant Compounds in Bell Pepper Varieties from Organic and Conventional Cultivation Before and After Freezing Process.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12516/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>