<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development of criteria und procedures for the evaluation of the European Action Plan of Organic Food and Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeffreys, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, St.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eichert, Ch.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Michelsen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vairo, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonzalvez, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within the EU funded project ORGAP a toolbox for the evaluation of the European as well as national action plans for organic food and farming has been developed (www.orgap.org). This toolbox was based on a comparative analysis of national action plans in eight countries (CH, UK, DE, IT, DK, SI, CZ, NL, ES), a meta-evaluation of existing evaluations of national action plans, workshops with national stakeholders and a European Advisory Committee, interviews with experts. Furthermore synergies and conflicts between national and the European Action Plan were identified.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12722/1/schmid_etal-2008-ISOFAR_Conference2008-ORGAP-final_version.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12722/2/schmid-etal-2008-OF-Modena2008_EU-session_ORGAP_presentation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, O.; Lampkin, N.; Jeffreys, I.; Dabbert, St.; Eichert, Ch.; Michelsen, J.; Zanoli, R.; Vairo, D. and Gonzalvez, V.    (2008) Development of criteria und procedures for the evaluation of the European Action Plan of Organic Food and Farming.       Paper at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science. 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR), in the Frame of the 16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12722/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>