<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Improving quality and safety and reduction of cost in the European organic and “low input” food supply chains: WP 6.1: Economic analyses of structures, conduct and performance of supply chains for organic foods in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
There are only a few studies describing the structures and performance of organic supply chains. And there is no study available with investigate the effect of supply chains on food quality and safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
The aim of subtask 6.1 is to analyse structures, conduct and performance of supply chains for organic foods in Europe.&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
The analysis of supply chains is based on the multi-sectoral qualitative analysis (MSQA) that provides a useful means to examine the relationship between selected economic variables and their performance in different sectors along the whole supply chain. These relationships will be recorded using descriptive and/or numeric scores in a matrix format. &#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
- Interviews with key-informants.&#xD;
- Interim report on organic food supply chain patterns in Europe (on the basis of interviews and a review of academic and grey literature).&#xD;
- Identifying of six commodities in eight countries and specific supply chains in each country. &#xD;
- Development of questionnaire for interviews with key actors of identified supply chains.&#xD;
PreTest with actors of one entire supply chain.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EU-QLIF: Supply Chain Analysis: Improving quality and safety and reduction of cost in the European organic and “low input” food supply chains: WP 6.1: Economic analyses of structures, conduct and performance of supply chains for organic foods in Europe.    Runs 2004 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Stolze, Matthias, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6272/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>