<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Value of Eco-Labelling - Executive Summary</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>China</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>John Paull’s book ‘The Value of Eco-labelling’ ‘ published by VDM Verlag examines the value that eco-labelling and geo-labelling can add to food. Which eco-labels and which place-of-origin labels add value? Just how much value do they add? And for which consumers? This study demonstrates that a knowledge of the method of production and the place of production of food has measurable monetary value for consumers. The study examines the value to consumers of particular eco-labels and geo-labels. ‘The Value of Eco-Labelling’ reports the values of Organic, Certified Organic, Natural and Eco, as well as of country-of-origin labelling (CoOL) and regional provenance labelling. The interaction effects of multiple food labelling claims are identified. Based on a raft of demographic measures, ‘The Value of Eco-Labelling’ identifies just which consumers are responsive to which claims. This book presents an efficient and effective methodology for quantifying consumer value. ‘The Value of Eco-Labelling’ presents a treasure trove of data, analysis, insights and surprises. ‘The Value of Eco-Labelling’ is a valuable resource for food producers, marketers and certifiers, as well as for agricultural departments, organisations, advisers, policy makers, consumer advocates and researchers. The Executive Summary is presented here.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>VDM Verlag</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16980/1/16980.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John    (2009) The Value of Eco-Labelling - Executive Summary.    In:      The Value of Eco-Labelling.  VDM Verlag, Saarbrücken, Germany, chapter Executive Summary, xvii-xxii.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16980/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>