<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Redistribution of sulphur during generative growth of barley with different sulphur and nitrogen status.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mortensen, JV</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjørring, JK</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of S and N application on the distribution and redistribution of S compounds in spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) was investigated in pot experiments by determination of changes in the content of total-, sulphate- and thiol-S in leaves, ears and stems during the grain-filling period. Nitrogen and sulphur had a clear interactive effect on the yield of all plant parts with little or no effect of S at low N application rates and similar low effect of N without S application. The sulphate concentration in the different plant parts was markedly affected by the S application rate. This effect was most pronounced in leaves, less in stems and least in ears. In S-replete plants leaf S decreased during grain development by an average of 28%, while in S-deficient plants the leaf S content did not change during the grain-filling period. About 70% of leaf N was redistributed to the ears in plants growing at adequate S supply compared with about 35% of leaf N in S-deficient plants.  The proportion of ear N and S originating from the redistribution of leaf N and S was 49% and 23%, respectively. This study verifies that S is relatively immobile in plants as the proportion of S redistributed from leaf tissue was considerably smaller than that of N. The results suggest that the availability of soil or root S during grain-filling is important for an adequate S supply to the developing grains as the distribution of S to the ears considerably exceeded the amount exported from the leaves.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/154/1/paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Eriksen, J; Nielsen, M; Mortensen, JV and Schjørring, JK   (2001) Redistribution of sulphur during generative growth of barley with different sulphur and nitrogen status.   Plant and Soil, 230, pp. 239-246.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/154/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>