<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>TRACEABILITY AMONG SMALLHOLDERS IN ORGANIC FRESH PRODUCE VALUE CHAINS: CASE OF NAIROBI</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gichure, Josphat Njenga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wahome, Raphael Githaiga</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karuri, Edward</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Karantininis, Kostas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Traceability enhances information sharing and disclosure thereby increasing trust among stakeholder along value chains. This research evaluated information flow along organic fresh produce value chains using a participatory study of organic certified farmers and outlets around Nairobi in 2012. Traceability was limited as majority of stakeholders were smallholders who had no functional traceability system. Presence of traceability was positively related to two factor groups; organizational activities and personnel perception. Variables in the organizational activities were also interrelated and include documentation, certification by other quality management standards, training on food safety and traceability system and monitoring. In addition, group activities increased trust among value chain actors. Extension services emphasizing on documentation, quality management certification, employee training, group activities and system monitoring should be conducted to improve traceability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23517/1/23517_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gichure, Josphat Njenga; Wahome, Raphael Githaiga; Karuri, Edward and Karantininis, Kostas    (2014) TRACEABILITY AMONG SMALLHOLDERS IN ORGANIC FRESH PRODUCE VALUE CHAINS: CASE OF NAIROBI.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridge, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 779-782.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23517/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>