<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dry cow therapy in an organic dairy herd of a milk and a dual purpose breed</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Dr. Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>According to the EU-Regulation for organic farming breeds chosen for the organic production should have the capacity to adapt to the local conditions to reduce the risk of diseases. The study compared the udder health status and the necessity of application of dry cow therapy (DCT) on cows of a dual purpose and a milk breed (Red and White Holsteins vs. Holstein-Friesian) kept under the same management conditions. Data records of one and a half year and 49 cows were analysed. 132 of 203 udder quarters were treated with an antibiotic at drying off. The treated quarters had significant higher readings for electrical conductivity, California Mastitis Test and the somatic cell count during lactation than the untreated group. Red and White Holstein cows received significantly more often a DCT than Holstein-Friesian cows. Thus, the results of our study do not support the presumption that older breeds are more robust against diseases and therefore fit better into organic dairy farming. Discussions about this topic should consider that the term “local condition” includes not only the climate but also the management conditions of the organic dairy farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11766/1/Barth_11766_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barth, Dr. Kerstin    (2008) Dry cow therapy in an organic dairy herd of a milk and a dual purpose breed.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11766/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>