<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Positive Mischungseffekte auf Ertrag und Stickstoffversorgung&#xD;
in Klee-Gras-Mischungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Huguenin-Elie, Olivier</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nyfeler, Daniel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Suter, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>High plant species richness has been shown to positively influence grassland biomass&#xD;
production. In mixtures containing two forage grass and two forage legume species&#xD;
we quantified the diversity-productivity effect and the nitrogen economy of the swards&#xD;
across a broad range of species proportions. Positive diversity-productivity effects&#xD;
resulted in higher yield (up to +35%) of the four-species grass-clover-mixtures than the&#xD;
highest yielding monoculture (transgressive overyielding). The diversity-productivity&#xD;
effect depended on the species proportion in the mixture and was maximal in well&#xD;
balanced mixtures with a clover proportion of 40 – 60%. Transgressive overyielding&#xD;
was significant over a fairly wide range of clover proportions. Well balanced grassclover-&#xD;
mixtures allowed obtaining up to 320 kg N ha-1 yr-1 deriving from symbiotic N2&#xD;
fixation and allowed an optimal transformation of fixed N into dry matter yield. These&#xD;
mixtures allowed benefiting from maximal fixation activity of the legumes without&#xD;
reducing the uptake of N from soil and fertiliser by the grasses in the sward.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14416/1/HugueninElie_14416.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Huguenin-Elie, Olivier; Nyfeler, Daniel; Suter, Matthias; Frossard, Emmanuel and Lüscher, Andreas    (2009) Positive Mischungseffekte auf Ertrag und Stickstoffversorgung in Klee-Gras-Mischungen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14416/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>