<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Can on-farm bioenergy production make organic farming more sustainable? - A model for energy balance, nitrogen losses, and green house gas emissions in a 1000 ha energy catchment with organic dairy farming and integrated bioenergy production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pugesgaard, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Møller, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, E.S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Can biogas and bioethanol production make organic farming more sustainable?&#xD;
- Results from a model for the fossil energy balance, Nitrogen losses, and greenhouse gas emissions in a 1000 ha energy catchment with organic dairy farming and integrated biogas and bioethanol production.&#xD;
&#xD;
Dalgaard T1, Pugesgaard S1, Jørgensen U1, Olesen JE1, Møller HB1 and Jensen ES2&#xD;
&#xD;
1) Dept. Agroecology and Environment. Faculty of Agricultural Sciences (DJF), University of Aarhus. DK-8830 Tjele. Denmark. Contact: tommy.dalgaard@agrsci.dk  &#xD;
2) Biosystems Department, Risø DTU, The National Laboratory for Sustainable Energy, The Technical University of Denmark DK-4000 Roskilde, Denmark &#xD;
&#xD;
The vision of organic farming systems, independent of fossil energy resources, with significantly lower nutrient losses, and no net contribution to the greenhouse gas emissions might be fulfilled via the integration of biogas production. This is an important hypothesis investigated in the www.bioconcens.elr.dk/uk/ research project.&#xD;
&#xD;
This poster illustrates preliminary results from a model for the fossil energy balance, Nitrogen losses, and greenhouse gas emissions in a 1000 ha energy catchment with organic dairy farming and integrated biogas production in Denmark. The model will draw on results from previous models (e.g the farmGHG model), and includes a number of organic dairy farm type components, including information on livestock production, housing, manure storage, manure and fodder import/export, crop rotations, yield levels, and soil types. In addition, a biogas plant model component evaluates effects of the inclusion of variable amounts of manures and crop residues from the specified farm types, into the biogas energy production. &#xD;
&#xD;
The model is intended to result in an overall catchment balance for the following three types of indicators: 1) the fossil energy use – i.e. the net fossil energy use minus the bioenergy production, 2) losses of Nitrogen in the form of nitrates, ammonia and nitrous oxide, and 3) the emission of the three main greenhouse gasses from agriculture: carbon dioxide, nitrous oxide and methane, measured in carbon dioxide equivalents. Moreover, these indicator values are specified for each of the farm types included in the model, and for the biogas plant component. Finally, selected model results are discussed in relation to the overall hypothesis of the research project, and it is discussed how the integration of biogas production in organic farming, can help to improve the self-sufficiency in Nitrogen, and thereby reduce the import of nutrients to the organic farming systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14801/1/14801.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pugesgaard, S.; Dalgaard, T.; Jørgensen, U.; Olesen, J.E.; Møller, H. and Jensen, E.S.    (2008) Can on-farm bioenergy production make organic farming more sustainable? - A model for energy balance, nitrogen losses, and green house gas emissions in a 1000 ha energy catchment with organic dairy farming and integrated bioenergy production.       Poster at:   FAO Workshop on Organic Agriculture and Climate Change. , Modena, Italy., June 18 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14801/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>