<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>In field N transfer, build-up, and leaching in ryegrass-clover mixtures</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, E S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, H</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two field experiments investigating dynamics in grass-clover mixtures were conducted, using 15N- and 14C-labelling to trace carbon (C) and nitrogen (N) from grass (Lolium perenne L.) and clover (Trifolium repens L. and Trifolium pratense L.). The leaching of dissolved inorganic nitrogen (DIN), as measured in pore water sampled by suction cups, increased during the autumn and winter, whereas the leaching of dissolved organic nitrogen (DON) was fairly constant during this period. Leaching of 15N from the sward indicated that ryegrass was the direct source of less than 1-2 percent of the total N leaching measured, whereas N dynamics pointed to clover as an important contributor to N leaching. Sampling of roots indicates that the dynamics in smaller roots were responsible for N and C build-up in the sward, and that N became available for transfer among species and leaching from the root zone. The bi-directional transfer of N between ryegrass and clover could however not be explained only by root turnover. Other processes like direct uptake of organic N compounds, may have contributed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14647/1/Full_length_paper_Jim_Rasmussen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, J ; Eriksen, J ; Jensen, E S and Høgh-Jensen, H     (2008) In field N transfer, build-up, and leaching in ryegrass-clover mixtures.   In:     Grassland Science in Europe, 13, pp. 559-561.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14647/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>