<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nutzung pflanzengenetischer Ressourcen für den ökologischen Landbau am Beispiel von Wintererbsen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, MSC Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graß, Dr. Rüdiger</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schüler, Dr. Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Winter peas were cultivated in Germany in the first half of the 20th century for green manure, green forage or as a threshing crop. So far they are mainly used in field ex-periments, e.g. at the University of Kassel. But winter peas are very interesting for or-ganic farming, because of their high N-fixation rate and their ability to suppress weeds effectively. In the vegetation period 2002/2003 twelve genotypes of winter peas from the German genebank in Gatersleben were examined in field trials. In the long and cold winter of 2002/2003 eight different genotypes from Germany, Hungary and the Balkan survived. The yield of the eight accessions as green forage and as a threshing crop (yield between 3 – 4 t/ha) are promising.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3410/1/3410.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, MSC Peer; Graß, Dr. Rüdiger and Schüler, Dr. Christian    (2005) Nutzung pflanzengenetischer Ressourcen für den ökologischen Landbau am Beispiel von Wintererbsen.  [Use of plant genetic resources in organic agriculture - the example of winter pea.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3410/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>