<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Strategies for medium-sized value-based food chains during growing process with a particular focus on the business logic and management concept</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Münchhausen, von, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulz, Kristin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haering, Anna Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Llamas Vacas, Rocio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Growth of values-based food chains holds particular challenges. The disconnection between producers and consumers require strategies that maintain and communicate values throughout the food chain. The objective of this paper is to analyze strategies organic food businesses have chosen to deal with growth, and in particular, strategies that focus on consumers’ expectations and producers’ business strategies. A literature review on the challenges of growing organic food chains provided the conceptual framework. The analysis of three case studies of organic food businesses shows that the values of food chains and the related business strategies aiming to maintain and transmit these values differ significantly. One case study business is closely linked to the farmers and the chain is characterized by the quality of products and process. The second case study focuses on reliability between chain partners, while the third is based on good cooperation aiming to secure income and employment.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>IFSA Europe, Leibniz-Centre for Agricultural Landscape Research (ZALF), Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Schobert, Heike</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Riecher, Maja-Catrin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fischer, Holger</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aenis, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Knierim, Andrea</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25694/19/25694.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25694/25/25694a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25694/31/25696.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Münchhausen, von, Susanne; Schulz, Kristin; Haering, Anna Maria and Llamas Vacas, Rocio    (2014) Strategies for medium-sized value-based food chains during growing process with a particular focus on the business logic and management concept.   In: Schobert, Heike; Riecher, Maja-Catrin; Fischer, Holger; Aenis, Thomas and Knierim, Andrea (Eds.)  Farming systems facing global challenges: Capacities and strategies, IFSA Europe, Leibniz-Centre for Agricultural Landscape Research (ZALF), Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin, Book of abstracts In: http://project2.zalf.de/IFSA_2014/documents/ifsa-2014-berlin-book-of-abstracts.pdf, p. 58.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25694/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>