<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An integrated study of the development of organic rice cultivation in the Camargue (France)-</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mouret, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hammond, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dreyfus, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Desclaux, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marnotte, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mesléard, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the Camargue, rice and durum wheat are associated in rotations that have an ambivalent ecological impact: on the one hand, these two crops contribute to the preservation of the surrounding ecosystem, while on the other hand, when cropped intensively, they can threaten the ecological equilibrium of this protected area. In this context, organic agriculture would seem to be an alternative adopted by a certain number of producers and processors. However, the pioneers of this practice encounter numerous problems, both agronomic and economic. The study presented here aims: to construct a pluridisciplinary approach to analyse the conditions of the development of organic cereal cultivation in the Camargue: to identify the principal factors that limit the development of this new practice: to produce knowledge useful in helping ricegrowers put into practice organic cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6492/1/turin-riz.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mouret, J.C.; Hammond, R.; Dreyfus, F.; Desclaux, D.; Marnotte, P. and Mesléard, F.    (2004) An integrated study of the development of organic rice cultivation in the Camargue (France)-.       Paper at:   International Conference on Challenges and Opportunities for Sustainable Rice-Based Production Systems., Torino, 13-15 Sept 2004.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6492/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>