<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modelling environmental effects of agriculture : the case of organic rye and grey partridge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miettinen, Antti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huhtala, Anni</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Our optimal control model identifies economic reasons as to why farmland bird populations have dramatically declined in modern agricultural landscapes. By integrating recreational wildlife values into farm level decision-making on arable crop choice and herbicide use, we derive those economic instruments needed for creating suitable conditions for game bird species on farmland. Based on the Finnish data available on the grey partridge (Perdix perdix), we illustrate how the optimal acreage subsidy for organically-grown areas, herbicide tax rates and the hunting licence fee could be estimated in monetary terms. Finally, we discuss the benefits and costs of cultivating organic cereals which will enhance preservation of the grey partridge.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>The European Association of Agricultural Economists EAAE</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8612/1/eaae.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Miettinen, Antti and Huhtala, Anni    (2005) Modelling environmental effects of agriculture : the case of organic rye and grey partridge.       Paper at:   The future of rural Europe in the global agri-food system : the XIth international congress of European Association of Agricultural Economists EAAE, Copenhagen, Denmark, August 24-27, 2005.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8612/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>