<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New challenges to improve organic bread wheat production in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>David, Christophe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Celette, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Abecassis, Joël</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carcea, Marina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hiltbrunner, Jürg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messmer, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peigne, Joséphine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Samson, Marie-Françoise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schweinzer, Agnes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomsen, I.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thommen, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The total organic area in the EU-27 had an annual average growth rate of nearly 15% from 1998 to 2006 with winter wheat being the most important cereal crop. Wheat yield in organic farming is around 30% to 70% of yield of conventional farming but higher premia for organic wheat may to some extent compensate for this. Bread wheat is grown in a variety of crop rotations and farming systems and four basic organic crop production systems have been defined. Nitrogen deficiency and weed infestation are considered to be the most serious threat in organic wheat production. Organic wheat producers will have to fulfil the technological needs of bakers although the requirements differ widely from small artisan bakers to large enterprises handling the organic bread processing. To maintain and expand organic wheat production, there is a need to control weed population, manage nitrogen nutrition and maintain crop diversity in the cropping system. In order to obtain a share in the premium price of organic wheat products, farmers may involve in further processing and marketing.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19483/1/OWBread_ISOFAR2011_David_et_al2011.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>David, Christophe; Celette, Florian; Abecassis, Joël; Carcea, Marina; Friedel, Jürgen K.; Corre-Hellou, Guénaëlle; Hiltbrunner, Jürg; Messmer, Monika; Peigne, Joséphine; Samson, Marie-Françoise; Schweinzer, Agnes; Thomsen, I.K. and Thommen, Andreas    (2011) New challenges to improve organic bread wheat production in Europe.       Lecture at:   3rd ISOFAR Scientific Conference, Gyeonggi Paldang, South Korea, September 26-October 5 2011.       [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19483/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>