<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer Appreciation of Carcass Quality of Organic vs Conventional Suckling Lamb Production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Palacios, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Revilla, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vivar-Quintana, A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lurueña-Martínez, M.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Severiano-Pérez, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Carcass characteristics of sucking lambs (n= 40) of two breeds reared under conventional and organic conditions were analysed including objective and subjective parameters for fatness and conformation, meat and fat colour. Consumer acceptance was also studied using the home-use test. Results showed that the characteristics of the carcass of suckling lamb were similar for both types of production systems pointing out that organic production system did not affect fatness or muscle development. However, organic meat was darker (higher L* and a* values) probably related with the higher amount of exercise, although fat was not more yellow. In contrast consumers did not consider organic meat darker and there were not significant differences in appearance related with the similar conformation. These results reflect that consumer perceive organic meat as at least as good as conventional production not only regarding environmental quality but also regarding carcass quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12563/1/12563.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Palacios, C.; Revilla, I.; Vivar-Quintana, A.M.; Lurueña-Martínez, M.A. and Severiano-Pérez, P.    (2008) Consumer Appreciation of Carcass Quality of Organic vs Conventional Suckling Lamb Production.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12563/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>