<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Exploring close consumer-producer links to maintain and enhance on-farm biodiversity</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Milestad, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Björklund, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Westberg, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Geber, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ahnström, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper deals with the question of whether local selling of farm products improves on-farm biodiversity. In contrast to the main agricultural trend of farms specialising and increasing in size in response to the national and global markets, increasing numbers of Swedish farmers are instead diverting their efforts towards selling at local markets. Based on a study of six farms, the paper explores the nature of diversity on these farms and identifies factors supporting diversity. The study shows that farmers who interact with consumers are encouraged to diversify their production. The actual crops and varieties grown are determined by a combination of the natural conditions prevailing on the farm and the conditions created by the farmer in terms of marketing strategy for the products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11641/1/11641.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Milestad, R.; Björklund, J.; Westberg, L.; Geber, U. and Ahnström, J.    (2008) Exploring close consumer-producer links to maintain and enhance on-farm biodiversity.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11641/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>