<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Combining physical, cultural and biological methods: prospects for integrated non-chemical weed management strategies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hatcher, Lecturer Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Melander, Senior scientist Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Physical, cultural and biological methods for weed control have developed largely independently and are often concerned with weed control in different systems: physical and cultural control in annual crops and biocontrol in extensive grasslands.  We discuss the strengths and limitations of four physical and cultural methods for weed control: mechanical, thermal, cutting, and intercropping, and the advantages and disadvantages of combining biological control with them.  These physical and cultural control methods may increase soil nitrogen levels and alter microclimate at soil level; this may be of benefit to biocontrol agents, although physical disturbance to the soil and plant damage may be detrimental.  Some weeds escape control by these methods; we suggest these weeds may be controlled by biocontrol agents.  It will be easiest to combine biological control with fire and cutting in grasslands; within arable systems it would be most promising to combine biological control (especially using seed predators and foliar pathogens) with cover-cropping, and mechanical weeding combined with foliar bacterial and possibly foliar fungal pathogens.  We stress the need to consider the timing of application of combined control methods in order to cause least damage to the biocontrol agent, along with maximum damage to the weed and to consider the wider implications of these different weed control methods.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Blackwell Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2003-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1469/1/Hatcher_Melander_WR.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hatcher, Lecturer Paul and Melander, Senior scientist Bo   (2003) Combining physical, cultural and biological methods: prospects for integrated non-chemical weed management strategies.   Weed Research, 43 (5), pp. 303-322.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1469/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>