<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Reproductive Management of Dairy Cows with Particular Reference to Organic Systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Diskin, Michel G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelly, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Reproductive efficiency is a major factor affecting production and economic efficiency indairy herds. In seasonally calving herds the requirement of good reproductive performance is of greater importance than in  other production systems in order to maximally exploit the use of grazed grass in the diet of the cow. Reproductive&#xD;
performance of lactating dairy cows worldwide has declined over the past 30 years in association with selection for milk yield. There is increasing and consistent evidence to&#xD;
suggest that at least some part of the decline in cow reproductive performance is related to underlying changes in reproductive physiology caused by high milk production and or negative energy balance (NEB) in early lactation. Organic systems of milk production demand high tight seasonal calving patterns, maximal production from grazed grass, low involuntary culling rates and the continuous genetic improvement of the herd for commercially important traits. Organic milk production systems should also allow for replacement rates of 25% - 30% to ensure a young herd age structure and low somatic cell counts (SCC). The objective of this paper is to review the role of management factors in herd reproductive performance with particular reference to organic herds.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Teagasc</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008-12-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18633/1/National%20Organic%20Conference%20Proceedings%20MAIN%20_3_PDF.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Diskin, Michel G. and Kelly, Frank    (2008) Reproductive Management of Dairy Cows with Particular Reference to Organic Systems.   In:     Teagasc Organic Production Research Conference Proceedings, Teagasc, Oakpark, pp. 26-41.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18633/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>