<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung eines schnellen Bio-Tests zur Untersuchung des Wirkungs-potentials von mikrobiellen Pflanzenstärkungsmitteln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Akter, Zafrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weinmann, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neumann, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Römheld, Volker</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plant-growth-promoting soil microorganisms are increasingly distributed on the world market. Nutrient mobilization, stimulation of root growth, enhanced resistance to envi-ronmental stress factors are discussed as possible mechanisms. These assumptions are based only on scarce scientific evidence due to limited reproducibility of pot and field experiments, limited information concerning the conditions for successful applica-tion, limited standardization of inoculum preparation and quality. Thus, the develop-ment of rapid screening tests is to demonstrate the principle effectiveness of biofertil-izers prior to set-up of labourous pot or field experiments is urgently required.&#xD;
In this study, a rapid bio-test with cucumber (Cucumis sativa L.) as an indicator plant was developed to evaluate the effectiveness of five commercial biofertilizers based on Trichoderma spp. and Bacillus spp. (Biohealth-G, Biohealth-WSG, Biomex, Vitalin T50 and SP11) using germination rate, root and shoot biomass, maximum root length, and leaf area as test parameters. The experiment was repeated twice with 6 replicates in hydroponic culture under controlled conditions (pH 5.5, 22° C; Light: 230 mmol cm2 sec-1). Biofertilizers were applied at the rate of 3 g per 2.5 l mineral nutrient solution. Germination rate was increased by 20 - 25% in all biofertilizer treatments compared to the control. After 2 weeks culture period, root dry weight and leaf area of Biohealth-G, Vitalin T50, SP-11 and Biomex-treated cucumber seedlings were significantly in-creased. Biohealth-G and Vitalin T50 showed significantly higher main root length and Biohealth-G higher shoot dry weight than the remaining treatments, while Biohealth-WSG did not cause differences compared to untreated control plants. The pathogen-antagonistic potential of Trichoderma strains can be easily tested by co-inoculation with the pathogenic fungus Gaeumannomyces graminis on malt extract peptone agar plates. The results suggest that the activity potential of different Trichoderma-based biofertilizers could be easily screened by using the described bio-test with cucumber seedlings.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9666/1/9666_Akter_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Akter, Zafrin; Weinmann, Markus; Neumann, Günter and Römheld, Volker    (2007) Entwicklung eines schnellen Bio-Tests zur Untersuchung des Wirkungs-potentials von mikrobiellen Pflanzenstärkungsmitteln.  [Development of a Rapid Bio-Test to Study the Activity Potential of Biofertilizers.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9666/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>