<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A history of demands: philosophy and agrobiology. The significance of the founding principles of organic farming within the framework of contemporary development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>BESSON, Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming originally deals with the problematic nature/technique within a holistic view. The order of things inspires organic agronomy and social thoughts on agriculture. The link between what is and what has to be socially is not thinkable within modern right and ethic, but it is in accordance with the ancient philosophy. A. Howard, R. Steiner, H.P. Rusch, M. Fukuoka, found their biology according to this fundamental way of behaving. The biology of those founders stands between various philosophical speculations, esoteric speculations, empirical observations, and scientific approaches. According to the ancient philosophy, these authors are suggesting an imitation of nature based on a cyclic understanding. Human intrusion in nature, although founding element of farming, remains hard to legitimate. Indeed the founders are anxious about the agricultural chemistry’s consequences on ecology and society. Today the biological foundation of organic farming could cross again with evolutionism and ecology. A more dynamic conception of nature will open new ways for agronomic reasoning. This also opens up on a more humanistic philosophy of farming. Nevertheless, the holistic ethic of organic farming remains an innovating source for its contemporary development.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15499/1/47-Besson.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>BESSON, Y.    (2009) A history of demands: philosophy and agrobiology. The significance of the founding principles of organic farming within the framework of contemporary development.  [Une histoire d’exigences : philosophie et agrobiologie. L’actualité de la pensée des fondateurs de l’agriculture biologique pour son développement contemporain.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 329-362.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15499/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>