<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>What breeding strategy(ies) should be carry up for organic winter wheat? Results and prospects from a long-term comparison with low input variety trials</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Le Campion, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oury, F. X.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morlais, J.Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walczak, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gardet, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gilles, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pichard, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rolland, Bernard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Breeding varieties adapted to various organic farming conditions is one solution, among others, to increase yields and improve organic winter bread wheat quality. From 2004 to 2011, INRA winter wheat breeders have conducted variety trials in three contrasting agro-climatic regions across north-west France to test the relative response of 25 to 30 diversified genotypes when cultivated in low input (FI) and organic (AB) conditions. The comparison of 17 paired management trials showed the relevance of low input conditions to identify genotypes adapted to organic farming conditions for yield and protein content. Such a selection environment is useful also to screen “GPD+” (positive Grain Protein Deviation) genotypes with better nutrient use efficiency. In contrast, our results highlighted the need to evaluate genotypes baking quality in organic conditions in which bread making ability is frequently lost.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26300/1/LeCampion_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Le Campion, A.; Oury, F. X.; Morlais, J.Y.; Walczak, P.; Gardet, O.; Gilles, S.; Pichard, A. and Rolland, Bernard   (2013) What breeding strategy(ies) should be carry up for organic winter wheat? Results and prospects from a long-term comparison with low input variety trials.  [Quelle(s) sélection(s) du blé tendre pour l’agriculture biologique ? Résultats et perspectives d’un comparatif avec les performances variétales en conduite « faibles intrants ».]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 443-454.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26300/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>