<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Suitability of different dairy cow types for an Alpine organic and low-input milk production system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Horn, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gasteiner, Johann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Podstatzky, Leopold</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haiger, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The  implementation of  a  seasonal, site adapted, pasture-based milk production system as applied in New Zealand and North Western Europe might be an alternative for the near future in  Alpine regions. As in such a  low-input system the fertility and secondary traits such as robustness  against  metabolic  challenges  of   dairy cows  is   of   crucial  importance,   it  is questionable whether conventional dairy cow types, which were selected primarily for  milk production under high-input conditions, are most suitable. Therefore the aim of this study was to compare two different genotypes concerning their suitability for an organic, low-input milk production system under  Alpine  conditions.  Between  2008  and  2011 records  from 91 lactations of Brown Swiss (BS) and a special strain of Holstein Friesian (HFL) were collected at an experimental  organic dairy farm. The BS cows represented the average Austrian  BS population  and were primarily selected for high milk yield. HFL cows were for  decades selected under low-input conditions and were primarily bred for  lifetime performance and ﬁtness. The dataset was analysed using multi-factorial statistical models. BS was superior for most milk production parameters, but not for  milk yield per unit of metabolic body weight. HFL had a lower body weight throughout the lactation, but mobilised signiﬁcantly less body reserves, indicating a shorter and less negative energy balance. Both breeds had similar total feed and energy intake, but HFL had a signiﬁcantly higher feed intake per unit of metabolic body weight.  Furthermore,  HFL  conceived earlier and had a  signiﬁcantly shorter  calving interval and an overall superior reproductive performance. Due to this, HFL has some advantages over conventional BS if managed in a pasture based, low-input milk production system, especially when block calving is involved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25136/1/1-s2.0-S1871141313000668-main.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Horn, Marco; Steinwidder, Andreas; Gasteiner, Johann; Podstatzky, Leopold; Haiger, Alfred and Zollitsch, Werner   (2013) Suitability of different dairy cow types for an Alpine organic and low-input milk production system.   Livestock Science, 153, pp. 135-146.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25136/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>