<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bedeutung von Ackerbohnendichtsaat und Horngries für den Ertrag bei Brokkoli (Brassica oleracea convar. Botrytis var. italica)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Veh, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graeff-Hönninger, Simone</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Claupein, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zikeli, Sabine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ziehm, Nele</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Close seeding of field beans (Vicia faba) has been regarded for several years as an option in organic agriculture for the short-term introduction of nitrogen into production systems. At the same time faba bean potentially supplies nitrogen (N) to crops and soil by N2 fixation and nitrogen release when crop biomass is finally mulched. The main objective of this project was to investigate and develop a method of N-supply to meet the demand of broccoli using organic N-sources. Based on the results it can be stated that yield of broccoli significantly increased in the treatment intensive legume cropping plus fertilizer when compared to an intensive legume cropping without horngrist. However, upon inspection, it was revealed that marketable yields were even higher, suggesting that a previous crop of grass-clover is more profitable than close seeding of field beans.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21347/1/21347_Veh.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Veh, Christine; Graeff-Hönninger, Simone; Claupein, Wilhelm; Zikeli, Sabine and Ziehm, Nele    (2013) Bedeutung von Ackerbohnendichtsaat und Horngries für den Ertrag bei Brokkoli (Brassica oleracea convar. Botrytis var. italica).       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21347/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>