<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil solarization for weed control in carrot.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Marenco, Ricardo Antonio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lustosa, Denise Castro</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil solarization is a technique used for weed and plant disease control in regions with high levels of solar radiation. The effect of solarization (0, 3, 6, and 9 weeks) upon weed populations,carrot (Daucus carota L. cv. Brasília) yield and nematode infestation in carrot roots was studied in São Luís (2o35' S; 44o10' W), MA, Brazil, using transparent polyethylene films (100 and 150 mm of thickness). The maximum temperature at 5 cm of depth was about 10oC warmer in solarized soil than in control plots. In the study 20 weed types were recorded. Solarization reduced weed biomass and density in about 50% of weed species, including Cyperus spp., Chamaecrista nictans var. paraguariensis(Chod &amp; Hassl.) Irwin &amp; Barneby,Marsypianthes chamaedrys (Vahl) O. Kuntze, Mitracarpus sp.,Mollugo verticillata L., Sebastiania corniculata M. Arg., and Spigelia anthelmia L. Approximately 40% of species in the weed flora were not affected by soil mulching. Furthermore, seed germination of Commelina benghalensis L. was increased by soil solarization. Marketable yield of carrots was greater in solarized soil than in the unsolarized one. It was concluded that solarization for nine weeks increases carrot yield and is effective for controlling more than half of the weed species recorded. Mulching was not effective for controlling root-knot nematodes in carrot.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2000-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20447/1/Marenco_soil.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Marenco, Ricardo Antonio and Lustosa, Denise Castro   (2000) Soil solarization for weed control in carrot.  [Solarização do solo para o controle de plantas daninhas na cultura de cenoura.]  Pesquisa Agropecuária Brasileira, 35 (10), pp. 2025-2032.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20447/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>