<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anbauverfahren mit Körnerleguminosen in viehlosen Betrieben des ökologischen Landbaus [Production methods for grain legumes in stockless organic farming systems]</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pommer, G</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Crop rotations of organic farms without livestock were compared on three sites for three years in three replications. The crop rotations consisted of a kernel legume and two cereals. Different distances in the rows of kernel legumes and various ways of intercropping after them should improve the yield of cereals. Within the kernel legumes peas (5.5 tons/ha) and faba beans (5.2 tons/ha) had high, lupins (2.5 tons/ha) low yields. The following crop winter wheat reached high yields (6.0 tons/ha) with no differences depending on the species of kernel legumes, their distances in rows or the variations in intercropping. The same occured with winter rye but on much lower yield level (4.0 tons/ha). It was not possible to improve the yield of cereals through species of kernel legume, the distance of rows in kernel legumes, or through intercropping.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Reents, Hans Jürgen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2001</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/788/1/kein-Dokument.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pommer, G    (2001) Anbauverfahren mit Körnerleguminosen in viehlosen Betrieben des ökologischen Landbaus [Production methods for grain legumes in stockless organic farming systems].   In: Reents, Hans Jürgen (Ed.)  Beiträge zur 6. Wissenschaftstagung zum Ökologischen Landbau, Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin, pp. 401-405.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/788/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>