<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Participatory plant breeding in Denmark</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Borgen, Anders</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersen, Rikke</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plant breeding gets more and more concentrated on a couple of multinational companies, and financing plant breeding via the traditional royalty founded certification system exclusive for the specific needs in organic farming is not profitable in most field crops. The seed certification system only allows pure line varieties, and the royalty funded breeding system tend to focus on monogenic resistance with s short durability on the marked. To develop new plant genetic material for organic farmers with durable stability and resistance, the Danish Organic Farmers Association has initiated a participatory plant breeding program with the aim to develop varieties and diverse populations for the organic farmers. The project is based within the advisory service in the organisation in cooperation with plant breeding research projects. In this way, it is the hope to overcome the economic and legal barrier for implementation of crop diversity and targeted selection for the different needs in the diverse organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18944/4/18944.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Borgen, Anders and Andersen, Rikke    (2010) Participatory plant breeding in Denmark.   In:     Breeding for resilience: A strategy for organic and low-input farming systems? EUCARPIA 2nd Conference of the "Organic and Low-Input Agriculture" Section, p. 144.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18944/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>