<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Cow Comfort&#xD;
- an advisorytool to secure animal welfare on organic dairy farms in Norway</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, Britt I. F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Grøva, Lise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kielland, Camilla</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic Cow Comfort is an advisory tool in animal welfare, developed to secure animal welfare on organic dairy farms in Norway. The farm advisory tool consists of&#xD;
•	A farm visit by a veterinarian and a production advisor both specialized in animal welfare and organic farming&#xD;
•	An evaluation of herd health and welfare through welfare assessment&#xD;
•	Advice on disease prevention and improve-ment of animal welfare&#xD;
•	Follow up visit by an advisor looking at im-plementation of new initiatives&#xD;
•	Counselling meetings with groups of farmer&#xD;
The evaluation of herd health and welfare is done with the help of checklists where animal based pa-rameters, farm management and operating systems, and human-animal relationship are recorded. A report is prepared after every farm visit with a health and welfare plan where specific measures for improve-ment of animal welfare are outlined.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8252/1/Abstract_Britt_Henriksen%2C_Organic_congress_06.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Henriksen, Britt I. F.; Grøva, Lise and Kielland, Camilla    (2006) Organic Cow Comfort - an advisorytool to secure animal welfare on organic dairy farms in Norway.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8252/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>