<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Green manuring for tropical organic cropping – A comparative analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sangakkara, Dr. Ravi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weerasekera, Mr. Danesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Prof.Dr. Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Green manuring is an essential component of tropical organic farming. Field studies evaluated the use of three legumes as in situ or ex situ green manures, along with a nonlegume green manure and a control to ascertain their impacts on soil properties and yields of maize and mung bean grown in major (wet) and minor (dry) seasons.  In situ green manuring, especially with legumes, had the most beneficial impact on soil properties, while with ex situ methods, the use of leaves alone improved soil properties. Yields were increased to a greater extent by green manuring in the minor season, and the in situ system proved to be more beneficial. In ex situ green manuring, greater benefits were obtained by the application of leaves alone.  The impact of different green manures and their application methods is presented.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12524/1/12524.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sangakkara, Dr. Ravi; Weerasekera, Mr. Danesh and Freyer, Prof.Dr. Bernhard    (2008) Green manuring for tropical organic cropping – A comparative analysis.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12524/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>