<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bioabfallkompost im biologischen Landbau – Auswirkungen auf&#xD;
die Gehalte von bioverfügbaren Schwermetallen im Boden</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Erhart, Eva</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bartl, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Putz, Berta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Horak, Othmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The accumulation of heavy metals in soils is a potential risk that may keep organic&#xD;
farmers from using biowaste compost. As the ecological effects of metals are related&#xD;
to mobile fractions rather than to total contents in the soil, we measured the total&#xD;
(aqua regia extractable) heavy metal contents, the readily available water soluble and&#xD;
the potentially bioavailable LiCl-extractable fraction of soil heavy metals in a field&#xD;
experiment after ten years with total applications of 95, 175 and 255 t ha-1 biowaste&#xD;
compost (fresh matter). Total soil contents of Cd, Cr, Cu, Ni and Pb in the compost&#xD;
treatments were not significantly higher than in the unfertilized control. Total Zn&#xD;
contents increased in the treatment with the highest application rate. In the mobile&#xD;
fractions Cd and Pb were not detectable. Cr, Ni and Zn contents were in the range&#xD;
published for unpolluted soils in other studies and did not show any differences&#xD;
according to treatment. Easily exchangeable Cu (in LiCl extract) was increased with&#xD;
compost fertilization. In several crops, lower Cd contents were measured with&#xD;
compost fertilization than without fertilization. Potatoes which had received mineral&#xD;
fertilizer had significantly higher Cd contents. Crop Zn contents were increased in the&#xD;
compost treatments. In conclusion, fertilization with high quality biowaste compost at&#xD;
such rates and after ten years of application gives no cause for concern with regard to&#xD;
both total heavy metal contents and available heavy metal fractions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14479/1/Erhart_14479.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Erhart, Eva; Hartl, Wilfried; Bartl, Barbara; Putz, Berta and Horak, Othmar    (2009) Bioabfallkompost im biologischen Landbau – Auswirkungen auf die Gehalte von bioverfügbaren Schwermetallen im Boden.       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14479/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>