<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Monitoring the Conversion to Organic Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Surboeck, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Juergen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heinzinger, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gollner, Manfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Specific methods</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A long term field monitoring concerning the development of Organic Farming is performed at the bio-farm “Rutzendorf “ of the BVW GmbH in the Marchfeld region east of Vienna. It is an interdisciplinary project of eleven research institutes, which started in 2003. The aims of the project are: examination of changes concerning soil and plant parameters accompanying the conversion to organic farming; investigation of the effects of different organic fertilisation systems (green manure, communal green forage compost, farmyard manure) on soil properties and on crop performances; analysis of existing biotopes (hedges and field stripes) on the farm, and planning and selective realization of new biotopes with the aim of enhancing the biodiversity of the area, offering habitats for beneficials and reducing wind erosion potential.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4348/5/Freyer_etal_monitoring_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Freyer, Bernhard; Surboeck, Andreas; Friedel, Juergen K.; Heinzinger, Markus and Gollner, Manfred    (2005) Monitoring the Conversion to Organic Farming.       Poster at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4348/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>