<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality aspects of processed organic baby food - Results of a case study from an expert consultation in the baby food industry in 10 European countries.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Seidel, Kathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The processor survey shows the general principles and understanding of quality for the processing of organic food from the processors’ point of view. In addition, possible problem areas regarding the question of product quality such as raw material, processing techniques, storage etc. are worked out. The results of the survey support the identification and definition of critical and essential control points as well as product quality parameters.&#xD;
This survey can therefore conclude three points of actions to improve the process quality.&#xD;
- Handling of raw material: transportation, storage, pre-processing&#xD;
   - Nutritional, safety and sensory QCCP&#xD;
- Cooking: time and temperature&#xD;
   - Nutritional and sensory QCCP&#xD;
- Preserving/ sterilizations&#xD;
   - Nutritional and safety QCCP&#xD;
Besides these QCCPs, organic baby food should break away from the baby food market and constitute a nutritional rich, environmentally friendly and safe product of high quality.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13554/1/seidel-etal-2008-QACCP_final_report.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Seidel, Kathrin; Kretzschmar, Ursula and Zanoli, Raffaele         (2008) Quality aspects of processed organic baby food - Results of a case study from an expert consultation in the baby food industry in 10 European countries.   Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13554/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>