<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Qualitative und quantitative Beurteilung des Verhaltens von Jungsauen während eines freiwilligen Annäherungstests</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pfeiffer, Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Free farrowing systems are required by organic standards (Commission regulation (EC) 889/2008). However, not only adequate housing design and good management but also sows which are able to rear piglets successfully in those systems are important. Several studies show a relation between approach time during behavioural tests and reproductive traits. So far behavioural traits are not considered when selecting gilts in Austria. The aim of this study was to perform a qualitative and quantitative behavioural assessment during a voluntary approach test at two organic gilt producers which could provide practical tools for behavioural assessment when selecting gilts. A total of 44 gilts was tested in a 3x3m arena and observed when approaching a test person. Qualitatively three components were found: “emotional state”, “proactiveness” and “self-confidence”. The second and third components were significantly related to quantitative parameters. The component “emotional state” may provide additional information. However, it remains to be investigated if this information is related to reproductive performance</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21257/1/21257_pfeiffer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pfeiffer, Christina; Leeb, Christine and Winckler, Christoph    (2013) Qualitative und quantitative Beurteilung des Verhaltens von Jungsauen während eines freiwilligen Annäherungstests.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21257/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>