<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>State of the art review (WP2). On healthy growth initiatives in the mid-scale values-based chain of organic food</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kvam, Gunn-Turid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjørkhaug, Hilde</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Austria</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Finland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>France</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Lithuania</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Norway</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sweden</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Core organic II project HealthyGrowth assumes that present organic value chains seem either to operate in local markets with direct sale or in conventional retail chains where organic qualities are not properly communicated (HealthyGrowth (HG) proposal 2010). Within this statement lies an observation from previous research that local organic market chains have inherent problems in moving from niche to volume and mainstream large-scale market chains have inherent problems in securing and advancing organic values. Therefore, the aim of the HealthyGrowth project is to investigate a range of successful mid-scale organic value chains in order to learn how they are able to combine volume and values. Before the participants of the project start collecting data on such chains, the first major step was to develop a state-of-the-art review of research on successful mid-scale values-based chains (ibid.). &#xD;
The objective of WP2 in HealthyGrowth is to compile the most current research on organic markets and value chains in a state-of-the-art review. The main focus has been on studies of mid-scale value-based food chains and growth processes in the organic food sector. The aim of the review is to learn more about growth processes with its challenges, options and risks. Moreover, the review is supposed to point out main mechanisms and organizational principles underlying the successful development of businesses or initiatives, and identify the theories and methodologies most commonly used in the field (HG proposal 2010). &#xD;
This report is based on national state-of-the-art reports from the participating countries of the HealthyGrowth project, consisting of research on successful mid-scale values-based chains in the ten HealthyGrowth countries Germany, Denmark, Slovenia, Lithuania, Austria, France, Sweden, Finland, Turkey and Norway. Additionally, a review of research from other countries is carried out. This report presents an analysis and summary of these reviews.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25620/7/25620.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kvam, Gunn-Turid and Bjørkhaug, Hilde         (2014) State of the art review (WP2). On healthy growth initiatives in the mid-scale values-based chain of organic food.    Centre for rural reseach.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25620/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>