<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Potential economic gains from using forage legumes in organic livestock systems in northern Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Doyle, Chris J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Topp, Cairistiona F E</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
Forage legumes, with their ability to fix nitrogen biologically, seem especially attractive for organic livestock production. In an attempt to assess their true potential, this study draws on a four-year trial conducted at 12 sites in northern Europe with four different forage legumes. One third of the sites were managed as organic systems, with the harvested forage being fed as silage to dairy cows. Based on the trial results, an economic assessment has been made of the potential of forage legumes to improve the competitive edge of organic dairy systems, relative to conventional grass-based ones. Although the results suggest that the organic milk price premium plays a major role in determining the comparative profitability of organic dairy systems, the use of forage legumes also gives a significant cost advantage to organic production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8298/1/doyle_topp_Forage_livestock_systems.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Doyle, Chris J and Topp, Cairistiona F E    (2002) Potential economic gains from using forage legumes in organic livestock systems in northern Europe.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 195-196.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8298/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>