<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleich von neuseeländischen und „einheimischen“ Holsteinkühen&#xD;
in erster Laktation unter Vollweide auf einem Biobetrieb</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schori, Fredy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Münger, Dr. Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cow types adapted to forage-based production systems are of particular interest for&#xD;
organic milk production, because of the limited use of additives (concentrates, pharmaceuticals&#xD;
etc.). The objective of this project was to study the aptitude of New Zealand&#xD;
Holstein cows (HNZ) to produce milk in a pasture-based production system with a&#xD;
shortened calving season (February to mid April) under organic conditions. 11 HNZ&#xD;
were compared 2007 to 11 farm-bred, “Swiss” Holstein cows (HCH), all of them during&#xD;
their first lactation, in a rotational pasture system on the organic farm “l’Abbaye” in&#xD;
Sorens (CH). With an average live weight (LW) at the beginning of 469 kg and a&#xD;
height at withers (WH) of 130 cm the HNZ were considerably smaller compared to HCH&#xD;
with 609 kg LW and 147 cm WH. During the first lactation the HNZ gained more body&#xD;
mass (63 kg vs. 24 kg, P &lt; 0.03) and had a higher average body condition score (3.03&#xD;
vs. 2.77, P &lt; 0.04). The milk production per HNZ was lower by 1000 kg milk (P &lt; 0.004)&#xD;
respectively 800 kg energy-corrected milk (ECM) (P &lt; 0.02). No differences were&#xD;
detected between the two cow types concerning the ECM production per 100 kg&#xD;
metabolic weight. Milk protein and lactose contents were significantly higher for HNZ&#xD;
and milk fat content was not significantly different. The somatic cell counts were similar&#xD;
for both types. Although the adaptation period on farm for HNZ had been short, they&#xD;
produced the same amount of ECM per kg metabolic weight and gained more body&#xD;
mass compared with HCH.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14381/1/Schori_14381.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schori, Fredy and Münger, Dr. Andreas    (2009) Vergleich von neuseeländischen und „einheimischen“ Holsteinkühen in erster Laktation unter Vollweide auf einem Biobetrieb.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14381/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>