<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil phosphorus status in organic and conventional vegetable farms in Southeast Queensland, Australia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nachimuthu, Gunasekhar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristiansen, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lockwood, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guppy, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The soil phosphorus (P) status (0-10 cm) of two farming systems (organic (OF) and conventional (CF) vegetable farms) at two locations (Gatton and Stanthorpe) was examined amongst a suite of soil fertility indicators. The P status was similar between farming systems, in contrast to some broad-acre organic systems. Examination of farm management records revealed substantial overlap between P inputs at both localities with CF systems also receiving organic inputs, e.g. green manure and composts. A statistical analysis of the effects of different inputs also indicated that P fertility did not vary significantly between farms. Soil P levels were medium to high across farm types indicating a potential environmental risk for vegetable producers particularly in sandy well drained soils. The three methods of extraction Colwell, Olsen and Resin were well correlated with each other and produced similar results indicating the similar nutrient pools exist between farming system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9879/1/Nachimuthu-etal-2007-PhosphorousAustralia.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nachimuthu, Gunasekhar; Kristiansen, Paul; Lockwood, Peter and Guppy, Chris    (2007) Soil phosphorus status in organic and conventional vegetable farms in Southeast Queensland, Australia.       Poster at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9879/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>