<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Fulfilling 100% organic pig diets: Concentrates</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Crawley, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main dietary challenge for pig producers is ensuring that feed fulfills the nutrient requirements of pigs, in particular with regards to protein and the correct amino acid profile. This is a particular challenge for organic pig producers as the use of synthetic amino acids is not allowed. There has been a derogation from the EU Organic Regulatory Board to allow organic pig and poultry producers to include up to 5% non-organic feed within their rations to assist in meeting the nutritional requirements of the birds. This derogation was due to finish at the end of December 2014 but has now been extended to 31 December 2017 when it will become compulsory under EU Regulations (EC) no 889/2008 to provide all organic livestock with feed derived from 100% organic origins. This guide discusses the potential of locally-sourced protein sources as viable alternative ingredients in pig concentrate diets.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Research Centre</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Smith, Jo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Gerrard, Catherine L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sumption, Phil</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2015-01-19</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28087/7/28087.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Crawley, K.     (editor): Smith, Jo; Gerrard, Catherine L. and Sumption, Phil (Eds.)    (2015) Fulfilling 100% organic pig diets: Concentrates.   ICOPP Technical Notes, no. 3. Organic Research Centre.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28087/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>