<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Chemical composition and antibacterial potential of Artemisia arborescens L. essential oil.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Militello, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Settanni, L</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aleo, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mammina, C</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moschetti, G</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giammanco, G M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blàzquez, M Amparo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carrubba, A</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study was undertaken to characterize the essential oil (EO) of Artemisia arborescens growing wild in Sicily. EO, extracted by steam distillation, was examined for its chemical composition and for its capability to inhibit some food-borne pathogen bacteria. A total of 43 compounds (13 monoterpene hydrocarbons, 14 oxygenated monoterpenes, 10 sesquiterpene hydrocarbons, three oxygenated sesquiterpenes and less amount of other three compounds), which account 93.73% of the total oil, were identified by gas chromatography and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. Oxygenated monoterpenes (57.32%) constituted the main fraction, with β-thujone as the main compound (45.04%), followed by the sesquiterpene hydrocarbon chamazulene (22.71%). Undiluted EO showed a large inhibition spectrum against strains of Listeria monocytogenes (34 out of 44), whilst it was ineffective against enterobacteria and salmonellas. The minimum inhibition concentration (MIC) was evaluated for the two most sensitive strains (L. monocytogenes 186 and 7BO) at two cellular concentrations (10(6) and 10(7) CFU ml(-1)). The lowest MIC (0.625 μl ml(-1), dilution of oil with acetone) was found for strain L. monocytogenes 186 at 10(6) CFU ml(-1).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Militello, M; Settanni, L; Aleo, A; Mammina, C; Moschetti, G; Giammanco, G M; Blàzquez, M Amparo and Carrubba, A   (2011) Chemical composition and antibacterial potential of Artemisia arborescens L. essential oil.   Current microbiology, 62 (4), pp. 1274-1281.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20544/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>