<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Mechanische Bodenbelastung - Effekte auf Eigenschaften des Oberbodens und den Ertrag von Erbse in Reinsaat und im Gemenge</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wild, Melanie</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brandhuber, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gronle, Annkathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lux, Guido</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmidtke, Knut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Demmel, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic agriculture legumes build the basis of soil fertility. A diminution of the legumes´ performance not only restricts their own yield but also the yield of the whole crop rotation. However, legumes – especially peas – are strongly affected by soil-born diseases and react sensitively to soil compaction. Aim of the study is to gain knowledge about the interaction of differentiated soil compaction on soil physical parameters and the yield of peas in a sole- and mixed cropping system with oat. We conducted field trials at four different sites where plots were passed with a wheel load of 2.6 t and 4.6 t before seeding. Results show that bulk density in the topsoil increased significantly with increasing wheel load, while soil porosity decreased. Compaction with 4.6 t resulted in 19 % less yield compared to unpassed plots, which corresponds to 8 % less yield performance per hectare when assuming a tire of 650 mm width and a working width at sowing of 3 m.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21513/1/21513_Wild.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wild, Melanie; Böhm, Herwart; Brandhuber, Robert; Bruns, Christian; Gronle, Annkathrin; Lux, Guido; Schmidtke, Knut and Demmel, Markus    (2013) Mechanische Bodenbelastung - Effekte auf Eigenschaften des Oberbodens und den Ertrag von Erbse in Reinsaat und im Gemenge.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21513/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>