<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Züchterische Bearbeitung von Süßlupinen für den ökologischen Landbau – Erste Ergebnisse zu Ertrags- und Qualitätsuntersuchungen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jansen, Gisela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jürgens, Hans-Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuhlmann, Josy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flamme, Wilhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lupines will be provided as feeding stuff with high quality for the organic farming. Therefore breeding selection of lupines and a complex quality analysis are necessary. In addition to agronomical characteristics quality parameters are estimated, such as protein content, amino acid composition, fat, fatty acid composition, starch and sugar as well as antinutritive substances (non-starch polysaccharides and alkaloides). On the basis of determined data, NIR/NIT-calibrations are developed as breeding relevant methods. The project serves to both opening up and use of genetic resources and breeding of lupines suitable for ecological cultivation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3286/1/3286.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jansen, Gisela; Jürgens, Hans-Ulrich; Kuhlmann, Josy and Flamme, Wilhelm    (2005) Züchterische Bearbeitung von Süßlupinen für den ökologischen Landbau – Erste Ergebnisse zu Ertrags- und Qualitätsuntersuchungen.  [Breeding of lupines for the ecological farming – First results regarding yield and quality investigations.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3286/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>