<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparative analysis of the impacts of marketing instruments on the organic market in Austria, the United Kingdom and Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zenner, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Foster, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wirthgen, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conclusions:&#xD;
&#xD;
This paper provides a comparative analysis of the impacts of the marketing instruments: The price-level can be identified as an important factor for further development. To promote sustained consumer demand, the premium price-level should be closer to the conventional price, although consumers are willing to pay some premium. Organic produce is associated with healthy food, which may appeal to consumers interested in healthy nutrition. Nevertheless, producers, processors and retailers of organic food should bear in mind general trends in food consumption and create organic food with lifestyle-oriented design. In future, supermarkets will become the main retail outlets for organic produce. In order to compete with larger, mainstream retailers, outlets like organic food shops or direct marketing channels should concentrate on offering special and added values e.g. by offering locally/regionally produced food or by creating an environment which provides the consumer with a unique shopping experience. Promotion activities are extremely important in influencing consumer behaviour, therefore all those involved should invest in further promotion activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
(ZENNER, S., FOSTER, C., PADEL, S. und B. WIRTHGEN (2000): Comparative analysis of the impacts of marketing instruments on the organic market in Austria, the United Kingdom and Germany. In: ALFLÖDI, Th., LOCKERETZ, W. und U. NIGLI: Proceedings 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference. Zürich, S. 523)</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, Th.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/927/1/zenner-2000-impacts-of-marketing-instruments.PDF</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zenner, S.; Foster, C.; Padel, S. and Wirthgen, B.    (2000) Comparative analysis of the impacts of marketing instruments on the organic market in Austria, the United Kingdom and Germany.   In: Alföldi, Th.; Lockeretz, W. and Niggli, U. (Eds.)  Proceedings 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference, p. 523.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/927/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>