<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New eco-compatible technologies of durum wheat production: a case study on winter wheat living  mulch by sub clover in Southern Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>LI, Mrs Zhifang</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper reports the trial comparing N management in two crop systems: winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) living mulch with subclover (Trifolium subterraneum L.)  (field 1), and winter wheat pure standing with organic N fertilization  (field 2). Subclover is supposed to fix N2 and to release a part of it to wheat plants. Wheat grain yield in field 1 is 2227kg/ha, in field 2 is 2272kg/ha, with no statistically-significant difference (95% level). However, the wheat biomass accumulation at the start of heading in field 1 (2635kg/ha) is significantly lower than that in field 2 (3100kg/ha). NPK content in wheat plant tissue is also obviously lower in field 1 than in field 2 during the stem extension stage. Soil soluble N content in field 1 is also lower than that in field 2 in the same period. DRIS (Diagnosis and Recommendation Integrated System method) is applied to illustrate N deficiency in field 1. Although after heading soil N availability in field 1 is higher than that in field 2, final N accumulation in wheat biomass is still 15% lower than in field 2. Subclover grows slowly during the early spring, while after winter wheat heading, it grows fast from 137.2kg/ha dry weight to 508.7kg/ha in 15 days. Soil soluble N content in field 1 is also higher than in field 2 during this period. However, when wheat plants start heading, the biomass accumulation is already nearly 90% of maximum biomass yield.  Evidence shows that the effect from sub clover fixed N2 is lower.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6428/1/LiZhifang02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>LI, Mrs Zhifang   (2002) New eco-compatible technologies of durum wheat production: a case study on winter wheat living mulch by sub clover in Southern Italy.  [Nouvelles technologies éco-compatibles pour la production de blé dur: cas d’étude sur un mulching de trèfle souterrain dans une parcelle de blé en Italie du Sud.]  Thesis, IAMB - Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Agriculture. Tesi Master of Science, no. 273. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6428/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>