<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Merging Ethics and Economics: Modernizing Values in Viennese Farmers' Markets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klimek, Milena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The values, goals and mission statements described by FM managers and individual vendors have been examined to understand their role within FMs and how they may affect or what they may have to offer CA in Austria and Minnesota. Initially, the strong following of CA, sharing the values of the IFOAM normative principles, in Minnesota offers many possibilities to bolster popularity and support for small farmers through FMs. &#xD;
More specifically, Viennese farmers’ markets may be able to gather support for farmers and communities alike if FMs would be seen as independent entities from the more permanent Viennese markets. This would allow for a separate purpose with different goals and values influencing the markets daily actions. &#xD;
These comparative farmers’ market case studies permit the understanding of the logistics and values of farmers’ markets in two cities independent of each other and across two continents. Preliminarily, a lack of prevalent values and ethics in Viennese markets due to the predominant market governance structure lead to a fragmented identity and purpose. Conversely, disjointed governance structures in Minneapolis markets lead to confusion of regulations, yet a variety of values and ethics clearly influencing the markets. The shared knowledge of this research should help both researchers and farmers’ market managers to exchange information and ideas that may contribute to the success of FMs and ultimately support small farmers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24364/1/24364_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klimek, Milena and Freyer, Bernhard    (2014) Merging Ethics and Economics: Modernizing Values in Viennese Farmers' Markets.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 41-44.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24364/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>