<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Recent experiences in application of homeopathy in farm animals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fidelak, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Objectives&#xD;
This RCCT should assess the efficacy of a fixed homeopathic combination for therapy of bovine clinical mastitis in order to minimize the use of antibiotics.&#xD;
Methods&#xD;
In a German organic dairy herd of about 300 cows cases of clinical mastitis received a homeopathic therapy using a predetermined treatment protocol and a certain diagnostic pattern. For treatment of acute mastitis the following remedies were used: Phytolacca, Bryonia, Echinacea and Belladonna or Aconitum depending on body temperature. Chronic mastitis were treated by Echinacea, Phytolacca and Hepar sulfuris. While at first antibiotics were totally banned, in the second period therapy failures received an additional intramammary antibiotic therapy. Clinical (CCR), bacteriological (BACCR) and bacteriocytological (TOTCR) cure rates were evaluated by quarter foremilksamples on the day of return to production, 5 and 8 weeks after recovery.&#xD;
Results&#xD;
In the study 126 cows (Verum:n=60/ Placebo:n=66) were enrolled. Cure rates in both treatment groups were nearly identical. CCR was 73% immediately and 47% eight weeks after treatment. The 107 quarters bacteriological infected did not show differences in BACCR (p&gt;0.05) but in TOTCR in favour of homeopathy. The TOTCR after 8 weeks was 32 % compared to 13% (p&lt;0.05). The consecutive antibiotic therapy increased cure rates in both groups between 10%-20% on time of evaluation and stage of recovery. Although antibiotics were decreased to 27% compared to conventional mastitis therapy, udder health could be increased.&#xD;
Conclusion&#xD;
The results suggest that homoeopathically supported health concepts in organic dairy herds are suitable to decrease the antibiotics input dramatically without impairment of udder health.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>The Royal London Homoeopathic Hospital</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18007/1/paper_plenary_session_fidelak_2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fidelak, Christian    (2006) Recent experiences in application of homeopathy in farm animals.   In:     Proceedings of Improving the Success of Homeopathy 5 - A Global Perspective , The Royal London Homoeopathic Hospital, London, UK, pp. 59-63.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18007/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>