<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ORWINE: towards a European regulation for organic wine-making</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Micheloni, MSc Cristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project aims at solving the legislative problem of the lack of EU regulation on organic wine-making by producing a scientific data set to support the EU commission to develop the legislative framework. Data about currently applied practices, consumer and market needs in significant areas were gathered in all significant wine producing areas of EU and some new member states. Test series with suitable and innovative technologies to improve the quality of wines from organic viticulture, allowing using a low level of sulphites are conducted and validated on selected pilot wineries.  Moreover the results and regulatory proposals are discussed with a participatory approach with stakeholders on national levels as well as on European level, ensuring a high acceptance of the proposed legislative framework. Besides a code of best practices as well as a simplified environment assessment tool will be developed to give guidance to produce high quality wine while limiting the impact on the environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12921/1/EOC2007_micheloni-poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Micheloni, MSc Cristina    (2007) ORWINE: towards a European regulation for organic wine-making.       Poster at:   European Organic Congress, Brussels, 4-5 December 2007.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12921/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>