<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss von Euterinfektionen auf Enzymaktivitäten&#xD;
in Ziegenmilch in der Frühlaktation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stuhr, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Larsen, Torben</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At present the analysis of somatic cell count (SCC) used for the detection of intramammary infections in cows is also recommended for goats, but due to various factors influencing SCC it allows only limited conclusions on the udder health of goats. The aim of the present study was to investigate the influence of infection status on different milk enzyme activities and SCC throughout the early lactation. 60 dairy goats were sampled at weekly intervals over a period of six weeks after kidding and the bacteriological status, milk SCC and the activity of N-acetyl-ß-D-glucosaminidase (NAGase), ß-glucuronidase (ß-glu) and lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) of udder halves were analysed. The infection status had a highly significant effect on SCC, ß-glu and LDH activity, but ß-glu was not influenced by the stage of lactation. Therefore the usefulness of ß-glu in the assessment of udder health status should be further proved.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21449/1/21449_Aulrich.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aulrich, Karen; Barth, Kerstin; Stuhr, Tanja and Larsen, Torben    (2013) Einfluss von Euterinfektionen auf Enzymaktivitäten in Ziegenmilch in der Frühlaktation.       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21449/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>