<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sortenprüfung Kernobst für den biologischen Anbau</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art: &#xD;
World-wide there is very little cultivar testing of pipfruit under the conditions of organic farming. No rare there appropriate breeding programs on-going. Thus, knowledge is very scare. &#xD;
&#xD;
Definition of the problem: &#xD;
Pipfruit as apple and pears are difficult to produce organically. A key disease is scab (Venturia sp.); but also susceptibility to leaf spot disease, monilia, sooty blotch disease, aphids, insects, biennial bearing, cracking etc. are major problems to overcome with organically approved methods and products. Additionally, also organic pipfruit have to achieve the high and significantly increased expectations in terms of outer and inner quality. &#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims: &#xD;
To find apple and pear cultivars suited for organic production. &#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology: &#xD;
Precision trials are planted at FiBL in Frick (20 cultivars per series in an in-out-system; trees are planted in two blocks: “very extensive” with 3 x 2 trees and “with usual care” 2 x 5 trees. Tree-wise we measure yield, tree vigour, disease and aphid damage, standard fruit quality, storage ability. Each year we organize several sensorial blind tests with larger consumer groups. Some advanced cultivars are also under On-Farm observation at 5 sites in organic orchards of all important growing regions of Switzerland. Trials with pears have started in 2005 only (10 cultivars and selections, planted at FiBL and Aubonne, each with two blocks of 5 trees per cultivar). &#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art: &#xD;
Regularly we publish a list of recommended apple cultivars suited for organic production and professional retail. New concepts for marketing and variety introduction could be derived from these activities (e.g. the “Taste-Group Concept”; or the “Variety Team” concept). Thus, the project had and still has a clear and very direct influence on production and marketing of the organic apple branch in Switzerland. Pear trials were started in 2005.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Organic Pipfruit: Sortenprüfung Kernobst für den biologischen Anbau.  [Testing of pipfruit cultivars for organic production.]   Runs 1994 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Weibel, Franco and Suter, Francisco, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6291/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>