<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Physicochemical characteristics of organic honey samples of africanized honeybees from Paraná River islands.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Alves, Eloi Machado</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sereia, Maria Josiane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Toledo, Vagner de Alencar Arnaut de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marchini, Luis Carlos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Neves, Carolina Antunes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Toledo, Tiago Cleyton Simões de Oliveira Arnaut de</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anacleto, Daniela de Almeida</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This research was carried out to evaluate the physicochemical composition of organic honey in Paraná River islands, in Porto Brasílio, State of Paraná. Honey was harvested directly from super of the colonies in three apiaries spread in the Floresta and Laranjeira Islands, from August 2005 to August 2006. Twenty-four samples of organic honey produced by Africanized honeybees were evaluated. The following parameters were analyzed: pH, acidity, formol index, hydroxymethylfurfural, ashes, color, electric conductivity and moisture. Three replications per sample were performed for laboratorial analysis, giving the means and standard deviation. Most honey samples were in conformity with the Normative Instruction 11 from October 20, 2000. However, 4.17% were not in accordance with the moisture standards, 8.33% showed high concentrations of hydroxymethylfurfural, thus, totalizing 12.50% of non-complying samples. Nevertheless, 87.50% of the analyzed honey samples are within the standards, being characterized as an organic product of excellent quality, with good commercialization perspectives in the market.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22376/1/Alves_Physicochemical.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Alves, Eloi Machado; Sereia, Maria Josiane; Toledo, Vagner de Alencar Arnaut de; Marchini, Luis Carlos; Neves, Carolina Antunes; Toledo, Tiago Cleyton Simões de Oliveira Arnaut de and Anacleto, Daniela de Almeida   (2011) Physicochemical characteristics of organic honey samples of africanized honeybees from Paraná River islands.  [Características físico-químicas de mel orgânico de abelhas africanizadas produzido nas ilhas do Rio Paraná.]  Food Science and Technology (Campinas), 31 (3), pp. 635-639.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22376/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>