<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Socio-cultural processes behind the differential distribution of organic farming in Denmark - a case study</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Risgaard, Marie-Louise</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frederiksen, Pia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kaltoft, Pernille</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Conversion to organic farming, along with driving forces and barriers, has been explored intensively during the past decade, while studies on localization and impacts of local socio-cultural processes on conversion to and diffusion of organic farming have been scarce. Concentrations of organic farms in Denmark have been identified at the county level, and moreover there appeared to be large within-county variation in the density of organic farms. The present study explores the local aspects of conversion to organic farming and the factors that may help explain the variations in density and distribution of organic farms within smaller areas. The study is based on nine qualitative interviews with organic farmers from two neighboring areas, referred to as “mainland” and “island”. Three farms were situated in the high-density area (mainland) and the remaining six in the low-density area (island). Furthermore, five advisors with connections to the area provided information on their local experiences and perceptions. Three main issues – to some extent interacting – are discussed: The first is price of land, related to local scarcity of land in the context of structural development and the effects of agricultural policies. The second is distance – both physical and mental. Cooperation and exchange of experiences among organic farmers was frequent on the mainland side, while isolation and lack of interaction was more common for the island farmers. Thirdly, the role of the advisory service and the existence of “champion farmers” are important: pioneer farmers on the mainland have been supported by committed advisors, while lack of organic “champion farmers” and low priority granted to organic farming among advisors, were found on the island.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8520/1/8520.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Risgaard, Marie-Louise; Frederiksen, Pia and Kaltoft, Pernille   (2007) Socio-cultural processes behind the differential distribution of organic farming in Denmark - a case study.   Agriculture and Human Values, 24 (4), pp. 445-459.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8520/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>