<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The European Market for Organic Products: Growth and Development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Michelsen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wynen, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roth, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The European Market for organic food has been growing rapidly in terms of both supply and demand during the 1990s. However, national markets develop in many different directions. In some countries the market share ist quiet high while in others a market for organic farming products nearly does not exist. This book detects and compares the national markets of the main organic products in 18 European countries - the 15 EU countries plus Switzerland, Norway and the Czech Republic - on the basis of the most comprehensive collection of data ever presented covering the period 1993 - 1997/1998. It is shown that European demand is far from being satisfied and the major efforts in organising a transparent international market  and developing marketing strategies is necessary to realise this potential. &#xD;
This book is aimed at policy makers, the private sector, researchers and students in the field of economics and politics of organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universität Hohenheim - Stuttgart Hohenheim</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1999</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8486/1/Organic_Farming_in_Europe_Volume07_The_European_Market_for_Organic_Products_Growth_and_Development.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Michelsen, J.; Hamm, U.; Wynen, E. and Roth, E.    (1999) The European Market for Organic Products: Growth and Development.    Organic Farming In Europe: Economics and Policy, no. Vol. 7. Universität Hohenheim - Stuttgart Hohenheim.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8486/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>