<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming Training and needs of stakeholders (Teachers and advisers); Status and proposals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>MORIN, J.-M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cresson, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bordeaux, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thomas, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The work carried out made it possible to better understand the devices of training, the knowledge of the training and development stakeholders, their expectations in the domainof organic farming. If the general principles and techniques of organic farming are fairly well known, their variation in practice is not easily normative. The courses, primarily based on knowledge transfer, are not very effective and the surveyed actors highlighted the value of networks and non-formal trainings. Proposals for changing devices are presented being based on such an innovative action in the Loire Valley with teachers and trainers. The issue of the integration of e-learning in these devices is presented with its potentialsand limits. The issue of educational resources concerning their format, their contents as the media used and their accessibility is addressed with proposals based on Swiss and the Loire Valley achievements.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26326/1/Morin_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>MORIN, J.-M.; Cresson, C.; Bordeaux, C. and Thomas, P.   (2013) Organic Farming Training and needs of stakeholders (Teachers and advisers); Status and proposals.  [Offre de formation sur l’AB et besoins des acteurs de la formation et du développement : Etat des lieux et propositions.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 139-148.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26326/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>