<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Trophobiosis Theory: A Pest Starves on a Healthy Plant</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Pests shun healthy plants. Pesticides weaken plants. Weakened plants open the door to pests and disease. Hence pesticides precipitate pest attack and disease susceptibility, and thus they induce a cycle of further pesticide use. &#xD;
&#xD;
This is the essence of Trophobiosis Theory, a thesis presented by Francis Chaboussou, an agronomist of the France’s National Institute of Agricultural Research (INRA), in “Healthy Crops: A New Agricultural Revolution”. After two decades, this important book is finally available in English.&#xD;
&#xD;
Plant pathologist Chaboussou (b.1908 - d.1985) saw with a clear eye that just as there are iatrogenic, doctor-caused, medical problems, likewise there are agrogenic, farmer-caused, agricultural problems. Chaboussou offers a lifetime’s insight into his vision for an agriculture without pesticides, and in so doing he offers a scientific underpinning for organic and bio-dynamic agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bio_Dynamics Tasmania Inc.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Domeney, Penny</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12894/1/12894.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2007) Trophobiosis Theory: A Pest Starves on a Healthy Plant.   Elementals - Journal of Bio-Dynamics Tasmania, 88, pp. 20-24.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12894/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>