<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic wheat quality from a defined Italian field-trial</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kokornaczyk, Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, Dr. Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roose, Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Busscher, Dr. Nicolaas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ploeger, Prof. Dr. Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic and conventional wheat grain (Triticum aestivum and Triticum durum) samples coming from a defined field trial in Italy were measured in 2005 and 2006 for their total protein content and the contents of lutein and zeaxanthin. Additionally the samples were analyzed by means of the biocrystallization method. The grain samples could be differentiated by the total protein content, which was higher in the conventional samples. The organic samples contained a higher lutein content in Triticum aestivum but lower in Triticum durum. Biocrystallization differentiated Triticum durum from Triticum aestivum and organic from conventional grown samples when visual evaluation was applied. Differentiation of farming systems was possible for biocrystallization evaluated with computerized texture analysis but not significant for all samples and years.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11732/1/Kokornaczyk_11732_rev.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kokornaczyk, Maria; Kahl, Dr. Johannes; Roose, Marco; Busscher, Dr. Nicolaas and Ploeger, Prof. Dr. Angelika    (2008) Organic wheat quality from a defined Italian field-trial.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11732/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>