<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleichende Querschnittsuntersuchungen zum Vorkommen von MRSA (Methicillin-resistente Staphylococcus aureus) in ökologisch wirtschaftenden und konventionell wirtschaftenden Schweinebetrieben in Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heine , Ulrike</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sommer , Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meemken , Dr. Diana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werner, Dr. Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Blaha, Prof. Dr. Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Occurrence of MRSA was assessed on 42 organic and 88 conventional pig herds in different regions of Germany by taking dust samples and nasal swabs. The number of nasal swabs was adapted to the herd size so that a MRSA-prevalence of 5 % could be detected. All samples were selectively enriched and cultured on MRSA-selective chromagar. All cultured isolates were confirmed by PCR. In addition, the spa-types were identified. The results of this cross-sectional study showed that 11 of the 42 (26%) examined organic pig herds were identified as MRSA-positive, whereas 92 % of the conventional pig herds were identified as MRSA-positive. In both husbandry systems, similar spa-types (t011, t034) were identified, which are associated with the MRSA ST398. To find out the specific risk factors for the occurrence of MRSA in pig herds questionnaires were used in both husbandry systems and will be evaluated in the second part of this ongoing study.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17575/3/Heine_17575.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heine , Ulrike; Sommer , Hendrik; Meemken , Dr. Diana; Werner, Dr. Christina; Sundrum, Prof. Dr. Albert and Blaha, Prof. Dr. Thomas    (2011) Vergleichende Querschnittsuntersuchungen zum Vorkommen von MRSA (Methicillin-resistente Staphylococcus aureus) in ökologisch wirtschaftenden und konventionell wirtschaftenden Schweinebetrieben in Deutschland.  [Occurrence of MRSA in organic pig herds in comparison to conventional pig herds.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17575/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>