<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labile phosphorus forms in irrigated and rain-fed semiarid Mediterranean grassy crops with long-term organic and conventional farming practices.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Romamyà, Joan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rovira, Pere</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The availability of organic fertilisers plays a major role in organic farming systems. Such systems exclude the use of synthetic fertilisers, whilst&#xD;
aiming to optimise internal nutrient cycling. The low availability of manures, particularly in dry areas, can lead to negative nutrient balances inmany&#xD;
organic farming systems. Such negative nutrient balances are mainly found for P and K. In this paper,we aim to study the availability of P in irrigated&#xD;
and rainfed semiarid Mediterranean grassy crops with long-term organic and conventional farming practices. NaHCO3 extracts were prepared from&#xD;
an array of soils from 16 plots, covering organic and conventional management in rainfed and irrigated conditions. Inorganic (NaHCO3-Pi) and&#xD;
organic P (NaHCO3-Po) were analysed in the extracts and related to soil properties (carbonate content, pH, organic C and N content). Rainfed,&#xD;
organically managed soils showed low P availability compared to conventionally managed soils. However, organically managed irrigated soils&#xD;
showed slightly higher NaHCO3-Pi than conventional soils. This is due to the fertilisation regime applied to the irrigated, organically managed&#xD;
systems. Such systems received four-fold the amount of manure applied to organically managed rainfed soils. In soils with low P availability,&#xD;
NaHCO3-Pi was largely depleted while NaHCO3-Po remained nearly unchanged. In soils with good or moderate P availability, NaHCO3-Pi&#xD;
appeared mainly to be regulated by soil organic matter (organic C and N). In conditions of low P availability, NaHCO3-Pi was mainly regulated by&#xD;
chemical processes related to soil pH and carbonate content. The regulation of NaHCO3-Po was less clear. Under low P availability, NaHCO3-Pi&#xD;
depletion occurred mainly in soils with high organic C and N and low pH. In low P soils with a high pH and carbonate content, NaHCO3-Pi&#xD;
appeared to be geochemically protected. In calcareous soils, management practices need to increase or maintain the level of soil organic C to&#xD;
facilitate mobilisation of the P reserve.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11486/1/Labile_phosphorus_forms_in_irrigated_and_rainfed_semiarid_Mediterranean_grassy_crops_with_long-term_organic_or_conventional_farming_practices.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Romamyà, Joan  and Rovira, Pere    (2007) Labile phosphorus forms in irrigated and rain-fed semiarid Mediterranean grassy crops with long-term organic and conventional farming practices.   European Journal of Agronomy, 27, pp. 62-71.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11486/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>