<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Organic Market in Switzerland and the EU - Overview and market access information for producers and international trading companies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Khanna, Ranjana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, Beate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richter, Toralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Staubli, Franziska</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic market is highly diverse. Production standards and certification and trade rules place considerable demands upon market participants. At the same time, this market holds out excellent opportunities for creative and circumspect producers, processors and traders. To operate successfully in organic import and export business alike, it is crucial to have accurate information on the potential of the specific organic market and on the conditions governing market access. The attractively designed handbook offers the very latest market information for producers an international trading companies, organized both by product group an by country on 80 pages. This second edition is updated in all chapters and has in addition three new markets: Austria, Italy and Sweden. In addition, the handbook provides an easily accessible overview of the - in some instances - quite complicates - import requirements applicable in Switzerland and the EU. In a further 50-page appendix, the handbook contains an extensive collection of addresses (trading companies, authorities, certification bodies, organizations etc.) and Internet Websites. The second edition of this handbook has been produced in English.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FiBL Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau, SIPPO Swiss Import Promotion Programme</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2607/2/kilcher-et-al-2004-bestellcoupon.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/2607/3/kilcher-et-al-2004-sippo-handbuch.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kilcher, Lukas; Khanna, Ranjana; Huber, Beate; Richter, Toralf; Schmid, Otto and Staubli, Franziska    (2004) The Organic Market in Switzerland and the EU - Overview and market access information for producers and international trading companies.     FiBL Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau, SIPPO Swiss Import Promotion Programme.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/2607/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>