<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Grundlagenforschung zur Wirkung potenzierter Substanzen auf Zwergerbsen (Pisum sativum) und Wasserlinsen (Lemna gibba)</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
Currently there is a lack of scientific proof of the effect of homeopathic potencies. Reproducing results of homeopathic studies is often difficult. There are no established controls for the quality of homeopathic potencies and the production of homeopathic remedies.&#xD;
&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Which factors influence the effect of homeopathic potencies on the growth of duckweed and dwarf peas?&#xD;
&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
To develop reproducible test systems to investigate questions of homeopathic basic research.&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
Blinded studies with systematic negative controls under controlled laboratory conditions. Measured parameters: growth (area, length).&#xD;
&#xD;
Results, conclusion, state of the art:&#xD;
Reproduction of the experiments of Claudia Scherr, which showed significant effects of potentised plant hormones on duckweeds. Experiments on the influence of seed quality of dwarf peas for their suitability as test organisms for homeopathic potencies.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6292/1/fibl-projekt-tiergesundheit-homoeopathika.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Grundlagenforschung zur Wirkung potenzierter Substanzen auf Zwergerbsen (Pisum sativum) und Wasserlinsen (Lemna gibba).  [Basic research into the effect of potentised substances on growth of duckweed and dwarf peas.]   Runs 2005 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Majewsky, Vera, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6292/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>