<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Modelling the ability of legumes to suppress weeds</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Storkey, Jonathan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Thomas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baddeley, J. A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marshall, Athole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jones, Hannah</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The ability of different legume cover crops to suppress annual weeds during the early establishment phase was compared using a simulation model of inter-plant competition and field observations. Height, partitioning parameters, extinction coefficients, crop density and time of emergence were recorded for 11 species sown in monocultures. A naturally occurring population of fat hen (Chenopodium album) was present on the experiment. The competition model was run to compare the expected suppressive ability of the different species on this weed. Samples of C. album were also taken from each plot immediately prior to cutting to provide some empirical observations. Predicted suppressive ability was correlated with seed size and height with large seeded, tall species such as white sweet clover being the most competitive. However, these species may recover poorly from mowing compromising their potential to suppress perennial weeds and a mixture of contrasting species may provide the optimum weed control.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19881/1/2011.Storkey_et_al.AAB.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Storkey, Jonathan; Döring, Thomas F.; Baddeley, J. A.; Marshall, Athole; Roderick, S. and Jones, Hannah   (2011) Modelling the ability of legumes to suppress weeds.   Aspects of Applied Biology , 109, pp. 53-58.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19881/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>