<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>An integrated simulation model to evaluate national policies for the abatement of agricultural nutrients in the Baltic Sea</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hyyti채inen, Kari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ahtiainen, Heini</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heikkil채, Jaakko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Helin, Janne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huhtala, Anni</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Iho, Antti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koikkalainen, Kauko</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miettinen, Antti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pouta, Eija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vesterinen, Janne</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study introduces a prototype model for evaluating policies to abate agricultural nutrients in the Baltic Sea from a Finnish national point of view. The stochastic simulation model integrates nutrient dynamics of nitrogen and phosphorus in the sea basins adjoining the Finnish coast, nutrient loads from land and other sources, benefits from nutrient abatement (in the form of recreation and other ecosystem services) and the costs of agricultural abatement activities. The aim of this study is to present the overall structure of the model and to demonstrate its potential using preliminary parameters.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15726/1/DP2009_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hyyti채inen, Kari; Ahtiainen, Heini; Heikkil채, Jaakko; Helin, Janne; Huhtala, Anni; Iho, Antti; Koikkalainen, Kauko; Miettinen, Antti; Pouta, Eija and Vesterinen, Janne   (2009) An integrated simulation model to evaluate national policies for the abatement of agricultural nutrients in the Baltic Sea.   MTT Discussion Papers (2), pp. 1-30.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15726/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>