<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Rübsen (Brassica rapa var. silvestris) als Fangpflanze zur Kontrolle von Schadinsekten in Winterraps</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Döring, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wedemeyer, Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Saucke, Helmut</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ulber, Bernd</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Previous studies have shown that most of the specialized rape pests prefer turnip rape over oilseed rape. In our studies two trap crop strategies were tested under field conditions in central Germany. In the first trial a turnip rape (Brassica rapa var. silvestris) strip was sown along the edges of the oilseed rape (Brassica napus) main crop. In the second trial a seed mixture of 95% oilseed rape and 5% turnip rape was sown and was compared to oilseed rape in pure crop. In both experiments the turnip rape trap crop was more attractive to cabbage stem flea beetle (Psylliodes chrysocephala) and pollen beetle (Meligethes aeneus) than the oilseed rape. Neither the border strip nor the intercropping was able to reduce the level of infestation of the oilseed rape crop and the damage caused by these pests. Both strategies were inapplicable to increase the grain yield of oilseed rape.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17444/3/Doering_17444.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Döring, Alexander; Wedemeyer, Rainer; Saucke, Helmut and Ulber, Bernd    (2011) Rübsen (Brassica rapa var. silvestris) als Fangpflanze zur Kontrolle von Schadinsekten in Winterraps.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 16.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17444/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>