<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Beschäftigung von Menschen mit Behinderung in der Landwirtschaft – die Rolle der Vernetzung mit „Grünen“ Werkstätten für behinderte Menschen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Baumgart, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flake, Albrecht</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The cooperation and link of “Workshops for Adapted Work” with actors from a respective region is an important issue in socio and regional politics because it can improve the inclusion of employees with disabilities and can create new possibilities of composite farm income. Our research investigates the prospects and conditions of such cooperation in a case study approach with four Workshops within Germany. In this survey we applied qualitative and quantitative methods of social sciences and investigated different stakeholders: disabled people (employees), farmers / entrepreneurs as (potential) employers and managers of such Workshops as experts. The data analysis includes descriptive statistics, content analysis and the Delphi method. The results will be published in a manual for Workshops and shall foster innovations in rural development and social services.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17687/6/Baumgart_17687.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Baumgart, Lukas and Flake, Albrecht    (2011) Beschäftigung von Menschen mit Behinderung in der Landwirtschaft – die Rolle der Vernetzung mit „Grünen“ Werkstätten für behinderte Menschen.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17687/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>