<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Conservation of livestock genetic resources by targeted on-farm management: a case study of Hinterwälder Cattle in the Southern Black Forest</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wanke, Diethild</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boehncke, Engelhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference. All EU countries are obliged to conserve livestock genetic resources (UN Convention on Biological Diversity, Rio, 1992). In-situ conservation is regarded as the most favourable approach. For rare and endangered livestock breeds extensive and organic farming systems seem appropriate. Council Regulation (EC) No 1804/1999 on organic farming recommends keeping indigenous breeds and strains that have adapted to local conditions. This project analyses the current situation and develops future scenarios for Hinterwälder farms. Aspects of farm structure, housing system, marketing concept, farm viability as well as environmental services and social factors were analysed in an interdisciplinary approach. Here, we summarise the analysis and concentrate on “Conversion to organic farming“ as one option. More than 30 % of Hinterwälder farms produce to EU organic standard, and a further 60 % could easily convert as they already fulfil the criteria for extensification grants. But most farms cannot achieve sufficient prices even for organic products. Moreover, investment in animal housing would be required to meet the organic standard. Enhancing farm viability is essential for conservation of Hinterwälder cattle, but many of the social and environmental services are beyond the reach of the market mechanism. Policy makers in particular are asked therefore to take a much wider interpretation of farming and the countryside.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8414/1/wanke_boehncke_livestock_genetic_resources.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wanke, Diethild and Boehncke, Engelhard    (2002) Conservation of livestock genetic resources by targeted on-farm management: a case study of Hinterwälder Cattle in the Southern Black Forest.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 237-242.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8414/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>