<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A critique of methodologies for the comparison of organic and conventional farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lee, Howard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fowler, Susan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper was presented at the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference of the Colloquium of Organic Researchers (COR).&#xD;
A review is presented of comparative studies of organic and conventional farming systems, with a special focus upon economic criteria. The different categories of comparison methodologies are critically reviewed. Conclusions are that classic experimentation has a valuable part to play but that more qualitative assessment can also be useful and should be encouraged. Careful allowance should be made for major background differences in management when comparing financial profitability. Longer term case studies, which try to monitor organic systems in their own right, should also be encouraged.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Powell, Jane</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>et al.,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8234/1/lee_fowler_system_comparison_methodologies.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lee, Howard and Fowler, Susan    (2002) A critique of methodologies for the comparison of organic and conventional farming systems.   In: Powell, Jane and et al.,  (Eds.)  Proceedings of the UK Organic Research 2002 Conference, Organic Centre Wales, Institute of Rural Studies, University of Wales Aberystwyth, pp. 281-284.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8234/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>