<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effectiveness of winter treatments with copper or lime sulphur to control Sooty Blotch on apple.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trapman, Marc</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 2002 and 2003 two randomized trials and three “on farm” trials where carried out&#xD;
to test the hypothesis that a single winter treatment could reduce the primary&#xD;
inoculum of Sooty Blotch sufficiently to prevent fruit disease during summer.&#xD;
copperoxychloride (0.2%-0.4%) and lime sulfur (4.0%-5.0%) were applied until run-off&#xD;
in March shortly before bud break. Assessments of Sooty Blotch incidence and&#xD;
severity where made immediately after harvest.&#xD;
The winter treatments with copperoxychloride did reduce disease severity during&#xD;
summer in one case. The treatments with lime sulfur reduced the disease level in&#xD;
three sites to some extent. However, winter treatments alone were not nearly as&#xD;
efficient as summer treatments. Therefore, we see no reason to advise this kind of&#xD;
treatment with lime sulfur in practice as the effectiveness is poor, the necessary&#xD;
spray cover can not be reached under practical conditions, and with the amount of&#xD;
material needed for this single spray five sprays can be made in summer that will be&#xD;
more effective to control the disease.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14075/1/12_Trapman_67_72.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trapman, Marc; Tamm, Lucius and Fuchs, Jacques G.    (2004) The effectiveness of winter treatments with copper or lime sulphur to control Sooty Blotch on apple.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 67-72.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14075/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>