<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Trout Ova/Fry also available from Danish Hatcheries</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jokumsen, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One year ahead of the deadline for implementation of complete organic aquaculture life cycle - organic ova/fry is available from danish hatcheries.According to the EU Regulation on Organic Aquaculture, the fish production shall exclusively be based on organic fry from 2016. Particularly, in organic farming, medication is only allowed within very strict limits. Therefore, the robustness of the fry to diseases is crucial. Especially, this concerns the most serious trout fry disease in Danish aquaculture, Rainbow Trout Fry Syndrome (RTFS). The robustness of the fry seems to be related to larval developmental rate and to the dietary content of specific Ω-3 fatty acids (HUFAs). Therefore  a recently launched project Robustfish are going to perform stress and RTFS tests to investigate if these two factors can be included in strategies to increase the robustness of the fry. Further, the effect on health and welfare of water treatments using approved agents in organic aquaculture is tested. RobustFish will create growth – based on organic principles and in a balance between environment, ethics and economy. However, the efforts will as well improve the productivity of the conventional trout farming by lower prevalence of RTFS, reduced medication and lower environmental impact. Connected to these efforts RobustFish also will provide needed knowledge about market conditions and consumer attitudes, including the competitive effect of increased production. Mapping the existing types of organic aquaculture products in European markets will pave the way for product development and increasing the Danish market share.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28635/6/28635.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jokumsen, Alfred     (2015) Organic Trout Ova/Fry also available from Danish Hatcheries.  [Økologiske ørredæg/yngel er også tilgængelig fra danske klækkerier.]  Aquaculture Europe, March 2015, 40 (1), pp. 27-36.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28635/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>