<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>ANIMAL HUSBANDARY PRACTICES OF SMALLHOLDER ORGANIC FARMERS IN UGANDA: CHALLENGES AND FUTURE PROSPECTS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nalubwama, Sylvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, Mette</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kabi, Fred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kiggundu , Muhammad</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Ninety certified organic pineapple producers were interviewed using a semi-structured questionnaire in Luwero and Kayung districts in Uganda. Data was analysed using statistical package for Social Scientists (SPSS). Results indicated that most organic farmers (81.1%) kept mostly cattle in combination with others species (goats, pigs and chickens). There was no significant difference (P&gt;0.05) in the numbers of pigs, poultry and chickens owned per farm in the two districts but there was significant difference (p=0.017) in the numbers of cattle. 62% of the farmers had indigenous breeds of cattle, 97.8% had goats, 87.5% had pigs and 100% of farmers had indigenous chickens. Crop residues formed bulk of feed for cattle (63.2%) and pigs (46%). Goats mostly depended on natural pastures (39.8%) and chickens were left to scavenge. Tethering was the most common grazing system in ruminants and pigs. Major challenges for livestock production were insufficient feeds and diseases mainly helminthes and tick borne diseases. Farmers had coping strategies including use of crop residues and herbal concoctions. However, most of farmers relied on use of conventional chemical and drugs in disease outbreaks.&#xD;
The future prospects of integrated organic systems and development of organic livestock production lies in research developing sustainable solutions suitable for organic systems. In addition to organic farmers giving more focus to livestock production for purposes of producing quality animal products for niche organic markets, household nutrition and improving on crop production. Government and private sector needs to consider investment in infrastructural development, improving farmer’s knowledge and providing appropriate inputs.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23794/1/23794%20Final%20IFOAM%20congress%20paper_Sylvia_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nalubwama, Sylvia; Vaarst, Mette; Kabi, Fred and Kiggundu , Muhammad    (2014) ANIMAL HUSBANDARY PRACTICES OF SMALLHOLDER ORGANIC FARMERS IN UGANDA: CHALLENGES AND FUTURE PROSPECTS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1123-1126.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23794/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>