<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Environmental risk assessment of genetically modified plants - concepts and controversies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hilbeck, Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Meier, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Römbke, Jörg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jänsch, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Teichmann, Hanka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tappeser, Beatrix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background and purpose: In Europe, the EU Directive 2001/18/EC lays out the main provisions of environmental risk assessment (ERA) of genetically modified (GM) organisms that are interpreted very differently by different stakeholders. The purpose of this paper is to: (a) describe the current implementation of ERA of GM plants in the EU and its scientific shortcomings, (b) present an improved ERA concept through the integration of a previously developed selection procedure for identification of non-target testing organisms into the ERA framework as laid out in the EU Directive 2001/18/EC and its supplement material (Commission Decision 2002/623/EC), (c) describe the activities to be carried out in each component of the ERA and (d) propose a hierarchical testing scheme. Lastly, we illustrate the outcomes for three different crop case examples.&#xD;
Main features: Implementation of the current ERA concept of GM crops in the EU is based on an interpretation of the EU regulations that focuses almost exclusively on the isolated bacteria-produced novel proteins with little consideration of the whole plant. Therefore, testing procedures for the effect assessment of GM plants on non-target organisms largely follow the ecotoxicological testing strategy developed for pesticides. This presumes that any potential adverse effect of the whole GM plant and the plant-produced novel compound can be extrapolated from testing of the isolated bacteriaproduced novel compound or can be detected in agronomic field trials. This has led to persisting scientific criticism.&#xD;
Results: Based on the EU ERA framework, we present an improved ERA concept that is system oriented with the GM plant at the centre and integrates a procedure for selection of testing organisms that do occur in the receiving environment. We also propose a hierarchical testing scheme from laboratory studies to field trials and we illustrate the outcomes for three different crop case examples.&#xD;
Conclusions and recommendations: Our proposed concept can alleviate a number of deficits identified in the current approach to ERA of GM plants. It allows the ERA to be tailored to the GM plant case and the receiving environment.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24705/1/Hilbeck-etal-2011-EnvironSciEu-23-13-p1-12.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hilbeck, Angelika; Meier, Matthias; Römbke, Jörg; Jänsch, Stephan; Teichmann, Hanka and Tappeser, Beatrix   (2011) Environmental risk assessment of genetically modified plants - concepts and controversies.   Environmental Sciences Europe, 23 (13), pp. 1-12.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24705/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>