<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Efficacy and Pertinence 01 Heat Treatments against Monilia Decay in Commerciai Condition</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Warlop, Franç,ois</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Post-harvest decay can lead to very important damages on stone fruits. especially in the Rhone valley.&#xD;
Hot water treatments are known to be efficient against many fruit pathogens including monilia, but industriai application remains difficult, since it can present some risks according to fruit maturity, thermostat accuracy of the engine&#xD;
We went on trying this alternative on peach decay, by testing a prototype lend by Xeda, in a professional station.&#xD;
Several parameters were to be evaluated : temperature and length of treatment, relation between both, container emptying, application of treatment period&#xD;
At the sa me time, we intended to assess eugenol (essenti al oil of clover) efficacy when added in hot water, for different concentrations, up to phytotoxicity.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14600/1/warlop_57.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Warlop, Franç,ois    (2002) Efficacy and Pertinence 01 Heat Treatments against Monilia Decay in Commerciai Condition.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, p. 57.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14600/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>