<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer Attitude and Behaviour towards Organic Food: Cross-cultural study of Turkey and Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mutlu, Nihan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic food market is very challenging in Europe and developing rapidly with&#xD;
different rates between western and eastern part. Consumers have raised great interest to&#xD;
healthy and tasty diet with high nutritional compounds, confidence in food safety,&#xD;
environmental and animal welfare concern and also sustainability. This paper presents&#xD;
cross-cultural results for organic food consumers in Turkey and Germany. Quantitative&#xD;
data is collected by survey method consisting of structured questions which are only&#xD;
targeted to organic consumers in both countries and analysed with SPPS 13 for&#xD;
Windows statistical data package.&#xD;
Results shows that, in Turkish consumers’ age is lower, household and children number&#xD;
is higher and gender is more equally distributed than Germany. Similarly, both&#xD;
consumers have high level of education and belonging to middle income groups. In&#xD;
contrast, Germans have more experiences with organic food and buying frequency is&#xD;
more than Turkey. Majority of the Turkish and German respondents thought that&#xD;
organic food is healthy, contain high nutritional value and have positive image about&#xD;
organic production methods. Certification as a compulsion is not well known among&#xD;
Germans, whereas, Turkish people have more problems in label recognition.&#xD;
Both in Germany and Turkey, supermarkets and organic retail shops will be the most&#xD;
preferred places and fresh fruits and vegetables will maintain their importance in the&#xD;
future market. Matured German market is not expecting big demand differences&#xD;
between products, whereas, some product categories especially meat products will&#xD;
burst-up in Turkish market. Cross-cultural consumer study shows that “heath” and&#xD;
“supporting organic movement and sustainability” are similarly standing on the top&#xD;
three places in the motivation list for Turkey and Germany, whereas high price and lack&#xD;
of availability reported as ruling barriers but with different degree of importance.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13727/1/MasterThesis-ConsumerStudy-TR-DE.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13727/2/MasterThesis-ConsumerStudy-TR-DE-presentation.ppt</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mutlu, Nihan   (2007) Consumer Attitude and Behaviour towards Organic Food: Cross-cultural study of Turkey and Germany.   Thesis, University of Hohenheim, Institute for Agricultural Policy and Markets.  .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13727/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>