<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic tree propagation under Welsh nursery conditions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Frost, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clarke, Aldwyn</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ornamentals, flower bulbs and tree nurseries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The demand for organically raised tree and hedging plants had been reported from organic farmers in Tir Gofal, as well as within the landscaping industry. Although there are a number of plant raising nurseries producing organically raised plants for vegetable and fruit production, there are no tree nurseries producing to organic standards. Nursery tree growers were concerned that there was currently too little known about the performance of tree seedlings in organic substrates (e.g. in root-trainers), nor about the nutrient supply to seedlings under organic regimes, nor about diseases control (especially fungal diseases such as mildew).&#xD;
Therefore, the development of three hedging species; Hawthorn, Hazel, Blackthorn, were tested for two growing systems in five different composts types; Ystwyth nursery mix, Peat based, Peat free based, Wood chip based, Organically certified green waste based.  The results of these trials are reported here.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11077/1/organictreepropagation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Frost, David and Clarke, Aldwyn         (2007) Organic tree propagation under Welsh nursery conditions.    Organic Centre Wales, ADAS Pwllpeiran, University of Wales, Aberystwyth.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11077/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>