<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic and healthy food strategies in schools&#xD;
-Separate strategies or two sides of the same coin?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project is a part of the iPOPY research project funded through the European Research Area program Core Organic I. &#xD;
The poster presents a study of the following hypothesis: Organic food service praxis/policy (POP) is associated with praxis/policies for healthier eating in Danish school food service. In other words, we wanted to test if organic procurement policies and the resulting praxis in schools can help to establish healthier eating habits among pupils  as compared to schools without organic  policies/praxis. &#xD;
A former study in Danish primary schools has shown that there is an association between organic school food policies and indicators (proxies) for healthy eating among children when (school food coordinators') statements on indicators (proxies) for healthy eating are used as variable. This project continues to search for the above signs  of associations but involving also a “bottom” level (pupils') perspective in addition to the “top” level (school food coordinators). &#xD;
The last perspective is going to be studied in a comparative study design where the Danish case (existing data from WBQ) will be compared with new data from school food service in Germany, Italy and Finland. These data is  collected through a web survey.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-11-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/vnd.ms-powerpoint</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17130/1/Poster.ppt</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>He, Chen    (2009) Organic and healthy food strategies in schools -Separate strategies or two sides of the same coin?       Poster at:   FOOD Denmark Congress 2009: A Career within Innovation?, DTU (Technical University of Denmark), Lyngby.      [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17130/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>