<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>High damage potential of seed-borne spot blotch in organically grown spring barley in Denmark</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pinnschmidt, Hans O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Bent J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Henrik J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Spot blotch of barley (Bipolaris sorokiniana, perfect state: Cochliobolus sativus) occurs wherever barley is grown but is normally not considered a major problem in Danish barley production. It is therefore not included in routine disease surveys or official variety testing in Denmark. However, recommended seed contamination thresholds are 30% for spring barley and 15% for winter barley. Several spring barley varieties were grown under organic (no seed dressing, mechanical weeding) and conventional (seed dressing with fungicides, herbicide application) production conditions at three sites in Denmark in 2003. The harvested seeds were analysed for contamination levels of seed-borne B. sorokiniana using a blotter method. The percentage of seeds contaminated with B. sorokiniana ranged from about 5 to 95 % and was highly depending on the site, production system and variety. Contamination levels of organically cultivated plots were about twice as high as those of plots receiving conventional treatments. The germinating ability of seeds was highly affected by the level of B. sorokiniana contamination and declined drastically at contamination levels above 60%. This effect appeared to differ among varieties. The 1000-grain weight was not affected by the level of spot blotch contamination of seeds. The results indicate that the importance of spot blotch may be underrated, especially in organic barley production and that the role of varietal resistance should be investigated. More results are expected from ongoing seed analyses.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DARCOF</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4740/1/4740.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pinnschmidt, Hans O.; Nielsen, Bent J. and Hansen, Henrik J.   (2005) High damage potential of seed-borne spot blotch in organically grown spring barley in Denmark.   DARCOFenews (1).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4740/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>