<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sortenprüfung Steinobst für den biologischen Anbau</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art: World-wide there is very little cultivar testing of stone fruit under organic conditions. Neither are there appropriate breading programs on-going. Thus, knowledge is very scare.&#xD;
&#xD;
Stone fruit as cherries, plums and apricots are very difficult to produce organically. A key disease is Monilia sp. Further problems to overcome are susceptibility to leaf spot disease, aphids, insects, cracking etc. Additionally organic stone fruit, too, has  to achieve the high and significantly changed market expectations (bigger and crisper fruit).&#xD;
&#xD;
The project aim is to find cherry (sweet and sour) and plum cultivars suited for organic production.&#xD;
&#xD;
Methodology: Precision trials are planted at Stone-Fruit Center Breitenhof of Agroscope Wädenswil at CH-Wintersingen. 15 cultivars of sweet cherry, 8 of sour cherry and 12 plum cultivars; 4 replicates. Some advanced cherry and plum cultivars are also under On-Farm observation. Apricots are evaluated only under On-Farm conditions in commercial organic orchards in canton Vallais.&#xD;
&#xD;
Results &amp; conclusion: Only few of 15 sweet cherry cultivars (new selections and old traditional varieties) show a potential for organic production (Julka and FAW 1075). Confirmation and On-Farm trials are going to be installed.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Organic Stone fruit: Sortenprüfung Steinobst für den biologischen Anbau.  [Testing of stone fruit cultivars for organic production.]   Runs 1999 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Weibel, Franco; Häseli, Andi and Tschabold, Jean-Luc, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6290/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>