<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A modelling framework for assessing adaptive management options of Finnish agricultural systems to climate change</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rötter, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehtonen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palosuo, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salo, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Helin , J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahiluoto, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aakkula, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Granlund, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rankinen, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carter, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Agrifood systems need to adapt to cope with the risks and opportunities related to global changes in&#xD;
climate, markets and policies. The impacts of these changes on food production, the environment and&#xD;
farmer livelihoods, as well as those of changes to technology and management practices, are not&#xD;
clearly understood. There is a need for improved assessment methods and tools that consider multiple&#xD;
factor and scale interactions (Van Ittersum et al., 2008). In recent years, European-wide consortia,&#xD;
such as SEAMLESS, have worked for creating flexible and widely applicable frameworks for&#xD;
integrated assessment and and modelling of agrifood systems That work has been valuable in&#xD;
developing common concepts, methods and more flexible frameworks (Ewert et al., 2009).. However,&#xD;
their relative generic character reduces its applicability when it comes to detailed regional applications,&#xD;
e.g. as needed in identifying promising climate change adaptation and mitigation options for&#xD;
agricultural systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>University of Natural Ressources and Applied Life Sciences</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16347/1/boku.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rötter, R.; Lehtonen, H.; Palosuo, T.; Salo, T.; Helin , J.; Kahiluoto, H.; Aakkula, J.; Granlund, K.; Rankinen, K. and Carter, T.    (2009) A modelling framework for assessing adaptive management options of Finnish agricultural systems to climate change.   In:     Extended abstracts, University of Natural Ressources and Applied Life Sciences (17), BOKU-Met Report, pp. 138-139.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16347/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>