<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulierungsmaßnahmen des Drahtwurmbefalls im ökologischen Kartoffelanbau: Ergebnisse einer Status-quo-Analyse</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schepl, Ute</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paffrath, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>More and more organic farmers lift potatoes which are damaged by wireworms (Agriotes spec. and Hemicrepidus niger). A nationwide status quo-analysis was carried out by the Chamber of Agriculture of North Rhine-Westphalia in 2002 and 2003. The survey included an intensive literature research, a questionnaire with 26 questions, on-site assessments, and on-farm trials. It was noticed that a long period of grass-clover cultivation in the crop rotation had a negative effect on the quality of potato tubers. Peas and lupines seemed to be the better pre-crops for a good quality of tubers in contrast to field beans and red clover. An autumn fertilization with manure resulted in a low feeding damage on potatoes by wireworms. Many perennial weeds some like twich-grass, dock and field thistle had a negative effect on the quality of potatoes fed by wireworms.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3578/1/3578.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schepl, Ute and Paffrath, Andreas    (2005) Regulierungsmaßnahmen des Drahtwurmbefalls im ökologischen Kartoffelanbau: Ergebnisse einer Status-quo-Analyse.  [Regulation of Wireworms in Ecological Potato Farming: Results of a Status-quo-Analysis.]  In: Heß, J. and Rahmann, G. (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3578/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>