<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Compost and digestate : sustainability, benefits, impacts for the environment and for plant production. Proceedings of the international congress CODIS 2008, February 27-29, 2008, Solothurn, Switzerland.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This proceedings volume contains the papers presented at the CODIS&#xD;
2008 congress held on 27 - 29 February 2008 in Solothurn (Switzerland).&#xD;
The composting and digestion of biogenic waste materials and the subsequent&#xD;
application of compost and digestate to soil contributes to nutrient&#xD;
recycling and renewable energy production. Moreover, compost and&#xD;
digestate can improve soil fertility and suppress plant diseases. On the&#xD;
other hand, compost and digestate may also contain a variety of pollutants&#xD;
hazardous to soil, such as heavy metals and organic contaminants.&#xD;
Compost and digestate have been thoroughly investigated in the framework&#xD;
of two associated projects entitled “Organic Pollutants in Compost&#xD;
and Digestate in Switzerland” and “Effects of Composts and Digestate on&#xD;
the Environment, Soil Fertility and Plant Health”. These projects yielded&#xD;
new insights into the properties of compost and digestate, mainly with&#xD;
regard to biological parameters and the occurrence of both “classic” and&#xD;
“emerging” organic pollutants.&#xD;
The CODIS 2008 congress was the final event of these two projects.&#xD;
For more information, see www.codis2008.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kupper, Thomas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Tamm, Lucius</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schwenk, Kaarina</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13135/1/fuchs-etal-proceedings-codis-2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fuchs, Jacques G.; Kupper, Thomas; Tamm, Lucius and Schwenk, Kaarina (Eds.)      (2008) Compost and digestate : sustainability, benefits, impacts for the environment and for plant production. Proceedings of the international congress CODIS 2008, February 27-29, 2008, Solothurn, Switzerland.    FiBL-Report. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13135/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>