<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss des Umbruchtermins von Kleegras&#xD;
auf Ertrag und Qualität von Sommerweizen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cais, Kathrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salzeder, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The risk of nitrogen leaching in winter after breaking of grass-clover sward can be reduced by delayed ploughing. The impact of ploughing date (either late autumn or spring) was compared regarding grain yield and baking quality of spring wheat. The field trial was conducted from 2001 to 2003 and from 2006 to 2008 on a trial site with sandy-loamy site conditions nearby Freising, Bavaria. Two varieties of spring wheat were examined. &#xD;
Higher baking quality (protein content, falling number, Zeleny index, wet gluten content, loaf volume) was identified in all years after ploughing in late autumn compared to spring ploughing. On the other hand, grain yield was higher after ploughing in spring in two of the six environments, but in one year the opposite occurred. This allows the conclusion that baking quality for spring wheat can be influenced by ploughing date in contrast to grain yield</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21339/1/21339_Urbatzka.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, Peer; Cais, Kathrin and Salzeder, Georg    (2013) Einfluss des Umbruchtermins von Kleegras auf Ertrag und Qualität von Sommerweizen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21339/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>