<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New methodology to design, test and improve organic agroecosystem prototyping under Mediterranean conditions.&#xD;
Case study: application to a pilot farm in the South of Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CHEHIDI, Hatem</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The sustainability of farming systems is related to the agroecosystem equilibrium. “Agro-designing” or EAFS prototyping is one methodology that can be used to assess and monitor organic farming agroecosystems. However, methods (MCR, ENM, EIM, EEPS, ECP, FSO and MSC) and parameters chosen for monitoring must be adapted to the specific agricultural conditions to design a suitable prototype. The single farm is the nucleus of agricultural production and the main starting point not only for identifying and reducing negative environmental impacts but also to promote and develop strategies to achieve long-term agroecosystem equilibrium. The “State of the Art” of the agroecosystem  “ Serra del Bosco” farm, located in Gravina di Puglia (Apulia-Southern Italy) and one of the pilot farms of the Regional Apulia Organic Farming Network, is presented as a case study for the application of EAFS methodology.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6474/1/HatemChehidi02.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CHEHIDI, Hatem   (2002) New methodology to design, test and improve organic agroecosystem prototyping under Mediterranean conditions. Case study: application to a pilot farm in the South of Italy.  [Nouvelle méthodologie pour concevoir, tester et améliorer le prototyping des agroécosystèmes biologiques dans les conditions méditerranéennes. Cas d’étude: application dans une exploitation pilote en Italie du Sud.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Tesi Master of Science, no. 279. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6474/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>