<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The role of atomic spectrometry in plant science</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Husted, Søren</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Persson, D.P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laursen, K.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, T.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pedas, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schiller, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hegelund, J.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schjørring, J.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) is the state-of-the-art technique for multi-elemental analysis of plant tissue. It provides a powerful tool in functional genomics, linking altered elemental profiles of mutants with gene expression and function. In addition, with its unmatched sensitivity, ICP-MS enables characterization of the substrate specificity and regulation of membrane transport proteins. Digestion of plant tissue has traditionally represented a bottleneck due to the low capacity of commercially available equipment. However, recent developments in micro-scaled digestion, combined with semi-quantitative analysis and chemometrics, have enabled high-throughput multi-elemental profiling and multivariate classification of large sample sets, thereby supporting a range of new applications in molecular breeding, quality assessment and authenticity testing of plants. Novel hyphenated techniques based on liquid chromatography and ICP-MS (LC-ICP-MS) have significantly improved the understanding of elemental species and their importance for e.g. the bioactivity of metals in plants. Development of procedures for sample pre-treatment, extraction and multi-dimensional separation now allows characterization of important metallo-biomolecules in plants, such as the coordination complexes of phytochelatins, metallothioneins, nicotianamine and inositol phosphates. These are key ligands involved in ion homeostasis, translocation and long-term storage of elements. Much emphasis has also been given to studies of covalently bound Se and As species, primarily due to their impact on human health. LC-ICP-MS has extensively been complemented by molecular mass spectrometry for structural information of biologically relevant species. This review covers the most recent developments in multi-elemental analysis (Part A) and speciation analysis (Part B) in plant science. A number of relevant cases are presented in order to demonstrate how the analytical developments have unravelled the functional roles of elements in plants science. These cases show that ICP-MS is an essential technology in plant metallomic platforms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19089/1/Review.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Husted, Søren; Persson, D.P.; Laursen, K.H.; Hansen, T.H.; Pedas, P.; Schiller, M.; Hegelund, J.N. and Schjørring, J.K.   (2011) The role of atomic spectrometry in plant science.   Journal of Analytical Atomic Spectrometry, 26, pp. 52-79.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19089/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>