<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Landscape Agroecology: managing interactions between agriculture, nature and socio-economy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, Tommy</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the art GIS and database technologies for landscape scale analysis and the modelling of land use and environmental impacts are presented. These methods have been developed at University of Aarhus in multidisciplinary collaboration with other research institutions throughout Europe; for example during the EU research projects www.mea-scope.org and www.sensor-ip.eu.  In the years to come, these landscape scale research methods are further developed and integrated with similar frameworks in other EU countries, and used for scenario studies (see for example the landscape components of http://www.nitroeurope.eu/, http://www.darcof.dk/research/darcofiii/refugia.html or http://www.darcof.dk/research/darcofiii/bioconcens.html).&#xD;
Scenario studies, visualised in geographical information systems, are useful to evaluate possible future landscape developments, and to identify potentials and limitations in combining multiple landscape functions. Here we focus on scenario systems that focus on exploring interactions between landscape functions – e.g. the interactions between farm management, economy, nutrient losses, fauna population dynamics, plant community development etc. Among others, scenarios for drinking water protection via increased set-aside grassland or afforestation are presented. It shows that benefits from subsidies targeted to areas with special interests in protection of drinking waters from nitrogen pollution differ from non-targeted subsidies. &#xD;
Experience has shown that working with scenarios and involving potential users at an early stage in development are important ways of focussing the work effort and ensuring that relevant tools are developed. Developments in data collection and collation at the EU level will allow similar systems to be developed elsewhere.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Liebnitz Institut für Agrarentwicklung (IAMO)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Schaft, F</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Balman, A</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19313/1/19313a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19313/2/19313b.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dalgaard, Tommy    (2009) Landscape Agroecology: managing interactions between agriculture, nature and socio-economy.    In: Schaft, F and Balman, A (Eds.)   Multi-level processes of integration and disintegration.  Monograph Series: Studies on the Agricultural and Food Sector in Central and Eastern Europe, no. 52. Liebnitz Institut für Agrarentwicklung (IAMO), Halle an der Saale, Germany, pp. 3-12.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19313/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>