<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einführung von Tiergesundheitsplänen in der ökologischen Milchviehhaltung - Ergebnisse einer deutschen Pilotstudie</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, Solveig</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>It was the aim to (1) identify major indicators of animal health in organic dairy farming&#xD;
(i.e. mastitis, lameness, metabolic/reproductive disorders, calf diseases) and to define&#xD;
respective goals, (2) to provide guidelines for the development of herd health plans&#xD;
based on these indicators and, (3) to carry out an implementation study on representative&#xD;
dairy farms taking farmers, veterinary surgeons as well as other advisors into&#xD;
account. 44 organic dairy farms were visited four times during 2006 and 2007. Following&#xD;
a thorough assessment, herd health plans were developed in 28 farms; herd&#xD;
health was then monitored for one year. After one year, treatment incidence for clinical&#xD;
mastitis was significantly lower in intervention farms. Also lameness prevalence was&#xD;
more reduced in intervention than in control farms (intervention study integrated in this&#xD;
project). Other health indicators were not significantly affected; however, this should&#xD;
be viewed in the light of the rather short period after implementation of the herd health&#xD;
plans. In conclusion, this farm-individual herd health planning tool has been demonstrated&#xD;
to effectively improve important dairy health aspects.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14451/1/Brinkmann_14451.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brinkmann, Jan; March, Solveig and Winckler, Christoph    (2009) Einführung von Tiergesundheitsplänen in der ökologischen Milchviehhaltung - Ergebnisse einer deutschen Pilotstudie.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14451/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>