<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Farming in Wales 1998 - 2003</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, Nic</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Powell, Jane</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 1998 Ron Davies MP, the then Secretary of State for Wales, established three industry working groups to develop action plans for the dairy, red meat and organic farming sectors in Wales. With the publication of the Organic Sector Action&#xD;
Plan in March 1999, the working group was restructured to form the Organic Strategy Group. In the four years since the publication of the action plan, there has been significant progress in the development of the organic sector in Wales. Organic production has increased, established organic producer groups and processing, distribution and retailing businesses have thrived, and many new businesses and initiatives have been established, bringing a greater business, social and cultural diversity to the organic community in Wales. But there have also been challenges, notably the difficulties faced by milk producers in finding markets for organic milk as a result of the dramatic increase in supplies – this illustrates the need for new initiatives to respond to a dynamic and changing situation as the organic sector develops. This report stands as a record of the achievements of the action plan, and the agencies that have supported its delivery.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10811/1/5yrcompeng.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/10811/2/5yrcompcym.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lampkin, Nic and Powell, Jane         (2003) Organic Farming in Wales 1998 - 2003.    Organic Centre Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/10811/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>