<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sooty Blotch of Apple: Etiology and Management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sutton, Turner B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williamson, Sharon M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sooty blotch is one 01 the most common diseases 01 apples in moist temperate growing regions. In 1920, Colby named the lungus that causes sooty blotch G/oeodes pomigena. G. pomigena was considered the sole cause 01 the disease until the 1990's when it was discovered that sooty blotch was a disease complex caused by several lungi. Pe/taster tructico/a, Geastrumia po/ystigmatis, and Leptodontium e/atius were associated with the disease in the southeastern US although it is likely that other lungi are a part 01 the complex in other areas. Management of the disease is based on cultural practices and lungicide applications. Removai 01 reservoir hosts is important in minimizing inoculum and pruning aids in reducing disease severity by lacilitating drying in the canopy. The principle method lor managing the disease is preventative lungicide sprays. Some lungicides have good eradicant activity and can be used along with a mode I to minimize lungicide applications.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14594/1/turner_43.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sutton, Turner B. and Williamson, Sharon M.    (2002) Sooty Blotch of Apple: Etiology and Management.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 43-48.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14594/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>