<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Resource effective control of Elymus repens</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ringselle, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andersson, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bergkvist, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aronsson, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Preliminary results show that there is room for improvement within existing control methods of couch grass (Elymus repens (L.) Gould). It may be possible to reduce the number of stubble cultivations during autumn by timing the treatment, and to reduce the cultivation depth by using a goose foot cultivator (5 cm) instead of a disc cultivator (10 cm), without sacrificing couch grass control efficiency. The first year of the experiment, the use of a goose foot cultivator resulted in less nitrogen leaching than cultivation by disc. A reduced number of stubble cultivations potentially reduces nutrient loss, fuel consumption and the workload of the farmer. &#xD;
Our experiments with cover crops to control couch grass in cereals has yet to prove significant effects on couch grass control, but cover crops combined with goose foot hoeing did reduce nitrogen leaching by more than a third compared to cultivation by disc. Further data is necessary to see if the system can be used to effectively control couch grass without significant yield losses. Regardless, it can reduce nitrogen leaching and potentially provide other ecosystem services, e.g. control weeds other than couch grass.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24433/1/24433.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ringselle, B.; Andersson, L.; Bergkvist, G. and Aronsson, H.    (2013) Resource effective control of Elymus repens.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 77-78.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24433/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>