<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of preceding crops on potato yield in organic and conventional farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kas, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Matejkova, Stepanka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Divis, Jiri</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Yields and qualitative parameters of four varieties of table potatoes, such as starch content and tuber size categories, were evaluated in organic and conventional farming during a three-year field experiment in Lukavec, Czech Republic. Potatoes were cultivated after two preceding crops and subjected to analyses. Based on analyses, significant difference between the conventional system and the organic system in the tuber yields was found. Further, the potato yield can be affected year, growing system and preceding crops. A significant influence of the preceding crops upon potato yields was proved. The potato yield after clover was about 8 t.ha-1 greater than after wheat amended with manure. No significant differences in yield were observed among the varieties. Potato yields differed in both growing systems during the observed years 2006 - 2008. The study proved that the starch content differed among varieties. It was confirmed that the difference in starch content depends on potato variety but does not depend on the growing system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Kas, Martin; Matejkova, Stepanka and Divis, Jiri   (2009) Effect of preceding crops on potato yield in organic and conventional farming.   Journal of Agrobiology, 26 (2), pp. 61-67.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21194/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>