<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality analysis of critical control points within the whole food chain and their impact on food quality, safety and health (QACCP)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kretzschmar, Ursula</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Hanne L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lauridsen, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mengheri, Elena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Seljåsen, Randi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The overall objective of the project was to optimise organic production and processing in order to improve food quality and increase health promoting aspects in consumer products. The approach was a chain analysis approach which addressed the link between farm and fork and backwards from fork to farm. The objectives were to test food authenticity on farm level and food quality and health in processing. The carrot was chosen as the model vegetable since it is common for the involved partners from industry and is processed for baby food; hence the results are relevant for other vegetables and organic food in general as well.&#xD;
- Identify and define critical and essential product quality parameters useful to optimise organic food quality&#xD;
- Compare products from different farming practices (conventional and within organic)&#xD;
- Performance of QACCP (Quality Analysis Critical Control Point, similar to HACCP methodology)&#xD;
- Test the impact of the food chain (focusing on processing techniques) on the product quality and safety&#xD;
- Test the impact of organic food on health</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22474/1/22474-07OE001-uni-kassel-kahl-2010-QACCP.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kahl, Johannes; Kretzschmar, Ursula; Kristensen, Hanne L.; Lauridsen, Charlotte; Mengheri, Elena; Särkkä-Tirkkonen, Marjo and Seljåsen, Randi         (2010) Quality analysis of critical control points within the whole food chain and their impact on food quality, safety and health (QACCP).    Universität Kassel, Fachbereich Ökologische Agrarwissenschaften, D-Witzenhausen, Fachgebiet Ökologische Lebensmittelqualität und Ernährungskultur.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22474/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>