<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PlantyOrganic: Results 2013</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hospers-Brands, A.J.T.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Anema, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bus, M.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>2013 was the second year of the "PlantyOrganic" system development in practice. The six-year rotation is laid out and measurements took place at soil and crop. With the exception of the potatoes in 2013 all crops had the pre-crop as foreseen in the design. The fertilizers used were completely produced in the own system, as foreseen in the system design. The amounts of nitrogen applied were about 45 % higher than in the design. Soil nitrogen is measured and used as input in the nitrogen model NDICEA. There was a sufficient match between measured and calculated level of soil mineral nitrogen. The crops performed well, with a high yield in carrots and oats, and a disappointing yield in wheat. In wheat nitrogen was limiting for the yield, we do not yet have a satisfactory explanation. In cauliflower a lack of nitrogen ijn the last phase of the growth had a negative effect on the quality and the crop could not be sold. All plots went green into the winter. Until now no research has been done on the availability of phosphate and potassium. Because there is no supply of these minerals from outside the system, the balance is negative. In time the circle could be closed by means of regional re-use of minerals, for example by the application of household waste compost. PlantyOrganic can become a very good research location for research on the mobilisation of phosphate (and potassium) in circumstances of low supply and/or low chemically analysed availability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Louis Bolk Instituut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26064/1/2892.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hospers-Brands, A.J.T.M.; Anema, D. and Bus, M.C.         (2014) PlantyOrganic: Results 2013.   Louis Bolk Instituut publications, no. 2014-013 LbP. Louis Bolk Instituut, Driebergen.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26064/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>