<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Consumer perception and communication on welfare in organic laying hen farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heerkens, Jasper</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tuyttens, Frank</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A major reason for increased societal popularity of organic production systems is the growing general discontent with intensive farming practices. However, urbanization leads to limited knowledge of farming and farm animal welfare. Consumers believe organic farming leads to better animal welfare, although most health and welfare issues seen in conventional systems are also found in organic poultry systems. The majority of consumers do not translate attitude and good intention into action, the actual purchase of organic products. Understanding this intention-behaviour gap may lead to increased sales of organic products. Effective communication and education can create trust, added additional values and credibility, and may lead to structured perceptions, convictions, values, norms, knowledge and interests and lead to better understanding of organic farming and farm animal welfare. Merchandising strategies can reduce barriers the consumer may encounter at the moment of decision making.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Braunschweig: vTI</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2012-09-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22351/1/Heerkens%202012%20Consumer%20perception%20and%20communication%20on%20welfare%20in%20organic%20laying%20hen%20farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heerkens, Jasper and Tuyttens, Frank    (2012) Consumer perception and communication on welfare in organic laying hen farming.   In:     Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, Braunschweig: vTI, pp. 75-78.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22351/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>