<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Untersuchungen zu Liegenischen für Milchziegen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Barth, Kerstin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ordolff, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Claus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The legislative rules of keeping ruminants on organic farms do not differentiate between the requirements of the different species for the housing systems. Thus, the types of locomotion typical for goats (e. g. climbing, jumping) have not to take in consideration in stables designed for goat keeping. Some farmers offer their animals elevated resting platforms (niches), but data concerning the preferences of the goats and the labour management of such areas are not available. A herd of non-lactating goats (breed: Bunte Deutsche Edelziege) was parted in six experimental groups with ten animals in each group. Over a period of seven days the animals were kept separated in a part of the stable furnished with resting niches. Twelve niches were arranged on three levels. Half of them contained a layer of deep-litter. The working time needed for cleaning of the niches was measured during each change of the groups. The cleanliness of the niches was documented by photography. Pictures were evaluated by means of an image processing system. Animal behaviour was registered by video-observation. The results showed a relationship between the labour time needed for cleaning of the niches and the preference of niches by the goats. Due to the necessary filling up with straw, the niches with the bedding of deep litter required the same amount of labour time as the niches without bedding, which needed more time for cleaning. The image processing system might be used to evaluate cleanliness of resting areas designed for other species, too.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3411/1/3411.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Barth, Kerstin; Ordolff, Dieter and Mayer, Claus    (2005) Untersuchungen zu Liegenischen für Milchziegen.  [Investigations of resting areas designed for goats.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3411/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>