<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effect of Cichorium intybus on helminth infections in pigs</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roepstorff, Allan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thamsborg, Stig Milan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lydehøj Hansen, Laurits</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bach Knudsen, Knud Erik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two similar trials were carried out to examine how dietary inclusion of an easily fermentable carbohydrate source such as chicory roots (Cichorium intybus) may effect established and establishing helminth infections in pigs. In the first trial varying feeding periods with crude chicory roots naturally rich in fructans (primarily inulin) were tested whereas crude chicory roots were compared with dried chicory roots and purified inulin in the second trial. In both trials pigs were infected with 3000 O. dentatum L3-larvae while fed a traditional standard diet. When the infections were well established and patent, experimental diets were introduced and the faecal egg counts monitored. Two weeks before the pigs were slaughtered all animals were infected with 3000 O. dentatum L3-larvae and 2000 A. suum eggs. In trial 1, substitution of 25 % of the daily energy intake with crude chicory roots initially decreased the excretion of O. dentatum eggs but slowly increased again over the 9 week feeding period. In trial 2, similar results were seen during a 6 week feeding period while dried chicory roots almost completely eliminated egg excretion. The effect on egg excretion did not seem due to elimination of adult worms but may have been the result of impaired fitness and a lower mating frequency of adult worms. The number of recovered immature O. dentatum were reduced by 4, 6, and 9 weeks feeding with crude chicory as well as 6 weeks on inulin or died chicory. The latter also seemed to impair or slow down the development of the larvae. The number of recovered A. suum larvae was also reduced by crude chicory roots, dried chicory roots and purified inulin. Overall, the dried chicory product had the most significant impact on the helminth infections.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4523/1/4523.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mejer, Helena; Roepstorff, Allan; Thamsborg, Stig Milan; Lydehøj Hansen, Laurits and Bach Knudsen, Knud Erik   (2005) The effect of Cichorium intybus on helminth infections in pigs.       [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4523/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>