<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Prelimenary results on a comparative study evaluating landraces of common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) in organic agriculture in a protected area (Northern Greece)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vakali, Dr. Christina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fokion, Dr. Papathanasiou</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ioannis, Dr. Papadopoulos</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eustathios, Dr. Tamoutsidis</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming requires cultivars or landraces that are specifically adapted to this low input cropping system. Six landraces of Greek common dry bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) and one from the neighbouring Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia (FYROM) were evaluated for different agronomic and physicochemical characteristics under organic conditions in the National Park of the lake Prespes, on the borders of Greece, FYROM and Albania. Significant differences among landraces were found in yield characteristics such as yield plant-1, pod plant-1 and seeds pod-1 with two of the landraces performing the best. The cooking time was estimated by measuring seed hardness using a penetrometer. There was a considerable variation between the landraces tested with cooking times between 25-45 minutes. Some of the landraces could be a useful resource for the development of organic farming systems in this protected area.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Sarapatka, Prof. Borivoj</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15874/1/Vakali.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vakali, Dr. Christina; Fokion, Dr. Papathanasiou;  Ioannis, Dr. Papadopoulos and Eustathios, Dr. Tamoutsidis    (2009) Prelimenary results on a comparative study evaluating landraces of common bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) in organic agriculture in a protected area (Northern Greece).   In: Sarapatka, Prof. Borivoj (Ed.)  Bioacademy 2009-Proceedings, pp. 22-26.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15874/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>