<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sowing time, false seedbed, row distance and mechanical weed control in organic winter wheat.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming, mechanical weed control in winter wheat is often difficult to carry out in the fall, and may damage the crop, and weed harrowing in the spring is not effective against erect, tap-rooted weeds such as Tripleurospermum inodorum, Papaver rhoeas, Brassica napus and others which have been established in the autumn. Some experiments concerning sowing strategy and intensity of  mechanical weed control, which included row distance, were conducted. The results underline the importance of choosing weed control strategy, including preventive measures, according to the weed flora in the field. In the experiment with low weed pressure and without erect weeds, there was very little effect of sowing strategy and row distance. In such a case, the winter wheat might as well be sown early, in order to avoid possible yield loss by later sowing, and at normal row distance to enhance the competitiveness of the crop. In the experiments with high weed pressure and erect weeds, the weed control was better with late sowing and large row distance (high intensity control), even though this was not always reflected in the yield. However, the trade-off for lower input to the soil seed bank in organic systems should be enough to balance off the risk of smaller yield.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Cloutier, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/216/1/Elspeet.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/216/2/Elspeet2000_iar.PDF</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/216/3/EWRS_Elspeet_2000_iar2.PDF</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Ilse A.    (2000) Sowing time, false seedbed, row distance and mechanical weed control in organic winter wheat.   In: Cloutier, Daniel (Ed.)  Abstracts 4th EWRS Workshop on Physical Weed Control, pp. 5-7.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/216/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>