<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vorratsschutz im Ökologischen Landbau: Entscheidungshilfe durch das &#xD;
Computerprogramm VOEL 1.0</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schöller, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dau, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prozell, S</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steidle, J.L.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reichmuth, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roßberg, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>VOEL 1.0 is a decision-support software for the protection of organic stored-products that was developed for store-keepers, farmers and pest control specialists in Ger-many. Most of the information given applies to all Central European countries, except for some legislative aspects concerning registration, which are specific for Germany. The program contains a decision-support module for monitoring and control of stored product pest, an encyclopedia on pests and beneficial organisms, a key for the deter-mination of these organisms, information on registered products for stored product protection in Germany, a data bank where literature concerning associations of pests and beneficials can be retrieved, a list of references on stored product protection in general and several original papers on stored-product protection.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9619/1/9619_Sch%C3%B6ller_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schöller, M; Dau, B; Prozell, S; Steidle, J.L.M.; Reichmuth, C. and Roßberg, D.    (2007) Vorratsschutz im Ökologischen Landbau: Entscheidungshilfe durch das Computerprogramm VOEL 1.0.  [Stored products protection in ecological farming: VOEL 1.0, a decision-support software.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9619/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>