<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Genetische Variation in der Resistenzinduktion gegenüber&#xD;
Phytophthora infestans bei Tomaten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sharma, MSc Kalpana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Butz, Dipl. Ing. Andreas F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Prof. Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>There are numerous instances in which induced plant resistance responses (IR) have&#xD;
been demonstrated. However, before IR can be made use of in practice it is important&#xD;
to understand as much as possible the ecology and genetics of the inducing agents&#xD;
and their interactions with plants and pathogens. Effects of host genetic background&#xD;
were tested with thirteen tomato varieties and two isolates of Phytophthora infestans.&#xD;
Isolate effects on inducibility were tested with six varieties and six pathogen isolates.&#xD;
Leaf disks of plants that had been treated with BABA (DL-3-aminobutyric acid) or&#xD;
water were inoculated seven days later with 20 µl sporangial solutions of 5*104&#xD;
sporangia ml-1. All experiments were repeated three times with six replications each.&#xD;
Disease reductions due to induction ranged from 43 to 100% and were independent of&#xD;
the susceptibility of the variety to the isolates when not induced. The interactions&#xD;
between isolate and variety with respect to inducibility were highly significant.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14359/1/Sharma_14359.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sharma, MSc Kalpana; Butz, Dipl. Ing. Andreas F. and Finckh, Prof. Maria R.    (2009) Genetische Variation in der Resistenzinduktion gegenüber Phytophthora infestans bei Tomaten.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14359/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>