<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>10 Jahre differenzierte Grundbodenbearbeitung im Ökologischen Landbau. Auswirkungen auf die Besiedlung mit Collembolen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bassemir, Ursula K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During 10 years a crop rotation schedule consisting of different crops (green fallow; intercrop: winter wheat; peas; intercrop: winter rye; summer barley) was combined with three different tillage techniques (plough, inverting to 30 cm depth, intensive; two-layer plough, inverting to 15 cm depth and loosening to 30 cm depth, reduced inverting; layer cultivator, loosening to 30 cm depth, conservation tillage). First results show a significant effect of crop on springtails. There is no significant effect of tillage techniques, although there is a tendency in slightly increased population density of springtails by using plough and layer cultivator. Further detailed results will be reported elsewhere.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3685/1/3685.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bassemir, Ursula K.    (2005) 10 Jahre differenzierte Grundbodenbearbeitung im Ökologischen Landbau. Auswirkungen auf die Besiedlung mit Collembolen.  [10 years specific soil management in organic agriculture. Effects on springtails.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3685/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>