<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality of potatoes from different farming systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krtkova, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulzová, Věra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Novotna, Hana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dvorak, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hajšlová, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Increasing public concern about environment and human health reflects in growing consumers´ interest in organic food. In order to have a free and informed choice between organic and conventional foods, an objective assessment of a product quality based on a sound scientific knowledge is needed. The aim of this project was an investigation of the influence of growing conditions on the potato (Solanum tuberosum) quality. Two traditional varieties (Katka and Finka) were grown at two different localities in Czech Republic. To determine a possible inter-annual variability, the experiments were performed on crops over a period of three consecutive years (2008 – 2010). The monitored parameters included biologically active compounds (chlorogenic acid, reducing sugars, amino acids, vitamin C etc.) and also toxic secondary metabolites (total glycoalkaloids and calystegines). Levels of these biologically active compounds depended mainly on the variety and climatic conditions such as year of farming, but the type of a cultivation system did not play a significant role. The currently investigated natural toxic alkaloids calystegines were found at higher concentration levels than the natural toxicants glycoalkaloides, monitoring of which is required by legislation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bioinstitut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20470/3/Abstrakt_3rd_Scientific_Conference_Krtkova_final_2-1.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krtkova, Veronika; Schulzová, Věra; Novotna, Hana; Dvorak, Petr and Hajšlová, Jana    (2011) Quality of potatoes from different farming systems.   In:     New findings in organic farming research and their possible use for Central and Eastern Europe, Bioinstitut, Olomouc 2011, pp. 85-89.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20470/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>