<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Incorporation of Nitrogen-15-Labeled Amendments into Physically Separated Soil Organic Matter Fractions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bosshard, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Manolov, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Physically separated soil organic matter (SOM) fractions may take different functions in soil N dynamics. We studied the effect of long-term organic matter (OM) management and different soil biological activity on the incorporation of N added with organic and mineral amendments into aggregate fractions and size density fractions. We applied 15N-labeled sheep feces, urine, and mineral fertilizer to microplots installed in plots of conventional (CONMIN) and bio-organic (BIOORG) cropping systems. Soil sampled 112 d after amendment was separated into macro-, microaggregates, and microstructures. Aggregates were then fractionated into free light fraction (LF), intra-aggregate particulate organic matter (iPOM),and the mineral-associated organic matter fraction (MF). Of total soil N, 67% was contained in macroaggregates. Size density fractionation of aggregates revealed that about 60% of soil N was stored in MF while LF and iPOM contained together &lt;3% of soil N. Despite longterm OM input and higher soil biological activity in BIOORG than CONMIN the two soils did not differ in the distribution and content of N in aggregate and size density fractions. Recovery of 15N in nonfractionated soil ranged from 20% (SlurryF) to 25% (SlurryU) of originally applied 15N. The small macroaggregates were for each amendment the major sink (7–12% of applied 15N). In all aggregates and for all amendments, MF was the most important 15N sink, totally containing between 6.6% (SlurryF) to 11.6% (SlurryU) of applied 15N. Less than 1% of applied 15N was recovered in LF, and even less (&lt;0.5%) in iPOM. The proportion of amendment-derived N in aggregate fractions and in several size density fractions (LF, fi ne iPOM, MF) was higher for urine than for feces and mineral fertilizer. Recovery of urine-derived 15N was greater in aggregate fractions of BIOORG than CONMIN soil. During dispersion of aggregates to obtain iPOM and MF, about 27% of total soil N and between 37 and 55% of 15N contained in non-fractionated soil was lost, showing the importance of aggregation to protect N.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26387/1/Bosshard_et_al_2008_SSSAJ_72_POM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bosshard, C.; Frossard, E.; Dubois, D.; Mäder, P.; Manolov, I. and Oberson, A.   (2008) Incorporation of Nitrogen-15-Labeled Amendments into Physically Separated Soil Organic Matter Fractions.   Soil Science Society of America Journal, 72 (4), pp. 949-959.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26387/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>