<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EFFETTO DELLA RAZZA E DEL TIPO DI ALIMENTAZIONE SU ALCUNI PARAMETRI QUALITATIVI DELLA CARNE SUINA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spanó, Alessandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The present study was carried out to establish the effect of   two feeding strategies on some qualitative parameters of fresh pork. Regarding the feed strategies the first group was called NORMAL(Norm) with available the 100% of concentrate that they needed and RESTRICTIVE (Rest) with only the 60% of concentrate available. Two market hogs DLY and TLY are raised up at the organic research platform of Aarhus University, Denmark, from August to October 2012. The market hogs were 32 female pigs, born from the progeny F1 of Landrace x Yorkshire (LY) sows sired by Duroc (D) or Tamworth (T) boars. The pigs were reared outdoors in paddocks 1625 m² and slaughtered at about 90 days of age. All pigs at the time of slaughter, were weighed and from each carcass several samples were taken from two muscle beams (biceps femoris and longissimus dorsi). Quality parameters evaluated were, the trend of pH and temperature within 24h postmortem, the color in the two muscles by Minolta Chroma Meter, the development of tenderness by shear force measurement (WBSF) in the samples aging for 1, 4 and 7 days. A group of tasters from University of Copenaghen was involved for the sensory evaluation of sample of longissimus dorsi and biceps femoris from DLY and TLY respectively with 4 day of aging time. The result of the panel test has been elaborated with the statistical program SAS. The result of the shear force obtain from the system (WBSF) has been compared with the result from panel test by SAS for evaluated eventual correlations. An assessment of the development of oxidation in meat samples, was finally performed through chemical extraction and spectrophotometric analysis on TBARS, using samples stored at 5 ± 1 ° C under fluorescent light (1000 LUX) for three days, in order to simulate the standard conditions of retail sale.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27301/7/27301.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spanó, Alessandro   (2014) EFFETTO DELLA RAZZA E DEL TIPO DI ALIMENTAZIONE SU ALCUNI PARAMETRI QUALITATIVI DELLA CARNE SUINA.    Masters thesis, University of Perugia, Italy.  .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27301/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>