<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Participatory Videos: A New Media for Promoting Organic Farming in Northern Bangladesh</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sarker, M.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Chowdhury, A.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MIah, M.A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peloschek, F.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Significance of agricultural extension to eliminate poverty, vulnerability, hunger and pollution is well-established in the perspective of developing countries. However, extension services in Bangladesh missed the opportunity to reduce poverty and pollution in a cost-effective way. This is due to lack of innovative ways to support farmer-to-farmer learning process. This paper presents the thoughts, empirical evidences and vision about approaches of video-mediated learning to enhance household food security and reducing pollution caused by agro-chemicals used in the field of agriculture. Following a model of participatory video (PV) supported women farmers’ capacity building process for preparation and use of botanical pesticide and vermin-compost in organic vegetables production. Findings of the study showed that PV has unexploited potentials to promote farmers’ innovation and adoption of organic farming by the farmers in the study area.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24056/1/24056%20Sarker%20et.%20al.%20paper%20OWC14_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sarker, M.A.; Chowdhury, A.H.; MIah, M.A.M. and Peloschek, F.A.    (2014) Participatory Videos: A New Media for Promoting Organic Farming in Northern Bangladesh.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 53-56.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24056/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>