<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Selection of genotypes with high N-use efficiency, weed competition and allelopathy in breeding materials of wheat and barley for organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project is an implementation of new knowledge and methods obtained and &#xD;
developed in earlier SLF and SJFR projects. The methods based on hydroponic &#xD;
selection for N-use efficiency and weed competition and a bioassay for allelopathy &#xD;
selections have now been used in an on-going project for selection of new breeding &#xD;
lines in wheat and barley, to identify new gene sources for allelopathy and to &#xD;
improve the gene pools. The efforts will continue in the new project with special &#xD;
emphasis on allelopathy where the new gene sources will be used to improve weed &#xD;
competition in wheat. Parallel with traditional selection using the bioassay, gene &#xD;
markers will also be looked for. Effective markers will facilitate incorporations &#xD;
of genes from less adapted cultivars. In the on-going project several interesting &#xD;
breeding lines have been produced. These and new selected lines will be further &#xD;
evaluated in organic yield trials. The hydroponic screening is here an effective &#xD;
method to select the most interesting lines for organic production out of several &#xD;
hundred from the conventional breeding programme.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Selection of genotypes with high N-use efficiency, weed competition and allelopathy in breeding materials of wheat and barley for organic farming.    Runs 2004 - 2008.      Project Leader(s): Didon, Ulla, Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6181/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>