<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Path to Otopia: an Australian Perspective</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Australia</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper is a response to an invitation from SASA to deliver a keynote address on the topic: "The History of Innovative Organic Knowledge: Past, Present (and Future?)” to the Soil Association of South Australia (SASA) on the occasion of the launching of the SASA Historical Research Archive at the State Library of South Australia, Adelaide. It identifies three waves of organic advocacy in Australia. It describes the author's recently published research on the Australian Organic Farming and Gardening Society (1944-1955), the world's first society to call itself an  "organic farming" society, the first society to publish an organic journal (the "Organic Farming Digest"), and the first society to publish a set of organic agriculture principles. Looking to the future, the term "Otopia" is coined to describe a state of 100% organic agriculture. At the historical rate of growth exhibited by the organic sector (data available for the past 8 years), it will take 584 years to reach a global state of Otopia if we assume arithmetic growth (of 27.1% pa), or 27 years if we assume compounding growth (of 16.4% pa).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15407/1/15407.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John    (2009) The Path to Otopia: an Australian Perspective.       Paper at:   Launch of the Historical Research Archive of the Soil Association of South Australia (SASA), State Library of South Australia, Adelaide, 4 February 2009.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15407/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>