<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Control methods against bugs (Hemiptera; Heteroptera) in organic apple and pear production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jaastad, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trandem, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hovland, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Opedal, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mogan, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Røen, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørum, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bjotveit, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>True bugs (Hemiptera; Heteroptera) are important pests in fruit production in Norway. In organic fruit pro-duction they may damage up to 40% of the crop. Several of the Heteropteran species attacking apple and pear are polyphagous, with many other hostplants than pome fruit. In organic production few control meth-ods are available against bugs. In this study we have tried a cultural control method (mowing of ground-cover) as well as spray applications of various biological insecticides against bugs. Spray application of azadirachtin (NeemAzal), rape oil and garlic extract (Ecoguard) were tested. Results indicate that the effect of mowing groundcover inside the orchard is variable and small. Applying NeemAzal reduced the number of bugs and damage. Oil and Ecoguard showed little effect in this study, however further testing is needed. Results from the first two years of the study will be discussed in relation to both cultural and direct control methods against bugs.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8817/1/ecofruit_12th_10.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jaastad, G.; Trandem, N.; Hovland, B.; Opedal, O.; Mogan, S.; Røen, D.; Sørum, O. and Bjotveit, E.    (2006) Control methods against bugs (Hemiptera; Heteroptera) in organic apple and pear production.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 55-60.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8817/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>