<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Implications of changes in seasonal mean temperature for agricultural production systems: three case studies</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Calanca, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spirig, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stoeckli, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Samietz, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Holzkämper, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hirschi, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>- The performance of dairy cows will suffer from elevated temperatures, reflecting the extent and uncertainty of projected warming in different scenarios, with a marked increase in heat stress for non-intervention scenarios (A1B and A2) toward the end of the century. This calls for the adoption of protective measures in the management of indoor and outdoor animal environments.&#xD;
&#xD;
- A substantial risk of a prolonged pest control season for the codling moth (an apple pest) is projected toward the end of the century for Northern Switzerland sites, and mid-century for the Ticino. Timely preventive programs are anticipated to represent a key ingredient of adaptation to changing risks from agricultural pests.&#xD;
&#xD;
- Results suggest that in the near future viticulture could benefit from increasing temperatures as a wider range of grape varieties could be grown. Toward the end of the century negative impacts from extreme temperatures are nevertheless expected to become important.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>OCCR, FOEN, MeteoSwiss, C2SM, Agroscope and ProClim</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25471/1/calanca-etal-2014-CH2014-Impacts_report-chapter9-p91-97.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Calanca, P.; Spirig, C.; Stoeckli, S.; Samietz, J.; Holzkämper, A. and Hirschi, M.    (2014) Implications of changes in seasonal mean temperature for agricultural production systems: three case studies.    In:   CH2014-Impacts (Ed.)  Toward Quantitative Scenarios of Climate Change Impacts in Switzerland.  OCCR, FOEN, MeteoSwiss, C2SM, Agroscope and ProClim, Bern, Switzerland, chapter 9, pp. 91-97.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25471/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>