<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The effects of feed composition on the sensory quality of organic rainbow trout during ice storage</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Green-Pedersen, Ditte Pedersen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hyldig, Grethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jacobsen, Charlotte</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baron, Caroline</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Henrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Quality and evaluation of inputs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The focus of this work was to study which effects the type of protein and lipid source in the feed for organic Rainbow trout influences had on the sensory quality of final product. Two and four different protein and lipid sources were used in the experiment respectively. The protein sources were fishmeal and a mixture of protein from organic vegetable, while the lipid sources were fish oil and organic oil from linseed, sunflower, rapeseed and grape seed. Sensory analysis was performed after 3, 5, 7 and 14 days of storage in ice. The results showed that both protein and lipid source in the feed can influence sensory characteristics of the trout. After 3 and 7 days of storage in ice differences in the sensory characteristics between rainbow trout’s which have had different lipid sources in the feed were observed. While a difference between the trout fed with different protein sources were observed after 14 days of storage, indicating that vegetable protein in the feed increases the self-life of organic rainbow trout.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18461/1/18461.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Green-Pedersen, Ditte Pedersen; Hyldig, Grethe; Jacobsen, Charlotte; Baron, Caroline and Nielsen, Henrik         (2011) The effects of feed composition on the sensory quality of organic rainbow trout during ice storage.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18461/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>