<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Selection and characterization of ‘low input’ farm groups in 3 macro-climatic regions in Europe for inclusion in a “farmer participatory” performance recording network (FP-PRN) and performance recording of currently used layer genotypes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Leenstra, Ferry</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bestman, Monique</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zeltner, Esther</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Niekerk, Thea</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Galea, Fabien</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reuvekamp, Berry</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In poultry, breeding is carried out by a very limited number of international operating breeding companies. For laying hens two companies dominate the market. Laying hens are in general 4-way crosses. Since 1960 the majority of commercial layers are bred and housed in cages. Non-cage housing started to appear again from 1980 onwards and increases slowly in importance, at first in Europe, but recently also in North America. It is questionable if birds bred to perform in cages are also suited for free range housing. In this project we examine the performance of current genotypes in free range systems (organic and conventional), and if and how an improved genotype for free range housing can be developed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-03-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18709/1/Leenstra-Poultry-aims.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18709/4/Leenstra-Poultry-aims-presentation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Leenstra, Ferry; Maurer, Veronika; Bestman, Monique; Zeltner, Esther; van Niekerk, Thea; Galea, Fabien and Reuvekamp, Berry    (2011) Selection and characterization of ‘low input’ farm groups in 3 macro-climatic regions in Europe for inclusion in a “farmer participatory” performance recording network (FP-PRN) and performance recording of currently used layer genotypes.       Paper at:   First LowInputBreeds Symposium on Ethical Consideration in Livestock Breeding, Wagningen, The Netherlands, March 15 and 16, 2011.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18709/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>