<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Micellar electrokinetic capillary chromatography—Synchronous monitoring of substrate and products in the myrosinase catalysed hydrolysis of glucosinolates</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bellostas, Natalia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sorensen, Jens Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sorensen, Hilmer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A micellar electrokinetic capillary chromatography (MECC) method has been developed for monitoring the myrosinase catalysed hydrolysis of 2-hydroxy substituted glucosinolates and the simultaneous formation of the corresponding degradation products (oxazolidine-2-thiones (OZTs) and nitriles). Glucosibarin ((2R)-2-hydroxy-2-phenylethylglucosinolate) was chosen as the model glucosinolate owing to the difficulties in determining hydrolysis rates of this type of substrates in traditional UV-assays. The method was afterwards validated with glucobarbarin ((2S)-2-hydroxy-2-phenylethylglucosinolate) and progoitrin ((2R)-2-hydroxybut-3-enylglucosinolate). Aromatic glucosinolates without a 2-hydroxy group in their side chains, such as glucotropaeolin (benzylglucosinolate) and gluconasturtiin (phenethylglucosinolate) were also tested. Formation of the glucosinolate&#xD;
hydrolysis products was monitored simultaneously at 206 nm and 230 nm. This allowed estimation of the extinction coefficient of the OZT derived from glucosibarin, which was found to be 18,000M−1 cm−1 and 12,000M−1 cm−1 at 206 nm and 230 nm, respectively. The developed method has limit of detection of 0.04mM and 0.06mM and limit of quantification of 0.2mM and 0.3mM for the glucosibarin derived OZT and nitrile, respectively. Linearity of the glucosinolate concentration was examined at six concentration levels from 2.5mMto 100mMand at 206 nm a straight line (R2 = 0.9996) was obtained. The number of theoretical plates (N) at the optimal system conditions was 245,000 for the intact glucosibarin,&#xD;
264,000 for the OZT and 252,000 for the nitrile.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Elsevier</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9260/1/9260.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bellostas, Natalia; Sorensen, Jens Christian and Sorensen, Hilmer   (2006) Micellar electrokinetic capillary chromatography—Synchronous monitoring of substrate and products in the myrosinase catalysed hydrolysis of glucosinolates.   Journal of Chromatography A.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9260/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>