<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Provision of information on organic soft fruit production OF0306</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Unspecified,</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Although there is a demand for organic soft fruit in the UK, especially from processors, these crops are only grown on a very small scale at present. As the demand for organic fruit continues to grow much of this is therefore currently met by imports. Lack of technical knowledge, information and advice for growers, together with uncertainties over the economics of production are at present major barriers preventing growers becoming involved in this area. The purpose of this project is to address this problem, by collating the knowledge gained on this topic in previous projects (OF0150), updating it with new developments and produce a technical guide on organic soft fruit production for growers. The content of the booklet is likely to be based on a booklet on the same topic that has been published by FiBL and this has already been translated to English as part of a previous DEFRA project (OF0150). The collated information will be available in a user-friendly format as a published booklet and over the Internet. The findings of the project will also be disseminated to growers and other stakeholders within the industry at a seminar dedicated to the topic of Organic Soft Fruit Production and through articles in the horticultural press. The dissemination of this knowledge should have a beneficial effect by contributing to increasing the interest in organic soft fruit production and giving growers greater confidence to convert to organic production and thus eventually increase the domestic production of organic soft fruit.&#xD;
&#xD;
The project is relevant to DEFRA as it fits in with its overall policy of assisting UK organic farmers to meet the growing demand for organic produce and provide the necessary information to enable farmers to assess whether they should convert to organic production.&#xD;
&#xD;
Objective&#xD;
The overall aim of this project is to provide information for growers on organic soft fruit production (raspberry, currants and gooseberry). The specific objectives will be to:&#xD;
1) to update, collect and review information on existing knowledge on, current practice and best practice techniques for organic production of raspberry, currants and gooseberry, building on the findings of OF0150. &#xD;
2) to produce a published technical booklet for growers - Organic soft fruit production (title to be confirmed)&#xD;
3) to disseminate the information to growers and other stakeholders in the organic fruit industry</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6710/2/organic_top_fruit_uk_OFo306.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Unspecified,          (2003) Provision of information on organic soft fruit production OF0306.    Henry Doubleday Research Association.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6710/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>