<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>KNOWING, CHARACTERIZING AND ASSESSING SYSTEMS OF ORGANIC CROP ROTATIONS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>fontaine, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>fourrié, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garnier, J.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Colomb, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Carof, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Aveline, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The choice of crop rotations in organic stockless cropping systems is the first leverage used to manage technical issues (to maintain soil fertility, to control pest and weeds) and economic issues (to insure income). The RotAB project (French Casdar funding 2008-2010) implemented complementary approaches to better knowing, characterizing and assessing arable crop rotations. Their conception depends on numerous factors such as the types of soil and climate (on which depend the types of crops, yield potential, possibility of mechanical weed control…) or the economic context (existence of outlets and continuity of markets). If nitrogen supply and weed control are the most important agronomic issues of organic farmers in stockless cropping systems, phosphorus availability appears to be the next important issue for soil fertility and system sustainability.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24050/1/24050_fontaine_rotaions_OWC14_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>fontaine, L.; fourrié, L.; Garnier, J.F.; Colomb, B.; Carof, M. and Aveline, A.    (2014) KNOWING, CHARACTERIZING AND ASSESSING SYSTEMS OF ORGANIC CROP ROTATIONS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 1, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 315-318.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24050/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>