<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss der Zufütterung von tanninhaltiger Esparsette auf den&#xD;
Proteinumsatz von weidenden Milchkühen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Arrigo, Herr Yves</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dohme, Frau Frigga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A study was carried out to investigate the potential of condensed tannins (CT) from&#xD;
sainfoin to minimize ruminal ammonia load in dairy cows grazing pasture with a high&#xD;
crude protein content (227 g/kg dry matter [DM]). Eight ruminally fistulated Holstein&#xD;
cows were supplemented with either 4 kg DM of dehydrated-pelleted sainfoin (CT&#xD;
content: 71 g/kg DM) or 4 kg DM of dehydrated-pelleted alfalfa (n = 4). Supplements&#xD;
were divided into two meals fed in the morning and in the afternoon before cows went&#xD;
on pasture. After adaptation to the diet (9 d) milk performance were measured on&#xD;
three consecutive days and ruminal fluid and blood were sampled on two consecutive&#xD;
days at 6:30, 8:00 and 16:30 h. Grass intake on pasture and the proportion of digested&#xD;
protein were estimated using the double n-alkane technique. The supplements were&#xD;
consumed completely. Grass DM intake was similar for treatments (P &gt; 0.05). Ruminal&#xD;
ammonia concentration increased in both treatment groups after the morning feeding&#xD;
(P &lt; 0.001) but was lower (P &lt; 0.05) for cows on sainfoin treatment than for cows on&#xD;
alfalfa treatment. The same trend was observed for plasma urea concentration&#xD;
(P = 0.06). Milk performance did not (P &gt; 0.05) differ between treatments. In conclusion,&#xD;
about 25% of sainfoin in the diet can decrease ruminal ammonia and plasma urea&#xD;
concentrations to a certain extent. However, to achieve a greater decrease sainfoin&#xD;
with a higher CT content has to be fed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13978/1/Arrigo_13978.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Arrigo, Herr Yves and Dohme, Frau Frigga    (2009) Einfluss der Zufütterung von tanninhaltiger Esparsette auf den Proteinumsatz von weidenden Milchkühen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13978/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>