<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production and processing of organically grown fiber nettle (Urtica dioica L.) and its potential use in the natural textiles industry: A review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vogl, C. R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hartl, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In Europe, the perennial stinging nettle was cultivated during the 19th century until the Second World War and has a long history as a fiber plant. Clone varieties dating back to the early 20th century are still maintained at European research institutions. The fiber content of clones ranges from 1.2 to 16% dry matter, and fiber yields range from 0.14 to 1.28 Mg/ha. Varietal purity of fiber nettle can only be achieved by planting cuttings. The harvesting of fiber starts in the second year of growth and the crop may produce well for several years. Several agronomic practices influence fiber quality, but causal relations are not yet well understood. Various parts of the fiber nettle plant can be used as food, fodder and as raw material for different purposes in cosmetics, medicine, industry and biodynamic agriculture. Organically produced fibers are in demand by the green textile industry and show potential that is economically&#xD;
promising.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6926/1/AJAA18_3_2003_nettle.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vogl, C. R. and Hartl, A.   (2003) Production and processing of organically grown fiber nettle (Urtica dioica L.) and its potential use in the natural textiles industry: A review.   American Journal of Alternative Agriculture, 18 (3), pp. 119-128.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6926/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>