<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Investigations on alternative substances for control of apple scab - results from sanitation trials</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>B., Pfeiffer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>S., Alt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., Schulz</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>B., Hein</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., Häfner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>A., Kollar</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The intention of this research project, which was supported within the "Bundesprogramm Ökologischer&#xD;
Landbau", was to look for alternatives in organic fruit growing to control apple scab, Venturia&#xD;
inaequalis. One important part of the investigations was the application of different substances like&#xD;
microbiological nutrient media, enzymes usually used for production of fruit juices and organic fertilizers&#xD;
on their effect on the ascospore potential on depots of fallen leaves. Some substances like&#xD;
TRYPTIC SOY BROTH increased the decomposition of the leaves significantly, other like BACTOFIL B&#xD;
and HUMOFIX showed nearly no effect on the decomposition, but reduced the ascospore potential in&#xD;
early spring by 80 % compared to the untreated control.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14078/1/15_Pfeiffer_79_84.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>B., Pfeiffer; S., Alt; C., Schulz; B., Hein; C., Häfner and A., Kollar    (2004) Investigations on alternative substances for control of apple scab - results from sanitation trials.  [Untersuchungen zum Einsatz alternativer Stoffe zur Regulierung des Apfelschorfes Ergebnisse aus den Falllaubversuchen.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 79-84.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14078/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>