<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Pflanzliche Hausmittel der Nordschweiz zur Behandlung von Haut und Wunden beim Nutztier</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Disler, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamburger, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study describes the composition of 34 traditional homemade herbal remedies used by farmers of 7 northern Swiss cantons in 49 different applications regarding wounds and other skin alterations in livestock. Twelve plant species from 8 families were identified. Matricaria recutita L. and Calendula officinalis L. were the most often administered plants both from the most frequently used plant family of Asteraceae. The processing of the formulations was mainly based on oil/fat and water extractions. Farmers used bathes, wash and compresses or simply the direct administration of ointments to the lesions. Regarding recent pharmaceutical and human clinical research results the use of the most often named plant species seems to be eligible.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21402/1/21402_Walkenhorst.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Disler, M.; Schmid, K.; Ivemeyer, S.; Hamburger, M. and Walkenhorst, M.    (2013) Pflanzliche Hausmittel der Nordschweiz zur Behandlung von Haut und Wunden beim Nutztier.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21402/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>