<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswirkungen unterschiedlicher Duroc-Genanteile auf die Fleisch- und Fettqualität ökologisch erzeugter Mastschweine</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brandt, Horst</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baulain, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brade, Wilfried</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lapp, Judith</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weißmann, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the present study including 190 organic fattening pigs of varying Duroc gene portion (0 %, 25 %, 50 %, and 75 %) was to analyze various meat and fat quality characteristics in order to deduce the optimal Duroc gene percentage in relation to different marketing goals. Increasing Duroc gene portions resulted (i) in increasing intramuscular fat contents, (ii) in improved meat quality characteristics (sensory properties, pH, electrical conductivity), (iii) in slightly increasing levels of saturated fatty acids, and (iv) in decreasing levels of mono-unsaturated fatty acids. It is concluded that Duroc gen portion should exceed 50 % only in marketing systems with a payment system including meat quality criteria.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21203/1/21203_Brandth.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brandt, Horst; Baulain, Ulrich; Brade, Wilfried; Lapp, Judith and Weißmann, Friedrich    (2013) Auswirkungen unterschiedlicher Duroc-Genanteile auf die Fleisch- und Fettqualität ökologisch erzeugter Mastschweine.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21203/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>