<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Innovation Research in High-Value Commodity Chains: Lessons Learned</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Henning Høgh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Odhong, Charles</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Odwonga, Richard N</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Halberg, Niels</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Systems research and participatory research</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The current paper reports on the main findings emerging from a research alternative to the two dominant paradigms in agricultural development. This alternative is both context-driven and problem-focused on the rapidly developing East African market-oriented agriculture that demonstrates high economic growth rates based on high-value market-driven commodity chains. The approach to this innovative research in high-value chains includes information feedback loops that bring back translated reports regarding market requirements, retailers’ requests, tailor made production techniques, etc. These reports include price determining information like preferences for certain quality attributes such as colour, size, and texture in addition to extrinsic quality attributes such as food safety, production method, as well as the values that are embedded in certified organic, environmental issues or place of origin. The research was conducted in close collaboration with farmers to increase the adoption rate of the innovations being developed.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Triomphe, Bernard</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23259/7/23259.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jensen, Henning Høgh; Odhong, Charles; Odwonga, Richard N and Halberg, Niels    (2013) Innovation Research in High-Value Commodity Chains: Lessons Learned.       Paper at:   International workshop on Agricultural Innovation Systems in Africa, Nairobi, Kenya, 29th-31st May, 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23259/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>