<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Production of potato crisps and chips in organic farming: Effect of sprinkler irrigation, manure and preceeding crop management of clover grass on yield and quality</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Norbert U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Irrigation and drainage</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In contrast to conventional agriculture the nutrient supply in organic potato production must be secured by preceding crop or organic fertilization. On lighter sites nitrogen mineralisation of organic fertilisation depends highly on water supply. Over two years field experiments with sprinkler irrigation relating to different manure fertilization and varied clover grass management systems (mulching, cut mowing) has been conducted and effects on yield, grading and qualitative properties of  processing potatoes has been surveyed. The tested clover grass management systems showed only a low effect on yield and quality on the following crop potato. In 2003 a small yield increase was  achieved by the mulching system. In the dry year 2003 the sprinkler irrigation had a great effect on yield, grading size and starch content of the potatoes for processing, especially in combination with manure.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8711/1/EAPR_Krause_Oral-end.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krause, Tanja; Böhm, Herwart; Loges, Ralf; Taube, Friedrich and Haase, Norbert U.    (2005) Production of potato crisps and chips in organic farming: Effect of sprinkler irrigation, manure and preceeding crop management of clover grass on yield and quality.   In:     16th Triennial Conference of EAPR - Abstracts of papers and poster, I Programme and oral presentations.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8711/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>