<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Optimisation of downy mildew (Plasmopara viticola) control in organic viticulture with low copper doses, new copper formulations and plant strengtheners,  results of four years of on farm research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hofmann, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heibertshausen, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baus-Reichel, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berkelmann-Loehnertz, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In three different wine growing regions in Germany, due to weather and infection conditions several fungicide (copper formulations) and plant strengtheners (Myco-Sin VIN®, Kendal®, Frutogard ®) applications against downy mildew are required in order to obtain satisfactory disease control. Results of the four years of on farm trials confirmed good efficacy of the copper based substances like copper hydroxide, partly in combination with two or three applications of potassium phosphonate, new copper-hydroxide formulation or copper oxychloride used in a low doses of   copper   and alternative products like Myco-Sin-VIN® (clay with high aluminium  content) in combination with Kendal® ( plant extract).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12483/1/Copper-reduction%2CU.Hofmann.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hofmann, U.; Heibertshausen, D.; Baus-Reichel, O. and Berkelmann-Loehnertz, B.    (2008) Optimisation of downy mildew (Plasmopara viticola) control in organic viticulture with low copper doses, new copper formulations and plant strengtheners, results of four years of on farm research.       Paper at:   Organic wine and viticulture conference, Levizzano near Modena, Italy, June 16 and 17, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12483/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>