<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>International Research Association for Organic Food Quality and Health (FQH)</dc:title>
  <dc:description>The International Research Association for Organic Food Quality and Health aims to establish a network of research institutions specialized in the background of organic food and its effect on human health. &#xD;
&#xD;
Interdisciplinary as well as specialised investigations on organic food quality concepts and novel research methods to study the influence of organic food on human health will be promoted.&#xD;
&#xD;
Activities&#xD;
&#xD;
Through a coordinating secretariat the FQH Association is implementing the following activities:&#xD;
 - implement joint research projects. Combining of resources e.g. by sharing samples for multiple testing as well as staff exchange among institutions to enhance more efficiency and effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
- evaluate, standardise and validate new methods to asses the quality of organic produce and its impact on human health.&#xD;
&#xD;
- organise international scientific conferences on organic food quality and health.&#xD;
&#xD;
- monitor of scientific quality of collective research projects, publications and conferences through a scientific advisory committee.&#xD;
&#xD;
- entertain active interaction with the organic food business and consumer groups to discuss research questions and results.&#xD;
&#xD;
- develop and run a website: www.organicfqhresearch.org&#xD;
&#xD;
- publish reports and articles related and relevant to the subject of organic food quality and health.&#xD;
&#xD;
- mobilise financial resources for the afore mentioned activities from within and outside the association.&#xD;
&#xD;
 &#xD;
Research topics&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
1.  Development of parameters and methods to differentiate between organic and non-organic products, including the development of quality indices.&#xD;
&#xD;
2. Identification and/or development of production and processing methods to obtain high quality food products.&#xD;
&#xD;
3. Determining the influence of organic products on health and disease resistance of human and animals by e.g. :&#xD;
&#xD;
4. Animal food studies&#xD;
Epidemiological research, i.e., on diseases in relation to lifestyle and nutrition; Studies of impact on population groups with diminishing resistance to illnesses.&#xD;
&#xD;
5.  Organic food safety</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Organization description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1155/1/index.html</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Organization}     International Research Association for Organic Food Quality and Health (FQH).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1155/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>