<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of health and welfare planning on the use of antibiotics and udder health in European dairy farms</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ivemeyer, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smolders, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gratzer, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henriksen, B.I.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Huber, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejdell, C.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roderick, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stöger, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vaarst, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Whitstance, L.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Winckler, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Walkenhorst, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>To improve the sustainability of dairy production  it is essential to establish  practices that reduce medicine use whilst safeguarding or improving herd health and productivity. Aiming at minimising medicine use through animal health and welfare planning (AHWP), 111farms in 6 countries were monitored as part of the wide CORE Organic lic ANIPLAN project. For this purpose, the number of udder treatments  with antibiotics was recorded. Somatic cell score (SCS) served as an indicator of udder health, and milk yield and average Iactation number were calculated at the farm Ievel from milk recording data. Treatment  and milk recording data were collected for a one year period before and after a first farm visit. AHWP was carried out either in stable schools or using one-to-one-advice. Generallinearmodels for repeated measures revealed a decrease in udder treatments  with antibiotics over all farms (P=0.004). SCS improved significantly over all farms (P=0.025), whilst milk yield and average Iactation number remained unchanged (P&gt;0.05). Choosing tudder health' as AHWP focus area (58% of the farmers) did not further improve the parameters investigated. The implementation of an AHWP process can be regarded as a feasible approach  to improve udder health and minimise medicine  use without impairment of productivity.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Wageningen Academic Publishers</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hogeveen, H.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lam, T.J.G.M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19962/1/Ivemeyer2011_ANIPLAN-udderhealth_%23imc11.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ivemeyer, S.; Smolders, G.; Brinkmann, J.; Gratzer, E.; Hansen, B. ; Henriksen, B.I.F.; Huber, J.; Leeb, C.; March, S.; Mejdell, C.M.; Roderick, S.; Stöger, E.; Vaarst, M. ; Whitstance, L.K.; Winckler, C.  and Walkenhorst, M.     (2011) Effects of health and welfare planning on the use of antibiotics and udder health in European dairy farms.   In: Hogeveen, H. and Lam, T.J.G.M. (Eds.)  Udder Health and Communication - Proceedings of the international mastitis conference, Wageningen Academic Publishers, pp. 69-76.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19962/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>