<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Host age selection behaviour of Trichogramma aurosum Sugonjaev &amp; Sorokina (Hymenoptera: Trichogrammatidae)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Samara, R.Y.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monje, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Host age selection in several German strains of Trichogramma aurosum Sugonjaev &amp; Sorokina was&#xD;
examined in laboratory choice tests under direct observation for 90 min., in order to select candidate&#xD;
strains for attempts at controlling the codling moth, Cydia pomonella L. (Lepidoptera: Tortricidae).&#xD;
Experiments were conducted at room temperature by exposing combinations of two host ages (zero&#xD;
vs. 4 and 1 vs. 5-day old) to a single female wasp. Host age did not appear to affect the wasps&#xD;
parasitization behaviour, although they spent longer time drilling on old eggs (4 and 5 days old)&#xD;
compared with fresh ones (0 and 1 day old). This not necessarily means that they preferred fresh&#xD;
eggs over old ones, since both type of hosts were parasitized in the choice test. Possibly an increased&#xD;
mechanical resistance of the chorion of older eggs was responsible for the prolonged drilling&#xD;
time. Mean drumming time was independent of host age. Mean duration of drilling and drumming&#xD;
was in general longest in the first and last egg attacked by all T. aurosum strains tested and&#xD;
for all host ages. Drilling time consumed more than 80% of the mean handling time of all strains&#xD;
tested for all host ages, followed by resting and walking.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14547/1/45_Samara_235_239.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Samara, R.Y.; Zebitz, C.P.W. and Monje, J.C.    (2004) Host age selection behaviour of Trichogramma aurosum Sugonjaev &amp; Sorokina (Hymenoptera: Trichogrammatidae).  [Selektion nach Wirtsalter durch Trichogramma aurosum Sugonjaev &amp; Sorokina (Hymenoptera: Trichogrammatidae).]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 235-239.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14547/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>