<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic and low intensive, traditional sheep farming in the Polish Carpathian Mts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Twardy, Dr. Stanislaw</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuzniar, Dr. Antoni</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The Polish Carpathians Mts. occupy about 19.6 thousands km2, which constitute over 6 % of the area of the country. The length of this mountain chain within Poland 's territory is 330 km and width is 60-80 km. In described agricultural land the permanent grasslands dominate. At lower elevation, i.e. about 600-650 m a.s.l. they are moved, and the above this elevation land is utilised as a pasture. In whole area the low input agriculture is practised, usually as sub-sistence farming, i.e. feeding the farmer and his fam-ily. Possible surpluses of food are sold in the local markets or directly to the tourists and holidaymakers, who are rather numerously visiting this glamorous mountain region. The described specific agriculture is favouring the organic production. Hence also in the area under consideration a numerous number of or-ganic farms occurs as well as the farmers who apply-ing for a certification. &#xD;
	The majority of the remaining are following the principles of good agricultural practices, manifesting among others, in careful use of manure and signifi-cant limitation in applying the chemical fertilisers. &#xD;
	In the paper the characteristics of husbandry and breeding of mountain sheep (stock, breed) will be presented as well as grazing management of large flocks, which are utilised for dairy production. Apart from natural determinants, production possibilities referring to plant and animal output will be presented as well as low-input, beyond technical method of pasture and sward improvement &#xD;
	All of the above will be analysed, based on the examples of several organic sheep farms, which are interested also in agro-tourism during summer and winter period. (on the limited scale). Those Farms are localised on an elevation 600-900 m. a.s.l. (the Tatry Mts.) and will be characterised in details as the typi-cal organic farms belonging to the group which are adapting the EC Regulation 2092/91 through local legislation. An analysis will be made of the principal crops (meadow, pasture), stocking rate, welfare, applied medicaments, manuring, and hygienic meas-ures. The results will be supplemented by a synthesis of research data derived from different sources, in-cluding the own research works</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8151/1/Stanislaw_Twardy_Poster_NY.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Twardy, Dr. Stanislaw and Kuzniar, Dr. Antoni    (2006) Organic and low intensive, traditional sheep farming in the Polish Carpathian Mts.       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8151/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>