<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The European Project and Literature Database for Organic Farming Research</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Willer, Helga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently an internet- based platform for organic farming research in Germany and Europe is established as part of the German internet portal for organic farming. This portal is financed by the German Ministry of Consumer Protection, Food And Agriculture within the federal scheme for organic agriculture. An important part of the research platform is a database, containing all relevant results and projects. This database was developed by the Danish Research Centre for Organic Agriculture (DARCOF) and should now become a European database with scientific information related to organic agriculture.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Italian Society for Organic and Biodynamic Animal Husbandry  / Associazione Italiana di Zootecnia Biologica e Biodinamica</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Associazione Italiana di Zootecnia Biologica e Biodinamica,</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/556/2/willer-2003-arezzo.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga    (2003) The European Project and Literature Database for Organic Farming Research.   In: Associazione Italiana di Zootecnia Biologica e Biodinamica,  (Ed.)  Proceedings of the International Symposium: Organic Animal Production: National and International Experiences, Italian Society for Organic and Biodynamic Animal Husbandry / Associazione Italiana di Zootecnia Biologica e Biodinamica.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/556/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>