<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Delayed nutrient application affects mineralisation rate during composting of plant residues</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dresbøll, Dorte Bodin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Ornamentals, flower bulbs and tree nurseries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The hypothesis that delayed addition of nutrient rich material to compost would influence the mineralisation pattern was investigated by studying N turnover in compost based on wheat straw and clover-grass hay. After 7½ weeks of composting almost twice as much N was mineralised when the addition of of some of the N-rich clover-grass hay was postponed, suggesting that this influenced the microbial succession. The delayed addition resulted in a second temperature peak and a decline in the pH. Despite the altered conditions no significant effect was observed on the weight loss or loss of C and N. In conclusion, compost processes can in a simple way be affected by delayed substrate application leading to a higher nutrient availability without altering other parameters significantly.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3419/1/3419.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dresbøll, Dorte Bodin and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian   (2005) Delayed nutrient application affects mineralisation rate during composting of plant residues.   Bioresource Technology, 96, pp. 1093-1101.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3419/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>