<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Department of the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs</dc:title>
  <dc:description>The aim of the Programme is to deliver knowledge to improve organic farming methods and he performance of the organic sector. Research includes assessment of agronomic and conomic performance, investigations into technical barriers to production and appraisal of the impact of organic farming on the environment. The research supports policy evelopment and decision making, and helps inform those considering conversion to organic methods and those already using such methods. &#xD;
This policy programme has two research programmes: &#xD;
Organic Farming: Production and Economics&#xD;
Environmental Impact of Organic Farming&#xD;
The key scientific objectives of the Programme are: &#xD;
(1)To obtain and evaluate data on the agronomic performance and profitability / costs of the main types of organic farm systems, during and after the conversion process (work is being undertaken on the following systems: stockless arable, upland sheep and beef, specialist dairy and field vegetable. &#xD;
(2)To quantify and evaluate the impact of organic farming on the environment, taking into account such externalities as pollution and the costs of dealing with such pollution, as well as the effects on wildlife and landscape quality. This can only be done relative to the impact of conventional production systems and assessed through reliable means of comparative study and evaluation.&#xD;
(3)To identify and develop improved techniques of organic production, in particular to overcome any recognised technical constraints. General areas for study include: optimising crop nutrient supply; methods of weed and pest/disease control; evaluation of the various inputs used (e.g. crop varieties, nutrient sources, animal breeds); and animal health and welfare practices. &#xD;
(4)To ensure that, for all relevant work, knowledge transfer and delivery is maximised.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Organization description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Organization}     DEFRA: Department of the Environment, Food and Rural Affairs.     Organization Leader(s): Murphy Bokern, Donal.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5573/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>