<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>L'impatto di comunità microbiche associate alle radici di melo in suoli stanchi nei meleti dell'Europa centrale</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Manici, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Topp, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gramm, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Perin, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper is a  paper oriented to Italian growers . It  aims at disseminating the main findings of a study performed within Work Package 1 of  BIO-INCROP project that has already been published on Applied Soil Ecology. This short paper presents a survey which refers  to three apple growing areas of Italy, Germany and Austria. The study on soil samples taken from multigeneration apple orchards of  those areas was performed with plant growth assay in pot at Laimburg Research Center (Bolzano Italy), while root-colonizing fungi and nematodes were evaluated in specialized laboratories. The main findings are described with the support of pictures and tables showing the plant growth response in relation to root colonization of rootstock plantlets.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Newspaper or magazine article</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25713/1/Frutticultura_2014.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Manici, L.; Kelderer, M.; Topp, A.; Gramm, D. and Perin, S.    (2014) L'impatto di comunità microbiche associate alle radici di melo in suoli stanchi nei meleti dell'Europa centrale.   Frutticoltura, March 2014, 2014 (3), pp. 32-35.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25713/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>