<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung und Rentabilität verschiedener Präparate von effektiven Mikroorganismen in einem ortsfesten Feldversuch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Urbatzka, Peer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wendland, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Salzeder, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Offenberger, Konrad</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Effective microorganisms (EM) were often applied in organic farming. The influence of three different compounds with EM (EM A, EM ceramic powder, Terra Biosa) was examined as compared with a control without application in a stationary field trial. The trial was conducted in 2004 – 2006 at Freising, Bavaria. Field beans, winter wheat and spring barley were grown. &#xD;
Higher crop yields in the variants with EM A and Terra Biosa application as well as higher crude protein content with EM ceramic powder application were determined compared to the control in each one of the three years. Susceptibility to diseases, resistance to lodging, thousand seed weight, sorting of grain yield and weed abundance were not affected by EM application. Taken into account the costs for compounds and application, the acquired surplus of variants with EM A and Terra Biosa was not profitable.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21081/3/21081_Urbatzka.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Urbatzka, Peer; Wendland, Matthias; Salzeder, Georg and Offenberger, Konrad    (2013) Wirkung und Rentabilität verschiedener Präparate von effektiven Mikroorganismen in einem ortsfesten Feldversuch.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21081/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>