<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Autumn sown catch crop understoreys as strategy to reduce nitrate leaching in winter cereals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mauscherning, Inken</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Taube, Friedhelm</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Under conditions with wet mild winters due to high nitrate leaching risk growing systems with high nitrogen (N) uptake efficiency in autumn are necessary, especially after pre crops with a high N release. In 2003 and 2004 a field trial was conducted in Northern Germany to investigate autumn N uptake and nitrate leaching in autumn sown winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) and winter oilseed rape (Brassica napus) grown intercropped with catch crops. Catch crops in pure stands were sown as control. In each system three catch crops common vetch (Vicia sativa), forage rape (Brassica napus) and oats (Avena sativa) were tested simultaneously. The experiment was run parallel after grass clover (high N status) and oats (low N status). N uptake, soil mineral nitrogen (Nmin) and nitrate leaching of all stands were determined. Especially with winter wheat intercropping with catch crops increased N-uptake in autumn. In all stands forage rape and oats led to a higher N uptake than common vetch. In comparison to pure sown winter wheat, intercropping reduced Nmin by more than 30 %. Nitrate leaching was highest after grass clover. Averaged over both pre crops intercropping of winter wheat and catch crops led to a reduction of nitrate leaching in a range of 38 to 60 %. Grown as intercrop to winter oilseed rape forage rape and oats decreased nitrate leaching compared to pure sown rape by 50 and 39 %, respectively. If cultivation of winter wheat after N intensive pre cop in winter mild climates is wanted, an intercropped production system with catch crops is a mean to reduce N leaching risks. Further investigations are necessary to clarify on yield performance of the main crops when growing together with catch crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12535/1/Loges_12535_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Loges, Ralf; Mauscherning, Inken and Taube, Friedhelm    (2008) Autumn sown catch crop understoreys as strategy to reduce nitrate leaching in winter cereals.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12535/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>