<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of morning vs. afternoon grazing on intramuscular fatty acid composition in lamb</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Vasta, Valentina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Italo Pagano, Renato</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luciano, Guiseppe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Scerra, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Caparra, Pasquale</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Foti, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cilione, Caterina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biondi, Luisa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priolo, Alessandro</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arvondo, Marcella</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to assess whether different grazing management affect animal performance and meat fatty acid composition. Thirty-five lambs were divided into three groups: 12 lambs grazed from 9 am to 5 pm (8h group); 11 lambs grazed from 9 am to 1 pm (4hAM group) and 12 lambs grazed from 1 pm to 5 pm (4hPM group). The trial was conducted over 72 days. The 8h lambs had greater DMI (P &lt; 0.0005) and final body weight (P &lt; 0.05) than the 4hPM and 4hAM lambs while carcass weight was not different between the three groups. The meat of the 4hPM lambs contained greater (P &lt; 0.05) percentages of polyunsaturated fatty acids, C18:2 cis-9 trans-11 and lower saturated fatty acids and C18:0 than the meat of the 8h and 4hAM lambs. It is concluded that allowing lambs to graze during the afternoon rather than during 8 h does not compromise the carcass yield and results in a healthier meat fatty acid profile.&#xD;
Summary&#xD;
&#xD;
This paper was written in the framework of the LowInputBreeds project: “Development of integrated livestock breeding and management strategies to improve animal health, product quality and performance in European organic and ‘low input’ milk, meat and egg production”. The LowInputBreeds project unites 21 partners from Europe and further afield and will develop integrated breeding and management strategies to tackle the issue of improved animal health and food quality. It will run until 2014 and is co-funded by the European Union’s Seventh Framework Programme for Research and Technological Development.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19565/1/Vasta_eta-l2012_Fatty_acids.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Vasta, Valentina; Italo Pagano, Renato; Luciano, Guiseppe; Scerra, Manuel; Caparra, Pasquale; Foti, Francesco; Cilione, Caterina; Biondi, Luisa; Priolo, Alessandro and Arvondo, Marcella   (2012) Effect of morning vs. afternoon grazing on intramuscular fatty acid composition in lamb.   Meat Science, 90 (1), pp. 93-98.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19565/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>