<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Etablierung eines „Beratungsnetzwerks Ökorinderzucht“ auf Basis des ökologischen Gesamtzuchtwerts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Krogmeier, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vogl, Elisabeth</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Metz, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Elsasser, Anton</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Daxenbichler, Anton</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Postler, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The goal of the project „Implementation of a consulting network for ecological dairy breeding based on the ecological total merit index” is the genetic improvement of dairy herds of ecologically working farms in Bavaria. The centerpiece of the project is the development of an ecological module within the internet-based commercial mating program of the LKV Bayern.&#xD;
The ecological mating program automatically analyses the breeding values for all cows and offers adequate sires for mating with respect to the genetic strengths and weaknesses of the cow compared with all cows on ecological farms. By working with the program the farmers get information on the genetic background of the herd and will become sensitized for problems of selection. The program can be handled by the farmer on its own or in the context of different consulting services.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21204/1/21204_Krogmeier.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Krogmeier, Dieter; Vogl, Elisabeth; Metz, Christoph; Elsasser, Anton; Daxenbichler, Anton and Postler, Günter    (2013) Etablierung eines „Beratungsnetzwerks Ökorinderzucht“ auf Basis des ökologischen Gesamtzuchtwerts.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21204/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>