<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Enhancing sorghum (Sorghum bicolar L)-cowpea (Vigna unguiculata L.) intercrop productivity through row arrangements and orientation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Muwanga, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tenywa, J. S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Owuori, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Esele, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Woomer, P.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Currently there is a concern over use of agrochemicals, particularly regarding residual effects. Sorghum and cowpea are staple crops as well as income earners in Uganda, but low yields characterize their output.  Limited research has been done to ameliorate this situation. This study was designed to improve the yields of intercropped sorghum and cowpea. Treatments included row arrangement (1:1 vs 2:2) and orientation (north south vs east west) and pure stands of both cowpea and sorghum. Parameters measured were dry matter and grain yield of intercrops, solar radiation interception, leaf area index and net benefits accruing from both intercrops. East west row orientation accesses greater light interception. Staggered row spacing boosted access to light by the cowpea understorey, leading to improve yield vis-à-vis an alternate row strategy. Finally, it is economically most beneficial to intercrop sorghum-cowpea in staggered double row arrangements.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4337/4/Muwanga_etal_4p_revised-ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Muwanga, S.; Tenywa, J. S.; Owuori, C.; Esele, P. and Woomer, P.L.    (2005) Enhancing sorghum (Sorghum bicolar L)-cowpea (Vigna unguiculata L.) intercrop productivity through row arrangements and orientation.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4337/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>