<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Efficacy of Armicarb (potassium bicarbonate) against scab and sooty blotch on apples.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Amsler, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schärer, Hansjakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Refardt, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A novel formulation of potassium bicarbon-ate (Armicarb) was evaluated in 2004 and 2005 as agent against apple scab and sooty blotch in several field trials. Armicarb controlled scab equally well as the reference treatments sulphur and copper. Armi-carb showed also excellent activity against sooty blotch. However, potential side-effects such as lenti-cell spot development need further investigation. At present, potassium bicarbonate is considered by the Swiss registration authorities as non-toxic to humans and in consequence, no residue levels have been specified. Armicarb has very interesting properties as a plant protection agent and its composition and risk profile are expected to fulfil the IFOAM standards for acceptance of novel plant protection agents to a very large extent.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8075/1/LT_HJS_Armicarb_7.4.06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8075/2/Tamm-etal-2006-Poster_Amicarb.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tamm, Lucius; Amsler, Thomas; Schärer, Hansjakob and Refardt, Matthias    (2006) Efficacy of Armicarb (potassium bicarbonate) against scab and sooty blotch on apples.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8075/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>