<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic olive selected innovations in the production systems in Spain</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Labrador, J</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonzálvez, V</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pajarón, M</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming can be seen as a whole innovation approach, but we can also find some single improved practices which can be diseminanted to other farmers in other regions.In this paper several innovations used in the production chain of olive trees in Spain have been identified in an inquiry made to 200 organic olive oil producers/processors. Some of this innovations were selected and discussed in detail regarding it´s adoption at the expert workshop organised by the Biolmed Project in the framework of the First Spanish Organic Olive oil production Symposium in Córdoba (Spain). The results of this discussions and the reference compilation about the selected innovations are presented here with a shortly description, adventages/disaventages, experiences and information sources. Most of the selected innovations in production methods can be easily adopted by organic farmers</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DIO</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Migliorini, Paola</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Minotou, Charikleia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lusic, Drazen</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hashem, Yousry</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Martinis, Aristotelis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19529/1/05_Labrador_FULL.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Labrador, J; Gonzálvez, V and Pajarón, M    (2011) Organic olive selected innovations in the production systems in Spain.   In: Migliorini, Paola; Minotou, Charikleia; Lusic, Drazen; Hashem, Yousry and Martinis, Aristotelis (Eds.)  Book of Abstract. International Conference on ORGANIC AGRICULTURE and AGRO-ECO TOURSIM in the Mediterranean, DIO.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19529/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>