<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vegetation in Danish field boundaries: A comparative study related to effects of agricultural practise</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Petersen, Sune</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Enrichment of biological diversity is often assumed to reflect good ecosystem integrity. Thus this&#xD;
variable has for some time been a key factor of management strategies and environmental programmes.&#xD;
The aim of the study presented here was primarily to observe, whether organic farming increases the&#xD;
biological diversity of field boundary vegetation when compared to conventional farming. Secondly,&#xD;
the aim was to consider, if increasing duration of the organic farming period also increases diversity.&#xD;
Finally, ecological interpretations of the data were given by comparing different agricultural practises&#xD;
in terms of general vegetation community patterns.&#xD;
The results documented that diversity of plant species was significantly higher within the organic field&#xD;
boundaries. Furthermore, there was a tendency towards higher diversity of plant species in the field&#xD;
boundaries that had been managed organically longest. Finally, analysis of community patterns&#xD;
revealed that Ruderal plant species are indicators of intensive or conventional farming. Altogether this&#xD;
study supports previous conclusions on low-intensive or organic farming as a method of enhancing the&#xD;
integrity of nature within the agricultural landscape.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1386/1/Vegetation_in_field_boundaries.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Petersen, Sune    (2003) Vegetation in Danish field boundaries: A comparative study related to effects of agricultural practise.       [Submitted]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1386/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>