<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Interesse von syrischen Obst- und Gemüseerzeugern auf ökologischen Landbau umzustellen mit dem Ziel des Exportes in die EU</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Issa, Irwa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hamm, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The export of organic fruit and vegetables to the European Union might offer a great opportunity for Syrian farmers and exporters. Yet, the organic sector in Syria is comparatively young and only a very small area of fresh fruit and vegetables (FFV) is organically managed. To date, little is known about Syrian farmers’ attitudes towards organic fruit and vegetable production. Therefore, the aim of this study was to explore the intentions and attitudes of Syrian farmers of FFV towards organic farming and the likelihood of converting their farms to organic production within the next five years. The study was based on a survey among 266 Syrian farmers. The theory of planned behaviour (TPB) was used as theoretical framework and partial least squares structural equation modelling (PLS-SEM) as the main tool for data analysis. The results show that the majority of farmers currently use at least one of the practices, which are also part of certified organic production, and hold strong positive attitudes and intentions to adopt organic production within the next five years.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-09-19</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27180/1/27180_issa.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Issa, Irwa and Hamm, Ulrich    (2014) Interesse von syrischen Obst- und Gemüseerzeugern auf ökologischen Landbau umzustellen mit dem Ziel des Exportes in die EU.       Paper at:   13. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde, 17. - 20. März 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27180/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>