<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alternative treatments in the control of psoroptic&#xD;
mange in a flock of organic production sheep.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Palacios, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lafuente, M.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de la Fuente, L.F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Abstract&#xD;
The aim of the experiment was to verify the efficacy of the treatment of psoroptic mange in a flock of Churra sheep farmed under organic production conditions, using alternative methods. One group, C Control (N=9), was given no treatment, a second group, TAH Antihomotoxic (N=10), was intramuscularly administered an antihomotoxic preparation every two days, thus receiving a total of seven injections over a two-week period. The third group, TCI Citronella (N=10), was topically administered a 1% solution of 50%essential Citronella Java oil and 50% Potassium Soap twice daily, in each milking, during the two-week period. A fourth group, TCIT Citronella+Thymol (N=10), was topically administered Citronella with 1% mother tincture of Thymol to boost the acaricide activity. The results obtained were analysed by ANOVA for scores and improvement of lesions. At the end of the experiment, TCI and TCIT showed significantly fewer lesions (P&lt;0.05) than the control group and TAH, no differences being detected between the latter two groups. Improvement was significantly higher (P&lt;0.05) in TCI (45%) and TCTT (48%) in comparison with the control group,which only showed 3% improvement. TAH improved by 30% (P&lt;0.05) in comparison with the control group. There were no significant differences between TCI and TCIT. &#xD;
In conclusion, treatment with essential Citronella Java oil and potassium soap can be used as an alternative to conventional methods to control psoroptic mange.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18614/1/Palacios_2009_Sheep.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Palacios, C.; Lafuente, M.A. and de la Fuente, L.F.    (2009) Alternative treatments in the control of psoroptic mange in a flock of organic production sheep.   In:     Options Méditerranéennes.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18614/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>