<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Attractive plant volatiles as a control method against apple fruit moth (Argyresthia conjugella Zell.)?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Jaastad, Gunnhild</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knudsen, Geir K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kobro, Sverre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bäckman, Anna-Carin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Witzgall, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bengtsson, Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Apple fruit moth, Argyresthia conjugella Zell. (Lepidoptera: Argyresthiidae), is the most important&#xD;
pest of apples in Scandinavia. In years when its primary host, rowan (Sorbus aucuparia L.), has little&#xD;
or no berries for egglaying, female A. conjugella fly into apple orchards to lay their eggs. In some&#xD;
years the entire apple crop can be destroyed. Volatiles from apples and rowan have been collected&#xD;
and identified. In GC-EAD tests females have responded to several compounds found in both&#xD;
rowan and apple. Some of these compounds were used in field trapping tests during 2002, and a&#xD;
mixture of two compounds trapped significantly more females and males compared to control traps.&#xD;
However, field trapping results from 2003 indicate that the two-compound blend seem to trap insects&#xD;
too late in the season to prevent egglaying in apples. Several new compounds were also&#xD;
tested in 2003, and some of these gave promising results. The results will be discussed in relation&#xD;
to use attractive plant volatiles as a control method against A. conjugella females.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14025/1/6_Jaastad_29_34.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Jaastad, Gunnhild; Knudsen, Geir K.; Kobro, Sverre; Bäckman, Anna-Carin; Witzgall, Peter and Bengtsson, Marie    (2004) Attractive plant volatiles as a control method against apple fruit moth (Argyresthia conjugella Zell.)?   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 29-34.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14025/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>