<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ist die Unterscheidung ökologisch und konventionell erzeugter&#xD;
Milch mittels Nahinfrarotspektroskopie möglich?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Aulrich, Karen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Molkentin, Joachim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of the investigations was to evaluate the ability of NIRS to differentiate between organically and conventionally produced milk. Milk from organic and conventional production systems was analysed for milk fat fatty acid content by gas chromatography, and NIRS calibrations were developed with these reference data by partial least square regression. As a result, a standard error of prediction of 0.099 % for C18:3ω3 and a regression coefficient of 0.9 were obtained. For the prediction of C20:5ω3 the standard error was 0.014 %, and the regression coefficient 0.84. The contents of ω3-fatty acids predicted by NIRS show seasonable differences with a higher level in organic milk samples. The mean value of C18:3ω3 content in organic milk was 0.73 ± 0.16 % and in conventional milk 0.42 ± 0.1%. The mean value of C20:5ω3 content in organic milk was 0.12 ± 0.02 % and in conventional milk 0.08 ± 0.01 %. &#xD;
The results indicated that NIRS had the potential to predict ω3-fatty acids in milk samples and could be used as fast method to monitor the milk production system.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9363/1/Aulrich_9363.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Aulrich, Karen and Molkentin, Joachim    (2009) Ist die Unterscheidung ökologisch und konventionell erzeugter Milch mittels Nahinfrarotspektroskopie möglich?       Poster at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9363/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>