<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>GM Crops in India: Why Open Pandora’s Box?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Das, Kasturi</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>India</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the backdrop of ever increasing resistance against GE in different parts of the globe, the UPA government is planning afresh to give transgenic crops a big push. A panel has been set up to formulate a National Biotechnology Policy by January 2005 so as to ensure a speedy approval of GM crops. The panel is likely to gather key inputs from the ‘Report of the Task Force on Application of Biotechnology in Agriculture’ headed by Dr. M.S. Swaminathan, who is again a member of the new panel. In this context the article reveals certain glaring flaws and contradictions inherent in the Task Force Report, that need to be taken into account before actually accepting its recommendations while formulating the proposed Biotechnology Policy. It analyses why promotion of GM crops is not compatible with economic wellbeing and livelihood security of farmers, health security of consumers, protection of environment, external trade and so on. Hence it calls for a moratorium on GM crops in India until conclusive scientific evidences are found regarding their short and long term implications. Finally it argues that the solution for the ongoing crisis in Indian agriculture lies in organic agriculture and not in genetic engineering, which is likely to worsen the situation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>www.gmwatch.org</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2004-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Web product</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4107/1/GM_Crops_in_India-Published.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Das, Kasturi    (2004) GM Crops in India: Why Open Pandora’s Box?   www.gmwatch.org.  Online at &lt;http://www.gmwatch.org/p1temp.asp?pid=54&amp;page=1 &lt;http://www.gmwatch.org/p1temp.asp?pid=54&amp;page=1&gt;&gt;.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4107/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>