<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung betriebsangepasster Strategien zur Reduktion des Kraftfuttereinsatzes in Bio-Milchviehbetrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Steinwidder, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Starz, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gotthardt, Agnes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pfister, Rupert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rohrer, Hannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In a three year on-going project 10 organic dairy farms are supervised by developing farm adopted strategies to reduce the concentrate input in dairy cow feeding. The researchers and advisors consult and accompany the pioneering group. They stimulate active learning and record the results and experiences. Different approaches are used in the project to achieve the project aim: (1) discussions about possible strategies and their results (2) on-farm documentations and observational research, monitoring and comparison, (3) evaluation and systematic inclusion of the experiences of farmers (stable schools), advisors and researchers in the project, (4) describing “systems that work”. Within the first two project years, farmers reduced the concentrate input from 925 to 770 kg per cow or 146 g to 121 g concentrate per kg produced ECM. Milk yield, milk composition animal health and fertility as well as economic results were not influenced negatively by reducing the concentrate input.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21195/1/21195_steinwidder.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Steinwidder, Andreas; Starz, Walter; Gotthardt, Agnes; Pfister, Rupert and Rohrer, Hannes    (2013) Entwicklung betriebsangepasster Strategien zur Reduktion des Kraftfuttereinsatzes in Bio-Milchviehbetrieben.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21195/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>