<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrated larvae production for feed in organic egg production</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project objectives are: &#xD;
&#xD;
- to develop and demonstrate a robust system to produce a new organic feed supplement consisting of live insect larvae with an ideal amino acid composition. The project provides a sustainable way to meet the requirement from EU for organic farms (100% organic feed by 2012) and improved animal welfare in poultry flocks. &#xD;
&#xD;
- to investigate the effect of larvae growth on the microbiology of the manure, including selected pathogens and human zoonotic bacteria to assess the microbiological safety to the system, &#xD;
&#xD;
- to investigate a prebiotic effect in the digestive system of poultry, &#xD;
&#xD;
- to demonstrate that the integrated ON-farm system is ideal for treating animal manure through composting with larvae and thereby recycle energy, N and P,&#xD;
&#xD;
- to investigate the effect of feeding on organic meat and eggs produced with the new feed composition through taste tests and laboratory tests,&#xD;
&#xD;
- and to demonstrate the high value of larvae digested manure as greenhouse and garden organic fertilizer product.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19605/1/BIOCONVAL.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    BIOCONVAL: Integrated larvae production for feed in organic egg production.  [Integreret larveproduktion til foder i økologisk ægproduktion.]   Runs 2011 - 2013.      Project Leader(s): Hansen, Arne Grønkjær , Teknologisk Institut.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19605/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>