<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Feeding strategies in Swiss organic farming to improve food quality and animal health</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Früh, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>At the moment, Switzerland has about 6,500 organic farmers, with 11 % of the agriculture area managed organically. The main regulations in organic farming are The Schweizer Bio-Verordnung (Swiss Government Regulation for Organic farming). These regulations are increasingly adapted to the EU-Regulation for organic farming. The BIO SUISSE regulation has further requirements. Nearly all organic farmers are BIO SUISSE farmers. The symbol of BIO SUISSE is a bud.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hovi, Malla</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sundrum, Albert</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Padel, Susanne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3321/1/frueh-2004-feeding-strategies-in-swiss-organic-farming.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Früh, Barbara    (2004) Feeding strategies in Swiss organic farming to improve food quality and animal health.    In: Hovi, Malla; Sundrum, Albert and Padel, Susanne (Eds.)   Organic livestock farming: potential and limitations of husbandry practice to secure animal health and welfare and food quality. Proceedings of the 2nd SAFO Workshop 25-27 March 2004, Witzenhausen, Germany.  SAFO Sustaining Animal Health and Food Safety in Organic Farming. A European Commission funded Concerted Action Project., pp. 55-57.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3321/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>