<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Residues in beeswax after conversion to organic beekeeping</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lodesani, Dr Marco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Costa, Dr Cecilia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Beekeepers interested in converting their honey farms to organic management must replace old combs with organic foundations. The experiment described in this paper compares two methods of replacement of old combs, “fast” (5 combs per year) and “slow” (2 combs per year), by measuring the levels of acaricide residues in the newly built combs. Considered acaricides were coumaphos (Perizin and Asuntol), fluvalinate (Apistan) and clorfenvinphos (Supona). Significant differences between the two replacement groups were observed only for the Apistan group in the third year, confirming high lipophilicity of fluvalinate. The residue levels in the newly built combs three years after beginning the conversion were significantly lower than initial levels for all products. Direct contamination of the combs was evaluated at the beginning of the trial and was found to be highest in Asuntol-treated hives and lowest in Perizin-treated hives. Residues in honey exceeding EU Maximum Residue Limit were found only in the case of Asuntol.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11602/1/Lodesani_11602_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lodesani, Dr Marco and Costa, Dr Cecilia    (2008) Residues in beeswax after conversion to organic beekeeping.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11602/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>