<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Waste composts as nitrogen fertilizers for forage leys</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tontti, Tiina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nykänen, Arja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kuisma, Miia</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two field experiments, conventional grass ley and organic grass-clover ley, were established with barley as a nurse crop in spring 2000 and given either low or high fertilization with mineral fertilizer (Mineral) or composts. The compost types were municipal biowaste (Biowaste), biowaste + sewage sludge (BioSludge) and cattle manure (Manure). Plant yields and nitrogen (N) uptakes were measured for three years and efficiency of N utilization was estimated. In single application of compost, the total N was mainly in organic form and less than 10% was in inorganic form. Along with increasing amount of inorganic N applied in compost, the yield, N uptake and N recovery increased during the application year. The highest compost N recovery in the application year was 12%, found with Biowaste. In the following years the highest N recovery was found where the lowest total N had been applied. Clover performance was improved in the organic grass-clover ley established with BioSludge fertilization, producing total ley yield comparable with Manure compost. High total N application in composts caused high N surplus and low N use efficiency over three years. Generally, moderate compost fertilization is suitable for ley crops when supplemented with mineral N fertilizer or clover N fixation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>MTT Agrifood Research Finland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16627/1/tontti.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tontti, Tiina; Nykänen, Arja and Kuisma, Miia   (2009) Waste composts as nitrogen fertilizers for forage leys.   Agricultural and Food Science, 18 (1), pp. 57-75.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16627/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>