<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of seed rate and row spacing in seed production of Festulolium</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Deleuran, L.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gislum, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boelt, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Establishment methods have proven to be of major importance for grass seed production. The objective of this research was to test the effect of different sowing techniques on plant establishment and the subsequent seed yield. Perennial ryegrass (Lolium perenne L.) is used as the model grass due to its large importance in Danish agriculture.&#xD;
In a three-year trial six different methods of under-sowing of perennial ryegrass in a spring barley cover crop were employed. Perennial ryegrass was either sown directly at different depths within the spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) rows or placed 2, 6 or 12 cm from the spring barley rows. Results of dry matter yield indicate that the best establishment of the grass occurred when placing the grass 6 or 12 cm from the cover crop row, and this is of importance in less vigorous grasses. Overall, no seed yield difference has been observed for perennial ryegrass when placing the grass 2, 6 or 12 cm from the cover crop row. Placement of the ryegrass seed crop 6 cm from the cereal row showed that a significant yield increase of 34-71 kg ha-1 can be obtained compared to sowing in the cereal row.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9066/2/9066.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Deleuran, L.C.; Gislum, R. and Boelt, B.   (2010) Effect of seed rate and row spacing in seed production of Festulolium.   Acta Agrculturae Scandinavia. Section B. Soil and Plant Science, 60 (2), pp. 152-156.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9066/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>