<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Promoting sustainable consumption and healthy eating:&#xD;
A comparative study among public schools in Denmark, Germany, Finland &amp; Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>He, Chen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since the Ottawa charter on the importance of health promotion in settings the school has been&#xD;
named as one of the most important arenas for interventions to promote physical activity and&#xD;
healthy eating. Especially the school food service has been the object of a change agenda that has&#xD;
been named the European school food revolution. This revolution is characterized not only&#xD;
attempts to promote healthy eating but also by attempts to make food supply and consumption&#xD;
more sustainable by integrating organic procurement policies. The current study aims at&#xD;
investigating how these two agendas work together. Do they compete or do they go hand in hand&#xD;
as previous studies suggest? And if this is the case does organic food schemes at school and related&#xD;
curricular activities then induce healthier eating behaviours among children? The research that is&#xD;
part of the iPOPY study was conducted among school food coordinators in public&#xD;
primary/secondary schools (children age from 6 to 15 years old) in Denmark, Germany, Finland and&#xD;
Italy. The study was initiated in Denmark, and subsequently performed in the other three countries&#xD;
through a web‐based questionnaire. The questionnaire was translated and adapted to fit the&#xD;
different languages and food cultures. The questionnaire researched the attitude, policies and&#xD;
serving practices regarding promoting organic foods and healthy eating habits through school food&#xD;
service and classroom activities. The data suggest that schools with organic supply tend to develop&#xD;
organisational environments that a more supportive for healthy eating than their non organic&#xD;
counterparts. However the results were only significant for Denmark and Italy, In Germany results&#xD;
were significant in some cases where as for Finland there were no differences or results were&#xD;
contradictory. The findings suggest the school food revolution is driven by different agendas but&#xD;
that awareness raising on nutrition and sustainability issues seems to be an important feature of&#xD;
many change processes. Findings also suggest that the two agendas although separated in the&#xD;
scientific literature is much more integrated in the everyday life perspective of school practitioners</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-07-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17325/1/preIUHPEGenevaABS%2BPPT.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>He, Chen and Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg    (2010) Promoting sustainable consumption and healthy eating: A comparative study among public schools in Denmark, Germany, Finland &amp; Italy.       Workshop at:   Linking Health, Equity &amp; Sustainability in Schools CICG, Geneva, July 10-11, 2010.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17325/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>