<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of Biogas Digestion of Slurry, Cover Crops and Crop Residues on Nitrogen Cycles and Crop Rotation Productivity of a Mixed Organic Farming System</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Möller, Dr. Kurt</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stinner, Walter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Manures and crop residues can be utilised for digestion, without any significant losses of nutrients. This paper presents the results of field trials about the effects of biogas digestion in a mixed organic cropping systems on nutrient cycling and yield of a whole crop rotation. Digestion of slurry affected yields and N uptake only after soil incorporation. The inclusion of crop residues for digestion increased the amounts of “mobile” manure. N uptake and yield of non-leguminous main crops increased about 10%, due to a more adapted allocation of nutrients within the whole cropping system by reallocation of N towards the crops with higher N needs. Additionally, removing the cover crops in autumn and their digestion increased the fertilizing efficiency of N, lowering the risk of leaching losses.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12308/1/Moeller_12308_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Möller, Dr. Kurt; Stinner, Walter and Leithold, Prof. Dr. Günter    (2008) Effects of Biogas Digestion of Slurry, Cover Crops and Crop Residues on Nitrogen Cycles and Crop Rotation Productivity of a Mixed Organic Farming System.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12308/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>