<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of intercropping and irrigation frequencies in the leaf development and taro (Cocoyam) productivity under organic management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Silva, Edmilson Evangelista da</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Azevedo, Pedro Henrique Sabadin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Almeida, Maxwell Merçon Tezolin Barros</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>De-Polli, Helvécio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Guerra, José Guilherme Marinho</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Irrigation and drainage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this work was to evaluate the influence of the intercropping and irrigation frequencies in the leaf development and productivity of taro (Colocasia esculenta) under organic management. The experiment was set up as a randomized complete block design, a factorial 2 x 2, with four replications. Taro was cultivated in monoculture or intercropped with Crotalaria juncea under two irrigation frequencies: every 3.5 days for 30 minutes and every 15 days for 2 hours. The intercropping increased taro petiole length but did not increase leaf area. The same effects were observed for irrigation frequency on the leaf area and petiole, length at the 30th and 60th days after C. juncea cutting. The amount of taro yield and offshoot number of class 1 (category up to 40g) were affected negatively by the intercropping. However the total number, total yield and average weight of the offshoot were not affected by the intercropping. The irrigation frequency promoted positive effects in the number and weight of offshoot (category of 80g weight or higher), as well as in the total taro yield and average offshoot weight. The conclusion was that the short frequency irrigation contributed for the development and productivity of taro offshoots and the intercropping with C. juncea did not decreased  the total productivity of taro cropping.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12595/1/Silva_12595_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Silva, Edmilson Evangelista da; Azevedo, Pedro Henrique Sabadin; Almeida, Maxwell Merçon Tezolin Barros; De-Polli, Helvécio and Guerra, José Guilherme Marinho    (2008) Influence of intercropping and irrigation frequencies in the leaf development and taro (Cocoyam) productivity under organic management.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12595/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>