<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparing attitudes and characteristics of&#xD;
organic, former organic and conventional&#xD;
farmers: Evidence from Ireland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Läpple, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Despite an overall growth rate of the organic farming sector in the European Union, a considerable number of farmers&#xD;
cease organic production each year. Given the commitment of many European governments to increase the size of their&#xD;
organic farming sectors, reducing the rate of withdrawals from organic production may be an easier option than&#xD;
attracting new farmers into organic farming. In order to reduce the rate of withdrawals, knowledge about those farmers is&#xD;
required. However, to date, little is known about farmers who adopt and subsequently abandon organic farming. This&#xD;
study attempts to fill this gap in the literature by comparing and contrasting the farm and personal characteristics of&#xD;
organic, former organic and conventional farmers. To this end, primary data from 596 Irish cattle and sheep farmers are&#xD;
utilized. Overall, the findings reveal significant differences between the three groups. More specifically, organic farmers&#xD;
are found to be the most environmentally aware farmers, who also rate information gathering as more important than the&#xD;
remaining two groups. Organic farmers are younger, better educated and more likely to be women than conventional&#xD;
farmers. Former organic farmers stand out to be the least risk averse group and also express lower environmental&#xD;
awareness than organic farmers. Conventional farmers are found to be the most profit oriented and least environmentally&#xD;
aware group. In addition, this group farms more intensely stocked enterprises than the remaining groups. The paper&#xD;
concludes with a discussion of some policy recommendations aimed at increasing the size of the organic sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Läpple, D.    (2012) Comparing attitudes and characteristics of organic, former organic and conventional farmers: Evidence from Ireland.   Renewable Agriculture and Food Systems, - (-), pp. 1-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22495/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>