<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Integrative control of  herbivore parasitism through better use of treatments and pastures. Tools for controlling anthelmintic use in small ruminants in organic agriculture : from animal to pasture.</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>All  grazing ruminants harbour parasites and in particular digestive-tract strongyles.  In organic farming the farmers cannot fully rely on anthelmintic treatments. Since alternative treatments are not yet available, two main possibilities for control are  the targeted selective treatment using synthetic anthelmintics at the right moment to the right animal or mixed/alternate grazing of cattle and sheep when feasble.  The targeted selective treatments necessitates more diagnostic, more time spent on the examination of animals and this requires willingness  to cooperate of the farmers. Even if the DISCO method (Diaerrhea score) or Famacha( degree of anemia based on colour of the eyelid to interpret anaemia) has proven technically valuable, it is noot sure they will be accepted in practice. An acceptance sociological study will be first undertaken to asses pro and cons in views of farmer, and to further  adapt the use of both methods (Disco and Famacha). &#xD;
The materials and methods employed are :&#xD;
1)	Evaluation of Disco in ewes and lambs (4 flocks/2 sites) at the Redon-Orcival Platform in Auvergne-France : number of samples/ individual versus group faecal samples/ in terms of actual parasitism-2005/2006&#xD;
2)	Evaluation of the Disco and Famacha in lambs grazed on pasture  articially seeded with plurispecific nematodes originating from the Basque country- 2005&#xD;
3)	Acceptance of Disco and Famacha on farms (Redon-Orcival; 10 private farms in Auvergne and 30 French Basque country : questionnaire co-written by parasitologist and a sociologist/visit/postal questionnaire-2006&#xD;
4)	Mixed grazing with cattle is currently studied at the Cambon public farm in Auvergne  2005-2006&#xD;
The result should be the promotion of indicators available to farmers associated with laboratory results. Leaflets and a web site would be the endterm of the study. Classical extension and scientific litterature should be produced in journals of the field</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Integrative control of herbivore parasitism through better use of treatments and pastures. Tools for controlling anthelmintic use in small ruminants in organic agriculture : from animal to pasture.    Runs 2005 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Cabaret, Jacques, INRA.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6802/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>