<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The influence of post-emergence weed harrowing on selectivity, crop recovery and crop yield in different growth stages of winter wheat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rueda–Ayala , Victor</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Jesper</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gerhards , Roland</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fournaise , N.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Crop tolerance and weed control in winter wheat were investigated to evaluate the influence of post-emergence weed harrowing at different crop growth stages on selectivity, crop recovery and crop yield. The importance&#xD;
of growth stage was investigated in autumn (Denmark) and spring (Germany). Selectivity was chosen as a measure of the relationship between weed control and crop soil cover, with crop recovery as a measure of how crop yield was affected by soil cover in the absence of weeds. Selectivity was unaffected by crop growth stage in autumn and spring. In autumn, 80% weed control was associated with 6% crop soil cover, whereas in spring, 80% weed control corresponded to 26% crop soil cover. Crop recovery was higher in late growth stages in autumn and spring. With 25% crop soil cover, crop yield losses occurred in the ranges of 1–4% in autumn and 0.3–0.8% in spring. Weed control experiments revealed that the maximum crop yield response&#xD;
to harrowing was comparable with herbicide treatment. The average yield gain was 13% in autumn (Denmark)&#xD;
and 27% in spring (Germany). This study contributes parameter estimates that can be used in future models to&#xD;
evaluate optimum harrowing intensity.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20110/4/20110.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rueda–Ayala , Victor; Rasmussen, Jesper; Gerhards , Roland and Fournaise , N.A.   (2011) The influence of post-emergence weed harrowing on selectivity, crop recovery and crop yield in different growth stages of winter wheat.   Weed Research, 51, pp. 478-488.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20110/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>