<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wie lässt sich das Vertrauen der Konsumenten in Bio-Lebensmittel erhöhen?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, Hanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Flurina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermanowski, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baumgart, Lukas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Morgner, Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kriege-Steffen, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boland, Hermann</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Trust is seen as one of the most crucial aspects when consumers decide whether or not to buy organic products. Our research investigates consumer trust in organic food and the effectiveness of enhancing consumer trust by communication strategies on traceability in a quantitative survey of 900 consumers in Germany. The survey focuses on consumer trust in the different actors involved in the organic supply chain as well as on criteria for assessing trustworthiness of organic products. The data analysis includes descriptive statistics and correlation analysis as well as multivariate analysis to identify distinct consumer segments with respect to specific trust characteristics and organic food consumption frequency. The results shall contribute to develop communication strategies for enhancing consumer trust in organic food.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17612/2/Stolz_17612.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Stolz, Hanna; Stolze, Matthias; Schneider, Flurina; Hermanowski, Robert; Baumgart, Lukas; Morgner, Marion; Kriege-Steffen, Astrid and Boland, Hermann    (2011) Wie lässt sich das Vertrauen der Konsumenten in Bio-Lebensmittel erhöhen?       Poster at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17612/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>