<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Undersowing legume crops for green manuring of lettuce</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, Jørn Nygaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The objective of this experiment was to investigate the potential of several species of undersown legume crops to deplete soil nitrate and to accumulate nitrogen. A further objective was to measure the effects of the legume crops as a green manure for a succeeding early lettuce crop. In two years, different undersown legume crops were compared to a control treatment where no crop was undersown. In November, at the end of their growing season, the legume crops reduced the content of mineral nitrogen in the top 1 m of the soil to one third of what was available when no crop was undersown. The N uptake in shoots and roots was in the range of 100-160 kg ha-1. The legume crops were incorporated at the beginning of April the succeeding year. In May, the content of soil mineral nitrogen was 3-4 fold the content in November. The main increase was seen in the top 0.25 m profile of the soils in which the legume crops had been grown. In July, the N mineralized from the incorporated legume crops and from other soil organic matter was estimated to be 36 and 38 kg ha-1, respectively. The yield of lettuce was increased by 20-45% when grown after legume green manure crops compared with the control treatment. The yield level was comparable to that obtained in conventional horticulture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1204/2/Biological_Agriculture_and_Horticulture_2003.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sørensen, Jørn Nygaard and Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian   (2003) Undersowing legume crops for green manuring of lettuce.  [Undersåning af bælgplanter til grøngødskning af salat.]  Biological Agriculture and Horticulture, 21 (4), pp. 399-414.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1204/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>