<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Operational strategies for optimizing grazing when using automatic milking systems in organic dairy production</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Oudshoorn, F.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Spörndly, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Buildings and machinery</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Successful grazing when using AMS is possible without having to devote a great deal of time to organize and fetch cows every day. However, a careful strategy and good infrastructure, and observation of cow behaviour and pasture  are necessary, and the herd has to adapt to the chosen design and routines. In practice, sectional permanent grazing, part-time grazing and structured rotational grazing have been shown to be successful, in terms of allowing outdoor grazing while still maintaining milking frequency and milk yield. In addition, part-time grazing can be combined with either of the other two systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Løes, Anne-Kristin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Langer, Vibeke</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Partanen, Kirsi</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pehme, Sirli</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Salomon, Eva</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sørensen, Peter</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ullvén, Karin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wivstad, Maria</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2013-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24571/1/24571.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Oudshoorn, F.W. and Spörndly, E.    (2013) Operational strategies for optimizing grazing when using automatic milking systems in organic dairy production.   In: Løes, Anne-Kristin; Askegaard, Margrethe; Langer, Vibeke; Partanen, Kirsi; Pehme, Sirli; Rasmussen, Ilse A.; Salomon, Eva; Sørensen, Peter; Ullvén, Karin and Wivstad, Maria (Eds.)  Organic farming systems as a driver for change, NJF Report, no. 9 (3), pp. 129-130.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24571/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>