<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Successfull Blossom Thinning and Crop Load Regulation for Organic Apple Growing with Potassium-bi-carbonate (Armicarb(R)): Results of Field Experiments over 3 Years and with 11 Cultivars</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weibel, Franco P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lemcke, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Monzelio, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Giordano, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kloss, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>With field trials over 3 years in a commercial organic orchard in Switzerland we have tested the efficacy of Armicarb® (potassium-bi-carbonate) for flower thinning in organic apple production. Over time, Armicarb was tested on 11 cultivars, at different application periods, in different concentrations, and always in comparison to other agents that are already allowed for thinning in organic fruit production in the European Union as e.g. lime sulphur, molasses, mechanical rope-thinner or combinations of methods. Armicarb proved to be an efficient and reliable thinning agent with an efficacy similar to the now recommended methods with rope device, molasses or lime sulphur but has the advantage to be an environmentally very friendly product. On the other hand, the risk for fruit russeting is comparably elevated especially with cultivars ‘Elstar’, ‘Golden Del.’ ’and ‘Gala’. Finally, we have elaborated cultivar-specific recommendations for the use of Armicarb for thinning purposes, which were the basis for the Swiss Federal approval to use Armicarb for thinning in conventional and organic apple production in 2011/2012.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21154/1/ejhs_thinning_Armicarb_13-12.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weibel, Franco P.; Lemcke, B.; Monzelio, U.; Giordano, I. and Kloss, B.   (2012) Successfull Blossom Thinning and Crop Load Regulation for Organic Apple Growing with Potassium-bi-carbonate (Armicarb(R)): Results of Field Experiments over 3 Years and with 11 Cultivars.  [Erfolgreiche Blütenausdünnung und Behangsregulierung für den biologischen Apfelanbau mit Kalium-bicarbonat (Armicarb (R)): Resultate von 3-jährigen Feldexperimenten mit 11 Sorten.]  European Journal of Horticultural Science, 77 (4), pp. 145-153.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21154/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>