<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Raumbezogene und multivariate Analyse der Einflussgrößen auf den Weißkleeanteil eines Dauergrünlandstandortes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gottardi, Sara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fricke, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The relationship between white clover (Trifolium repens), site conditions, species composition and forage quality has been analysed by conducting a factor analysis (incl. varimax rotation) based on data sets sampled along a 50 m grid on a 20 ha permanent grassland site in Central Germany with heterogeneous site conditions, sown in 1998. Three factors which are related to the appearance of white clover has been interpreted, showing a positive relationship of white clover to (A) Lolium perenne on heavy and productive soils, (B) Poa pratensis and Festuca rubra on heavy and stony soils at slopes and ridges and (C) Lolium perenne and weeds on wet soils along the field border, often characterised by sward damage. The white clover factor loadings sometimes are not very strong, depending on complex interactions and a distinct site heterogeneity. Further analysis is in progress.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3807/1/3807.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gottardi, Sara and Fricke, Thomas    (2005) Raumbezogene und multivariate Analyse der Einflussgrößen auf den Weißkleeanteil eines Dauergrünlandstandortes.  [Spatial and multivariate analysis of factors influencing white clover proportions on a permanent grassland site in Central Germany.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3807/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>