<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic breeding should select for plant genotypes able to efficiently exploit indigenous Probiotic Rhizobacteria</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bosco, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baruffa, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Picard, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In order to rapidly achieve crop varieties adapted to organic crop production systems, it is of crucial importance to know plant genotype potential for positive interactions with soil indigenous microflora. In this frame, European research efforts are now considering beneficial non-symbiotic (probiotic) rhizobacteria as an essential factor for sustainable plant breeding. Published findings are beginning to elucidate how probiotic rhizobacteria contribute to plant nutrient assimilation and disease resistance. Future efforts for crop breeding in organic agriculture should take into the right account the capacity of plants to efficiently exploit indigenous probiotic rhizobacteria in low-input cultural conditions.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>DARCOF</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Andreasen, C. Bo</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Elsgaard, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sondegaard Sorensen, L.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hansen, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8645/1/Bosco_et_al_word.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8645/2/Bosco_et_al_JOC-2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bosco, M.; Baruffa, E. and Picard, C.    (2006) Organic breeding should select for plant genotypes able to efficiently exploit indigenous Probiotic Rhizobacteria.   In: Andreasen, C. Bo; Elsgaard, L.; Sondegaard Sorensen, L. and Hansen, G. (Eds.)  Organic Farming and European Rural Development - Proceedings of the European Joint Organic Congress, DARCOF, pp. 376-377.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8645/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>