<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Below ground nitrogen dynamics in the sequence clover-grass maize in the DOK long term experiment</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mayer, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oberson, Astrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>L端scher, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frossard, Emmanuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hammelehle, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigated the effect of organic versus conventional cropping systems on the below ground nitrogen inputs of Trifolium pratense L., its transfer to corresponding grass and the fate in the soil organic matter in the clover-grass ley of the DOK long term experiment, Switzerland. BGN tended to be largest in conventional and organic treatments with standard fertilisation and decreased with lower fertilisation intensity. The largest amount of clover N transferred to grass was observed in the minerally fertilised conventional treatment. Clover N derived from rhizodeposition was rapidly stabilised in all treatments to clay rich fractions and thus clover N will have a relatively low direct N contribution to subsequent nonlegumes.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Th端nen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24030/1/24030_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mayer, Jochen; Oberson, Astrid; L端scher, Andreas; Frossard, Emmanuel and Hammelehle, Andreas    (2014) Below ground nitrogen dynamics in the sequence clover-grass maize in the DOK long term experiment.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Th端nen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 4, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 1031-1034.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24030/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>