<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic vine growing: from breaking new ground to bringing back the taste of the terroir</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>TEIL, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>BARREY, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming certification has certainly contributed to unifying organic production, particularly by reducing the number of private charters. However, this reduction should not be misleading. Organic agriculture cannot be reduced to just a label and includes other requirements related to ethics, agronomy and economic policy whose implementation contributes to the diversification of marketing organisations that selectively ensure the marketing of organic products. Furthermore, in the case of viticulture, organic producers have recently placed more emphasis on the taste quality of their wines that they have linked in various ways to the quality of the environment. This new link between taste and environment has added a new complexity to marketing organisations and has given impetus to the use of environmentally-friendly vine-growing practices that have become a resource for the development of wines that are strongly identified with a terroir. Therefore, an increasing number of quality wines make use of organic or biodynamic practices to make better wines that are more representative of the quality of their terroir, but that do not emphasize the corresponding certification in order to keep their quality message clear.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15448/1/51-Teil.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>TEIL, G.  and BARREY, S.    (2009) Organic vine growing: from breaking new ground to bringing back the taste of the terroir.  [La viticulture biologique : de la recherche d’un monde nouveau au renouvellement du goût de terroir.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 427-440.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15448/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>