<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tests on the effectiveness of mass trapping by Eco-trap (Vyoril) in the control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin) in organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Caleca, Virgilio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rizzo, Roberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Battaglia, Isabella</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Palumbo Piccionello, Manuela</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Tests on the effectiveness of mass trapping by Eco-trap  (Vyoril) in the control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin) in organic farming were carried out in 2003 and 2004. The tests took place into two organic olive groves located in Agrigento and Trapani (Sicily); in both years the olive cultivar was Cerasuola. In Agrigento, it was considered the effectiveness of Eco-trap vs. bottle traps baited with diammonium phosphate; while in Trapani the effectiveness of Eco-trap added to other products admitted in organic farming (two products containing kaolin and one containing copper) was evaluated. In 2003, year with a low B. oleae population density, no statistically significant difference resulted among Eco-trap, bottle traps with diammonium phosphate and control. In 2004 B. oleae infestations were high; although some statistically significant differences among plots with Eco-traps and plots without them emerged, the additional power of Eco-trap in controlling B. oleae resulted very limited in plots sprayed with kaolin products and more consistent in the plot with copper hydroxide. The economic advantage of the use of Eco-trap, also in comparison with repellent and antiovipositional products, still remains doubtful.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7976/1/Caleca_et_alIOBC.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Caleca, Virgilio; Rizzo, Roberto; Battaglia, Isabella and Palumbo Piccionello, Manuela   (2007) Tests on the effectiveness of mass trapping by Eco-trap (Vyoril) in the control of Bactrocera oleae (Gmelin) in organic farming.   IOBC WPRS Bulletin.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7976/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>