<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>N USE AND PARTITIONING IN CORIANDER (CORIANDRUM SATIVUM L.)&#xD;
AFTER ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL N FERTILIZATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Carrubba, Alessandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Militello, Marcello</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Catalano, Caterina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In coriander, a well known spice herb, many studies concerning the effect of N fertilization have been conducted in special areas where the cultivation of such plant has a major importance, such as India. Limited information is available as concerns the response of coriander to N fertilization under Mediterranean climatic conditions, above all when organic N fertilizers (mandatory when organic cropping management is chosen) are used. This work refers about some observations realised from 2004 to 2006 by an experiment on organic and mineral N fertilization techniques in coriander, carried on in the experimental farm “Sparacia”&#xD;
(Cammarata, AG, Sicily). Similarly to what suggested for other species, each year at harvest time, for each fertilizer treatment, seeds yield and plant biomass were weighed and the respective N content was determined in order to compare N plant uptake with total and mineral N measured in the soil before and after cropping cycle. From such data a few indices were calculated in order to get information about the efficiency of use by plants of the tested N forms. Some differences in N partitioning and use efficiency according to treatment were noticed, suggesting an overall higher efficiency of N chemical fertilizers.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fertilitas Agrorum</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Sequi, P.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ferri, D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Montemurro, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vonella, Alessandro Vittorio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Fornaro, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20545/1/Roma_Nfert_Npart.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Carrubba, Alessandra; Militello, Marcello and Catalano, Caterina    (2009) N USE AND PARTITIONING IN CORIANDER (CORIANDRUM SATIVUM L.) AFTER ORGANIC AND CONVENTIONAL N FERTILIZATION.   In: Sequi, P.; Ferri, D.; Montemurro, F.; Vonella, Alessandro Vittorio and Fornaro, F. (Eds.)  MORE SUSTAINABILITY IN AGRICULTURE: NEW FERTILIZERS AND FERTILIZATION MANAGEMENT, Fertilitas Agrorum, pp. 345-350.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20545/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>