<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auswirkungen von Fusarium solani f. sp pisi, Fusarium avenaceum und Mycosphaerella pinodes auf Sommererbsen im Topfversuch</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bacanovic, Jelena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Šišić, Adnan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruns, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Finckh, Maria R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Foot rot is an important limiting factor in pea production in Germany (Pflughöft, 2008). The disease is caused by a pathogen complex consisting of Ascochyta complex pathogens (Mycospharella pinodes, Phoma medicaginis and Ascochyta pisi) and Fusarium spp. However, little is known about the specificity of single pathogens of the complex and their impact on plant performance. In order to address this problem pot experiments with five isolates each of Fusarium solani f.sp pisi, Fusarium avenaceum and Mycosphaerella pinodes were carried out in controlled conditions. Three weeks after sowing and inoculation disease symptoms were assessed and plant growth parameters measured. All pathogens caused root discoloration and development of disease symptoms on pea seedlings. However, there were significant differences in symptom severity and effects on plant performance. Fusarium avenaceum was the most aggressive pathogen causing severe wilting symptoms and high reduction in fresh weight of pea. Fusarium solani f.sp pisi was the second most aggressive pathogen, but did not significantly affected plant weight. On the other hand, symptoms due to inoculation with M. pinodes appeared less severe. Nevertheless, plant fresh weights were greatly reduced as a result of infection.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21417/1/Bacanovic_etal_Sommererbsen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bacanovic, Jelena; Šišić, Adnan; Bruns, Christian and Finckh, Maria R.    (2013) Auswirkungen von Fusarium solani f. sp pisi, Fusarium avenaceum und Mycosphaerella pinodes auf Sommererbsen im Topfversuch.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21417/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>