<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Preliminary Results on Contents of Resveratrol in Wine of Organic and Conventional Vineyards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lévite, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Adrian, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Phytoalexins are compounds synthesised by plants in response to various stresses. In grapevines, these compounds belong to the stilbene family. Several studies have shown that resveratrol is usually triggered by infection of berries by Botrytis cinerea. In organic viticulture, grapevines are usually more stressed by attempted or successful infections of various pathogens than in conventionally grown grapevines. Furthermore, crop protection agents such as acidified clays or copper may trigger defence reactions of the plants. The aim of this study was to verify if differences between organically and conventionally produced wines exist. The preliminary results will be used as a starting point for further research of quality aspects of organic grape-vine production.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL) und Stiftung Ökologie und Landbau</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Meier, Urs</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9107/1/l%C3%A9vite-etal--2000-winecongress.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lévite, D.; Adrian, M. and Tamm, L.    (2000) Preliminary Results on Contents of Resveratrol in Wine of Organic and Conventional Vineyards.   In: Willer, Helga and Meier, Urs (Eds.)  Proceedings 6th International Congress on Organic Viticulture, Forschungsinstitut für biologischen Landbau (FiBL) und Stiftung Ökologie und Landbau, SÖL Sonderausgabe 77, pp. 256-257.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9107/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>