<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Non-compliance in organic farming: A cross-country comparison of Italy and Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gambelli, Danilo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Solfanelli, Francesco</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, Raffaele</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zorn, Alexander</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lippert, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, Stephan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This paper describes the Italian and German organic certification systems, including the institutions involved and the definitions of non-compliance and sanctions. Although they are both implementations of the same EU regulatory framework, these systems differ in many respects. Case study data from control bodies on non-compliance and sanctions are presented and analysed using binary choice models. This analysis shows that the occurrence of slight non-compliance and greater farm acreage are significant risk factors that explain severe non-compliance in both countries. However, to implement an efficient risk-based inspection system in the future, the data collection process must be improved and extended to examine personal attributes of  farmers and operators.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27763/1/27763.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gambelli, Danilo; Solfanelli, Francesco; Zanoli, Raffaele; Zorn, Alexander; Lippert, Christian and Dabbert, Stephan   (2014) Non-compliance in organic farming: A cross-country comparison of Italy and Germany.   Food Policy.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27763/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>