<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SPECIES IDENTITY IMPORTANT TO ACHIEVE BENEFITS OF DIVERSE GRASSLAND MIXTURES</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>de Wit, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Eekeren, Nick</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wagenaar, Jan-Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smeding, Frans</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In semi-natural grasslands, plant diversity has shown to correlate with increased primary production and reduced weed invasion. If such positive effects also apply to low input agricultural grasslands, the resource-use efficiency could be improved. &#xD;
To investigate whether other grassland species and diverse grassland mixtures could be more productive, a grassland on a shallow sandy soil in the south of the Netherlands was sown in April 2009 with seven non-leguminous grassland mixtures. Though some sown species vanished quickly, diverse mixtures proved less susceptible for invading species three years after sowing (p&lt;0.05). Yields in 2010 and 2011 were 11% higher for mixtures with two functional groups of grassland species compared with mixtures with only one functional group (p&lt;0.05).  A further increase in species diversity did not further increase production though overyielding was significant, transgressive overyielding was not apparent, mainly due to the strong effect of one specific functional group: mixtures containing tussock grass had a 14% higher production than mixtures without tussock grass. Tussock grass (mainly Dactylis glomerata) also had a major effect on botanical composition: Trifolium repens did invade into mixtures without tussock grass to a much higher extent (19% of the ground cover) than into mixtures with tussock grass (6%; p&lt;0.01). However, total ground cover by invading species was mainly influenced by the number of functional groups present in the sown mixture.&#xD;
The results suggest that diverse grassland mixtures can improve agricultural production and reduce the susceptibility of grass sods for invading species, but that the specific composition of the mixtures has a strong influence.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23959/1/23959%20dewit%20divers%20grassland%20OWC14_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>de Wit, Jan; van Eekeren, Nick; Wagenaar, Jan-Paul and Smeding, Frans    (2014) SPECIES IDENTITY IMPORTANT TO ACHIEVE BENEFITS OF DIVERSE GRASSLAND MIXTURES.   In:     Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 803-806.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23959/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>