<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Aroma-active secondary oxidation products of butter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mallia, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Escher, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rehberger, Brita</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schlichtherle-Cerny, Hedwig</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Butter contains vitamins, minerals and unsaturated lipids, such as polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFA) and conjugated linoleic acids (CLAs). However the oxidative stability and consequently the shelf-life of milk products are inversely correlated with their PUFA and CLA content.&#xD;
The objective of this study is the evaluation of the oxidative stability and sensory quality of PUFA/CLA-enriched butter versus conventional butter, with both types of butter being produced at ALP. For this purpose, new chemical and sensory-based methods will be developed, as well holistic complementary methods.&#xD;
This paper focuses on a preliminary study achieved using conventional butter, subjected to a long storage and to oxygen and light exposure, to develop a gas chromatography olfactometry (GC-O) method able to detect the aroma-active compounds originated from oxidation. This will be one of the methods used for the evaluation of the oxidative stability of PUFA/CLA-enriched butter.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9734/1/mallia-etal-2007-butter.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mallia, Silvia; Escher, Felix; Rehberger, Brita and Schlichtherle-Cerny, Hedwig    (2007) Aroma-active secondary oxidation products of butter.       Paper at:   3rd QLIF Congress: Improving Sustainability in Organic and Low Input Food Production Systems, University of Hohenheim, Germany, March 20-23, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9734/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>