<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2008</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>World</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The 2008 edition of this annual publication documents recent developments in global organic agriculture. It includes contributions from representatives of the organic sector from throughout the world and provides comprehensive organic farming statistics that cover surface area under organic management, numbers of farms and specific information about commodities and land use in organic systems. The book also contains information on the global market of the burgeoning organic sector, the latest developments in organic certification, standards and regulations, and insights into current status and emerging trends for organic agriculture by continent. &#xD;
&#xD;
For this edition, all statistical data and regional review chapters have been thoroughly updated. Completely new chapters on organic agriculture in the Pacific, on the International Task Force on Harmonization and Equivalence in Organic Agriculture and on organic aquaculture have been added.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Earthscan</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Yussefi-Menzler, Minou</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sorensen, Neil</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18420/1/9781844075928.jpg</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>other</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18420/11/world-of-organic-agriculture-2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Willer, Helga; Yussefi-Menzler, Minou and Sorensen, Neil (Eds.)      (2008) The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2008.     Earthscan, London.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18420/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>