<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PhytoMilk: Effect of silage botanical composition and harvest system on organic milk composition</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Höjer, Annika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinsson, Kjell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gustavsson, Anne-Maj</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The effect of silage botanical composition and harvest system on organic milk composition was studied in a feeding trial. Twenty-four Swedish Red dairy cows in mid lactation were allocated randomly to three treatments in a 3×3 Latin square design with each period of three weeks. The treatments were birdsfoot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus L.)/grass silage in two-cut system (B, 16 % birdsfoot trefoil), red clover (Trifolium pratense L.)/grass silage in two-cut system (R2, 42 % red clover) and red clover/grass silage in three-cut system (R3, 38 % red clover). Milk samples from the last week in each period were analyzed for fat and protein concentration. Milk yield was 28.7 ±1.0, 30.3 ±3.2 and 28.6 ±1.4 kg ECM day-1 (mean and SD) for treatment B, R2 and R3 respectively. Milk fat concentration was 5.00 ±0.38, 4.75 ±0.01 and 4.98 ±0.25 g 100 g-1 milk and milk protein concentration was 3.62 ±0.19, 3.54 ±0.08 and 3.57 ±0.09 g 100 g-1 milk for B, R2 and R3 respectively. Harvest system and botanical composition of silage does not seem to affect milk yield or composition.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-09-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18295/1/EGF_2010_KSLA.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18295/4/EGF_abstract_Annika_H%C3%B6jer_inskickad.docx</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Höjer, Annika; Martinsson, Kjell and Gustavsson, Anne-Maj    (2010) PhytoMilk: Effect of silage botanical composition and harvest system on organic milk composition.   In:     Book of Abstracts of the 23rd General Meeting of the European Grassland Federation, p. 111.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18295/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>