<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einsatz von Pheromonfallen zum Monitoring von Schnellkäfern (Agriotes spp.) in Vorfrüchten zu Kartoffeln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Dr. agr Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The infestation of potatoes with wireworms is also in organic farms an increasing problem. The percentage of marketable potatoes is clearly reduced by the grub of wireworms. The grading is much more time-consuming and the produce is sometimes not saleable. In consequence the profitability of potato production is at risk. A monitoring of the occurrence of click beetles (Agriotes spp.) is possible with pheromone traps. First results of the year 2004 showed a very high occurrence of A. lineatus (2148 click beetles per trap) in clover grass (prec-crop to potatoes) on an organically managed farm in Northern Germany. The occurrence of A. obscurus was much lower with 257 click beetles per trap. The experiments should be continued over the next years in consideration of different sites and other pre-crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>kassel university press GmbH, Kassel</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Heß, J</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3488/1/3488.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Böhm, Dr. agr Herwart and Krause, Tanja    (2005) Einsatz von Pheromonfallen zum Monitoring von Schnellkäfern (Agriotes spp.) in Vorfrüchten zu Kartoffeln.  [The use of pheromone traps for monitoring click beetles (Agriotes spp.) in preceding crops to potatoes.]  In: Heß, J and Rahmann, G (Eds.)  Ende der Nische, Beiträge zur 8. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, kassel university press GmbH, Kassel.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3488/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>