<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Food. Consumers 'Choices and Farmers' Opportunities</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Aquaculture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Consumers’ attention to food safety issues and environmental issues has increased overwhelmingly in recent decades because of their increased concern about their own health, the environment’s health, and the crises and emergencies reported worldwide. Once the only option, organic agriculture has always been a production option followed by at least a few farmers all over the world. These farmers were prompted by ethical and environmental motivations, as well as by committed consumers who supported organic agriculture thanks to a separate but fairly elitist distribution channel. Organic food now has become a viable alternative for an increasing number of consumers that are worried about the presence of chemicals residues and the negative consequences on the environment caused by intensive production methods. Many farmers also now see organic farming as a way to stabilize or even increase their income due to public policy support and growing market demand.&#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Food: Consumers' Choices and Farmers' Opportunities gives an overview of the organic sector, both in Italy and in the United States, and demonstrates how agricultural economists are performing analyses dealing with organic produce on different points in the supply chain. It deals with economic issues raised by organic farming and takes into account both the consumer's needs and the managerial and budget constraints experienced by the farmers. Also farm management methodologies and marketing analyses are used with specific research topics involving several industries in the agri-food sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer, New York</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Canavari, Maurizio</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Olson, Kent D.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13018/2/978-0-387-39581-4_BookPDF1_00PrefaceContents.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Canavari, Maurizio and Olson, Kent D. (Eds.)      (2007) Organic Food. Consumers 'Choices and Farmers' Opportunities.     Springer, New York.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13018/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>