<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Olsenella skatologenes sp.nov., a 3-methylindole (skatole) and 4-methylphenol (p-cresol) producing bacterium isolated from pig faces</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Li, Xiaoqiong</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Rikke Lassen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Højberg , Ole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Canibe, Nuria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Bent Borg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Strain SK9K4T, a strictly anaerobic, non-motile, non-sporulating, Gram-positive, saccharolytic coccobacillus was isolated from pig feces. SK9K4T metabolized indol-3-acetic acid to 3-methylindole (skatole), which is the main contributor to boar taint and also produced 4-methylphenol (p-cresol) from p-hydroxyphenylacetic acid. Phylogenetic analyses based on 16S rRNA gene sequences revealed that the isolate represented a new lineage within the genus Olsenella of the family Atopobiaceae. Strain SK9K4T was most closely related to the type strains of the three recognized Olsenella species; Olsenella profusa DSM 13989T (93.6%), Olsenella uli DSM 7084T (93.5%) and Olsenella umbonata DSM 22620T (92.7%). DNA–DNA relatedness values of strain SK9K4T with O. profusa, O. uli  and O. umbonata were 28.3 %, 69.1% and 27.2 %, respectively. The genomic DNA G + C content was 62.1 mol% and the major cellular fatty acids (&gt;10%) were C14:0 and C18:1 w9c. The major end product of glucose fermentation was lactic acid, with minor amounts of acetic acid and formic acid; no hydrogen was produced. Differences in fatty acid profiles, MALDI-TOF mass spectra of cell extracts, physiological and biochemical characteristics differentiate the strain SK9K4T from other recognized species of the Olsenella genus and indicate that the isolate represents a novel species within this genus, for which the name Olsenella skatologenes sp. nov., is proposed. The type strain is SK9K4T (=JCM 19907T =DSM 28304T).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28042/3/28042.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Li, Xiaoqiong; Jensen, Rikke Lassen; Højberg , Ole; Canibe, Nuria and Jensen, Bent Borg   (2014) Olsenella skatologenes sp.nov., a 3-methylindole (skatole) and 4-methylphenol (p-cresol) producing bacterium isolated from pig faces.   International Journal of Systemic and Evolutionary Microbiology.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28042/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>