<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The impact of organic farming on mineral composition of cow milk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hanuš, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Landová, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Macek, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Genčurová, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rozsypal, Roman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vorlíček, Zdeněk</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roubal, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Milk mineral matters are important in human nutrition, especially Ca, Mg and I. Increase of milk Mg along decrease of NPK soil fertilization under the Czech Republic (CR) conditions was predicted. This hypothetical prediction is based on antagonistic relationships between K fertilization, Mg level in cow roughage feeding and transfer of Mg into milk. In difference testing the conventional (C) cow milk was reference versus organic (O) milk. Holstein bulk milk samples (BMS) from winter and summer season in 4 C (n = 32 BMSs) and in 4 O (n = 16) herds were investigated. 6 herds were and 2 C were not grazed, other nutrition was typical under the CR conditions. Average MY of C herds was 7016±1068 and MY of O herds was 7037±422 kg per lactation. Macro- and microelements were investigated: Ca, P, Na, Mg and K (in mg kg-1); I (in μg l-1), Mn, Fe, Cu and Zn (in mg kg-1). Somatic cell count (SCC) was lower (P&gt;0.05) in O herds (geometric mean 216 &lt; 267 103 ml-1). There were differences (P&lt;0.05) in Na (O higher), I (O lower), Mn (O lower), Cu (O higher) and Zn (O lower). Ca results C 1213 and O 1257 mg kg-1 are comparable to late result 1222 and higher than in bygone times 1160 mg kg-1 at lower MY and comparable SCC 243 103 ml-1. Results of Na and differences in Mg and Ca (P&gt;0.05) in terms of trends confirm predicted hypothesis that Na, Ca and Mg will be higher after NPK fertilization decrease. Smaller investigated changes in mineral composition were better for human nutrition in O. Key words: organic farming, dairying, cow milk, mineral milk composition, inorganic fertilizer, calcium, magnesium</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Scientific Pedagogical Publishing</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Hanuš, O.; Landová, H.; Macek, A.; Genčurová, V.; Rozsypal, Roman; Vorlíček, Zdeněk and Roubal, P.    (2008) The impact of organic farming on mineral composition of cow milk.  [Vliv ekologického hospodaření na minerální složky kravského mléka.]    Scientific Pedagogical Publishing, Jihočeská univerzita České Budějovice.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21308/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>