<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Are there alternatives to copper for controlling grapevine downy mildew in organic viticulture?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dagostin, Silvia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schärer, Hans-Jakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pertot, Ilaria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Downy mildew caused by the obligate biotrophic oomycete Plasmopara viticola is one of the most important and devastating diseases of grapevine. Copper-based fungicides are used to control the disease in organic vineyards. However, since 2006, copper use has been limited by an European Commission regulation. In this study conducted from 2004 to 2007, we tested materials that might replace copper in organic viticulture, under controlled greenhouse and field conditions at two locations in Europe (northern Italy and Switzerland). We tested 112 different treatments, including biocontrol agents, materials of animal origin, homeopathic preparations, inorganic materials, microbial extracts, natural derivatives, plant extracts, physical methods and synthetic materials. Good control results were observed for two new copper formulations, but one of them induced phytotoxic effects. Two of the plant extracts provided good control on both leaves and clusters, and six of them controlled the infection on clusters only. One biocontrol agent reduced symptoms on leaves and bunches. Three of the other treatments provided good control on leaves, and four of them provided good control on bunches. Clay was as effective as copper on both leaves and bunches. Currently, even if there is no treatment that is as effective as copper for controlling grapevine downy mildew in organic vineyards, Yucca schidigera and Salvia officinalis extracts and Trichoderma harzianum, could be considered as promising candidates to be developed. This study may help the development of an integrated management program in which a less effective product is applied in combination with copper, to reduce the total quantities of copper applied.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26499/1/JCRP2633_DAgositn_etal_2011.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dagostin, Silvia; Schärer, Hans-Jakob; Pertot, Ilaria and Tamm, Lucius   (2011) Are there alternatives to copper for controlling grapevine downy mildew in organic viticulture?   Crop Protection, 30, pp. 776-788.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26499/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>