<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Winter wheat roots grow twice as deep as spring wheat roots, is this important for N uptake and N leaching losses?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cortasa, Montserrat Salmerón</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Cropping systems comprising winter catch crops followed by spring wheat could reduce N leaching risks compared to traditional winter wheat systems in humid climates. We studied the soil mineral N (Ninorg) and root growth of winter- and spring wheat to 2.5 m depth during three years. Root depth of winter wheat (2.2 m) was twice that of spring wheat, and this was related to much lower amounts of Ninorg in the 1 to 2.5 m layer after winter wheat (81 kg Ninorg ha-1 less). When growing winter catch crops before spring wheat, N content in the 1 to 2.5 m layer after spring wheat was not different from that after winter wheat. The results suggest that by virtue of its deep rooting, winter wheat may not lead to high levels of leaching as it is often assumed in humid climates. Deep soil and root measurements (below 1 m) in this experiment were essential to answer the questions we posed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16121/2/16121.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thorup-Kristensen, Kristian; Cortasa, Montserrat Salmerón and Loges, Ralf   (2009) Winter wheat roots grow twice as deep as spring wheat roots, is this important for N uptake and N leaching losses?   Plant and Soil, 322, pp. 101-114.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16121/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>