<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wageningen Universiteit en Researchcentrum</dc:title>
  <dc:description>Wageningen University and Research Centre (Wageningen UR for short) is a leading international knowledge institute in the fields of nutrition and health, sustainable agricultural systems, environmental quality and processes of social change. Its path-breaking research and innovative education form a vital contribution to the quality of life. Wageningen UR is known for its critical, enterprising and internationally oriented researchers and students. They are capable of bringing together knowledge from a wide variety of disciplines in order to develop a comprehensive view of public issues and to understand the implications of these for human life, animal life, plant life and the environment. Its knowledge institute consists of Wageningen University, (applied) research institutes, and a training and advisory centre. In January 2004, the Van Hall Larenstein polytechnic became part of Wageningen UR. Wageningen UR has 7,400 employees and over 8,500 students. The research institutes carry out strategic, applied and practical research for businesses, governments and stakeholder groups. The university’s strength lies in its fundamental and strategic research. It also produces graduates that are employable in a broad range of fields. &#xD;
The research institutes and university work together closely in five areas of expertise: Agrotechnology &amp; Food, Animal, Environmental, Plant and Social Sciences. Current important research themes include food safety and the green environment. &#xD;
Coordination of the research on organic agriculture within the Wageningen UR organization is delegated to the Innovatiecentrum Biologische Landbouw (IBL - Innovation Centre Organic Agriculture) of Wageningen UR. Contact person for organic agriculture research is Mrs. Greet Blom, head of the IBL.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Organization description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Organization}     WUR: Wageningen Universiteit en Researchcentrum.  [Wageningen University and Research Centre.]    Organization Leader(s): Blom-Zandstra, dr.ir. M. (Greet).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5317/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>