<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bedeutung von Verbrauchereinstellungen für Kauf und Ausgabenhöhe bei Öko-Lebensmitteln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the past, predominantly interviews have been used to valuate the German demand for organic food and associated consumers’ attitudes. These interviews’ explanatory power is limited due to consumers’ overestimation of household expenditures, buying frequencies or quantity of organic food. When using consumer panels, it is possible to simultaneously examine realised behaviour together with attitudes of consumers obtained by panel insertions. Such methodology enables to identify which attitudes affect spending for organic food. Therefore these attitudes should be taken into account within applied marketing policy for organic food.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Österreichische Gesellschaft für Agrarökonomie ÖGA, Wien</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Hambrusch, Josef</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hunger, Franz</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Oedl-Wieser, Theresia</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Penker, Marianne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Peyerl, Hermann</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pistrich, Karlheinz</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Pöchtrager, Siegfried</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Reiter-Stelzl, Josefa</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15139/1/niessen-2008-OeGA_Tagungsband_2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Niessen, Jan    (2008) Bedeutung von Verbrauchereinstellungen für Kauf und Ausgabenhöhe bei Öko-Lebensmitteln.    In: Hambrusch, Josef; Hunger, Franz; Oedl-Wieser, Theresia; Penker, Marianne; Peyerl, Hermann; Pistrich, Karlheinz; Pöchtrager, Siegfried and Reiter-Stelzl, Josefa (Eds.)   Neue Impulse in der Agrar- und Ernährungswirtschaft?! 18. Jahrestagung der Österreichischen Gesellschaft für Agrarökonomie, Tagungsband 2008.  Österreichische Gesellschaft für Agrarökonomie ÖGA, Wien.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15139/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>