<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Carbon sequestration in organic and conventional managed soils in the Netherlands</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sukkel, Wijnand</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Geel, Willem</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Haan, Janjo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Next to other important agronomic and ecological aspects, the organic matter sequestration in the soil plays an important role in the CO2 balance. Based on detailed farm registrations, the input of effective organic matter and the changes in carbon sequestration in the soil was calculated for a large number of organic and conventional farms in the Netherlands. Results show that both organic and conventional management resulted in a decrease of the pool of organic carbon in the soil. The average decrease for the conventional management was 401 kg ha-1 year-1 and for the organic management 261 kg ha-1 year-1. The input of effective organic matter in the soil was significantly higher in organic than in conventional farms. Animal manure was the main contributor to this difference.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12300/1/12300.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sukkel, Wijnand; van Geel, Willem and de Haan, Janjo    (2008) Carbon sequestration in organic and conventional managed soils in the Netherlands.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12300/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>