<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Understanding earwig phenology in top fruit orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gobin, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peusens, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moerkens, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leirs, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Earwigs, Forficula auricularia, are key generalist predators to a variety of orchard pests.&#xD;
However, numbers of earwigs have declined in both organic and IPM orchards in recent&#xD;
years. Both Integrated and Organic fruit growers have tried to re-establish earwig&#xD;
populations, thus far with little success. To understand earwig population dynamics and to&#xD;
find measures to increase natural orchard populations, we conducted a detailed&#xD;
phenological survey of earwigs in orchards. Earwigs were sampled while sheltering during&#xD;
daytime in artificial refuges. They move into the trees from the third nymph stage onwards.&#xD;
In most orchards, a small second brood is produced in summer, and this has a positive&#xD;
impact on population size in fall. We see only minor differences in phenology between&#xD;
apple and pear orchards, mainly caused by differences in alternative hiding places.&#xD;
Earwigs show an inexplicable reduction in numbers at the timing of moulting into adults.&#xD;
When earwig phenology is correlated with pest phenology in apple and pear, its use for&#xD;
pest control of major pests is clear.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13678/1/208-212.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gobin, B.; Peusens, G.; Moerkens, R. and Leirs, H.    (2008) Understanding earwig phenology in top fruit orchards.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 208-212.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13678/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>