<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Development and structuring of the sector of full field organic vegetables in cereal zones</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Perret, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Béliard, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rigault, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic vegetable consumption shows a progress that proved to be steady over years. Nevertheless, the offer of organic vegetables remains insufficient. The CasDar program dedicated to organic field vegetables, 2010-2013, aimed at studying the conditions for the development of large-scale production, by technical answers, and by contributing to the organization of the sector. This action, that concerned six regions of the North and the Central France, was led by players of the sector, producers, wholesalers, transformers, distributors. This favored a shared analysis of strengths and weaknesses of the sector. In a second step, the partners developed tools, to meet the identified stakes, that can be used in the zones of production of full field vegetables in cereal regions and available to the actors of the sector.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26328/1/Perret_2013_CIAG_Vol32.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Perret, C.; Béliard, E. and Rigault, A.   (2013) Development and structuring of the sector of full field organic vegetables in cereal zones.  [Développement et structuration de la filière légumes de plein champ biologiques dans les exploitations de grandes cultures.]  Innovations Agronomiques, 32, pp. 149-161.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26328/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>