<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einsatz von pflanzlichen Futterzusätzen zur Prophylaxe von E.coli - bedingten Durchfällen bei Absetzferkeln</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hagmüller, Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vielhaber, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gallnböck, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zitterl-Eglseer, Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this investigation was to examine the effect of different feed additives on prophylaxis of weaning diarrhoea.184 piglets were divided into 3 experimental groups and one control group by compensating randomisation. Feed additives were either herbs (“Herbenterosan”), oligogalacturonides (“Enteronid”) or lignocellulosis (“Agrocell”). Piglets were reared according to Council Regulation EC Nr. 889/2008 and weaned at 40 days of age. From day 4 after weaning until day 8 faeces of the piglets were examined every day to create a faecal score of each group (= group sum). Firm faeces were characterised as “0”, pasty faeces as “1” and liquid faeces as “2”. Live weight was examined regularly. Blood samples were collected twice for the analysis of haptoglobin and electrolytes.&#xD;
The Herbenterosan group showed the lowest group sum in faecal scoring. It was followed by the Enteronid group, the control group and the Agrocell group. No difference between groups was found in haptoglobin values. Electrolyte values (sodium, potassium and chloride) coincided with faecal scores: lower faecal score meant better values of electrolytes and conversely.&#xD;
The three different phytogenic feed additives were not able to prevent piglets from diarrhoea. The Herbenterosan group showed best values in faecal score and live weight gain.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17350/3/Hagm%C3%BCller_17350.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hagmüller, Werner; Vielhaber, Barbara; Gallnböck, Markus and Zitterl-Eglseer, Karin    (2011) Einsatz von pflanzlichen Futterzusätzen zur Prophylaxe von E.coli - bedingten Durchfällen bei Absetzferkeln.  [The effects of plant additives on prophylaxis of weaning diarrhoea.]      Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17350/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>