<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Preliminary study of the organic citrus nursery management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>EL GHARAAS, Youssef</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A preliminary trial on citrus nursery management by organic means has been conducted with the aim of seed treatment for conservation, soil fertility management and spider mite control. The seed treatment was performed by a combination of thermotherapy and  different allowed fungicides (Copper, Equisetum, and Bordeaux mixture). The fifty percent copper solution protected the seeds for at least two months. The soil fertility management considered the rootstocks production (Citrange troyer, Sour orange, Rough lemon and Trifoliate orange) and  took into account the major ingredients, macronutrients and micronutrinets. In the major ingredients, the soil was found to be essential and the combination of the peat moss sand and soil with equal quantities gave a suitable mixture. When the macronutrients were studied, a poultry manure-based fertilizer gave the best growth when applied at different rates, depending on the rootstock type. Also the micronutrients performed the best when incorporated in the mixture. The phytosanitary management study tested three approved products to control spider mites (pyrethrins, sulphur and mineral oils). The three treatments were found to be efficient in the control of the mites and showed specificity toward the controlled species</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6659/1/ElGharassYoussef03_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>EL GHARAAS, Youssef   (2003) Preliminary study of the organic citrus nursery management.  [Etude préliminaire sur la gestion d’une pépinière d’agrumes.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science, no. 299. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6659/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>