<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A study on four feeding strategies of 100% organic origin for piglets concerning performance, health status, losses and economy in organic agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Weißmann, Friedrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bussemas, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Falk, Anna</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic agriculture is defined as a low-external-input-system but piglets’ necessity for high quality diets seems to contradict low-external-input feeding strategies. Hence, a total of 361 piglets was tested from day 14 – 63 post natum concerning performance, health status, losses and diet costs by means of four feeding strategies of 100%&#xD;
organic origin: (i) high-external-input diet, (ii) medium-external-input diet, (iii) lowexternal-input diet, each with grass-clover-silage as roughage source, and (iv) above&#xD;
mentioned low-external-input diet with straw replacing grass-clover-silage. The highexternal-input-diet achieved the significantly highest live weight gain; all other&#xD;
strategies were similar at a lower level. There were no differences in health status and loss rates between the four strategies. Low-input-strategies were economical at best in producing a standardized 20 kg piglet. A verification of the results is necessary with a higher number of piglets for a final recommendation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thuenen Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, Gerold</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Godinho, Denise</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-09-12</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24630/1/weissmann_feeding-strategies_paper_1.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Weißmann, Friedrich; Bussemas, Ralf and Falk, Anna    (2012) A study on four feeding strategies of 100% organic origin for piglets concerning performance, health status, losses and economy in organic agriculture.   In: Rahmann, Gerold and Godinho, Denise (Eds.)  Tackling the Future Challenges of Organic Animal Husbandry, Johann Heinrich von Thuenen Federal Research Institute for Rural Areas, Forestry and Fisheries, pp. 288-290.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24630/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>