<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A new visual trap for Rhagoletis cerasi (L.) (Diptera: Tephritidae).</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Daniel, Claudia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mathis, Samuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Feichtinger, Georg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The European cherry fruit fly, Rhagoletis cerasi (L.) (Diptera: Tephritidae), is the most important pest of sweet cherries in Europe. The aim of our experiments was to develop a new, cost-efficient, lead chromate-free and more eco-friendly trap for monitoring and mass trapping of R. cerasi. Five different-colored yellow panels and three different trap shapes were compared to a standard Rebell® amarillo trap in three experimental orchards in 2012. Trap color F, with a strong increase in reflectance at 500–550 nm and a secondary peak in the UV-region at 300–400 nm, captured significantly more flies than the standard Rebell® amarillo trap. Yellow traps with increased reflectance in the blue region (400–500 nm) were least attractive. Trap shape was of minor importance, as long as the object was three-dimensional and visible from all directions. Based on economic and practical considerations, a cylinder-shaped trap ―UFA-Samen Kirschenfliegenfalle‖ was developed for commercial use and is currently under on-farm evaluation.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26808/1/insects-05-00564.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Daniel, Claudia; Mathis, Samuel and Feichtinger, Georg   (2014) A new visual trap for Rhagoletis cerasi (L.) (Diptera: Tephritidae).   insects, 5, pp. 564-576.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26808/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>