<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Knowledge synthesis: Animal health and welfare in organic pig production - Final Report COREPIG</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Früh, Barbara</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bochicchio, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Edwards, Sandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hegelund, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leeb, Christine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heinonen, Mari</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maupertuis, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Werne, Steffen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiberg, Sophia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prunier, Armelle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roepstorff, Allan</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lubac, Stanislas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bonde, Marianne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rousing, Tine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sundrum, Albert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindgren, Kristina</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This report reviews the available information on the welfare of pigs when maintained according to organic standards in Europe. It begins by overviewing the populations of organic pigs in different countries at the time of writing (2007), the organic standards which govern their management and the systems in which they are typically kept. It then reviews for each stage in the production cycle (sows, suckling piglets, weaned pigs and fattening pigs) the available literature on health and welfare problems which might be experienced by the animals and the hazards which might give rise to these problems. Finally the report reviews the methods current available for the measurement of pig health and welfare and the extent to which monitoring systems currently exist in different countries, or might be developed. The information gathered in this review formed the basis for the subsequent development of tools for use in a HACCP based management and surveillance system for organic pig herds. These tools will assist the organic pig farmer to prevent selected pig diseases and welfare problems by monitoring and controlling the risk factors. Further details can be found on the COREPIG project website www.icrofs.org/coreorganic/corepig.html</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Edwards, Sandra</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18419/1/18419.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Früh, Barbara; Bochicchio, David; Edwards, Sandra; Hegelund, Lene; Leeb, Christine; Heinonen, Mari; Maupertuis, F.; Sundrum, Albert; Werne, Steffen; Wiberg, Sophia; Mejer, Helena; Prunier, Armelle; Roepstorff, Allan; Lubac, Stanislas; Bonde, Marianne; Rousing, Tine; Sundrum, Albert and Lindgren, Kristina     (editor): Edwards, Sandra (Ed.)    (2011) Knowledge synthesis: Animal health and welfare in organic pig production - Final Report COREPIG.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18419/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>