<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Langjährige Auswirkungen reduzierter Bodenbearbeitung auf unterschiedlichen Standorten</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Berner, Alfred</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dierauer, Hansueli</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Messmer, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil tillage</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Results on the applicability of reduced tillage systems are reported to be highly site dependent. To broaden our experience under organic farming, we performed a mid-term experiment comparing RT with conventional tillage (CT: plough) on a loamy clay in Frick (Switzerland). We found, that crop yield was reduced during the conversion period from conventional tillage (CT) to a RT system, but in the second experimental phase, RT exerted higher yields, resulting in a yield increase of 13% in mean. Soil organic matter in the 0 to 10 cm soil layer was 0,37 % higher under RT than under CT, without any difference in the 10 to 20 cm layer. In 2008 and 2009, we established two new experiments on loamy soils, comprising the factors tillage, fertilisation and maize varieties. First year results indicated 5% lower yields under RT, and high maize genotype x environment (tillage system and fertilisation level) interactions. On-farm stripe experiments proofed to be most valuable for farmers involvement in the actual research area and for bi-directional knowledge transfer from farmers to researchers and vice versa.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17771/5/Maeder_17771.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mäder, Paul; Berner, Alfred; Dierauer, Hansueli and Messmer, Monika    (2011) Langjährige Auswirkungen reduzierter Bodenbearbeitung auf unterschiedlichen Standorten.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17771/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>