<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Response of old, new and organically bred winter wheat cultivars in different farming systems:concept and experimental layout in the DOK field trial</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hildermann, Isabell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thommen, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dubois, David</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wiemken, Andres</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boller, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maeder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farmers often use winter wheat (Triticum aestivum L.) cultivars that have been bred under conventional high-input conditions. We test the hypothesis, whether old and organically bred cultivars are better adapted to low-input conditions through a better functioning of the symbiosis with arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi (AMF). Our aim is to assess the nutrient acquisition potential of old, new and organically bred winter wheat cultivars and to identify the role of AMF for nutrient uptake and growth. In October 2006, an experiment with 10 wheat cultivars was superimposed to all four field replicates of the DOK long-term experiment, comprising four different treatments with increasing nutrient input: unfertilized, biodynamic low and moderate intensity and conventional mineral system. Growth and harvest parameters such as plant density and length, growth habit, plant health, yield and grain quality will be assessed. Shoot and root samples were taken at tillering and flowering to analyse nitrogen and phosphorus content and AMF root colonization. In this paper, the current state of literature findings in the field of organic breeding is summarized and the experimental setup for variety testing in an existing long-term trial is outlined.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12307/1/Hildermann_12307_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hildermann, Isabell; Thommen, Andreas; Dubois, David; Wiemken, Andres; Boller, Thomas and Maeder, Paul    (2008) Response of old, new and organically bred winter wheat cultivars in different farming systems:concept and experimental layout in the DOK field trial.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>