<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Weiterbildung von Managern und Führungskräften auf&#xD;
ökologisch wirtschaftenden Bauernhöfen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>May, BSc Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>van Elsen, Dr. Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Are organic farms suited to offer educational training for managers and stakeholders&#xD;
working in leading positions in companies or institutions? Eight interviews with experts&#xD;
were carried out in 2007 and analysed by methods of qualitative social research.&#xD;
Substantial deficiencies of managers and executives lie in the field of soft skills and&#xD;
have their origin in the school system among other reasons. The basic precondition for&#xD;
a successful course/training is the transfer of items that were perceived and learned in&#xD;
daily life. The experts are convinced that organic farms are well suited to offer&#xD;
educational courses and seminars for managers and executives especially because of&#xD;
some characteristics of organic farming: holistic and systemic perception, ethical&#xD;
values, farm diversity, sustainability, exposure to time und bounds, coherences on&#xD;
different farm levels etc. The ways of performance can be different (conceptual&#xD;
design, participants, target group, topic, methodology, marketing, etc.). To assure&#xD;
sustainable success three parameters are essential: professionalism, reliability and&#xD;
exclusiveness.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14364/1/May_14364.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>May, BSc Christian and van Elsen, Dr. Thomas    (2009) Weiterbildung von Managern und Führungskräften auf ökologisch wirtschaftenden Bauernhöfen.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14364/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>