<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Antifungal activity of phenolic compounds extracted from dried olive pomace</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Winkelhausen, Eleonora</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pospiech, Robert</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Laufenberg, Günther</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The antifungal activity of phenolic compounds extracted from olive pomace against Alternaria solani, Botrytis cinerea and Fusarium culmorum was investigated. Olive pomace, a by-product of olive oil production, was used as a source of phenolic compounds. The extracted phenolics were added to a medium to reach phenol concentration of 0,1 and 0,2 %(w/v) and tested for their antifungal activity against the three fungi. In addition, the fungi were cultivated in a medium containing a commercial fungicide in the concentration of 0,2 % (w/v). Both of the phenolic concentrations inhibited the growth of all three fungi with the higher being more effective. It resulted in a four-fold reduction of the mycelial growth rate of A. solani and F. culmorum. The present study demonstrated that the phenolic compounds derived from olive pomace hold a good promise as a natural fungicide against common pathogens to crops.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15290/1/winkelhausen-etal-2005-BCTM_Mazedonien.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Winkelhausen, Eleonora; Pospiech, Robert and Laufenberg, Günther   (2005) Antifungal activity of phenolic compounds extracted from dried olive pomace.   Bulletin of the Chemists and Technologists of Macedonia, Vol. 24 (1), pp. 41-46.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15290/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>