<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dose-dependent response of nitrogen stable isotope ratio to proportion of legumes in diet to authenticate lamb meat produced from legume-rich diets</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Devincenzi, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Delfosse, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Andueza, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nabinger, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Prache, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigated the dose-dependent response in lamb meat of stable nitrogen isotope ratio to the dietary proportion of legumes, and the ability of the nitrogen isotope signature of the meat to authenticate meat produced from legume-rich diets. Four groups of nine male Romane lambs grazing a cocksfoot pasture were supplemented with different levels of fresh alfalfa forage to obtain four dietary proportions of alfalfa (0%, 25%, 50% and 75%) for 98 days on average before slaughter (groups L0, L25, L50 and L75).&#xD;
We measured the stable nitrogen isotope ratio in the forages and in the longissimus thoracis muscle. The d15N value of the meat decreased linearly with the dietary proportion of alfalfa. The distribution of the d15N values of the meat discriminated all the L0 lambs from the L75 lambs, and gave a correct classification score of 85.3% comparing lambs that ate alfalfa with those that did not.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25033/1/Devincenzi-etal-2014-FoodChemistry-152-p456-461.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Devincenzi, T.; Delfosse, O.; Andueza, D.; Nabinger, C. and Prache, S.   (2014) Dose-dependent response of nitrogen stable isotope ratio to proportion of legumes in diet to authenticate lamb meat produced from legume-rich diets.   Food Chemistry, 152, pp. 456-461.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25033/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>