<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards animal oriented rearing methods in organic production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of the foundations of organic animal production systems is that animals are kept in a more natural way. In terms of housing, animals get more space, have access to outside areas and are fed organic rations. This results in unique, farm-specific production systems with emphasis on animal welfare and product quality. In recent years it has become clear that strategies to rear replacement animals are getting more important. There is a public demand for more animal oriented, sustainable production systems. Also farmers realize that rearing is the key to raise suitable animals that fit into their production system. Circumstances during the rearing period affect health, wellbeing and production, not only during the rearing period itself, but also during later life. In organic egg production and in organic milk production farmers realize that organic&#xD;
production requires organically sound rearing practices!</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Monique, Bestman</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Wagenaar, Jan-Paul</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Proceedings</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8456/1/1738.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Monique, Bestman and Wagenaar, Jan-Paul (Eds.)    (2006) Towards animal oriented rearing methods in organic production systems.    . Proceedings of  International Training and Exchange workshop, QLIF project, Driebergen, February 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8456/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>