<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>FiBL-Betriebsnetz</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>State of the Art:&#xD;
In most existing farm networks the choice of participating farms rests upon pragmatic criteria, such as the willingness of farmers to cooperate. The representativeness of the farm (farm type) is often not taken into account. However, for socio-economic and interdisciplinary research subjects the farm type often matters. Furthermore, existing farm networks are mostly targeted to either collecting economic data or participatory research in technical questions. Participatory economic research, though, is rare.&#xD;
The data base for economic data in organic farming is fragmentary. Improving this data base will support farmers in their strategic decisions, extension and research in their work and will help farmers’ associations to develop their policy.&#xD;
Definition of the problem:&#xD;
Lack of basic socio-economic data in organic farming, e.g. incomes.&#xD;
Farmers are insufficiently involved in socio-economic research.&#xD;
Project aims:&#xD;
To enhance a regularly updated economic data base for organic farming.&#xD;
To foster socio-economic on farm research.&#xD;
To improve cooperation of farmers, extension and research in socio-economic questions.&#xD;
Methodology:&#xD;
-Farm network of 55 organic farms, divided into 11 groups&#xD;
-Methodological choice of participating farms&#xD;
-Yearly analysis of farm accounts&#xD;
-Yearly recordings of production costs, producer prices and yields&#xD;
-Regular participatory research projects</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    FiBL-Betriebsnetz.  [FiBL-FarmNet.]   Runs 2005 - 2009.      Project Leader(s):  Rudmann, Christine, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5911/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>