<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The role of organic agriculture in networks for rural development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schäfer, Prof. Dr. Martina</dc:creator>
  <dc:description>The paper presents results on the societal contributions of organic agriculture that go beyond environmental benefits derived from organic standards of production. Based on a survey and case studies, the differing contributions toward rural development by organic farms in Brandenburg (Germany) are demonstrated, including  their social and regional engagement, building of bridges between urban and rural areas, and promotion of regional marketing and tourism. Further, the paper highlights the organizational context of these entrepreneurial activities and differentiates between entrepreneurial networks, networks of sustainable regional development, and civil networks. Looking closer at the types of networks the farms are part of and their significance for the societal engagement of organic farms, allows the drawing of conclusions regarding strategies of support for regional development. The identification of key actors and structures that promote regional development seems to be especially important for peripheral rural areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7233/1/abstractdenmark.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7233/2/7233_Schafer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schäfer, Prof. Dr. Martina    (2006) The role of organic agriculture in networks for rural development.       Paper at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7233/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>