<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The role of ectomychorrizal fungi in nitrogen acquisition in California oak woodlands.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>T. AL DAMRAT, Rasha</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In northeastern California oak woodland, we measured Nitrogen uptake by ectomycorrhizal (ECM) oak roots (Quercus douglasii, blue oak, Quercus wislizenii, live oak). In February 2005, after sampling fine roots of 5 blue and 5 live oaks, we added 15NH4+ to soils, waited one month then resampled. ECM root tips were separated into 21 morphotypes and analyzed for 15N.  Blue oak ECM diversity was higher than that in live oak. Few morphotypes (33%) were common to both oak species. More abundant morphotypes took up less 15N than less abundant morphotypes. We hypothesized that ECM species more ‘active’ in N uptake would be more frequent in soil cores. However, our data did not support our hypothesis; and ECM species present in few cores were more enriched in 15N than species present in many soil cores.  We believe our data are the first to demonstrate functional biodiversity of ECM fungi for N uptake.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7011/1/RashaAldamatar05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>T. AL DAMRAT, Rasha   (2005) The role of ectomychorrizal fungi in nitrogen acquisition in California oak woodlands.  [Le rôle des champignons ectomycorhiziens dans l’acquisition de l’azote dans la chênaie en Californie.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 402. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7011/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>