<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erste Ergebnisse mit dem Einsatz von K-hydrogencarbonat in Südtirol</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the EC at the moment only cupper and sulphur products are allowed to regulate a multiplicity of diseases in different vegetable crops. On the other hand it is well know that both have also negative side effects on beneficial organisms and the soil. Since many years researches are looking for alternatives to reduce and substitute the use of the mentioned products.&#xD;
Bicarbonates are substances which were pointes out for many years. They are present in nature and were used in the past in organic farming. Until now there was no registration for them in the EC as plant protection materials. There is a palpable possibility that it would change in future, what will open the possibility to apply for the introduction of potassium bicarbonate in annex 2B of the EC Reg. 2091/92. In South Tyrol in the last years were carried out field trials which showed an interesting efficacy against scab. Frequent use of potas-sium bicarbonate increased the mineral content of potassium in the fruits and increased the number of fruits with bitter bit during storage.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8824/1/ecofruit_12th_17.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Casera, Claudio and Lardschneider, Ewald    (2006) Erste Ergebnisse mit dem Einsatz von K-hydrogencarbonat in Südtirol.  [First results of the use of potassium bicarbonate against scab in South Tyrol.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 93-97.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8824/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>