<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Output und Public Expenditure Implications of the Development of Organic Farming in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gambelli, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic Farming is becoming a key issue in the context of the present EU agro-environmental policy lines. However, its specific impact on agricultural output and on public expenditure is still scarcely investigated. In this book, Raffaele Zanoli and Danilo Gambelli provide a detailed analysis of the consequences that organic farming has produced insofar on these aspects for EU countries and three European non-EU countries - NO, CH, CZ - drawing on the latest studies in this field. The emphasis throughout is on factual information and empirical data provision, making this book a valueable resource to understand the success, challenges and prospects of the policy support to organic farming in Europe. &#xD;
This book is aimed at policy makers, the private sector, researchers and students in the field of economics and politics of organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart - Hohenheim</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>1999</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/8472/1/Organic_Farming_in_Europe_Volume04_Output_and_Public_Expenditure_Implications_of_the_Development_of_Organic_Farming_in_Europe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zanoli, R. and Gambelli, D.    (1999) Output und Public Expenditure Implications of the Development of Organic Farming in Europe.    Organic Farming in Europe: Economics and Policy, no. Vol. 4. Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart - Hohenheim.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/8472/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>