<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Züchterische Verbesserung der sensorischen Qualität der&#xD;
Pastinake (Pastinaca sativa L.) im Praxisbetrieb</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Horneburg, Bernd</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bauer, Dieter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bufler, Gebhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Parsnip (Pastinaca sativa L.) is one of the few cultivated plants domesticated in&#xD;
Europe. The crop is underutilised and the number of available varieties is small in&#xD;
Central Europe. On-farm management of genetic resources can be an important&#xD;
means to increase infraspecific diversity, and to improve the quality of crops. In the&#xD;
present experiment quality-improvement by progeny selection on-farm was&#xD;
investigated. In a first step parsnips were selected for organoleptic quality by a&#xD;
technique that allows to harvest seeds from the plant tested. In a second step,&#xD;
progenies of positive- and negative-selected plants were compared with the original&#xD;
population. The experiment was carried out with the varieties Aromata (2006) and&#xD;
White King (2008) in biodynamic management. Organoleptic quality was determined&#xD;
according to a key developed for parsnip. Sugar contents were determined.&#xD;
Organoleptic selection significantly improved sweetness and flavour and can be&#xD;
recommended. However, selection was not efficient to improve texture.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14145/1/Horneburg_14145.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Horneburg, Bernd; Bauer, Dieter and Bufler, Gebhard    (2009) Züchterische Verbesserung der sensorischen Qualität der Pastinake (Pastinaca sativa L.) im Praxisbetrieb.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14145/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>