<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Content of lignan, cadmium and some other chemical components in linseed and oil hemp varieties in south-western part of Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Saastamoinen, Marketta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pihlava, Juha-Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eurola, Merja</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Lignans are phytoestrogens found ubiquitously throughout the plant kingdom and thus are also&#xD;
present in our diet. After ingestion lignans go through various transformations and in the end&#xD;
they form mammalian lignans by microbial conversion. The amount of these mammalian lignans&#xD;
in human body is linked to the reduced risk of various hormonal dependent cancers such as&#xD;
breast cancer. Flaxseed (Linum usitatissimum L.) is one of the richest sources of lignans used in&#xD;
the human diet. Unfortunately, flaxseed also picks up cadmium very efficiently from the soil,&#xD;
which has to be kept in mind when choosing what regions to cultivate it in. SDG-lignan,&#xD;
cadmium and lead contents were studied in linseed, flax and oil hemp variety samples. Oil&#xD;
hemp samples were seeds of the very low THC cannabinoid variety Finola. Linseed varieties&#xD;
were Helmi, Heljä, Laser, Abacus and Sunrise and flax varieties were Martta and Belinka. Both&#xD;
farm and trial samples were studied. SDG lignan contents of linseed and flax variety samples&#xD;
varied 4840-9560 mg kg-1. Helmi linseed variety had higher SDG lignan content than that of&#xD;
Laser. Cadmium contents of linseed and flax variety samples varied from 0.36-1.11 mg kg-1.&#xD;
Cadmium contents of oil hemp samples were 0.017 mg kg-1 and 0.023 mg kg-1. Lead&#xD;
concentrations were rather low in all samples. There was wide variation in the cadmium content&#xD;
of linseed samples cultivated at different locations. It is important to cultivate linseed at high pH&#xD;
soils with low heavy metal content, in order to prevent cadmium accumulation.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18315/1/Saastamoinen.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Saastamoinen, Marketta; Pihlava, Juha-Matti and Eurola, Merja    (2010) Content of lignan, cadmium and some other chemical components in linseed and oil hemp varieties in south-western part of Finland.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18315/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>