<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Seasonal population dynamics of inoculated and indigenous steinernematid nematodes in an organic cropping system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Philipsen, Holger</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study was based on naturally occurring and inoculated populations of steinernematid nematodes. The nematode populations were monitored spring and autumn in two following years in an organic cropping system and changes in population size were related to the presence of potential insect hosts. Nematode population were estimated in terms of nematode incidence (percentage of positive soil samples) by using Tenebrio molitor larvae as bait. The population of naturally occurring nematodes (Steinernema affine (Bovien) and S. feltiae (Filipjev)) was generally at a low level (0-17 % incidence for S. affine and 0-18 % incidence for S. feltiae). Inoculated S. feltiae established well in half of the plots where inoculation had been performed and reached incidences of 87 %. Establishment of inoculated nematodes, and population dynamics in general, was clearly influenced by the presence of insect hosts. In crops with high densities of potential hosts (Sitona lineatus in pea and partly Delia radicum in cabbage), nematode incidence increased from spring to autumn whereas nematode incidence remained unchanged or decreased when few hosts were present (in barley, carrots, alfalfa and leek).</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Perry, Roland</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3881/1/3881.htm</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nielsen, Otto and Philipsen, Holger   (2004) Seasonal population dynamics of inoculated and indigenous steinernematid nematodes in an organic cropping system.   Nematology, 6 (6), pp. 901-909.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3881/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>