<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökobilanz integrierter und ökologischer Apfelerzeugung in Hamburg</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Geier, Uwe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frieben, Bettina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gutsche, Volkmar</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 1997-1999 a life-cycle assessment of organic-extensive, organic-intensive and integrated apple production in Hamburg was carried out. The investigation was based on an analysis of 7 organic and 7 integrated farms in Hamburg and the surrounding area. The life-cycle assessment included 12 impact categories. The functional unit (1 kg apple or 1 ha farm land) differed depending on the impact categories. Compared to integrated production, organic production gave advantages in the impact categories ecotoxicity, human toxicity, drinking water protection, biodiversity and landscape image, whereas integrated production showed better results in the environmental effects that are caused by energy use. The investigation revealed potential for optimisation of organic production concerning the biotope structure, the use of copper preparations and especially the use of energy and machinery.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14914/1/130_geier_u.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Geier, Uwe; Frieben, Bettina; Gutsche, Volkmar and Köpke, Ulrich    (2000) Ökobilanz integrierter und ökologischer Apfelerzeugung in Hamburg.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  9. Internationaler Erfahrungsaustausch über Forschungsergebnisse zum Ökologischen Obstbau. Beiträge zur Tagung vom 3.-4. Februar 2000 in Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 130-134.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14914/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>