<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lernpotenziale des Scheiterns. Problemzentrierte Untersuchung&#xD;
des Einsatzes von ökologischen Lebensmitteln außer Haus</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rückert-John, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>John, René</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Research on organic farming and especially on the use of organic food products in the eating out sector has so far focused on successful strategies of implementation. The underlying political and scientific orientation on values resulted in difficulties of the description of the “real” situation in the empirical field. The research is concerned with the two positive values: success and organic. Processes of non-success are often neglected. This paper will present how the common research perspective and potentials of learning can be extended by an empirical observation of a so-called “rejection” on the use of organic food products in the eating out sector. For this purpose a theoretical approach of organisational structures, its changes as well as theoretical assumptions about the term non-success are required. The presentation of these assumptions on the research concept is based on a current project conducted by the authors.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14307/1/R%C3%BCckertJohn_14307.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rückert-John, Jana; John, René and Niessen, Jan    (2009) Lernpotenziale des Scheiterns. Problemzentrierte Untersuchung des Einsatzes von ökologischen Lebensmitteln außer Haus.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>