<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Crop responses to 15N-labelled organic and inorganic nitrogen sources</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>El-Naggar, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>El-Araby, Ahmed</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>de Neergaard, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, Henning</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A major challenge for low¬-external-input farming systems is to secure the N supply. Lack of synchrony between mineralization of organic N sources and plant N requirements is causing many growers to use different techniques to overcome this problem. One of these techniques is the application of soluble water extracts of different farm residues and plants. A field study was conducted to study the crop uptake of applied 15N-labeled alfalfa and clover extracts as compared to the N uptake from15N-glycine and three levels of 15N-(NH4)2SO4. The results show that total N accumulation in the field crops, squash and lettuce, was primarily affected by the amount of added N (P&lt;0.05) and not by the form in which the N was applied (P&gt;0.05). The utilization efficiencies of N (pNdff) from plant extracts and glycine increased (P&lt;0.05) gradually from 10, 20, to 30 days after application in contrast to (NH4)2SO4 which peaked in utilization efficiencies of 56% around 20 days after application. The pNdff reached 60%, 40% and 36% of the applied glycine, alfalfa and clover extracts, respectively in lettuce. Squash showed the same pattern during at 10, 20 and 30 days however the proportion of N derived from most of the treatments was higher in squash than in lettuce (p&lt;0.05). These results indicate that plant extracts of clover and alfalfa can be used as efficient N fertilisers in low-external-input agroecosystems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18305/1/18305.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>El-Naggar, Ahmed; El-Araby, Ahmed; de Neergaard, Andreas and Høgh-Jensen, Henning   (2008) Crop responses to 15N-labelled organic and inorganic nitrogen sources.   Nutrient Cycling in Agroecosystems, 80, pp. 49-60.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18305/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>