<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Sensory evaluation of processed wheat from a defined field- trial (QualityLowInputFood)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ploeger, Prof. Dr. Angelika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roeger, Monika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lueck, Dr. Lorna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leifert, Prof. Dr. Carlo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The integrated project QualityLowInputFood (QLIF) aims to improve quality, ensure safety and reduce costs along the organic and “low input” food supply chains. Beside safety, freshness, general health benefits as well as nutritional value, one reason for consumers demanding organic foods are more tasty products (Bourn/Prescott 2002). Therefore it is important to evaluate how the sensory attributes such as taste, flavour and texture of fresh and processed products are influenced by the different management systems. For sensory evaluation, in crop year 2005  seven wheat samples were assessed by a trained sensory panel, each with 4 field replicates (in total = 28 samples). The wheat samples were processed to wholemeal bread and biscuits for evaluation. &#xD;
&#xD;
A descriptive panel (12 persons) was well trained according DIN 10967 as well as for quantitative descriptive analysis (QDA). This method enables to show a complete product profile with all sensory characteristics and their intensity in appearance, aroma, texture, mouthfeel and flavour attributes.&#xD;
&#xD;
For wholemeal-bread, results in crop year 2005 showed no significant differences between the different farming systems. The influence of varieties were higher than farming management effects. The varieties “Paragon”, “Zebra” and “Fasan” were significant different to “Monsun” in texture attributes.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12178/1/Ploeger_12178_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ploeger, Prof. Dr. Angelika; Roeger, Monika; Lueck, Dr. Lorna and Leifert, Prof. Dr. Carlo    (2008) Sensory evaluation of processed wheat from a defined field- trial (QualityLowInputFood).       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12178/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>