<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Crop production and N leaching in arable organic farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, Jørgen E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Askegaard, Margrethe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The possibilities for increasing grain yields and reducing N leaching losses in organic ce-real production through manipulation of crop rotation design were investigated in a field experiment on different soil types in Denmark from 1997 to 2000. Three experimental fac-tors were included in the experiment in a factorial design: 1) proportion of grass-clover and pulses in the rotation, 2) catch crop (with and without), and 3) manure (with and with-out). Three four-course rotations were compared (Table 1). Two of the rotations had one year of grass-clover as a green manure crop, either followed by spring wheat or by winter wheat. The grass-clover was replaced by winter cereals in the third rotation. Animal ma-nure was applied as slurry in rates corresponding to 40% of the N demand of the cereals.&#xD;
&#xD;
The largest effects on both dry matter and N yields were caused by differences between sites caused by differences in soils, climate and cropping history. The rotation without a green manure crop produced the greatest total yield. Dry matter and N yields in this rota-tion were about 10% higher than in the rotation with a grass-clover ley in one year of four. Therefore, the yield benefits from the grass-clover ley could not compensate for the yield reduction as a result of leaving 25% of the rotation out of production. There were no dif-ferences in dry matter and N yields in grains between the rotations, where either spring or winter cereals followed the grass-clover ley. There were only small yield benefits from the use of catch crops at the crop rotational level.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>NJF</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Topi-Hulmi, M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1809/1/B0071.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Olesen, Jørgen E.; Askegaard, Margrethe and Rasmussen, Ilse A.    (2003) Crop production and N leaching in arable organic farming.       Paper at:   NJF's 22nd Congress "Nordic Agriculture in Global Perspective", Turku, Finland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1809/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>