<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lernen durch Scheitern beim Einsatz von Bio-Lebensmitteln in der Außer-Haus-Verpflegung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>John, René</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rückert-John, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niessen, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Knowledge management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The increasing importance of the eating-out sector has to be seen as a driver for the continued growth of the organic food market. Focusing on unsuccessful use of organic products this project analyses potentially useful information that could be deployed for strategic recommendations. There were 26 qualitative case studies conducted. Using guidelines, different histories or the establishment of organic food offers were explored. Additionally thirteen experts in the organic eating-out sector were surveyed. Beside descriptive findings concerning the communal feeding sector and the individual feeding sector a comparison analysis uncovered that decisions are department-specific within the respective organizations of eating-out. Critical success factors for organic offers concern not only the clientele, but also product quality, supply, certification constraints as well as the support of the superior organizational purpose. The problems are driven by external impulses, which are differently received by the departments of the organization however. This was a result of insufficient reflection on the purpose for using organic food products, the organization’s objectives as well as the necessary resource demands. With the help of structural recommendations, the process of introducing organic products can be based on strategic and focused planning in regard to purpose and means considering the reflection about made deci-sions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17708/3/Rueckert-John_17708.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>John, René; Rückert-John, Jana and Niessen, Jan    (2011) Lernen durch Scheitern beim Einsatz von Bio-Lebensmitteln in der Außer-Haus-Verpflegung.       Paper at:   11. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Gießen, 15.-18. März 2011.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17708/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>