<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>DEVELOPMENT OF ORGANIC SEED PRODUCTION SYSTEM OF  LOWLAND VEGETABLES AND FIELD LEGUMES AT BPI-LBNCRDC AND STRENGTHENING PARTNERSHIP IN CALABARZON, MIMAROPA AND BICOL REGION(PHASE 1)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gabertan, Herminigilda A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tepper, Lorna M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cueva, Mercedes L. Dela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buctuanon, Eugenia M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One and a half hectare organic seed production area was established in the Center. Organic seeds harvested were conserved for future use and a significant amount was distributed to farmer groups in partner areas and to other interested individuals in some important occasions. Existing practices used in organic crop production (including organic pesticides and nutrient supplements used) adopted by the Center were found to help in supplying nutrients to crop and in minimizing insect pests and disease occurrence. However, there is a need to do more detailed study on the effectiveness of these practices.  &#xD;
Evaluation of seed yield performance of different varieties of crops grown was done. Highest yielders were BPI-Cp3 (1.05 tons/ha) in cowpea; PSB Ps2 (1.54 tons/ha) and NSIC Ps5 (1.4 tons/ha) in pole sitao; NSIC Mg14 (0.88 ton/ha) in mungbean; and BPI-Tm9 (0.057 ton/ha) in tomato. &#xD;
Positive ROI was obtained by highest yielder varieties of cowpea, pole sitao, mungbean and tomato. In cowpea, BPI-Cp3 had 154.319% ROI; in pole sitao, PSB Ps2 334.917% ROI; while NSIC Ps5 had 295.379% in mungbean; NSIC Mg14 had 6.70% ROI; and in tomato, BPI-Tm9 had 63.390% ROI.&#xD;
Organic certification was granted by OCCP to the Center on June 24, 2013. A total of 1.28 hectare area and 675 kg organic seeds was certified as organic by the certifying body. The OCCP seal allowed for use by the Center is “Organic-in-Transition”.&#xD;
The project had established partnership with the Organization for Industrial, Spiritual and Cultural Advancement (OISCA) in Quezon; the Madrigal Foundation Inc.; and the Christ life Community in Camarines Sur. It had also partnered with the Department of Agriculture-Palawan Agricultural Experiment Station (DA-PAES) in Palawan. Harvest festivals and trainings were conducted in these areas. A total of 211 training participants attended and these activities were documented in Quezon, Bicol region, and Palawan. These accomplishments have motivated the team to continue its efforts on expanding the technology around the country by establishing more partnerships in different areas in the Philippines.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23337/7/23337.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gabertan, Herminigilda A.; Tepper, Lorna M.; Cueva, Mercedes L. Dela and Buctuanon, Eugenia M.    (2014) DEVELOPMENT OF ORGANIC SEED PRODUCTION SYSTEM OF LOWLAND VEGETABLES AND FIELD LEGUMES AT BPI-LBNCRDC AND STRENGTHENING PARTNERSHIP IN CALABARZON, MIMAROPA AND BICOL REGION(PHASE 1).       Poster at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23337/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>