<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Erhöhte Trockenstresstoleranz von Kleegras nach&#xD;
reduzierter Bodenbearbeitung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Berner, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nietlispach, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frei, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Dr. U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Dr. P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Grass-clover leys are an integral part of organic rotations. We performed an&#xD;
experiment with reduced tillage (RT) and conventional tillage (CT) using mouldboard&#xD;
ploughing in a rotation in Frick (Switzerland) on a heavy soil and 1000 mm mean&#xD;
annual precipitation. The grass-clover mixture was sawn in autumn 2005 after uniform&#xD;
seed bed preparation with a rotary hoe in both tillage systems without ploughing. After&#xD;
emergence most of the clover seedlings collapsed in the CT plots due to draught,&#xD;
while they survived in the RT plots. This led to a much higher share of clover in the&#xD;
mixture under RT. Grass-clover yields were 29 and 23% higher in RT than in CT plots&#xD;
in the first and second year of cultivation in 2006 and 2007, respectively. Grass grown&#xD;
in RT plots was higher in nitrogen (N), phosphorous (P), potassium (K) and&#xD;
magnesium (Mg) content than in CT plots; clover contained solely more P in RT plots.&#xD;
Over all grass-clover had better growing conditions in RT compared to CT plots in our&#xD;
experiment, reflecting after-effects of the differentiated tillage schemes applied for the&#xD;
preceding arable crops. It is suggested that reduced tillage has a high potential to&#xD;
improve water stress tolerance of cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14425/1/Berner_14425.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Berner, A.; Nietlispach, B.; Frei, R.; Niggli, Dr. U. and Mäder, Dr. P.    (2009) Erhöhte Trockenstresstoleranz von Kleegras nach reduzierter Bodenbearbeitung.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14425/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>