<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Managing the necessary cross-disciplinary approach to organic farming research programmes: example of an organic bread programme.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>VIAUX, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>TAUPIER-LETAGE, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>ABECASSIS, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This programme was developed within a cross-disciplinary approach resulting from five project proposals focusing on the organic wheat, flour and bread sector. More than 30 researchers from nine academic research laboratories, five technical centres, three development agencies and four industrial firms were involved in the project, covering a large area of expertise (from genetics to sociology). The programme adopted a reverse engineering approach, starting from consumer expectations and travelling, link-by-link, up the food chain. A qualitative study of consumer perception and expectations showed that organic bread was perceived as a natural, nourishing and healthy product, and that although its organoleptic characteristics (volume, texture, etc.) were a determining factor, they in no way totally accounted for the quality of the product. Nutritional value and safety must also be taken into consideration, especially in the case of occasional consumers. Based on this study, work was undertaken to find processing conditions to turn grain into flour and flour into bread, which would meet those expectations. New roller milling diagrams were developed at the industrial scale in order to produce flour with higher fibre and micronutrient contents. Studies of the bread-making process have shown that higher levels of lactic acid bacterium production in millstone flour are probably linked to its mineral content. A more acidic environment, due to sourdough fermentation, increases phytasic activity (improving digestibility) and increases mineral bioavailability, including magnesium. Based on those findings, prototype breads were developed and assessed by two panels of 60 people in two different regions of France. The results showed that it was possible to produce bread that satisfied consumers’ sensory and nutritional expectations by adapting the fractionation processes during bread-making according to the characteristics of the wheat.&#xD;
&#xD;
Finally, this programme resulted in a large number of publications and created a dynamic process between participants. It served as the backbone for several complementary satellite programmes that enhanced the original research while being integrated and supported by the project management committee.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15457/1/25-Viaux.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>VIAUX, P. ; TAUPIER-LETAGE, B.  and ABECASSIS, J.    (2009) Managing the necessary cross-disciplinary approach to organic farming research programmes: example of an organic bread programme.  [Comment gérer la nécessaire approche pluridisciplinaire et transversale des programmes de recherche en agriculture biologique ? L’exemple du programme « pain bio ».]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 183-196.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15457/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>