<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The Network of Ecological Compensation Areas in Switzerland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schlatter, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Since 1993, the Swiss law and Ordinance on Direct Payments for Agriculture (ODP) enables farmers to be compensated for ecological measures. A catalogue lists different possible measures which can be implemented at farm level both to create space for nature and biodiversity and to generate an alternative income for farmers. Measures include the maintenance of e. g. semi-natural structures in the landscape such as high-stem trees, hedges, pastures and meadows which are not intensively used (detailed catalogue: ART 2009). Succeeding a fast increase in the number of these areas, stagnation has been observed (BIODIVERSITYMONITORING 2009). Additionally, it has become evident, that many compensation areas are in unfavourable conditions for biodiversity and their quality, especially species richness, is low. This motivated the extension of the ODP with an additional ordinance which tackles two main points: Ordinance on Regional Promotion of Quality and Networking of Ecological Compensation Areas in Agriculture (OEQ 2001).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Bundesamt für Naturschutz (BfN)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Cowan, Carolin</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Epple, Cordula</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Korn, Horst</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schliep, Rainer</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Stadler, Jutta</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20307/1/schlatter-schader-2010-BfN-Skript264_p49-52.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schlatter, Christian and Schader, Christian    (2010) The Network of Ecological Compensation Areas in Switzerland.    In: Cowan, Carolin; Epple, Cordula; Korn, Horst; Schliep, Rainer and Stadler, Jutta (Eds.)  Working with Nature to Tackle Climate Change - Report of the ENCA / BfN Workshop on “Developing ecosystem-based approaches to climate change – why, what and how”.  BfN – Skripten, no. 264. Bundesamt für Naturschutz (BfN), Berlin, Deutschland, pp. 49-42.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20307/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>