<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Grünlandbewirtschaftung mit differenzierter Intensität - Ausgewählte Ergebnisse eines Parzellenversuchs am Standort Dummerstorf</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Titze, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jakobs, Marion</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The influence of different fertilization (NPK, PK, 0) and cutting frequency (2, 4 or 6 cuts) on dry matter yield, feeding value and plant composition of the sward of fen soil permanent grassland was investigated over five years. A randomizedblock design with plots was used, with three blocks. Effect of N application (NPK with 140 kg N/ha per year) was very low, because of a high N-mineralisation rate in the fen soil. Under intensive management (4 or 6 cuts) the PK-treatment (without N) reached a high feeding value as well as a high dry matter yield. This result may be very important for organic grassland farming on fen soils. Deficiencies in soil nutrients (0-treatment), especially potassium, reduce dry matter yield, high quality forage plants content of the sward and mineral content of the herbage.&#xD;
&#xD;
--&#xD;
(Sprache des Volltextes: Deutsch)</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5130/1/h33-06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Titze, Andreas and Jakobs, Marion   (2004) Grünlandbewirtschaftung mit differenzierter Intensität - Ausgewählte Ergebnisse eines Parzellenversuchs am Standort Dummerstorf.   Mitteilungen der Landesforschungsanstalt für Landwirtschaft und Fischerei Mecklenburg-Vorpommern, 33.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5130/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>