<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Farmers adoption of integrated crop protection and organic farming: Do moral and social concerns matter?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mzoughi , Naoufel</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>We investigate empirically the role of moral and social concerns in farmers' decision to adopt integrated crop protection (IP) and organic farming (OF). A survey questionnaire has been sent to 1286 fruit-growers and vegetable producers located in the French areas of Alpes de Haute Provence, Hautes-Alpes and Vaucluse. Analysis of individual responses (N = 243) shows that, although economic concerns play a strong role, a significant number of respondents give high importance to moral and social ones. We also examine how these considerations matter according to different crop protection strategies, that is, conventional farming, IP and OF. Using a multinomial logistic regression, we find that (1) social concerns (e.g., showing to others one's environmental commitment) drive both IP and OF adoption, (2) moral concerns (e.g., do not feel guilty about one's choices) increase the probability of organic farming adoption only, and (3) farmers who give high importance to economic concerns (e.g., cutting production costs) are less likely to adopt OF.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-04-19</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26304/1/Mzoughi_2011_EcolEcon_Vol70.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mzoughi , Naoufel   (2011) Farmers adoption of integrated crop protection and organic farming: Do moral and social concerns matter?   Ecological Economics, 70 (8), pp. 1536-1545.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26304/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>