<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Auslaufnutzung von Legehennen und Nahrungsangebot im &#xD;
Grünauslauf bei mobiler Haltung im Sommerhalbjahr</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Trei, Gerriet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Henning, Anna Carolin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lott, Mirka</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hörning, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Poultry</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Aim of the study was to carry out the outdoor use of laying hens and the feed supply from pasture in a mobile housing system in the summer time. Eight groups with 50 hens were used (Lohmann Brown Plus). The hens were kept in two mobile houses and according to the EU rules for organic agriculture. In a first subsequent experiment two area sizes (2,5 vs. 4,0 m²) and in a second subsequent experiment two frequencies of moving (7 vs. 14 days) were compared. &#xD;
The outdoor use was recorded via direct observations of behaviour (scan and focal sampling). On average 64 % of hens were recorded in the run. Number of hens was decreasing with increasing distance from the hen houses (3 distance zones). Most frequent behaviour was foraging (45 % of hens in the run). Area sizes and frequency of moving had only few influences on hen distribution and behaviour in the run.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21588/1/21588_trei.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Trei, Gerriet; Henning, Anna Carolin; Lott, Mirka and Hörning, Bernhard    (2013) Auslaufnutzung von Legehennen und Nahrungsangebot im Grünauslauf bei mobiler Haltung im Sommerhalbjahr.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21588/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>