<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of composts on growth and on yield quality of two crops, in a organic experimental farm of Southern Italy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Verrastro, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>El Hanafi Sebti, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hewidy M. Ramadan, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diacono, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cocozza, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Miano, T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil management in Organic Agriculture (OA) aims to improve the soil fertility (SF) supplying exogenous Organic Matter (OM) with composted and not – composted material. Hence, a two-year field experiment was carried out on a experimental farm of the Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari (IAMB) in Apulia Region, Italy, to evaluate the effects, on organically cultivated plant growth and quality (as nitrate accumulation – nitr), of Compost (Comp) also in comparison to commercial organic fertilizers. Our investigations, in particular, aimed to evaluate the influence of Comp on Broccoli crop (Brassica oleracea var. Italica) cultivar Canoe and two varieties of tomato (Solanum lycopersicum Mill var. Vespro and Multiplo). However, despite our broad results, more studies need to improve common knowledge about Comp effects especially for OA management.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12568/1/isofar2008_Verrastro.rtf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Verrastro, V.; El Hanafi Sebti, K.; Hewidy M. Ramadan, M.; Diacono, M.; Cocozza, C. and Miano, T.    (2008) Effect of composts on growth and on yield quality of two crops, in a organic experimental farm of Southern Italy.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12568/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>