<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic versus conventional potatoes – is there basis for consumers preference?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schulzová, Věra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hajšlová, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Diviš, Jiří</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Botek, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to investigate the influence of growing conditions on the quality of potatoes from organic farming systems as compared to that from conventional farming. In our previous study conducted in the years 1996 – 1999 we recognised some differences between the potatoes (Solanum tuberosum) from organic and conventional farming. To demonstrate the general validity of observed trends, follow up study was established in Czech Republic in the years 2002-2005. &#xD;
The ultimate goal of the project was to collate data for the assessment of a potential influence of foods from organic production system on consumers´ health by studying differences between potatoes grown in both systems (for this purpose the levels of potentially toxic compounds as well as nutritionally valuable components with regard to variety, geo-graphical location and inter-annual variation were determined).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7130/1/Schulzova_Organic_Congress_2006.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schulzová, Věra; Hajšlová, Jana; Diviš, Jiří and Botek, Petr    (2006) Organic versus conventional potatoes – is there basis for consumers preference?       Poster at:   Joint Organic Congress, Odense, Denmark, May 30-31, 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7130/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>