<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Biological activity of glucosinolate derived compounds isolated from seed meal of Brassica crops and evaluated as plant and food protection agents</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bellostas, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casanova, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Garcia-Mina, J.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, L.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jørgensen, L.N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kudsk, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Madsen, P.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, J.C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Glucosinolates are amino acid derived allelochemicals characteristic of plants of the order Capparales. These compounds are present in seeds of agriculturally common Brassica crops in varying quantities depending on the species (ref). The use of the remaining seed cake after oil extraction has traditionally been limited by the concentration of these compounds. However, the extraction of glucosinolates from seed meal is nowadays possible and it further contributes to an increased quality of the seed meal for feed (Sørensen et al., this conference). Glucosinolates are hydrolysed by endogenous enzymes (myrosinases; EC 3.2.1.147) and a number of compounds are produced depending on the parent glucosinolate and the environmental conditions.1 Among these compounds, oxazolidine-2-thiones are known for their antinutritional effects on monogastric animals, whereas isothiocyanates are fungicidal, nematocidal and herbicidal.2,3 The possibility for using glucosinolates as precursors for environmental friendly biocides therefore exists, which could contribute to increase the value of the Brassica seed meal.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11398/1/11398.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bellostas, N.; Casanova, E.; Garcia-Mina, J.M.; Hansen, L.M.; Jørgensen, L.N.; Kudsk, P.; Madsen, P.H.; Sørensen, J.C. and Sørensen, H.    (2007) Biological activity of glucosinolate derived compounds isolated from seed meal of Brassica crops and evaluated as plant and food protection agents.       Paper at:   12th International Rapeseed Congress, Wuhan, China, 26-29 March 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11398/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>