<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Towards a European Framework for Organic Market Information. Proceedings of the Second EISfOM European Seminar, Brussels, November 10 &amp; 11, 2005</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project European Information System for Organic Markets (EISfOM) is a concerted action funded by the European Commission under key action 5 (Quality of Life) of the 5th Framework Research and Technological Development Programme (QLK5 2002-02400).&#xD;
The main aim of the project is to develop a framework for the collection and processing of data on organic production and markets.&#xD;
At the second EISfOM seminar, which took place in November 2005 in Brussels, a draft framework for a European Information System for Organic Markets was discussed and defined.&#xD;
The proceedings of the seminar provide the papers presented, covering farm production, farm financial data, prices, consumers/consumption and supply balances/international trade. Detailed project information is available at  www.eisfom.org&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Table of Contents&#xD;
Foreword&#xD;
&#xD;
Towards a European Framework for Organic Market Information - Welcome and Opening Speech&#xD;
Nikiforos Sivenas	&#xD;
&#xD;
European Action Plan for Organic Food and Farming - DG Agriculture Initiatives under Action Point 3&#xD;
Eric Willems	&#xD;
&#xD;
Eurostat Initiatives on Organic Food and Farming Statistics	&#xD;
Lourdes LLorens Abando	&#xD;
&#xD;
European Case Studies on Information Systems for  Organic Markets – Results and Recommendations&#xD;
Norbert Gleirscher	&#xD;
&#xD;
Towards a Framework for European Organic Market Information - the EISfOM Vision and Summary of Recommendations&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin and Markus Rippin	&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
The EISFOM Proposals&#xD;
Klaas Jan Kramer, Markus Rippin, Helga Willer &#xD;
&#xD;
The EISfOM Proposal for Production: Ministry User Response	&#xD;
Nathalie Rison Alabert	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Comment on the EISfOM Proposal Farm Production: Certifyer Response	&#xD;
Michaela Coli 	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Administrative and Statistical Data Collection System for Organic Farming in Poland –  Recommendations for Improvement&#xD;
Marta Wróblewska and Sylwia Zakowska-Biemans	 &#xD;
	 &#xD;
The EISfOM Framework for Harmonising Organic Farm Production Data – Do the Proposals Work for us?	&#xD;
Phil Stocker	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Eurostat and ZMP Codes and Classification systems–  Different Approaches and Ways to Harmonisation&#xD;
Markus Rippin and Diana Schaack	55&#xD;
&#xD;
Estimating Supply and Demand in Scotland’s Organic Sector: The SAC Organic Market Link Project&#xD;
Caroline Bayliss	 &#xD;
&#xD;
From Agricultural Census Data towards Harmonised Organic Production Data	&#xD;
Arthur I.M. Denneman 	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Information System for Organic Markets in Lithuania	&#xD;
V. Rutkovienė, G. Abraitytė, A. Savilionis, E. Čijauska	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Characteristics of the organic data flow in Flanders: AMS: a key actor in Flanders for monitoring, reporting and analysis of organic data&#xD;
Vincent Samborski, Koen Carels, Dirk Van Gijseghem	&#xD;
 &#xD;
The Organic Market in Croatia&#xD;
Sonja Karoglan Todorovic and Darko Znaor	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Farm Level Production Data in Latvia’s Organic Farms&#xD;
Livija Zarina	 &#xD;
 &#xD;
EISfOM Recommendations Concerning Farm Financial Data&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin	 &#xD;
&#xD;
‘Organic’ Sampling and Weighting in Farm Accountancy Data Networks – A Discussion Note on Standard Gross Margins and Calibration&#xD;
Beat Meier	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Sampling of Organic Farms in the Dutch FADN:  Lessons Learned&#xD;
Hans C.J. Vrolijk	 &#xD;
&#xD;
The Ministry Perspective of FADN&#xD;
Rainer Meyer	 &#xD;
&#xD;
The FADN and the Analysis of Organic Farming:  the Italian Perspective&#xD;
Paola Doria and Alfonso Scardera,	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Berater-Praxis-Netzwerk (BPN) –  the Consultant-Producer-Network&#xD;
Rainer Löser	 &#xD;
&#xD;
The Use of a Benchmark Tool Based on FADN for  the Management of Organic Dairy Farms&#xD;
Alfons Beldman, Wil Hennen and Gerben Doornewaard	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Farming in FADNs –  Comparison Issues and Analysis&#xD;
Frank Offermann and Nicolas Lampkin	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Data Requirements for the Modelling of the Economic Potential for Conversion to Organic Farming&#xD;
Eva Kerselaers, Lieve De Cock and Ludwig Lauwers	&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Osservatorio Prezzi Bio: A Model of Analysis of Price Trends on the Organic Food Markets Francesco Giardina and Benedetta Torani	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Defining an EU-Reference System for Price Collection and Processing for Organic Products&#xD;
Markus Rippin	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Experiences of organic consumer-producer cooperatives in Andalusia (Spain): composition of the prices &#xD;
Itziar Aguirre	&#xD;
&#xD;
Experiences of Collecting Direct Sales Data in the UK&#xD;
Natalie Geen and Chris Firth	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Experiences of a Price Exchange Group for UK Organic Vegetable Growers	134&#xD;
Natalie Geen and Chris Firth	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Approaches to Improving the Availability of European Organic Consumption and Retail Data  – Methodological and Economic Issues&#xD;
Toralf Richter	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Results of an International Workshop on European Consumer and Retailer Panel Data for Organic Products in Bonn&#xD;
Paul Michels	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Biological Agriculture in the Netherlands:  Working Towards Five Percent Organic&#xD;
Johan Bakker&#xD;
&#xD;
Consumption of Organic Food in Spain&#xD;
Carmen Fuentes Bol	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Consumer and Retail Panel Data for Organic Foods: the German ‘Puzzle Approach’	156&#xD;
Barbara Bien	 &#xD;
&#xD;
European Consumer Panel Reporting of Organics&#xD;
Elizabeth May	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Information on Trade in Organic Products – The International Agency Point of View&#xD;
Alexander Kasterine	&#xD;
&#xD;
	 &#xD;
The Need for Data from the Viewpoint of Policy Makers&#xD;
Peter Crofts	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Need for Data from the Viewpoint of Policy Makers: A Third Country Perspective	168&#xD;
Juan Carlos Ramírez and Nora Liliana Puppi	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Organic Trade Association Perspective  A Questionnaire for Scientists and Statisticians&#xD;
Conrad Thimm	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Stakeholder Perspectives on Organic Food Supply Balances  and International Trade Data&#xD;
Alexander Gerber	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Market Supply Balances and International Trade Data for Organic Goods: the viewpoint of the stakeholders&#xD;
Victor Gonzálvez	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Data for Supply Balances and International Trade – Possibilities to Build up Data Collecting and Processing Systems&#xD;
Guido Recke and Ulrich Hamm	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Compiling Supply Balance Sheets&#xD;
Francis Weiler	 &#xD;
&#xD;
International Trade in Organic Products from the Perspective of a National Statistical Office&#xD;
Poul Henning Larsen	 &#xD;
	 &#xD;
Institutional structures for EISfOM&#xD;
Markus Rippin, Nicolas Lampkin and Raffaele Zanoli	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Building European Knowledge: Towards the Seventh Framework Programme 2007-2013&#xD;
Danielle Tissot	 &#xD;
&#xD;
Conclusions of the 2nd EISfOM European Seminar&#xD;
Nicolas Lampkin</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rippin, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lampkin, Nicolas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Vaughan, Alison</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6054/1/rippin-etal-2006-eisfom.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rippin, Markus; Willer, Helga; Lampkin, Nicolas and Vaughan, Alison (Eds.)      (2006) Towards a European Framework for Organic Market Information. Proceedings of the Second EISfOM European Seminar, Brussels, November 10 &amp; 11, 2005.     Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6054/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>