<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EU-Beitritt und die wirtschaftlichen Folgen für Öko-Betriebe &#xD;
in den neuen Mitgliedsländern</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Zander, Katrin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thobe, Petra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The adaptation of the European agricultural policy began in 2004 in most of the new member states and is associated with significant changes in support at the farm level. Typical farm modelling showed that with the accession to the EU, the economic per-formance of organic farms in selected Eastern European study countries will improve largely until 2013. The increase in income is almost exclusively attributed to increasing payments. Modelling of different organic market scenarios shows that the marked increase in payments could also compensate for losses if organic markets would develop in an unfavourable manner. Thus, the economic success of organic farms in the selected new member states depends highly on the persistence of the newly introduced payments in the face of increasing production costs.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9288/1/9288_Zander_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Zander, Katrin and Thobe, Petra    (2007) EU-Beitritt und die wirtschaftlichen Folgen für Öko-Betriebe in den neuen Mitgliedsländern.  [EU-Accession and the economic consequences for organic farms in the new member states.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9288/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>