<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>A polyocular framework for research on multifunctional farming and rural development</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Noe, Egon</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Alrøe, Hugo F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Langvad, Anne Mette S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paradox of multifunctionality is that, on the one hand, the specialized functionalities of agriculture only arise because of the functional differentiation of social systems and scientific disciplines and, on the other hand, multifunctionality can only enter as a way to mediate between conflicts, interests and fragmented knowledge when different functions and observations of functions combine. The aim of this paper is to contribute to a theoretical and methodological platform for multidisciplinary research on multifunctional farming. With the notions of polyocular cognition and polyocular communication we introduce a second order, interdisciplinary communication process that can meet the challenge of creating a shared view on multifunctional farming. Polyocular communication must be based on other rules than the rules of the involved disciplines. Whereas disciplinary communication is about providing consistent, efficient and precise knowledge in the context of a sharply delimited research world, polyocular communication is about extending a multidimensional space of understanding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15580/1/A_polyocular_framework_final_submit_18dec07-for_print.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Noe, Egon; Alrøe, Hugo F. and Langvad, Anne Mette S.   (2008) A polyocular framework for research on multifunctional farming and rural development.   Sociologia Ruralis, 48 (1), pp. 1-15.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15580/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>