<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Durum wheat in conventional and organic farming: yield amount and pasta quality in Southern Italy.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fagnano, Massimo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fiorentino, Nunzio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>D'Egidio, Maria Grazia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Quaranta, Fabrizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ritieni, Alberto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ferracane , Rosalia</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Raimondi, Giampaolo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Five durum wheat cultivars were grown in a Mediterranean area (Southern Italy) under conventional and organic farming with&#xD;
the aim to evaluate agronomic, technological, sensory, and sanitary quality of grains and pasta. The cultivar Matt produced the&#xD;
best pasta quality under conventional cropping system, while the quality parameters evaluated were unsatisfactory under organic&#xD;
farming. The cultivar Saragolla showed the best yield amount and pasta quality in all the experimental conditions, thus proving&#xD;
to be the cultivar more adapt to organic farming. In all the tested experimental conditions, nivalenol (NIV) and deoxynivalenol&#xD;
(DON) occurrence was very low and the other mycotoxins evaluated were completely absent. These data conﬁrm the low risk of&#xD;
mycotoxin contamination in the Mediterranean climate conditions. Finally, it has been possible to produce high-quality pasta in&#xD;
Southern Italy from durum wheat grown both in conventional and organic farming.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11378/1/TSWJ_973058_grano_duro.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fagnano, Massimo; Fiorentino, Nunzio; D'Egidio, Maria Grazia; Quaranta, Fabrizio; Ritieni, Alberto; Ferracane , Rosalia and Raimondi, Giampaolo   (2012) Durum wheat in conventional and organic farming: yield amount and pasta quality in Southern Italy.   TheScientificWorldJOURNAL, 2012, pp. 1-9.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11378/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>