<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alpha-tocopherol and beta-carotene in legume-grass mixtures as influenced by wilting, ensiling and type of silage additive</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lindqvist, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nadeau, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Søren K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Effects of wilting, ensiling and type of additive on a-tocopherol and b-carotene contents in legume–grass mixtures were examined. Swards of birdsfoot trefoil + timothy (Bft + Ti), red clover + timothy (Rc + Ti)and red clover + meadow fescue (Rc + Mf) were harvested as a first regrowth in August 2005. Forage was wilted to a dry-matter (DM) content of 273 g/kg and ensiled without additive or with an inoculant or acid. Wilting decreased a-tocopherol concentration by 30% in the Bft + Ti mixture (P = 0.015). Untreated Bft + Ti silage had higher a-tocopherol content than red clover silages (56.9 vs. 34.2 mg/kg DM; P = 0.015). The a-tocopherol concentration of Bft + Ti forages increased during ensiling from 41.1 mg/kg DM in wilted herbage to 56.9, 65.2 and 56.8 mg/kg DM in untreated, inoculated and acid-treated silage respectively(P = 0.015). The inoculant increased a-tocopherol content in the red clover silages (50.1 vs. 34.2 mg/kg DM; P = 0.015) compared with untreated red clover silages. Red clover mixtures had lower b-carotene content than Bft + Ti (32.3 vs. 46.2 mg/kg DM; P = 0.016), averaged over treatments. In conclusion, wilting had small effects but the use of bacterial inoculant as an additive and a Bft + Ti mixture increased a-tocopherol concentration in the silage.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19764/1/j_1365-2494_2011_00827_x.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lindqvist, H.; Nadeau, E. and Jensen, Søren K.   (2011) Alpha-tocopherol and beta-carotene in legume-grass mixtures as influenced by wilting, ensiling and type of silage additive.   Grass and Forage Science, ?, ?-?.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19764/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>