<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss eines positiven Handlings von Mastbullen auf die&#xD;
Stressreaktivität der Tiere und auf die Fleischqualität</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Spengler Neff, Anet</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Probst, Johanna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hillmann, Edna</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leiber, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigated whether a positive handling had a stress reducing effect on&#xD;
beef cattle. Eight finishing bulls were randomly assigned to a handling group and a&#xD;
control group. The handling group received 10 times 4 minutes of positive handling,&#xD;
spread over 5 weeks before slaughter. After 5 weeks avoidance distance had decreased&#xD;
in the handling group, but not in the control group. No differences in behaviour&#xD;
were observed during trailer loading. Handled animals showed less stress-indicating&#xD;
behaviour when entering the stunning box. Blood samples were taken before handling&#xD;
sessions and one day before slaughter and during exsanguinations. Cortisol-, lactateand&#xD;
glucose concentrations were elevated in sting blood of all animals. Control animals&#xD;
showed higher lactate and glucose concentrations in sting blood than handled&#xD;
animals. In meat quality tests control animals showed higher cooking losses than&#xD;
handled animals. Those results imply that a calmative handling in the forefront of&#xD;
slaughter can decrease animals’ stress reactions at slaughter.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14412/1/SpenglerNeff_14412.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Spengler Neff, Anet; Probst, Johanna; Hillmann, Edna and Leiber, Florian    (2009) Einfluss eines positiven Handlings von Mastbullen auf die Stressreaktivität der Tiere und auf die Fleischqualität.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14412/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>