<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Entwicklung regionaler Vermarktungsstrategien gefährdeter Tomatensorten in NRW, Deutschland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klein, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simons, Johannes</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Banik, Ina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Köpke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four old and endangered tomato cultivars were cultivated in a greenhouse under organic conditions. With an average yield between 10 to 12 kg m-2, these old cultivars can compete with those tomato cultivars currently dominating the organic market. New marketing strategies were developed, tested in focus groups and offered on the re-gional market in organic shops and in a staff canteen. Both a coloured tomato basket and a mixed tomato fruit salad were positively evaluated by the consumers. Short distribution distances, preserving biodiversity and organic production were important preference factors for the consumers.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9282/1/9282_Klein_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klein, Daniela; Simons, Johannes; Banik, Ina and Köpke, Ulrich    (2007) Entwicklung regionaler Vermarktungsstrategien gefährdeter Tomatensorten in NRW, Deutschland.  [Development of Regional Marketing Strategies of Endangered Tomato Cultivars in NRW, Germany.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9282/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>