<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecofruit: International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This conference represents a continuation of previous meetings and is intended to bring together active researchers and advisers involved in organic fruit growing to discuss latest results and methods. The main object is the coordination of research and to organize joint research projects. The official language of the workshop is English. Contributions are possible in English and German. Oral presentations will be simultaneously translated to English.&#xD;
&#xD;
---------------------&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
Table of Contents of the "10th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing and Viticulture 2002":&#xD;
&#xD;
Fruit-growing - Resistance breeding&#xD;
- Breeding apples with durable disease resistance&#xD;
- Yield and Quality of New Scab-Resistant Apple Varieties&#xD;
- Alleyway groundcover management and scab resistant apple varieties &#xD;
&#xD;
Fruit-growing - Insect control&#xD;
- Effect of Quassan, a Quassia product, against Sawflies (Hoplocampa testudinea) &#xD;
- Control of the apple sawfly (Hoplocampa testudinea Klug) with extracts from Quassia amara L: Quality and combination with NeemAzal-TS &#xD;
- Control of Adoxophyes orana FvR with entomopathogens and NeemAzal-TS: first approach for optimal combination strategies &#xD;
   &#xD;
Fruit-growing - Control of Sooty blotch&#xD;
- Sooty Blotch of Apple: Etiology and Management &#xD;
- First Examinations to date the exactly Time of Infection of Sooty Blotch &#xD;
- Influence of application strategy of coconut soap on the development of sooty blotch on apple &#xD;
  &#xD;
Fruit-growing - Control of post harvest disease&#xD;
- Use of Thermotherapy and Natural Antifungal Compounds against Post Harvest Diseases on Apples  &#xD;
- Erste Ergebnisse der Heißwasserbehandlung an ökologisch erzeugten Äpfeln &#xD;
- Efficacy and Pertinence of Heat Treatments against Monilia Decay in Commercial Conditions &#xD;
- Results of an experiment on storage diseases at the apple variety Pinova &#xD;
  &#xD;
Fruit-growing - Control of apple scab&#xD;
- The post infection use of lime sulphur to control apple scab Experiences in the Netherlands 1999-2002 &#xD;
- Control of venturia inaequalis: substitutes for and reduced use of copper &#xD;
- Greenhouse-Experiments on control of Venturia inaequalis - First Results &#xD;
- Apfelschorfbekämpfung 2001 unter besonderer Berücksichtigung der Berostung &#xD;
- Mode of action of lime sulphur against apple-scab (Venturia inaequalis)  &#xD;
- Inhibition of the germination of conidia from Venturia inaequalis using lime sulphur, sulphur, copper and Ulmasud in comparison to Dithianon &#xD;
   &#xD;
Fruit-growing - fruit quality and fruit thinning&#xD;
- Parameters for apple quality and an outline for a new quality concept &#xD;
- Screening of agents for thinning blossoms of apple trees &#xD;
- Neem Azal TS against the cherry fruit moth Argyresthia pruniella L in sour cherry &#xD;
- Results of 5 years of thinning trials with lime sulphur In South Tyrol &#xD;
  &#xD;
Viticulture - copper replacement and plant defence&#xD;
- Copper replacement in organic viticulture - state of the art in legislation and research &#xD;
- Biology of Plasmopara viticola - Approach to a biological control of grapevine downy mildew &#xD;
- Induced resistance: a strategy for the control of grape downy mildew? &#xD;
- Grapevine Berry Phenolic Compounds in Relation with Plant Water Status &#xD;
- Disease-resistant vine varieties as a tool to minimize the use of copper &#xD;
  &#xD;
Viticulture - copper replacement by use of plant extracts and plant defence&#xD;
- About the use of antagonistic bacteria and fungi &#xD;
- Use of Reynoutria sachalinensis plant extracts, clay preparations and Brovibacillus brevis against fungal diseases of grape berries &#xD;
- Fungicidal preparations from Inula viscosa  &#xD;
- Effects of plant extracts on downy mildew of vine-laboratory and field experiments &#xD;
- Evaluation of environmentally friendly products for control of fungal diseases of grapes &#xD;
  &#xD;
Viticulture - practical experience in organic viticulture&#xD;
- Effects of different cultivation techniques on vineyard fauna &#xD;
- Kupferreduzierung im ökologischen Weinbau in Deutschland Feldversuche und praktische Erfahrungen &#xD;
- Copper reduction and copper replacement - results and experiences of 12 years on farm research &#xD;
   &#xD;
Posters fruit-growing&#xD;
- Undergrowth of late summer sowings at the tree strip &#xD;
- Persistence of the biological effect of codling moth granulovirus in the orchard - preliminary field trials &#xD;
- Influence of fungicides used in organic orchards on the net-photosynthesis of apple trees &#xD;
- Effects of a "Pflanzenstärkungsmittel" on yield influencing factors of apple, first results from the PR China &#xD;
- ´Classy Apple project' to reduce the quality gab between suppley and demand of organic apples &#xD;
- Effect of root pruning on productivity and performance of the apple varieties "Jonagold" and "Elstar" &#xD;
- Main problems and first approach for solutions in organic nursery production &#xD;
- Testing of new strawberry varieties for organic production &#xD;
- Medicinal plants in late blight management of organic potato &#xD;
- Replant problems in South Tyrol: role of fungal pathogens and microbial populations in conventional and organic apple orchards &#xD;
- Organic Horticulture Research at HDRA &#xD;
&#xD;
Posters viticulture&#xD;
- Assay system to screen for compounds inducing PR-gene expression in grape vine (Vitis spec) &#xD;
- Ovules Culture and Plant Formation of Hybrid Progeny of Seedless Grape &#xD;
- Tests with Milsanaâ and Brevibacillus brevis for side-effects against Typhlodromus pyri (Acari, Phytoseiidae) and Aphidius rhopalosiphi (Hymenoptera, Braconidae) &#xD;
- Cueva - a new copper fungicide based on copper salts &#xD;
- Lava Granules - a way to improve the Soil Structure? &#xD;
- Test and valuation of a new system for under-vine cultivation (SIEGWALD HS 1200) in organic viticulture &#xD;
&#xD;
---------------------&#xD;
&#xD;
For Table of Contents of the 9th Conference ("9. Internationaler Erfahrungsaustausch über Forschungsergebnisse zum Ökologischen Obstbau vom 3.-4. Februar 2000 in Weinsberg" - in German only) see "Additional Abstract" on this web page (full texts available at www.infodienst-mlr.bwl.de/la/lvwo/Veroeff/Erfahrungsaustausch9.htm).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>text/html</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1618/1/ecofruit.htm</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    Ecofruit: International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing.  [Internationale Wissenschaftstagung zum ökologischen Obstbau.]   Runs 1995 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V., Staatliche Lehr- und Versuchsanstalt für Wein- und Obstbau and Eugrof, (European Group of Researchers on Organic Fruit-Growing).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1618/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>