<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regulation of cytochrome P450 mRNA expression in primary porcine hepatocytes by selected secondary plant metabolites from chicory (Cichorium intybus L.)</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, Martin Krøyer</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klausen, Christina Lindgaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ekstrand, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Chicory (Cichorium intybus) has been shown to induce enzymes of pharmacokinetic relevance (cytochrome P450; CYP). The aim of this study was to investigate the effects of selected secondary plant metabolites with a global extract of chicory root, on the expression of hepatic CYP mRNA (1A2, 2A19, 2C33, 2D25, 2E1 and 3A29), using primary porcine hepatocytes. Of the tested secondary plant metabolites, artemisinin, scoparone, lactucin and esculetin all induced increased expression of specific CYPs, while esculin showed no effect. In contrast, a global extract of chicory root decreased the expression of CYP1A2, 2C33, 2D25 and 3A29 at high concentrations. The results suggest that purified secondary metabolites from chicory affect CYP expression and thereby might affect detoxification in general, and that global extracts of plants can have effects different from individual components.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-19</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24791/7/24791.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, Martin Krøyer; Klausen, Christina Lindgaard and Ekstrand, Bo   (2013) Regulation of cytochrome P450 mRNA expression in primary porcine hepatocytes by selected secondary plant metabolites from chicory (Cichorium intybus L.).   Food Chemistry, 146 (1), pp. 255-263.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24791/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>