<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Einfluss unterschiedlicher Konkurrenzverhältnisse beim Mischanbau von Som-mergerste und Erbse auf den Kornertrag, die Kornqualitäten und der symbiontischen N2-Fixierung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dahlmann, Christoph</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>von Fragstein und Niemsdorff, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Field experiments with spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) and field pea (Pisum sativum L.) were carried out in three subsequent growing seasons 2004 to 2006 at the Hessian State Estate Frankenhausen located near Kassel in Central Germany. Spring barley and field pea were sown out as sole crops and intercropped with different seed rates in replacement and additive design, using two sowing modes: row by row (IC) and mixed intercropping (MC). Intercropping (IC and MC) was able to increase grain yield in most of the treatments. The Land Equivalent Ratio (LER) was always higher than 1, indicating that plant growth factors were used more efficiently by the intercrop than by the sole crop. Besides, the N content in spring barley grain was increased by intercropping. The influence of the sowing mode was much less profound than that of the seed rate. The proportion of nitrogen derived from the atmosphere (% Ndfa) of peas was higher when cultivated together with spring barley.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9755/1/9755_Dahlmann_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dahlmann, Christoph and von Fragstein und Niemsdorff, Peter    (2007) Einfluss unterschiedlicher Konkurrenzverhältnisse beim Mischanbau von Som-mergerste und Erbse auf den Kornertrag, die Kornqualitäten und der symbiontischen N2-Fixierung.  [Influence of different competitions in spring barley-field pea intercropping on grain yield, quality and the proportion of nitrogen derived from the atmosphere.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9755/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>