<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Breeding of resistant strawberry cultivars for organic fruit production – Diallel crossing strategies and resistance tests for Botrytis cinerea and Xanthomonas fragariae</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bestfleisch, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Höfer, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Richter, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hanke, M.-V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schulte, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Peil, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Flachowsky, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic strawberry production suffers from high yield losses caused by numerous fungal and bacterial diseases. Two of the most important diseases are the grey mould disease caused by Botrytis cinerea Pers. (teleomorph Botryotinia fuckeliana), and the bacterial angular leaf spot disease caused by Xanthomonas fragariae (Kennedy &amp; King). Beside cultivation methods and organic plant protection measures, the development of resistant cultivars seems to be the most promising strategy in order to improve the productivity in organic strawberry cultivation. Therefore, we established resistance tests to determine resistant and susceptible strawberry cultivars and breeding selections. In a first run, 40 different cultivars and selections were tested for their susceptibility towards B. cinerea by artificial inoculation of fruits and leaves and evaluation of the disease symptoms. Plants of 40 cultivars were tested for susceptibility to X. fragariae by artificial inoculation in the greenhouse. In a diallel crossing approach, 12 commonly cultivated strawberry cultivars have been crossed reciprocally and propagated in a field trial. Important characteristics of the progeny such as ripening time, yield, morphological traits and occurrence of diseases have been evaluated for a period of two consecutive years and lead to the determination of general (GCA) and specific (SCA) combining abilities. Together with the results of the resistance tests we identified a set of genotypes that show resistant characteristics towards B. cinerea and might be suitable for use in organic cultivation systems. Furthermore, they can be used for targeted breeding experiments in the future.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-02-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20553/1/Bestfleisch-etal-2012-StrawberryEcofruit.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bestfleisch, M.; Höfer, M.; Richter, K.; Hanke, M.-V.; Schulte, E.; Peil, A. and Flachowsky, H.    (2012) Breeding of resistant strawberry cultivars for organic fruit production – Diallel crossing strategies and resistance tests for Botrytis cinerea and Xanthomonas fragariae.   In:   Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO) (Ed.)  Proceedings of the 15th international conference on organic fruit production, pp. 221-227.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20553/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>