<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SIGMEA: Sustainable introduction of GM crops into European Agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>EU Project on Traceability and Co-Existence&#xD;
The EU-funded “Co-Extra” project is now exploring the co-existence and traceability of genetically modified (GM) and non-genetically modified (non-GM) products. It contains eight separate work packages. All in all 54 institutes and companies are involved in the research project which is funded by the EU with 13,52 Mio € for four years.&#xD;
In work package 3, FiBL is examining the economic costs and benefits of traceability and co-existence together with eight other European partners. Each country will examine a different set of products.&#xD;
In Switzerland, the first step will be to analyse the produce flow for maize and rapeseed and to identify the stakeholders in the value-added chain. This part of the project will be completed in the summer of 2006. Subsequently, the costs caused by traceability and co-existence will be calculated and it will be assessed whether customers would be willing to pay a higher price for guaranteed non-GM produce. In the final phase of the project the economic consequences of consumers' reactions to the new EU rules on labelling and traceability will be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
Further Information:&#xD;
&#xD;
GM and non-GM supply chains: their CO-EXistence and TRAceability &#xD;
www.coextra.org &lt;http://www.coextra.org&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
Contact persons at FiBL:&#xD;
- Matthias Stolze (http://www.fibl.org/english/fibl/team/stolze-matthias.php)&#xD;
- Bernadette Oehen (http://www.fibl.org/english/fibl/team/oehen-bernadette.php)&#xD;
- Marion Morgner (http://www.fibl.org/english/fibl/team/morgner-marion.php)&#xD;
&#xD;
Coextra project coordinator:&#xD;
&#xD;
Yves BERTHEAU&#xD;
Institut National de la Recherche Agronomique (INRA)&#xD;
Phytopathologie et méthodologies de la détection&#xD;
RD 10 - Route de Saint CYR&#xD;
F-78026 Versailles cedex&#xD;
France&#xD;
Tel: +33 1 30 83 32 04&#xD;
Fax: +33 1 30 83 31 95&#xD;
Email: bertheau@versailles.inra.fr &lt;MAILTO:bertheau@versailles.inra.fr&gt;</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    SIGMEA: SIGMEA: Sustainable introduction of GM crops into European Agriculture.  [Nachhaltige Einführung von GV-Nutzpflanzen in die Europäische Landwirtschaft.]   Runs 2004 - 2007.      Project Leader(s): Stolze, Matthias, Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), CH-5070 Frick.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6225/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>