<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Technologische Alternativen zum herkömmlichen Einsatz von Pökelstoffen in Öko-Fleischwaren</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Beck, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marx, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lücke, F.-K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On the basis of literature research and opinions of meat processors and other experts, this paper discusses alternatives to the currently permitted use of curing agents in the processing of organic meat. These alternatives include (i) the reduction of addition of nitrite to levels sufficient for the desired sensory properties, (ii) the in situ bacterial formation of nitrite from nitrate naturally present in added vegetable preparations, and (iii) not making use of the beneficial effects of nitrite on the colour and aroma of the product at all. Measures to be taken to compensate for the effects of nitrite, as well as problems in implementation of technological alternatives are discussed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9417/1/9417_Beck_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Beck, A.; Marx, B. and Lücke, F.-K.    (2007) Technologische Alternativen zum herkömmlichen Einsatz von Pökelstoffen in Öko-Fleischwaren.  [Technological Alternatives to the Use of Curing Agents in organic meat products.]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9417/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>