<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of Different Defoliation Systems of Ryegrass–Clover on Yield and Selected Quality Parameters of Organic Potatoes (Solanum tuberosum L.) for Industrial Processing at Harvest and After Storage</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dresow, Jana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Krause, Tanja</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Haase, Norbert U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loges, Ralf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, Jürgen</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The nitrogen supply plays an important role in achieving quality characteristics in organic potato farming. Different defoliation systems of ryegrass–clover may influence the amount of fixed nitrogen available to the tubers. In a field experiment, the effect of different defoliation systems (cutting, mulching and a combination of them) of the pre-crop ryegrass–clover on selected quality attributes of organically grown potatoes, destined for processing into French fries (cv. Agria) or crisps (cv. Marlen), were conducted in two consecutive years (2003 and 2004).&#xD;
Parameters studied included compounds related to the sensory properties of potato food (tuber dry matter, starch, reducing sugars) as well as nutritional quality (nitrogen,minerals). Selected agronomic parameters such as total tuber yields and tuber size distribution were also compared. Furthermore, the influence of additional slurry fertilisation and 4 months of storage on these parameters were investigated. Total yields and portion of tuber yield 50–60 mm were significantly affected by the pure mulching variant in 2003. In 2003, the starch concentration at harvest, as well as after storage, was above the required minimum of 22% (cv. Marlen) and 19% (cv. Agria),while in 2004, this was slightly beneath these values. In 2004, a significant increase of starch concentration by the pure cutting variant was observed. In both years, mulched ryegrass–clover caused a decrease in tuber DM contents of 2.10 and 3.54%, respectively, compared to the cutting systems. Fertilisation significantly decreased DM and starch concentration. In 2004, the reducing sugar concentration of tubers of cv. Marlen from the pure cutting system was with 2.1 g kg−1 FM above the required maximum of 1.5 g kg−1 for crisps. In addition, storage led to a three to fivefold increase of reducing sugars concentrations in the tubers in this year. After slurry fertilisation, 8.8% higher N contents and up to 36% higher K concentrations were measured. Mulching of the pre-crop combined with slurry application led to an up to 61% higher tuber K concentration compared to the cutting system. The results indicate that different defoliation systems of the pre-crop ryegrass–clover and slurry fertilisation had only minor effects on internal tuber quality attributes. Quality parameters were more affected by the prevailing weather conditions in combination with the genotype of different potato cultivars.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27887/1/10.1007_s11540-013-9239-8_print.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dresow, Jana; Krause, Tanja; Haase, Norbert U.; Loges, Ralf; Heß, Jürgen and Böhm, Herwart   (2013) Effect of Different Defoliation Systems of Ryegrass–Clover on Yield and Selected Quality Parameters of Organic Potatoes (Solanum tuberosum L.) for Industrial Processing at Harvest and After Storage.   Potato Research, 56 (3), pp. 179-204.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27887/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>