<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Soil quality indicators in organic and conventional farming systems in Slovakia</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Lehocka, Zuzana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klimekova, Marta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bielikova, Magdalena</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In this study we compare some chemical and biological soil properties using the organic and conventional systems. In 2003 and 2004 the soil characteristics were observed on the precise field experiment plots in Borovce (near Piešťany, in the western part of the Slovak Republic) where organic management has taken place since 1995. The soil representative is loam and clay, loam degraded Chernozem on loess. The chemical and biological soil properties were determined within two farming systems: organic and conventional. The lower values of soil reaction and the higher contents of organic matter and inorganic nitrogen in the soil were measured under organic treatment. Organic management also positively affected a number of the cellulolytic and ammonification bacteria as well as microbial biomass content, ammonification and nitrification activity. The earthworm population was more developed at the organic variant. During the years 2003 and 2004, after eight years of organic management utilisation, the tendency of increased biological activity in the soil under organic management was observed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12169/1/Lehocka_12169_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Lehocka, Zuzana; Klimekova, Marta and Bielikova, Magdalena    (2008) Soil quality indicators in organic and conventional farming systems in Slovakia.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12169/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>