<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Emmer wheat using and growing in the Czech Republic</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Konvalina, Petr</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stehno, Zdenek</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Capouchova, Ivana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan (Jr.)</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Juza, Martin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moudry, Jan</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Emmer wheat [(Triticum dicoccum Schrank (Schuebl)] is after bread, durum and spelt wheat further species of wheat&#xD;
used for economic purposes. Organic farmers and producers have become more and more interested in marginal crops&#xD;
such as the tetraploid emmer wheat because of its suitability for organic farming. In spite of its historical role, present distribution of emmer is very limited. The work analyzes the problem of growing possibilities of emmer and its suitability for cultivation in organic farming. In the Czech Republic it is grown only a few farms, but in Austria is more popular now. Possible candidates for the cultivation of emmer has several options about where to obtain a suitable variety. The best option appears to be the choice of legally protected variety Rudico. Another option would be to obtain seed from abroad or multiplication of seed of its own genetic resources. Among important properties of emmer belongs e.g. considerably high resistance to some fungal diseases, which make it advantageous in organic system of growing. Hulled grain requires procedure of peeling. High grain quality, first of all high protein content, predetermines emmer wheat for preparation of healthy dishes in bio quality. The grains are suitable for the production of unyeasted products&#xD;
because of their specific quality. As the emmer wheat is grown especially in the organic farming system, the processing of grains has to respect the individuality of this obsolete cereal species. It may be used for the production of healthy regional food products.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20770/1/IASI_-_konvalina_a_kol..pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Konvalina, Petr; Stehno, Zdenek; Capouchova, Ivana; Moudry, Jan (Jr.); Juza, Martin and Moudry, Jan   (2010) Emmer wheat using and growing in the Czech Republic.   Lucrări Ştiinţifice, Seria Agronomie, 53 (2), pp. 15-19.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20770/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>