<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ecological Animal Husbandry in the Nordic Countries. Proceedings from NJF-seminar No. 303. Horsens, Denmark 16-17 September 1999</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>During the last decade there has been a rapid development and a great increase in the area of organic farming, both in the Nordic countries and in the rest of Europe. This development is due to an increased marked, but also due to an increased interest in society because organic farming contributes to a better environment and a more healthy animal husbandry. &#xD;
&#xD;
During this development it is a great challenge for research to give explanations and to follow up and provide the knowledge that is needed in society, i.e. research is an important factor to secure quality, health and sustainability in the production. &#xD;
&#xD;
Often, research and practical agriculture in the Nordic countries face the same problems. The aim of the NJF/DARCOF seminar at Horsens was thus to present current research projects from the different countries. Through a presentation of research projects it is possible to learn from experience obtained in the different countries and it becomes possible to create a far more extensive collaboration across the frontiers.&#xD;
&#xD;
In this report the various presentations are collected and elaborated. The desire is to contribute to the development of research in organic animal husbandry, and to promote both Nordic and international co-operation in the area.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Hermansen, John E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lund, Vonne</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Thuen, Erling</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3057/1/dar_2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hermansen, John E.; Lund, Vonne and Thuen, Erling (Eds.)    (2000) Ecological Animal Husbandry in the Nordic Countries. Proceedings from NJF-seminar No. 303. Horsens, Denmark 16-17 September 1999.   DARCOF Report, no. 2. Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3057/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>