<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Regionalvermarktung und Bio-Produkte: Spannungsverhältnis oder sinnvolle Ergänzung?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Banik, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Simons, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Several studies on organic and region-of-origin labelled products assume that combining both characteristics enhances the success of the products on food markets. This paper presents results of two surveys which together give an insight into the compatibility of advertising the characteristics “organic” and “produced in the region of consumption” (regional products) for the case of Germany. Based on indepth interviews, the surveys reveal that the combination of both characteristics can complement each other but can also lead to unfavourable effects for both, organic and regional products. Hence, if market segments for organic and regional products are too small to serve them separately, the contrariness of the characteristics should be taken into account for developing adequate communication strategies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9548/1/9548_Banik_Vortrag.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Banik, I. and Simons, J.    (2007) Regionalvermarktung und Bio-Produkte: Spannungsverhältnis oder sinnvolle Ergänzung?  [Regional marketing and organic products: Contrariness or reasonable completion?]      Paper at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9548/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>