<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Certifying Out of Home Operators in Europe. European Forum for Certification. Summary of a Forum held at the BioFach Congress 2009</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Strassner, Carola</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Values, standards and certification</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>As in previous years the annual meeting on organic certification in the out-of-home sector took place at the&#xD;
congress of the BioFach Trade Fair, on the 22nd of February 2009. As a conclusion to this meeting this&#xD;
report now summarizes the main topics of the “European Forum for Certification” with the focus on the&#xD;
presentations in Nuremberg. The presenters delivered insight into the various situations in their countries&#xD;
and indicated the challenges that they currently are dealing with. Depictions included developments in&#xD;
Belgium, Finland, Italy, Germany, Norway, Switzerland and The Netherlands. After describing and discussing&#xD;
the issues the country presenters agreed to have this paper developed by the organisers, which gives a&#xD;
short overview of the proceedings to all participants and to all interested in this topic.&#xD;
&#xD;
The Council Regulation (EC) No 834/2007 on organic production and labelling of organic products came into&#xD;
force on January 1, 2009. It repeals the former Regulation (EEC) No 2092/91 and for the first time explicitly&#xD;
refers to mass catering (out of home). The Regulation excludes catering and eating enterprises from&#xD;
mandatory certification whilst at the same time giving each country the option how best to proceed. How do&#xD;
member countries deal with this new situation? The presenters go into detail and this summary&#xD;
characterizes some detailed situations in the following pages.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ICROFS</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2009-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17427/1/CORE_PSR__Stra_Proc_euCert_2009_VF.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Strassner, Carola         (2009) Certifying Out of Home Operators in Europe. European Forum for Certification. Summary of a Forum held at the BioFach Congress 2009.    ICROFS, Tjele, Denmark.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17427/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>