<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Proposals for Regulation of Botanicals</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Tamm, Lucius</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Speiser, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mercier, Thierry</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Plants and plant extracts, here called 'botanicals', have been used for plant protection for a long time. Quantitatively, the most important botanical is pyrethrum, followed by azadirachtin, rotenone and essential oils. The current regulatory systm for pesticides is often seen as a major hurdle for the market introduction of new botanicals. The EU-funded Specific Support Action project 'REBECA' has held a series of workshops with stakeholder representatives. The following propopsals for improvement were elaborated: (1) development of a specific guidance document for botanicals; (2) adapted requirements concerning the characterisation of the active substance(s); (3) relaxations concerning identification and analytical methods for 'impurities'; (4) adapted requirements concerning the description of manufacturing methods; (5) adapted requirements for risk assessment, taking into account the history of safe use of the substance; (6) adapted requirements concerning efficacy evaluation. During the final conference of the REBECA project, it was evaluated which proposals can be implemented easily (and therefore in a short timespan). Also, the impact on the duration of the registration process and on the costs of registration (for the applicant) were assessed for each proposal. Fenugreek, neem extract/Quassia, lecithine and laminarine were selected as representative botanicals. For these substances, the REBECA proposals would decrease registration costs substantially.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science + Business Media B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18739/1/Speiser_etal_2011_botanicals.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Tamm, Lucius; Speiser, Bernhard and Mercier, Thierry    (2011) Proposals for Regulation of Botanicals.    In:      Regulation of Biological Control Agents.  Springer Science + Business Media B.V., Dordrecht Heidelberg London New York, pp. 289-304.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18739/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>