<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Comparison of organic and conventional farming system in term of energy efficiency</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klimeková, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lehocká, Z.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study was to compare the energy use in cereal crop rotation in conventional and organic farming system in terms of additional energy inputs, gross energy production, energy profit and energy efficiency evaluation in years 2003 – 2005 in the stationary field experiment established on degraded Chernozem on loess in a maize – barley growing region in south west Slovakia (near Piešťany town).  Increased energy inputs caused the increase of production in the Conventional Farming System. The Conventional System was more energy demanding (about 52.5%) in comparison with the ecological one. The most energy demanding crops were those amended by farm yard manure: maize for grain (21.31 GJ ha-1in the organic system, 34.18 GJ ha-1in the conventional system) and winter wheat (17.20 GJ ha-1in the organic system, 24.60 GJ ha-1in the conventional system). The highest energy gain provided maize for grain in both farming systems (179.22 GJ ha-1in the conventional system and 177.99 GJ ha-1in the organic system).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9841/1/9841_Klimekov%C3%A1_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klimeková, M. and Lehocká, Z.    (2007) Comparison of organic and conventional farming system in term of energy efficiency.       Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, Stuttgart, Deutschland, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9841/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>