<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Researching Sustainable Systems. International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, coordinated by the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR) in co-operation with the International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM) and the National Association for Sustainable Agriculture Australia (NASAA).&#xD;
Adeledaide, Australia, 21 - 23 September 2005</dc:title>
  <dc:description>The International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture Researching Sustainable Systems will be coordinated by the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR) in co-operation with the International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM) and the National Association for Sustainable Agriculture Australia (NASAA). The conference is a main module of the 15th IFOAM Organic World Congress*, hosted by NASAA. The conference will be held in Adeledaide, Australia, 21 - 23 September 2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
ISOFAR will be in charge of reviewing papers for the scientific conference and for the programme coordination.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Other</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/3000/1/isofar-2004-researching-sustainable-systems.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>(2004) Researching Sustainable Systems. International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, coordinated by the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research (ISOFAR) in co-operation with the International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM) and the National Association for Sustainable Agriculture Australia (NASAA). Adeledaide, Australia, 21 - 23 September 2005.   .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/3000/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>