<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Feeding mastitis milk to organic dairy calves: effect on health and performance during suckling and on udder health at first calving</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Abb-Schwedler, Katharina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maeschli, Ariane</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Boss, Renate</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Graber, Hans U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Steiner, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Klocke, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Beef cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Background&#xD;
Infection pathways of S. aureus udder infections in heifers are still not well understood. One hypothesis is that calves become infected with S. aureus via feeding mastitis milk. Especially on small-scale farms, pasteurisers are not economic. The purpose of this randomised comparative study was to investigate the influence of feeding milk containing S. aureus genotype B (SAGTB) on the health and development of calves and udder health of the respective heifers. Additionally, a method reducing the bacterial load to obtain safer feeding milk was tested. Thirty-four calves were fed mastitis milk from cows with subclinical SAGTB mastitis. One group was fed untreated milk (UMG). For the other group, milk was thermised at 61°C for one minute (heat treated milk group = HMG). After weaning, calves were followed up until first calving. A milk sample of these heifers was taken at first milking to compare udder health of both groups.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-11-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28099/1/s12917-014-0267-7.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Abb-Schwedler, Katharina; Maeschli, Ariane; Boss, Renate; Graber, Hans U.; Steiner, Adrian and Klocke, Peter   (2014) Feeding mastitis milk to organic dairy calves: effect on health and performance during suckling and on udder health at first calving.   BMC Veterinary Research , 10 (267), pp. 1-11.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28099/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>