<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Assessing nutrient and sediment transport for Water Framework Directive  purposes using the SWAT model - a case study in SW Finland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bärlund, Ilona</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kirkkala, Teija</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kämäri, Juha</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The ecological status of lake Pyhäjärvi, located in south-western Finland, may be classified as moderate due to its elevated nutrient concentrations and algal biomass production. Thus, the Yläneenjoki river basin, accounting for &gt;50% of the total phosphorus loading to the lake, was chosen as the Finnish test catchment in the Benchmark models for the Water Framework Directive project. One aim of the project was to test the suitability of models like the catchment scale model SWAT for the assessment of nutrient and sediment transport and management options needed to meet the surface water quality requirements.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16279/1/pollutants5.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bärlund, Ilona; Kirkkala, Teija and Kämäri, Juha    (2006) Assessing nutrient and sediment transport for Water Framework Directive purposes using the SWAT model - a case study in SW Finland.       Paper at:   Transport and retention of pollutants from different production systems : NJF seminar 373, Tartu, Estonia, 11-14 June 2006.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16279/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>