<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>European Information System for Organic Markets</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Surveys and statistics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The project European Information System for Organic Markets (EISfOM) is a European Concerted Action, funded under under key action 5 (Quality of Life) of the 5th Framework Research and Technological Development Programme  of the European Union. The project will run from 2003 to 2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
EISfOM aims to build up a framework for reporting valid and reliable data for relevant production and market data about the European organic sector in order to meet the needs of policy makers, farmers, processors, wholesalers and other actors involved in organic markets. &#xD;
&#xD;
The major outputs of EISfOM will be&#xD;
- A review of existing data collection systems&#xD;
- Proposals to improve data quality and data collection systems for organic markets&#xD;
- Recommendations for future development and co-ordination of data collection systems in 32 European countries&#xD;
&#xD;
The project is managed the project partners core partners and representatives of key international organisations, including Eurostat, the European Commission, the Food and Agriculture Organisation (FAO), the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) and the International Federation of Organic Agriculture Movements (IFOAM). &#xD;
&#xD;
The EISFOM member network unites numerous experts, including representatives of regional, national and European statistical offices and the private organic sector.&#xD;
&#xD;
The following institutions are part of the EISfOM partnership:&#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 1 (Coordinator): University of Wales Aberystwyth, Institute of Rural Sciences, led by Dr. Nicolas Lampkin, Llanbadarn Campus, UK- SY23 3AL Aberystwyth Ceredigion&#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 2: Research Institute of Organic Agriculture FiBL, Fachgruppe Sozio-Ökonomie, Dr. Toralf Richter, Ackerstrasse /Postfach, CH-5070 Frick, Tel. +41 62 8657272, Fax +41 62 8657273, E-mail toralf.richter@fibl.org, Internet http://www.fibl.org &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 3: Leopold Franzens Universität Innsbruck, Zentrum für Berglandwirtschaft, Dipl.-Ing. Markus Schermer, Technikerstr. 13, A-6020 Innsbruck, Tel. +43 512 507 5690, Fax +43 512 507 2817, E-mail markus.schermer@uibk.ac.at, Internet http://www2.uibk.ac.at/berglandwirtschaft/ &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 5: Zentrale Markt- und Preisberichtstelle (ZMP), FB Ökologischer Landbau, Markus Rippin, Rochusstr. 2-6, D-53123 Bonn, Tel. +49 228 9777 0, Fax +49 228 9777 369, E-mail markus.rippin@zmp.de, Internet http://www.zmp.de &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 6: Università Politecnica delle Marche, Dipartimento di Ingegneria Informatica, Gestionale dell'Automazione (DIIGA), Prof. Dr. Raffaele Zanoli, Via Brecce Bianche, I-60131 Ancona, Tel. +39 071 2204929, Fax +39 071 2204858, E-mail zanoli@agrecon.unian.it, Internet http://www.agr.univpm.it/ &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 7: Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming (DARCOF), Claus Bo Andreasen, P.O. Box 50, Foulum, DK-8830 Tjele, Tel. +45 89 99 10 35, Fax +45 89 99 16 73, E-mail clausbo.andreasen@agrsci.dk, Internet http://www.foejo.dk &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 8: Warsaw Agricultural University SGGW, Faculty of Human Nutrition Sciences and Consumer Studies, Dr. Sylwia Zakowska-Biemans, Nowoursynowska 159 C, PL-02-776 Warszawa, Tel. +48 22 843 90 41 ext. 112 91, Fax + 48 22 847 27 83, E-mail zakowska@alpha.sggw.waw.pl, Internet www.sggw.waw.pl &#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 9: WUR Landbouw Economisch Institut, Dr. Klaas Jan Kramer, P.O. Box 29703, Burgermeester Patijnlaan 19, NL-2502 LS Den Haag, Tel. + 31 70 3358245, Fax +31 70 3615624, E-mail klaasjan.kramer@wur.nl&#xD;
&#xD;
- Partner 10: Universität Kassel, Fachbereich Ökologische Agrarwissenschaften, Fachgebiet Agrar- und Lebensmittelmarketing, Prof. Dr. Ulrich Hamm, Steinstraße 19, D-37213 Witzenhausen, Tel. +49 5542 98-1284, Fax +49 5542 98-1286, E-mail hamm@uni-kassel.de, Internet http://php.uni-kassel.de/fb11cms/alm/default.php?cPath=1</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Project description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1096/1/eisfom_2004_about.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1096/2/eisfom_2004_press_release_august_2003.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1096/3/eisfom_2004_press_release_may_2004.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/1096/4/eisfom_2004_press_release_may_2004_figures_europe.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Project}    EISfOM: European Information System for Organic Markets.    Runs 2003 - 2006.      Project Leader(s): Lampkin, Nicolas, University of Wales.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/1096/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>