<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Field tests with Madex Plus against CpGV-resistant codling moth populations in organic orchards in 2006</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Volk, F.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>When resistance to the Mexican isolate of Cydia pomonella Granulovirus (CpGV-M) arose&#xD;
in several organic orchards in Germany in 2004 and 2005, the future of codling moth&#xD;
control became a serious concern of organic fruit growing. In 2006, a new virus isolate&#xD;
from Andermatt Biocontrol AG (Madex Plus) was first tested in two field trials in organic&#xD;
orchards on codling moth populations resistant against the Mexican isolate of CpGV.&#xD;
Madex Plus showed a better efficacy on these populations than Madex 3. However, larval&#xD;
mortality larvae seemed to be somewhat delayed. A very good effect was shown in&#xD;
population control. The number of larvae in corrugated card board belts was significantly&#xD;
reduced after treatment with Madex Plus. In addition to these trials, on-farm trials in all&#xD;
orchards concerned of the CpGV-M resistance were carried out. The results of on-farm&#xD;
trials showed the same tendency: high efficacy in population control against a background&#xD;
of slightly delayed larval death. In 2007, Madex Plus was applied successfully in all&#xD;
organic orchards with CpGV-M-resistant codling moth populations in Germany.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13706/1/261-264.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, J.; Zimmer, J.; Volk, F. and Zebitz, C.P.W.    (2008) Field tests with Madex Plus against CpGV-resistant codling moth populations in organic orchards in 2006.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 261-264.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13706/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>