<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Anfälligkeit neuer Kartoffelsorten gegenüber Kraut- und Knollenfäule (Phytophthora infestans) und Rhizoctonia (Rhizoctonia solani) – entscheidend für Ertrags- und Qualitätssicherung im biologischen Anbau</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dupuis, B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Reust, W</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schwärzel, R</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hebeisen, Th</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ballmer, Th</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Musa, T</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Potato is affected by numerous diseases. Among those diseases, late blight (Phytophthora infestans) and rhizoctonia (Rhizoctonia solani) have a strong economic impact. Organic farming doesn’t have efficient protection products to control those diseases and to guarantee yield and production quality. Furthermore, we observe that organic food chain propose the same cultivars as the traditional food chain and those cultivars are generally susceptible to late blight. Regarding to the trials managed to propose new cultivars to Swiss cultivars recommendation list, there are numerous new cultivars with interesting resistance profile. Among 141 cultivars tested, 30 could be proposed to the organic food chain. Indeed, those cultivars are less susceptible to late blight and rhizoctonia and can cover the whole range of potato utilization from boiled potato to French fries and crisps.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14780/1/Late_Blight_ACW_ART_final.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dupuis, B; Reust, W; Schwärzel, R; Hebeisen, Th; Ballmer, Th and Musa, T    (2009) Anfälligkeit neuer Kartoffelsorten gegenüber Kraut- und Knollenfäule (Phytophthora infestans) und Rhizoctonia (Rhizoctonia solani) – entscheidend für Ertrags- und Qualitätssicherung im biologischen Anbau.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologsicher Landbau, ETH Zürich, 11.-13.2.2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14780/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>