<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Welche Bodenzusätze helfen bei der Lösung von Problemen mit Feldaufgang in Spinat?</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meyer, Audrey</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fuchs, Jacques G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schärer, Hansjakob</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Damping-off of spinach, caused by soil-borne pathogens, is one of the most serious problems in organic spinach production. To overcome these problems soil amendments based on specific strains of micro-organisms or based on organic material are proposed. In pot experiments under controlled conditions 14 microbial strains and six organic soil amendments were tested on their ability to suppress soil borne diseases and to improve plant stand establishment. In a subsequent field experiment with the best treatments, soil amendments with compost showed the best effect while products based on single strains of micro-organisms failed to improve plant stand establishment. It is concluded that under high disease pressure a diverse population of microorganisms as it can be found in compost may more effectively suppress soil borne diseases than single strains of micro-organisms.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21556/1/21556_Meyer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meyer, Audrey; Fuchs, Jacques G. and Schärer, Hansjakob    (2013) Welche Bodenzusätze helfen bei der Lösung von Problemen mit Feldaufgang in Spinat?       Poster at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21556/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>