<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>SOFTPEST MULTITRAP - MANAGEMENT OF STRAWBERRY BLOSSOM WEEVIL AND EUROPEAN TARNISHED PLANT BUG IN ORGANIC STRAWBERRY AND RASPBERRY USING SEMIOCHEMICAL TRAPS</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Wibe, Atle</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cross, Jerry V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hall, David R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Trandem, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sigsgaard, Lene</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Baroffio, Catherine</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ralle, Baiba</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fountain, Michelle T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Many growers of organic strawberry and raspberry have large losses in yield and reduced quality of their products because of insect damage. For many insects species pheromones and host plant volatiles are of major importance in mate finding and host plant location. In this project we want to extend our knowledge of these systems to develop effective control measures to control these pests in organic crops. The focus will be on the strawberry blossom weevil, the European tarnish plant bug and the raspberry beetle.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23830/1/23830%20SOFTPEST%20MULTITRAP%20Wibe%20et%20al._MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Wibe, Atle; Cross, Jerry V.; Borg-Karlson, Anna-Karin; Hall, David R.; Trandem, Nina; Sigsgaard, Lene; Baroffio, Catherine; Ralle, Baiba and Fountain, Michelle T.    (2014) SOFTPEST MULTITRAP - MANAGEMENT OF STRAWBERRY BLOSSOM WEEVIL AND EUROPEAN TARNISHED PLANT BUG IN ORGANIC STRAWBERRY AND RASPBERRY USING SEMIOCHEMICAL TRAPS.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 883-886.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23830/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>