<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Governance Structures for the Multifunctionality of Agriculture in the EU - Bottom-up View of Local Stakeholders in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schader, Christian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The multifunctional character of agriculture has gained increasing attention in both policy and research over the last few years. The most relevant policy initiative for the programming period 2000-2006 in terms of multifunctionality is Council Regulation (EC) No 1257/1999, while LEADER+ is of particular interest due to its innovative approach to governance (Schader and Stolze, 2005a).&#xD;
In order to improve governance structures it is necessary to find out what the governance situation is at the regional level and what regional stakeholders think about the multi-level governance system. So far, there is little empirical evidence regarding the way local stakeholders perceive governance processes in the EU in terms of rural development. The aims of this study were:&#xD;
- to identify the governance structures relevant to the multifunctionality of agriculture,&#xD;
- to determine the strengths and weaknesses of regional implementation of the second pillar of the EU Common Agricultural Policy,&#xD;
- and to develop recommendations for good governance in rural development policy.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Gesellschaft für Wirtschafts- und Sozialwisssenschaften des Landbaues e.V. (GEWISOLA)</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Kuhlmann, F.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schmitz, P.M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13386/1/schader-stolze-2007-poster-giessen06.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schader, Christian and Stolze, Matthias    (2007) Governance Structures for the Multifunctionality of Agriculture in the EU - Bottom-up View of Local Stakeholders in Europe.   In: Kuhlmann, F. and Schmitz, P.M. (Eds.)  Good Governance in der Agrar- und Ernährungswirtschaft, Gesellschaft für Wirtschafts- und Sozialwisssenschaften des Landbaues e.V. (GEWISOLA).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13386/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>