<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Evidence on the effect of healthy and sustainable school meals system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Denmark</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Public expenditure to counteract the effects of unhealthy lifestyle is increasing in most western countries and as a result health public healthy nutrition strategies to ounteract this development is to an increasing extent informed by evidence. Evidence is normally defined as an proof of the fact that interventions has an impact on some recognised problem of societal concern by using some generally and scientifically accepted method. Within the field of promotion of healthy and sustainable eating among young people a number of authoritative supranational bodies including Council of Europe, Commission of EU and WHO has called for action to be taken at school. Such policy documents are important to initiate action however they cannot create progress alone. This paper introduces the evidence approach to promotion of healthy and sustainable eating at school by drawing on recent school intervention studies. It discusses the role of evidence in relation to other types of policy informing sources such as except opinion, cases stories and best practices.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15840/1/15840.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Mikkelsen, Bent Egberg    (2007) Evidence on the effect of healthy and sustainable school meals system.       Speech at:   International Alimenterra Conference: The role of public food service in promoting sustainable rural development, health environmental and food education., Sevilla, November 7-9, 2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15840/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>