<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Stabilization and plant uptake of N from 15N-labelled pea residue 16.5 years after incorporation in soil</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Laberge, Guillaume</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ambus, Per</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nielsen, Henrik Hauggaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Erik Steen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The decline of N from 15N-labelled mature pea residues was followed in unplanted soil over 16.5 yr. Eight years after residue incorporation, 24% of the residue 15N input was still present in the soil and, after 16.5 yr, 16% of the residue 15N input remained. A double exponential model successfully described the decay of N from 15N-labelled pea residues. The total residual 15N declined with average decay constants of 1.45 yr−1 for the 30 d to 1 yr period and of 0.07 yr−1 for the 1–16 yr period. Sixteen years following incorporation of the residues, indicator plants growing in residues-amended soils were obtaining 1.7% of their N from residue N. This is, to our knowledge, the longest study on decay of N in soils from 15N-labelled crop residues. The current study thus provides a unique data set for our empirical understanding of N-dynamics in agricultural systems, which is a prerequisite to parameterize and validate N-simulation models.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11213/1/11213.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Laberge, Guillaume; Ambus, Per; Nielsen, Henrik Hauggaard and Jensen, Erik Steen   (2006) Stabilization and plant uptake of N from 15N-labelled pea residue 16.5 years after incorporation in soil.   Soil Biology and Biochemistry, 38 (7), pp. 1998-2000.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11213/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>