<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Winter treatments against the woolly apple aphid (Eriosoma lanigerum): products and timing of applications</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Casera, Claudio</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic apple growing the woolly apple aphid (Eriosoma lanigerum) is still an unsolved&#xD;
problem. Various approaches to use beneficial insects were not really effective. Only&#xD;
winter treatments with mineral oils showed partial and fluctuating success.&#xD;
In 2006 and 2007 field trials were carried out to evaluate the efficacy of winter treatments&#xD;
to control woolly apple aphids. The efficacy of several products (different mineral oils, lime&#xD;
sulphur, and lime sulphur + mineral oil) was tested in comparison to an untreated control,&#xD;
and possible side effects on the population of predatory mites were investigated. The&#xD;
study furthermore aimed at establishing the best timing of the application against the target&#xD;
pest.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13676/1/196-202.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Lardschneider, Ewald and Casera, Claudio    (2008) Winter treatments against the woolly apple aphid (Eriosoma lanigerum): products and timing of applications.   In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 13th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 18thFebruary to 20th February 2008 at Weinsberg/Germany, pp. 196-202.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13676/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>