<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Management of red clover content of organic grassland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nykänen, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leinonen, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nykänen-Kurki, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The clover content is an important factor in organic grassland management to optimize yield, feeding value and pre-crop effect of the ley. The variation of red clover (Trifolium pratense) content in swards of different age is often rather high in Finland. In the ongoing field experiment (1999-2002) staggered sowing of red clover seed was tested to regulate the clover content of the mixed sward. Sowing strategy did not have clear effect on the clover content or the yield of the sward. However the seeding rate affected the clover density of the field (plants/m²) in the first year. After two years the differences were equated. The best strategy to control the clover amount in the mixed swards seems sowing of 2 or 3 kg/ha (100 or 150 seeds/m²) clover seeds in establishment and then oversow on a first second ley year 1 or 2 kg/ha (50 or 100 seeds/m²).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Latvia University of Agriculture</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2002</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4075/1/4075.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nykänen, A.; Leinonen, P. and Nykänen-Kurki, P.    (2002) Management of red clover content of organic grassland.   In:     Scientific aspects of organic farming, Latvia University of Agriculture, pp. 101-103.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4075/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>