<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Quality control of reared parasitoids:preliminary study on the application of RAPD Molecular Marker technique to the model Opius concolor.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>SFEIR, Thérèse</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Olive</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The evaluation of field efficiency of reared Opius concolor released to control the olive fly, in the presence of indigenous populations interfering with release results becomes unreliable. RAPD (Random Amplified Polymorphic DNA) molecular marker technique was proposed to differentiate between indigenous and reared populations.Indigenous samples were collected from several regions in Puglia-Basilicata-Sardinia. Reared populations were brought from the insectarium of Cagliari-Sardinia .The initiation of a biomolecular work lead to the setting of a starting protocol, with an adequate extraction method, elements concentration, and primers applied.The preliminary observations on laboratory population in comparison with collected indigenous ones have shown diagnostic markers with NP4 primer of 620 bp, and with A10 of 260bp-760bp. The latter could be considered important in monitoring the released insect field efficiency. These findings assure the reliability of the RAPD methodology in evaluating quality of reared Opius at field level.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2003</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6658/1/SfeirTherese03.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>SFEIR, Thérèse   (2003) Quality control of reared parasitoids:preliminary study on the application of RAPD Molecular Marker technique to the model Opius concolor.  [Control de qualité de parasites d’élevage: étude préliminaire sur l’application de la technique du marqueur moléculaire RAPD sur le modèle Opius concolor.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic Farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 298. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6658/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>