<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Instant infusion pasteurisation of bovine milk. I. Effects on bacterial inactivation and physical-chemical properties.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hougaard, A.B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hammershøj, Marianne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vestergaard, Jannie S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Poulsen, Ole</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ipsen, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Processing, packaging and transportation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Two types of milk, skim milk and non-standardized raw milk, were heat treated using direct heating by instant infusion pasteurization with treatment temperatures in the range from 72°C to 120°C and with holding times of less than 1 second. Indirect heating by HTST pasteurization (72°C for 15 seconds) was used for comparison. The inactivation of microorganisms reached at least the same level when using instant infusion pasteurization compared to HTST pasteurization. Changes in the physical-chemical properties were observed in the skim milk fractions of instant infusion pasteurized non-standardized milk, whereas for instant infusion pasteurized skim milk less influence from the treatments was observed.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/16582/1/16582.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hougaard, A.B.; Hammershøj, Marianne; Vestergaard, Jannie S.; Poulsen, Ole and Ipsen, R.   (2009) Instant infusion pasteurisation of bovine milk. I. Effects on bacterial inactivation and physical-chemical properties.   International Journal of Dairy Technology, 62 (4), pp. 484-492.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/16582/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>