<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Alternatives to Synthetic Chemical Antiparasitic Drugs in Organic Livestock Farming in Europe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hoste, Hervé</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sotiraki, Smaragda</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejer, Helena</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heckendorn, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maurer, Veronika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Thamsborg, Stig</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Gastrointestinal parasitism with helminths and protozoa remains a major threat in cattle and small ruminant production and has been “rediscovered” in pig and poultry production systems operating under organic farming rules because of the requirement to grant outdoor access to the animals. The control of these parasitic infections is a key issue for the economic viability of farms and for animal welfare. Control solutions aim at (i) providing the agronomical bases for parasite control through rational management of pastures; (ii) stimulating the host immune response through different means; (iii) exploring and evaluating the efficacy of new drugs (i.e., phytotherapy, homeopathy and nutraceuticals); and (iv) developing new concepts of application of chemical antiparasitic drugs (e.g., targeted selective treatments).&#xD;
These four control principles will be illustrated with examples taken from the different livestock production systems. The perspectives of current research are to provide both organic and conventional farmers with a “basket of options” to be adapted to the various situations, in order to achieve more sustainable, integrated approaches to parasite control.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Springer Science+Business Media</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Bellon, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Penvern, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25741/1/Chapter%208_ProofPDF-2HH.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hoste, Hervé; Sotiraki, Smaragda; Mejer, Helena; Heckendorn, Felix; Maurer, Veronika and Thamsborg, Stig    (2014) Alternatives to Synthetic Chemical Antiparasitic Drugs in Organic Livestock Farming in Europe.    In: Bellon, S. and Penvern, S. (Eds.)   Organic Farming, Prototype for Sustainable Agricultures.  Springer Science+Business Media, Dordrecht, chapter 8, pp. 149-169.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25741/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>