<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>BREVE RESEÑA DE LA EVOLUCION DE LA AGRICULTURA ORGANICA EN COLOMBIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>CRUZ URIBE, FABIAN</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Animal husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop husbandry</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Country reports</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Colombia had during 2010 around 40190 Ha. Organic, with 7400 Ha. in conversion process. This  mean that only 0,1% of the land was cultivated organically, very few in comparission with Argentina and Mexico that keep an area around 2-3% during the las 5 years. Colombia has 70% of their organic area dedicated to produce fruits, coffee and heart of palm, and other 25% to produce oils and cane. The country produced in 2010 around 7 millions tons of organic products. Colombia   had sucessfull experiences in production and marketing of some tropical products as banana, mango, pineapple, dried fruits, coffee, and palm oil. But it is very poor their experience in animal production. Led by the Agricultural Ministry, there are an Interinstitutional Organic Agriculture Committee to promove the normativity, technological development, education, certification process, quality, marketing and others activities considered in the National Plan of Organic Agriculture, otherwise the research process in this area in Universities and research institution are very low. This article try to show the situation of Organic Agriculture in Colombia to promote their development.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Working paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18245/1/CRUZ_2011_RESENA_.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>CRUZ URIBE, FABIAN    (2011) BREVE RESEÑA DE LA EVOLUCION DE LA AGRICULTURA ORGANICA EN COLOMBIA.  [BRIEF REVIEW OF THE ECOLOGICAL AGRICULTURE EVOLUTION IN COLOMBIA.]   Working paper, FACULTAD DE MEDICINA VETERINARIA Y DE ZOOTECNIA, UNIVERSIDAD ANTONIO NARIÑO.   [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18245/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>