<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Salmonella Infection Level in Danish Indoor and Outdoor Pig Production Systems measured by Antbodies in Meat Juice and Faecal Shedding on-farm and at Slaughter</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Bonde, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sørensen, J.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pigs</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The prevalence of Salmonella shedding was compared in 34 organic, conventional outdoor, and indoor pig herds. Individual faecal and meat juice samples from 30-50 pigs per herd were analysed for presence of Salmonella, and Salmonella antibodies, respectively. We found low levels of Salmonella shedding on farm and at slaughter in organic and conventional outdoor herds compared to indoor pigs. Overall 5,5 % of the pigs were seropositive. The serological test result was associated with Salmonella shedding at slaughter in pigs from conventional systems, but not in organic pigs. The duration of transport did not affect the risk of Salmonella shedding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13728/1/13728.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Bonde, M. and Sørensen, J.T.    (2007) Salmonella Infection Level in Danish Indoor and Outdoor Pig Production Systems measured by Antbodies in Meat Juice and Faecal Shedding on-farm and at Slaughter.   In:     “ANIMAL HEALTH, ANIMAL WELFARE AND BIOSECURITY” PROCEEDINGS, 2, pp. 729-734.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13728/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>