<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of farm heterogeneity and methods for upscaling on modelled nitrogen losses in agricultural landscapes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Dalgaard, Tommy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hutchings, Nicholas J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dragosits, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Olesen, J.E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Drouet, J.L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cellier, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Landscape and recreation</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The aim of this study is to illustrate the importance of  farm scale heterogeneity on nitrogen (N) losses in  agricultural landscapes. Results are exemplified with a chain of N models calculating farm-N balances and distributing the N-surplus to N-losses (volatilisation, denitrification, leaching) and soil-N accumulation/release in a Danish landscape. Possible non-linearities in upscaling are assessed by comparing average model results based on (i) individual farm level calculations and (ii) averaged inputs at landscape level. Effects of the non-linearities that appear when scaling up from farm to landscape are demonstrated.&#xD;
Especially in relation to ammonia losses the non-linearity between livestock density and N-loss is significant (p &gt; 0.999), with around 20-30% difference compared to a scaling procedure not taking this non-linearity into account. A significant effect of farm type on soil N accumulation (p &gt; 0.95) was also identified and needs to be included when modelling landscape level N-fluxes and greenhouse gas emissions.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19043/4/19043.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Dalgaard, Tommy; Hutchings, Nicholas J.; Dragosits, U.; Olesen, J.E.; Kjeldsen, Chris; Drouet, J.L. and Cellier, P.   (2011) Effects of farm heterogeneity and methods for upscaling on modelled nitrogen losses in agricultural landscapes.   Environmental Pollution,  159 (11),  3183-3192.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19043/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>