<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ökologischer Kreislauf Moorbad Harbach: Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) for Agricultural Plant Production and Transportation</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kratochvil, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fromm, E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Heß, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Freyer, B.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Community development</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 1992 the community of Moorbad Harbach (Austria), located near the border of the Czech Republic and dominated by extensive agricultural practice on small scale farms, decided to initiate activities for regional devolopment. About 40 farms (27 %) converted to organic farming, a local marketing service as well as regional food processing businesses (slaughterhouse, dairy), operating as linkages between regional agriculture and the local spa hotel were founded. The basic idea for the work presented here was to evaluate the – especially ecological – consequences of such a regional conversion. One part of this attempt of evaluation was carried out as a LCA for the agricultural production in Moorbad Harbach. The emphasis of the study was to compare plant production before and after the regional conversion to organic farming. In another step changes in transportation distances and quantities with special regard to transport of raw milk and milk products were quantified.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>vdf Hochschulverlag, Zürich</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Alföldi, T.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Lockeretz, W.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Niggli, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2000</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4116/1/4116-kratochvil-r-et-al-2000-IFOAM-lifecycle.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kratochvil, R.; Fromm, E.; Heß, J. and Freyer, B.    (2000) Ökologischer Kreislauf Moorbad Harbach: Life Cycle Assessment (LCA) for Agricultural Plant Production and Transportation.   In: Alföldi, T.; Lockeretz, W. and Niggli, U. (Eds.)  Proceedings 13th International IFOAM Scientific Conference., vdf Hochschulverlag, Zürich, p. 169.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4116/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>