<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Current Evaluation Procedures for Fertilizers and Soil Conditioners Used in Organic Agriculture. Proceedings of a workshop held April 29–30, 2004 at Emerson College, Great Britain</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Canali, Stefano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stopes, Christopher</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, Otto</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Speiser, Bernhard</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Table of Contents&#xD;
	&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in Austria&#xD;
Alexandra Hozzank and Wilfried Hartl	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in the Czech Republic&#xD;
Anamarija Slabe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in Denmark&#xD;
Rasmus Ørnberg Eriksen and Erik Steen Kristensen&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in France&#xD;
Marie-Christine Monnier	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in Germany&#xD;
Peter von Fragstein	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in Italy&#xD;
Stefano Canali	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in the Netherlands&#xD;
Chris Koopmans and Jan Bokhorst	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in Poland&#xD;
Anamarija Slabe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in Portugal&#xD;
Alexandra Maurer da Costa&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in Slovenia&#xD;
Anamarija Slabe	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in Spain&#xD;
Victor Gonzálvez	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in Switzerland&#xD;
Alfred Berner, Bernhard Speiser and Otto Schmid	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming in the United Kingdom&#xD;
Francis Blake, Robert Haward	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in the USA&#xD;
Brian Baker	&#xD;
&#xD;
Fertilizers and soil conditioners in organic farming  in third countries&#xD;
Anke Würth</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick, Switzerland</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4701/1/</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Canali, Stefano; Stopes, Christopher; Schmid, Otto and Speiser, Bernhard    (2005) Current Evaluation Procedures for Fertilizers and Soil Conditioners Used in Organic Agriculture. Proceedings of a workshop held April 29–30, 2004 at Emerson College, Great Britain.    FiBL-Report, no. 6. Research Institute of Organic Agriculture (FiBL), Frick, Switzerland.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4701/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>