<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Bioactive compounds - added value for potato from genetic resources and waste streams</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rokka, Veli-Matti</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gavrilenko, Tatjana</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Virtanen, Elina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Valkonen, Jari P.T.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Exotic potatoes other than S. tuberosum ssp. tuberosum cultivars may have a high&#xD;
interest in terms of commercialization in Russia and in Europe. In Finland, on the&#xD;
market there is already one potato cultivar called Blue Congo, which has a dark purple&#xD;
skin also with a purple flesh. This clearly shows that potatoes even with considerably&#xD;
irregular shape and completely exceptional flesh colour can have market potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
Some potato species are known to have high protein content in tubers, which is also&#xD;
important for need of production in developing countries. Certain genotypes can be&#xD;
valuable sources of vitamins, dietary fibre and certain minerals such as copper,&#xD;
potassium, iron and magnesium. Potatoes may also contain a broad variation of&#xD;
NJF Report Vol 6 No 2 Year 2010&#xD;
29&#xD;
phytonutrients that have antioxidant capacity. Among the health-promoting&#xD;
compounds there are carotenoids, flavonoids, caffeic acid and tuber storage protein&#xD;
patatin, which exhibit activity against free radicals and have antimicrobial, antiinflammatory&#xD;
and antiallergic properties (Brown et al. 2007, Ritter et al. 2008).&#xD;
&#xD;
Potatoes earlier cultivated only by American Indians can offer a high reservoir for&#xD;
developing novel products. Some tubers may have colored flesh, which can be a useful&#xD;
new criterium for potato crisp production. Determinations of dry matter content, chip&#xD;
colour, oil absorption and cooking time are important for potato processing. Low oil&#xD;
content associated with high dry matter and consistent chip colour are favourable to&#xD;
economic and health concerns (Ritter et al. 2008). Therefore NPS potatoes are a great&#xD;
source of high quality french fries and crisps. Excellent flavours and attractive colours&#xD;
with variable shapes may result in products with novelty appeal. Some genotypes of&#xD;
NPS collection may also show inhibition of the angiotensin converting enzyme I (ACE),&#xD;
a biochemical factor which has an effect on blood pressure (hypertension) (Mäkinen et&#xD;
al. 2008).</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Nordic Association of Agricultural Scientists</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Niemeläinen, O.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kiviharju, E.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/msword</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18285/1/Rokka.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rokka, Veli-Matti; Gavrilenko, Tatjana; Virtanen, Elina and Valkonen, Jari P.T.    (2010) Bioactive compounds - added value for potato from genetic resources and waste streams.       Paper at:   Plant breeding and management for human nutrition - How we can produce more healthful crops and food products? NJF seminar 419, Forssa, Finland, 10-11 June 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18285/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>