<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>PhytoMilk: Effects of botanical composition and harvest system of legume/grass silage on fatty acid, α-tocopherol and β-carotene concentration in organic forage and milk</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Höjer, Annika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinsson, Kjell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, Søren K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gustavsson, Anne-Maj</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Red clover and high proportion of forage in dairy cow diet  increases the concentration of bioactive substances in milk, e.g. unsaturated fatty acids and antioxidants. In the present experiment twenty-four Swedish Red dairy cows were fed three silages in a Latin Square design to study the effect of silage botanical composition and harvest time on milk fatty acid, α-tocopherol and β-carotene concentration. The silages were red clover/grass silage (mixture of first and second cut), red clover/grass silage (mixture of first, second and third cut) and birdsfoot trefoil/grass silage (mixture of first and second cut). Botanical composition and harvest system affected silage vitamin and fatty acid concentration with higher concentrations of α-linolenic acid, α-tocopherol and β-carotene in red clover/grass silage (mixture of three harvests). Milk linoleic and α-linolenic acid concentration was higher with the two red clover diets but α-tocopherol, β-carotene and retinol concentration was not affected.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen , Jim</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Schacht, Margit</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Helgadóttir, Áslaug</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2010-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18829/1/18829.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Höjer, Annika; Martinsson, Kjell; Jensen, Søren K. and Gustavsson, Anne-Maj    (2010) PhytoMilk: Effects of botanical composition and harvest system of legume/grass silage on fatty acid, α-tocopherol and β-carotene concentration in organic forage and milk.   In: Rasmussen , Jim; Schacht, Margit and Helgadóttir, Áslaug (Eds.)  The potential of forage legumes to sustain a high agricultural productivity - a Nordic perspective, 6 (3), NJF Report, pp. 133-136.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18829/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>