<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Tintagel: In the Footsteps of Rudolf Steiner</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Paull, John</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Switzerland</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>United Kingdom</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>History of organics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>On his final visit to Britain, Rudolf Steiner delivered three lectures a day during the Anthroposophical Society’s Summer School at Torquay (11-22 August 1924). Steiner took one day out of this hectic schedule to be a tourist for a day. The decision took him as far west as he ever ventured in his lifetime - to Tintagel on the west cost of Cornwall. The Tintagel visit occurred just two months after Steiner’s Agriculture Course and less than six weeks before Rudolf Steiner retreated from public life entirely. On this, his tenth visit to Britain, Steiner lectured on Anthroposophy and Waldorf education. The opportunity for agriculture lectures in Britain never arose, and there had been no Anglo attendees at the Koberwitz course. However, the Tintagel day trip put together with Steiner for the day, some of those who would play a significant role in the development of biodynamic agriculture. Marna Pease went on to be the secretary of Britain’s Anthroposophical Agricultural Foundation, founded in 1928. Elizabeth Vreede had been at Koberwitz and later attended the first Annual Meeting of the Anthroposophical Agricultural Foundation in London. Guenther Wachsmuth had also attended Koberwitz and he was the head of the Natural Science Section of the Goetheanum and worked with Ehrenfried Pfeiffer. George Kaufmann (Adams) was translating for Steiner and he would soon be the first to translate the Agriculture Course into English. Photographs included are of the Tintagel castle ruins, the Camelot Hotel and the Knight's table.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22492/17/22492.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22492/7/TintagelCastleRuins.JohnPaull.JPG</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22492/12/TintagelCastleEntrance.%20JohnPaull.JPG</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Paull, John   (2012) Tintagel: In the Footsteps of Rudolf Steiner.   Journal of Bio-Dynamics Tasmania, 107 (Spring), pp. 11-15.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22492/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>