<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Carbon footprints of organic dairying in six European countries—real farm data analysis</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Hietala, Sanna Maria</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Smith, Laurence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Knudsen, Marie Trydeman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kurpa, Sirpa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Padel, Susanne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hermansen, John E.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Dairy farming is the largest agricultural contributor to greenhouse gas emissions in Europe. In this study, the carbon footprint of organic dairying was evaluated by means of a life cycle assessment, based on real farm data from six European countries: Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Finland, Italy and United Kingdom. &#xD;
A total of 34 farms were analysed. The assessment was carried out using an attributional approach with system boundaries from cradle to farm gate. In relation to dairy production, a functional unit of 1 kg of energy corrected milk was used. The results gave an average of 1.32 kg CO2 equivalents per kilogramme of energy-corrected milk with standard deviation of 0.22, which is consistent with recent studies. The main contributor to this is enteric fermentation from producing animals, resulting in 45%of total GHG emissions,which is also consistent with previous studies.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2015</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28882/1/Hietala%202015_A10.1007%252Fs13165-014-0084-0.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Hietala, Sanna Maria; Smith, Laurence; Knudsen, Marie Trydeman; Kurpa, Sirpa; Padel, Susanne and Hermansen, John E.   (2015) Carbon footprints of organic dairying in six European countries—real farm data analysis.   Organic Agriculture, 5 (2), pp. 91-100.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28882/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>