<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Langzeitversuch Darmstadt</dc:title>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil biology</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Post harvest management and techniques</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In 1980 a fertilization trial started at the Institute for Biodynamic Research in Darmstadt, Germany, comprising farmyard manure treatments with and without biodynamic preparations and mineral fertilization, each at various levels. The objective of the project was to study the product quality of vegetables and of rye. After this four year project, interesting differences began to emerge with respect to the soil parameters of organic and mineral treatments. Thus the trial was continued. After some years of a transitional period without particular investigations, a detailed soil biological project was carried out in 1989-1991, focusing on the effects of fertilization upon C- and N-dynamics, enzyme activities and microbial biomass in the soil. A third experimental period (from 1992 to 1999) has focused on the yield formation of cultivated crops and the long-term effects of fertilization treatments upon soil and crop development. From 2000 until now, the effects of changed fertilization treatments on soil organic matter development, soil biological activity, crop growth and yield is investigated.</dc:description>
  <dc:type>Research facility description</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5147/1/rabsss99.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>{Facility}   Langzeitversuch Darmstadt.  [Long-term trial Darmstadt.]   Start 1980.       Facility Leader(s): Raupp, Dr Joachim, IBDF - Institut für Biologisch-Dynamische Forschung e.V..</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5147/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>