<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effect of annual  self-reseeding legumes on subsequent crops (particularly  durum wheat) into a long-term rotation program under organic farming.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>WEHBE, Elias</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Soil nitrogen fertility management is a major concern in organic farming. Nitrogen fixation by legumes is a potential solution especially in multi-annual crop rotation program. This study aims at assessing the effect of fifteen legume cultivars on wheat as third subsequent crop and at identifying the most efficient and suitable cultivars for a long-term rotation program.T. subterraneum cv. York and T. glanduliferum cv. Prima induced the best effects on wheat, particularly on total biomass, number of grains, dry matter production and increased yield by 670% and 567% respectively compared to the control. They showed also, together with Trifolium subterraneum cv. Dalkeith and Trifolium incarnatum cv. Caprera, to be the most efficient over the whole rotation experiment proving the important role that legumes can play into sustainable organic cropping systems.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/7007/1/EliasWehbe05.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>WEHBE, Elias   (2005) Effect of annual self-reseeding legumes on subsequent crops (particularly durum wheat) into a long-term rotation program under organic farming.  [Effet des légumineuses annuelles à ressemis sur les cultures successives (particulièrement,le blé dur) dans un programme de rotation à long terme en agriculture biologique.]  Thesis, IAMB Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Bari, Organic farming. Collection Master of Science IAMB-CIHEAM (International Centre for advanced Mediterranean agronomic studies), no. 403. .   [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/7007/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>