<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Schulverpflegung in Hessen unter Berücksichtigung der Integration biologischer Lebensmittel.&#xD;
&#xD;
Diplomarbeit vorgelegt dem Prüfungsausschuss des Studienganges Oecotrophologie für die Fachrichtung Ernährung und Hauswirtschaft an der Fachhochschule Münster</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Heidebur, Nicole</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This diploma thesis discusses the school system and school catering in the German federal&#xD;
state Hesse with regard to an integration of organic food. Specifically, the potential as&#xD;
well as limitations for the integration of organic food in school meals are considered.&#xD;
The German federal states are responsible for the organisation and administration of the&#xD;
German school system. Their policy of the recent years induced a rise of all-day schools,&#xD;
which have to offer warm meals for their pupils. Healthy school meals and the use of organic&#xD;
food can have a positive influence on the eating behaviour of pupils, which indicates&#xD;
the high importance of this issue. The organisation of school meals is characterized by&#xD;
heterogeneous structures with varying responsibilities and different ways of implementation.&#xD;
The school meals are mostly prepared by externals – only a few schools manage the&#xD;
preparation by themselves. So far there have been no legal guidelines in Hesse that regulate&#xD;
the quality of school meals or the implementation of organic food. A political programme&#xD;
in Hesse called „Schule und Gesundheit“ (S &amp; G) takes steps to ensure the quality&#xD;
and healthy aspects of the school meals in voluntary schools. However, this programme&#xD;
affects only a small number of schools so far. But it can be expected that more&#xD;
and more schools will implement these steps in the future.&#xD;
The usage of quality standards, health promotion and the integration of organic food primarily&#xD;
depends on the interests and individual initiatives of the local agents. Therefore the&#xD;
federal state government and the municipalities should be requested to create mandatory&#xD;
conditions. In some communities adequate regulations have already been initiated. The&#xD;
results of this thesis show that many schools are already along their way to regarding&#xD;
quality standards, healthy aspects and organic food. However, there is still a high need of&#xD;
support and advice in the new field of school meals. The coordination centre for school&#xD;
meals in Hesse and a campaign for organic food in the catering of children and young&#xD;
adults play an important role to achieve this goal. Nevertheless, a higher availability of&#xD;
personal advice would be helpful to meet the strong need for support. Expanding the capacities&#xD;
of the responsible agents can be seen as one of the most important steps as an&#xD;
intelligent planning of the school meals is a necessary basis for a successful integration of&#xD;
organic food. Strategies for the future should aim at increasing the sensitivity of the responsible&#xD;
agents when it comes to school meals and reduce common prejudices, especially&#xD;
those regarding the price of organic food. Municipal school projects for organic food&#xD;
in school meals and an effective communication would be helpful for a further progress.&#xD;
Moreover, strategies have to be developed to increase pupils’ acceptance of school meals&#xD;
and to ensure a discussion about organic food in school lessons.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Thesis</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17414/1/Diplomarbeit_Nicole_Heidebur.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Heidebur, Nicole   (2010) Schulverpflegung in Hessen unter Berücksichtigung der Integration biologischer Lebensmittel. Diplomarbeit vorgelegt dem Prüfungsausschuss des Studienganges Oecotrophologie für die Fachrichtung Ernährung und Hauswirtschaft an der Fachhochschule Münster.    Diplomarbeit thesis, Fachhochschule Münster, Deutschland.  .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17414/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>