<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Cultivation technology influences the occurrence of potato early blight (Alternaria solani) in an organic farming system</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Runno-Paurson, Eve</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hansen, Merili</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Tein, Berit</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Loit, Kaire</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jõgi, Kätlin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luik, Anne</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Metspalu, Luule</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eremeev, Viacheslav</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Williams, Ingrid</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mänd, Marika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Root crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Nowadays, organically produced products have become more popular than ever and interest in them is still &#xD;
growing fast. The early blight causal pathogen Alternaria solani has not been considered a great threat to potato in &#xD;
northern climate conditions in the past and has not been routinely sprayed against. During our study early blight &#xD;
was evaluated in 2010 and 2011 on the plants of a potato cultivar ‘Reet’ in an organic farming experiment. In our &#xD;
study, both growing seasons were very favourable for early blight development. Significant differences between &#xD;
the two cultivation technologies were found (F1,12 = 4.84, p = 0.048). In 2010, the area under disease progress curve &#xD;
(AUDPC) value was 303 on cover crop (CC) plots and 990 on CC + M (manure) plots that is three times higher, &#xD;
whereas in 2011, the AUDPC value was 967 on CC plots and 1195 on CC + M plots. Our results confirm that potato &#xD;
early blight has become a serious problem in North-East European organic potato fields and thus susceptible potato &#xD;
cultivars cannot be recommended for growing in an organic farming system. However, it is possible to influence &#xD;
the development severity of early blight by selecting the proper growing technology. Since, in the changing climate &#xD;
conditions and in susceptible cultivars, early blight is a potato disease that can cause early defoliation of plants and crop death, there is a need for resistant potato cultivars.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>Runno-Paurson, Eve; Hansen, Merili; Tein, Berit; Loit, Kaire; Jõgi, Kätlin; Luik, Anne; Metspalu, Luule; Eremeev, Viacheslav; Williams, Ingrid and Mänd, Marika   (2014) Cultivation technology influences the occurrence of potato early blight (Alternaria solani) in an organic farming system.   Zemdirbyste-Agriculture, 101 (2), pp. 199-204.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26802/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>