<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Ertrag und Futterwert von Mais-Bohnen Gemengen als Ganzpflanzensilage in der Milchviehfütterung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fischer, Jenny</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Böhm, Herwart</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop combinations and interactions</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Cereals, pulses and oilseeds</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Germany</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Silage maize is a valuable forage crop for dairy cows in Organic Farming due to its high energy concentration and the high yield potential. One limitation to maize silage as a feed for dairy cows is the low crude protein concentration (Armstrong et al. 2008). To improve the protein content of maize silage a field experiment of maize-bean intercropping was carried out at the Institute for Organic Farming (Schleswig-Holstein, sL, 740 mm, 8.7°C). In the experiment different bean varieties (Phaseolus vulgaris, Phaseolus coccineus, Vicia faba) and -species are evaluated. Especially the climbing Phaseolus beans have the potential to increase the protein content due to their high biomass production. The aim of the field experiment is to detect maize-bean intercropping systems with a high yield potential and good feed value. Furthermore the fermentability of the maize-bean silage was evaluated in a subsequent silage trial.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21482/1/21482_Fischer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fischer, Jenny and Böhm, Herwart    (2013) Ertrag und Futterwert von Mais-Bohnen Gemengen als Ganzpflanzensilage in der Milchviehfütterung.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21482/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>