<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Effects of four tanniferous plant extracts on the in vitro exsheathment of third-stage larvae of parasitic nematodes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>D., BAHUAUD</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>C., MARTINEZ-ORTIZ DE MONTELLANO</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>S., CHAUVEAU</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F, PREVOT</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>F., TORRES-ACOSTA</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>I., FOURASTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>H., HOSTE</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The anthelmintic properties of tanniferous plants and of their secondary metabolites represent one possible alternative to&#xD;
chemotherapy that is currently being explored as a means of achieving sustainable control of gastrointestinal nematodes in&#xD;
ruminants. Previous in vivo and in vitro results suggest that tanniferous plants can have direct anti-parasitic effect against&#xD;
different stages of nematodes. However, the mode of action of the bioactive plant compounds remains obscure. The&#xD;
objectives of the current study were (1) to examine the hypothesis that extracts of tanniferous plants might interfere with&#xD;
the exsheathment of third-stage infective larvae (L3); (2) to assess the role of tannins in the process by examining the&#xD;
consequence of adding an inhibitor of tannins (polyethylene glycol: PEG) to extracts. The effects of 4 tanniferous plant&#xD;
extracts on exsheathment have been examined on L3 of Haemonchus contortus and Trichostrongylus colubriformis. Artificial&#xD;
exsheathment was induced in vitro by adding hypochlorite solution to larval suspension. The evolution of exsheathment&#xD;
with time was measured by repeated observations at 10-min interval for 60 min. The selected plants were: genista&#xD;
(Sarothamnus scoparius), heather (Erica erigena), pine tree (Pinus sylvestris), and chestnut tree (Castanea sativa), with tannin&#xD;
contents ranging from 1.5 to 24.7% of DM. Extracts of a non-tanniferous plant (rye grass, tannin content: 0.3% of DM)&#xD;
were included in the assay as negative controls. The extracts were tested at the concentration of 600 mg/ml and the effects&#xD;
were compared to the rate of exsheathment of control larvae in PBS. No statistical differences in the pattern of&#xD;
exsheathment was observed after addition of rye grass or genista extracts for both nematode species and with heather&#xD;
extracts for T. colubriformis. In contrast, pine tree extracts on larvae of both species and heather extracts with H. contortus&#xD;
induced a significant delay in exsheathment. Last, contact with chest nut extracts led to a total inhibition of the process for&#xD;
both nematodes. These results suggest that extracts of tanniferous plants might affect a key process in the very early stages&#xD;
of larval invasion of the host. In most cases, the addition of PEG led to a total or partial restoration towards control values.&#xD;
This suggests that tannins are largely involved in the inhibitory process. However, other secondary metabolites may also&#xD;
interfere with the process that would help to explain some of the differences in response observed between the two&#xD;
nematode species.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/6980/1/dianeparasitology.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>D., BAHUAUD; C., MARTINEZ-ORTIZ DE MONTELLANO; S., CHAUVEAU; F, PREVOT; F., TORRES-ACOSTA; I., FOURASTE and H., HOSTE   (2005) Effects of four tanniferous plant extracts on the in vitro exsheathment of third-stage larvae of parasitic nematodes.   Parasitology.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/6980/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>