<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Study the effects of conventional and low input production system on quantitative and qualitative yield of Silybum marianum L.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Haj Seyed Hadi, Mohammad Reza</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Darzi, Mohammad Taghi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sharifi Ashoorabadi, Ebrahim</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This investigation was carried out in the spring of 2005 – 2007 in the Research Station of Rangelands in Hamand - Damavand region of IRAN to study the effects of conventional and low input production systems on seed yield and sylimarin percentage of Silybum marianum L. This experiment was done in split-split plot based on randomized complete block design with 3 replications. Treatments were 2 production systems (Conventional and Low input system) in the main plots, 3 planting time (25 of March, 4 and 14 of April) in the sub plots and 2 seed types (Improved and Native of Khoozestan) in the sub-sub plots. Results showed that there was a significant difference between production systems. The highest height (125.8cm) and number of capitols per plant (10.4) were obtained in conventional system. While other traits including capitol diameter (7.028cm), number of seed per capitol (125), 1000 seed weight (25.006g), seed yield (1888.072kg/ha), silymarin percentage (%7.711) and silymarin yield (150.443lit/ha) were recorded in the low input system. Results showed that because of using vermicopmpost and its effects on plant growth in low input system, highest seed yield and silymarin yield were obtained in this treatment.  Seed planting in the first time of planting (25 of March) had the same effect on growth and yield. Highest values were recorded in the first time of planting (25 of March). Also, improved seed caused more seed and silymarin yield. Results showed that for getting highest seed and silymarin yield, using improved seed and low input production system is necessary. Also, according to the climatic condition, seed must be planted as early as possible. In this investigation, the best time of planting is 5 March).</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11941/1/Haj_Seyed_Hadi_11941_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Haj Seyed Hadi, Mohammad Reza; Darzi, Mohammad Taghi and Sharifi Ashoorabadi, Ebrahim    (2008) Study the effects of conventional and low input production system on quantitative and qualitative yield of Silybum marianum L.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11941/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>