<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Klassifizierung von pflanzlichen Produkten aus ökologischem&#xD;
und konventionellem Anbau durch Messung sekundärer Pflanzenstoffe</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Roose, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahl, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ploeger, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The content of secondary plant compounds in plants is influenced by various environmental&#xD;
factors. Cultivation and fertilization are factors which are characteristic for the&#xD;
farming system organic or conventional. Within a german governmental funded project&#xD;
(BÖL02OE170/F) carrot, maize and wheat samples from different farming systems&#xD;
(defined trials and farm pairs) are differentiated and classified using their polyphenolic&#xD;
and carotenoid contents and profiles, respectively.&#xD;
The samples from organic farming could be differentiated from samples which were&#xD;
conventionally grown as statistical significant for carrot and wheat samples in a two&#xD;
year repetition. The samples could be classified by both, polyphenolic as well as&#xD;
carotenoid profiles. The sum parameters only can not be applied for the differentiation&#xD;
and classification of the samples. Factors like cultivar and site have a strong influence&#xD;
on the classification. Therefore for the classification of the carrot samples according to&#xD;
the farming systems land site must be included.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14186/1/Roose_14186.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Roose, M.; Kahl, J. and Ploeger, A.    (2009) Klassifizierung von pflanzlichen Produkten aus ökologischem und konventionellem Anbau durch Messung sekundärer Pflanzenstoffe.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14186/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>