<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Overføring av smittestoffer fra ku til kalv i melkefôringsperioden - en litteraturstudie</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Grøndahl, Ann Margaret</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Johnsen, Julie Føske</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mejdell, Cecilie Marie</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Dairy cattle</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The purpose of this literature review was to&#xD;
evaluate if it should be avoided to keep the cow&#xD;
and calf together after birth because of the risk of&#xD;
transmission of infectious pathogens from the cow to&#xD;
the preweaning calf. The sources of transmission of&#xD;
common infections in newborn calves are described.&#xD;
E.coli, rotavirus, bovine coronavirus, Clostridium spp.,&#xD;
Cryptosporidium spp., Giardia and Eimeria spp. are&#xD;
ubiquitous, and infected calves can excrete extreme&#xD;
numbers of microorganisms and cause contamination&#xD;
of the environment. According to the literature, microorganisms in the environment represent a higher risk&#xD;
than adults for transmission to the newborn, and hygienic&#xD;
measures and good passive immune status of the&#xD;
newborn are important prophylaxes. Transplacental&#xD;
transmission of bovine virus diarrhea virus may cause&#xD;
persistently infected individuals, which represent the&#xD;
most important route of viral shedding. Mycoplasma&#xD;
bovis usually cause infection in newborn calves with&#xD;
the pathogen often transmitted from the environment.&#xD;
The importance of the cow for direct transmission to&#xD;
the calf is dubious. Resent research has demonstrated&#xD;
that Mycobacterium avium subsp. paratuberculosis&#xD;
can be spread by bio-aerosols, and that intrauterine&#xD;
infection is quite common. Some authors suggest that&#xD;
separation of the dam and calf might be less effective&#xD;
in preventing the spread of this infection than previously&#xD;
anticipated. The authors’ conclusion is that cows&#xD;
in Norway do not represent a greater risk of transmission&#xD;
of pathogens to the newborn calf than the other&#xD;
calves and young animals in the herd.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-05-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18844/1/Ku-kalv_Overf%C3%B8ring_av_smittestoffer_NVT_2011.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Grøndahl, Ann Margaret; Johnsen, Julie Føske and Mejdell, Cecilie Marie   (2011) Overføring av smittestoffer fra ku til kalv i melkefôringsperioden - en litteraturstudie.  [TRANSMISSION OF PATHOGENS FROM THE COW TO THE PREWEANING CALF – a literature study.]  Norsk Veterinærtidsskrift, 2011 (4), pp. 211-219.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18844/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>