<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The organic aquaculture sector in Italy: a Delphi evaluation of the market potentialities</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Castellini, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mauracher, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Roma, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Deboni, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gaviglio, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Ragazzoni, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Produce chain management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The paper draws out the possibilities of development and increase of organic farmed fish in Italy, evaluating both technical and economic aspects, for breeding, market, political, regulatory and environmental issues. The survey has been conducted using the Delphi technique, in three rounds with a panel of national experts. The analysis offers interesting insights and useful suggestions addressed to the organic aquaculture sector.&#xD;
Authors chose Delphi methodology according to the paper’s objective: the study is in fact aimed at exploring the evolution dynamics (positive or absent) for a less-developed market like the one of the Italian organic fish. This method allows to create a forecast by collecting and evaluating experts’ opinions about the organic fish market; these experts are divided in homogeneous groups and selected as privileged observers of the phenomenon.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy,  U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24288/1/24288_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Castellini, A.; Mauracher, C.; Roma, R.; Deboni, A.; Gaviglio, A. and Ragazzoni, A.    (2014) The organic aquaculture sector in Italy: a Delphi evaluation of the market potentialities.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 769-772.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24288/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>