<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Raufutter als Alleinfutter für Kaninchen – Auswirkungen auf das&#xD;
Fettsäurenmuster des Fleisches</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Meier, Janina S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leiber, Florian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Burger, Bettina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wettstein, Hans-Rudolf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hatt, Jean-Michel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Clauss, Marcus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kreuzer, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four groups of eight New Zealand hybrid rabbits were fed ryegrass meal only, alfalfa&#xD;
meal only, ryegrass and oats 1:1, or alfalfa and oats 1:1. Diets were offered ad libitum&#xD;
in pelleted form from 5-30 weeks of age, when they were slaughtered. Intramuscular&#xD;
fatty acid profiles were determined in the Musculus quadriceps of the left hindleg.&#xD;
Feed intake was not statistically different between the four groups, nor was carcass&#xD;
weight. The main effect of the forage-only diets on the fatty acid profiles was a decrease&#xD;
of monounsaturated and an increase of polyunsaturated fatty acid (PUFA)&#xD;
proportions. Within PUFA, the n-3 fatty acids more than doubled with forage-only&#xD;
compared to forage-oats diets, while the n-6 fatty acids slightly decreased. In general,&#xD;
the proportion of n-3 fatty acids in intramuscular fat of forage-only fed rabbits was&#xD;
extraordinarily high compared to any other meat of agricultural origin. The results&#xD;
demonstrate a specific advantage of roughage-based diets in the nutrition of productive&#xD;
herbivores, which is also known for ruminants.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14387/1/Meier_14387.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Meier, Janina S.; Leiber, Florian; Burger, Bettina; Wettstein, Hans-Rudolf; Hatt, Jean-Michel; Clauss, Marcus and Kreuzer, Michael    (2009) Raufutter als Alleinfutter für Kaninchen – Auswirkungen auf das Fettsäurenmuster des Fleisches.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14387/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>