<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Agro-environmental evaluation of vineyard management using organic farming and integrated plant production systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>FORGET, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>LACOMBE, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>DURAND, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Viticulture</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic farming is often considered to be the most environmentally-friendly crop management system, even if integrated production also aims at decreasing the impact of agriculture on the natural environment. In order to establish references for the agro-environmental evaluation of these two production systems in relation to grape growing, INRA carried out an initial study from 2001 to 2004 at the plot scale. This study focused on two grape varieties (Merlot N and Cabernet Sauvignon) in its Couhins vineyard (Graves cru classé), located on two organically-farmed plots and two plots using integrated production, a system based on the implementation of decision rules aimed at limiting the number of pest control treatments. Production means only differed in terms of pest control management (choice of products and application strategy). Each of the parcels covered approximately 0.30 ha. An agro-environmental evaluation of these two systems was made for 2003, using the INDIGO Vigne method at the plot level. Because of their nature, the choice of parameters for the indicators used determines the interpretation of the results. Nevertheless, it appears that the environmental impact of integrated production is more favourable in this case than that of organic farming, particularly in terms of pest control and energy indicators. One of the reasons for this is the high number of applications of pest control treatments in organic farming and, as a result, higher energy consumption, as well as the use of copper that has a major impact on deep waters, the ground and the air. The two systems can decrease their environmental impact by limiting the number of tractor runs for soil maintenance. Flexibility appears to be greater in the case of integrated production since, contrary to organic farming, it can use herbicides under the row. The calculation of the agro-environmental evaluation on the parcel using integrated protection with chemical weeding under the row leads to a clear improvement of the energy indicator, without significantly decreasing the value of the pest control indicator. Natural sodding of the inter-row, when the vigour of the vineyard allows it, provides an effective solution since the decrease in the number of tractor runs leads to an improvement of erosion and organic matter indicators. This type of evaluation should be carried out at the scale of a group of plots or of an entire wine-farm. Ground maintenance is an important factor in decreasing the impact of grape growing on the environment. In this respect, organic farming offers some promising prospects.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>BELLON, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>DIOLEZ, A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>HUYGHE, C.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>PENVERN, S.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>SAVINI, I.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/15490/1/35-Forget.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>FORGET, D. ; LACOMBE, J.  and DURAND, A.    (2009) Agro-environmental evaluation of vineyard management using organic farming and integrated plant production systems.  [Evaluation agri-environnementale de la conduite de la vigne en agriculture biologique et en production intégrée.]  Carrefours de l'Innovation Agronomique, 4, pp. 253-258.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/15490/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>