<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Influence of management practices on quality and biodiversity of tomatoes in Germany</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Klein, Daniela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kumar, Ramesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Koepke, Ulrich</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Four old and endangered tomato cultivars were cultivated under greenhouse conditions with different levels of organic N-fertilisation and harvest at different maturity stages in order to develop a conclusive concept to preserve the diversity of old, endangered and multicolour cultivars. First results of several physio-chemical and sensory parameters were analysed to describe product quality. In order to assess consumer acceptance, 550 consumers were interviewed. The individual attributes of the cultivars, which differ in size, shape, colour, taste and health-related, beneficial physio-chemicals, are promoted by optimal harvest time. A combination of these cultivars distributed in regional markets is considered as a suitable concept for saving these endangered cultivars.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/4395/1/4395-Klein_etal_4p_revised-ed.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Klein, Daniela; Kumar, Ramesh and Koepke, Ulrich    (2005) Influence of management practices on quality and biodiversity of tomatoes in Germany.       Paper at:   Researching Sustainable Systems - International Scientific Conference on Organic Agriculture, Adelaide, Australia, September 21-23, 2005.     [Unpublished]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/4395/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>