<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dynamics of nitrogen concentration on intercropped ryegrass.</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Skonieski, Fernando Reimann</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Viégas, Julio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Cruz, Pablo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nornberg, José Laerte</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Production systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The dynamics of nitrogen (N) in ryegrass intercropped with different forage species with regard to dry matter (DM) accumulation within an agroecological transition system was evaluated. Annual ryegrass was intercropped with black oats (RY + BO), white clover (RY + WC) and forage peanut (RY + FP). The experimental design was completely randomized, with three replications. The study applied the N dilution model for plant tissue which comparatively uses modifiable factors of the environment at optimal levels. The model shows decline in N concentration due to the DM accumulation of temperate grass pastures. Data were compared to model by the root mean square deviation analysis. Dilution coefficient (β), used in all pasture samples, was lower than -0.60. Highest N concentration decline in plant tissues, due to DM accumulation, occurred in RY + WC pastures (β = -0.94), followed by RY + FP (β = - 0.86) and RY + BO (β = - 0.67), respectively. Ryegrass intercropped with white clover showed the highest N content in plant tissue, with a nitrogen nutrition index close to the proposed model.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2011-05-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28516/1/Skonieski_dynamics.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Skonieski, Fernando Reimann; Viégas, Julio; Cruz, Pablo and Nornberg, José Laerte   (2011) Dynamics of nitrogen concentration on intercropped ryegrass.  [Dinâmica da concentração de nitrogênio em azevém consorciado.]  Acta Scientiarum. Animal Sciences, 34 (1), pp. 1-6.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28516/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>