<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Seasonal fluctuation in concentrations of α-tocopherol and β-carotene in forage herb and legume species and a grass-clover mixture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Elgersma, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jensen, S.K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Most studies in forages have been carried out with perennial ryegrass and legume species such as white clover. Recently, alfa-tocopherol and beta-carotene in a number of dicotyledonous forage species were compared to a grass-clover mixture. To develop management guidelines, insight into seasonal patterns across the various harvests and years is important. Therefore, four herb species, three legumes and a perennial ryegrass-white clover mixture were investigated in a cutting trial with four harvests (May-Oct) during 2009 and 2010.&#xD;
Concentrations of alfa-tocopherol and beta-carotene were highest in October and lowest in July.&#xD;
Biodiverse pastures could have added benefits in farming practice as various herbs outperformed the grass-clover mixture regarding alfa-tocopherol concentration, particularly in autumn.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-06-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/24710/6/24710.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Elgersma, A.; Søegaard, K. and Jensen, S.K.    (2013) Seasonal fluctuation in concentrations of α-tocopherol and β-carotene in forage herb and legume species and a grass-clover mixture.   In:     Grassland Science in Europe, 18, pp. 258-260.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/24710/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>