<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>New optimized technique for mechanical control of Elymus repens</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kristensen, Erik  Fløjgaard</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Melander, Bo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Nørremark, Michael</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Weed management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Elymus repens (coach grass) is traditionally controlled by repeated and prolonged stubble cultivation. However, the efficacy is strongly depending on weather and secondly on the exposure of rhizomes. The shorter the required period of cultivation stays the more compliance with the objective in organic farming where farmers aim at minimizing leaching of nutrients by keeping the soil plant-covered during autumn and winter.&#xD;
Effective technique and strategies for uprooting, exposing and destroying Elymus repens are needed. In a Danish organic research project the focus is on technological solutions for uprooting, exposing and destroying of the rhizomes within a short time span. Machines of standard type, modified machines and machines constructed for other purposes have been studied. &#xD;
The results show that it is difficult to achieve a high percentage of uprooting when using machines giving a high area capacity, e.g. spring loaded tine cultivator and rigid tine cultivator with modified spike discs at the rear.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-09-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18343/1/18343.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/18343/4/18343a.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kristensen, Erik Fløjgaard; Melander, Bo and Nørremark, Michael    (2010) New optimized technique for mechanical control of Elymus repens.       Paper at:   AgEng 2010. International Conference on Agricultural Engineering, Clemont Ferrand, France, 6-8 September, 2010.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/18343/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>