<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The constitution of trust: Function, configuration and generation of trust in Alternative Food Networks</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Thorsøe, Martin H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kjeldsen, Chris</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Social aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Markets and trade</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Consumer issues</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research methodology and philosophy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Alternative Food Networks (AFN) is often mentioned as a way to reconfigure the link between producers and consumers and build trust in the food system. This article explores the function, configuration and generation of trust in AFNs. The structure is twofold. First we discuss the theoretical underpinnings of trust, in both recent AFN literature and in sociology, and develop a conceptual framework for analyzing trust in AFN. Second, we explore the function, configuration and generation of trust in the Food Communities of Copenhagen and Aarhus (in Danish: “Fødevarefællesskaberne”). The Food Communities are a network of urban consumers sourcing organic products from regional producers. Empirically, the article demonstrates that trust functions as a mechanism that creates  coherency and which facilitates cooperation in the food network. Furthermore, the Food Communities are characterized by high levels of systemic and personal trust. Several mechanisms, like managing expectations, establishing trustworthiness, and developing a common normative basis, are employed and contribute to the generation and maintenance of trust.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-05</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27315/7/27315.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Thorsøe, Martin H. and Kjeldsen, Chris   (2014) The constitution of trust: Function, configuration and generation of trust in Alternative Food Networks.   Sociologia Ruralis.     [In Press]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27315/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>