<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Udder health at a Swedish research farm with both organic and conventional dairy cow management</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fall, DVM Nils</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Emanuelson, Professor Ulf</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Martinsson, Kjell</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jonsson, Simon</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Our aim was to compare udder health in groups of organically and conventionally managed cows, using data from a longitudinal study in a Swedish dairy-research farm. Management of the groups was identical except for feed composition and the feeding regimen. Our dataset included all lactating cows calving from 1 September 1990 to 31 August 2001 (145 organically and 151 conventionally managed cows).&#xD;
&#xD;
Udder health was assessed by the geometric average somatic-cell count (SCC) within 150 days after calving, by the number of monthly SCC tests &gt;200,000 cells/ml within 150 days after calving and by presence of lactations with veterinary-treated cases of clinical mastitis. The effect of animal group was analysed by multivariable linear, Poisson and logistic-regression models, controlling for factors such as lactation number, breed, year, season and milk yield.&#xD;
&#xD;
The groups did not differ in any measure of udder health. We had power to rule out differences of at least 33,000 cells/ml in the geometric average somatic-cell count, an incidence rate ratio of 0.65 in the incidence of high-SCC milk-testing occasions, and an odds ratio of 0.43 in veterinary treated cases of mastitis.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>ELSEVIER B.V.</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Erb, Professor Hollis</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2008-02</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13099/1/PVM%2C_Fall_et_al.%2C2008.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Fall, DVM Nils; Emanuelson, Professor Ulf; Martinsson, Kjell and Jonsson, Simon   (2008) Udder health at a Swedish research farm with both organic and conventional dairy cow management.   Preventive Veterinary Medicine, 83 (2), pp. 186-195.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13099/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>