<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Vergleich zweier Humusbilanzmethoden in der praktischen Anwendung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sommer , Hendrik</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Leithold, Günter</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Humus balance methods are used to estimate the humus situation on arable land of a farm. Guarantee for a stable yield is a sufficient supply of humus. There for it is necessary to use the appropriate balance method. The humus balance method from Leithold has been compared with the one that is described at Hülsbergen (2002) by using the Software Model REPRO. The humus balances of the investigated farm increased continuous throughout the study period. Based on the entire study period the humus supply increased 4 percentage points per year from 70% to 125%. The results of this study leads to the conclusion that improving the humus supply primarily resulted in the increase of livestock. The intensification of milk production has improved the supply of humus. Basically, it can be stated that the use of both methods has led to similar statements regarding the development of the farm.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21562/1/21562_sommer.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sommer , Hendrik and Leithold, Günter    (2013) Vergleich zweier Humusbilanzmethoden in der praktischen Anwendung.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21562/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>