<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Eprints - the international archive for research publications about organic agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, I.A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology transfer</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Research communication and quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Organic Eprints is an open, on-line archive for research in organic food and farming with more than 10,000 publications - and growing rapidly. There are 15,000 registered users of Organic Eprints. All use of the archive is free of charge.&#xD;
The archive contains scientific and popular articles, reports, presentations, project descriptions, books and other research publications. For each publication there is a short summary along with bibliographic and other information. In most cases, the full articles are&#xD;
freely available for download. The workshop aims to make the participants aquainted with Organic Eprints, so that they in the future can use the system for searching for research publications and other information about research in Organic agriculture and for depositing their own work. The participants will be guided through registering and searching and shown how to deposit papers.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Neuhoff, Daniel</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Halberg, Niels</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Rasmussen, Ilse A.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Hermansen, John</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Ssekyewa, Charles</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Sohn, Sang Mok</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2011</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19569/4/19569.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Rasmussen, I.A.    (2011) Organic Eprints - the international archive for research publications about organic agriculture.       Workshop at:   Third Scientific Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research, held at the 17th IFOAM Organic World Conference - Organic is Life, Namyangju, Gyeonggi Paldang, Republic of Korea, 28th Sept. - 1st Oct. 2011.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19569/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>