<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Impact of Organic Vegetable Production System in Kiambu and Kajiado Counties of Kenya</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Ndungu, Samuel Kiruku</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Macharia , Ibrahim Ndegwa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kahuthia, Ruth Gathu</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wahome, Raphael Githaiga</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The study was conducted to evaluate the impact of organic production system on profitability of smallholder vegetable production systems in the two counties so as to appraise its contribution to improvement of rural livelihoods. The study collected data on costs and returns for a sample of 208 smallholder vegetable farmers who were composed of 78 organic and 130 conventional farmers. Impact of organic production system was evaluated using propensity score matching technique. Organic vegetable production system was found to have a positive significant impact of increasing farm gross margin by US$0.58 representing 89.5% among smallholder producers in Kiambu and Kajiado Counties of Kenya. The study recommended promotion of organic production system as a tool that can be used to improve livelihoods especially in the rural areas.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-04-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/28897/7/28897.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Ndungu, Samuel Kiruku; Macharia , Ibrahim Ndegwa; Kahuthia, Ruth Gathu and Wahome, Raphael Githaiga   (2013) Impact of Organic Vegetable Production System in Kiambu and Kajiado Counties of Kenya.   Journal of Environmental Science and Engineering, A2 (4), pp. 256-266.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/28897/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>