<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Animal Health and Welfare Planning - A Review</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Nicholas, Phillipa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jasinska, Aleksandra</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Food security, food quality and human health</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding and genetics</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In UK, animal health planning is being increasingly promoted and implemented in both the organic and conventional livestock sectors – health planning is compulsory for organic certification in the UK.  The type health planning that is taking place and the health plans being used vary widely across the UK livestock industry.  This study details how health and welfare plans are promoted and implemented by British Governments, industry quality assurance and organic certification bodies.  Details of animal health and welfare planning activities taking place in other European countries are also detailed though these activities are limited compared to the UK.  An analysis of the key principles of health and welfare plans and planning identified from these review is presented and these principles compared with those derived at the first ANIPLAN Workshop held in Denmark in October 2007.  A review of attitudes towards health and welfare planning is presented and shortcomings of the “UK style” of health planning identified so that conclusions can be drawn as to how best to take effective animal health and welfare planning forward into European partner countries via the ANIPLAN project.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13409/1/13409.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Nicholas, Phillipa and Jasinska, Aleksandra    (2008) Animal Health and Welfare Planning - A Review.    In:     CORE Organic project nr. 1903 - ANIPLAN. CORE Organic project nr. 1903 - ANIPLAN, no. Report from 1st ANIPLAN project workshop. .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13409/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>