<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Recept ur marknadsförarens kokbok: ingredienser och tillredningsanvisningar för en inbjudande lägerskola : miljölägerskola Eco Learn</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Miemois, Annika</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Environmental aspects</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The primary aim of the work was to examine the market situation for camp schools and more explicit for the project Eco Learn. A market research was done by analyzing customers, competitors and external factors. In order to develop a camp school based on actual customer needs, a survey was carried out in Finland-Swedish compulsory schools. The market research made it possible to examine the premises for an attractive camp school offer. The work was finally summarized in a SWOT-analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
The theoretical frames of the work consisted of service marketing and service development with focus on the tourism sector. In addition, fundamental theories about tourism products were examined. Despite the many differences between physical products and services, both aim to satisfy customer needs. When creating new products for the market, systematic product development should be applied. This can be considered as a process, hopefully resulting in a product showing concrete customer benefits.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14727/1/met65.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Miemois, Annika         (2005) Recept ur marknadsförarens kokbok: ingredienser och tillredningsanvisningar för en inbjudande lägerskola : miljölägerskola Eco Learn.   Jordbruk och livsmedelsekonomi, no. 65. Forskningscentralen för jordbruk och livsmedelsekonomi.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14727/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>