<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>The contribution of conversion to organic food and farming to the analysis of dynamics and governance in transitions towards sustainable agri-food systems</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sautereau, Natacha</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bellon, Stéphane</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Sustainable agri-food system approaches are rooted both in the environmental movements and in the political-economic critique of the contemporary system. Organic food and farming (OF&amp;F) as an alternative agri-food system among others encompasses multiple dimensions and performances, enabling the study of conversion as a prototype of transition. We use the multilevel pathways framework to describe the transition process. We first present OF&amp;F as a heterogeneous entity and examine the consequences of acknowledging its diversity. We show that OF&amp;F as an innovation influences the mainstream design of agri-food systems, and we explore the strategies of the actors in charge of its development. We then introduce how different levers can influence types and levels of conversion, with actors who have diverse expectations to articulate.&#xD;
This raises the issue of time frames with short-term adaptations and long-term transitions. Finally, we introduce the market itself as a composition of sectors and territories. We argue that this diversity has to be kept beyond consensus to build multiple strategies. We represent the initiatives of different networks in their spatial and social dimensions. This begs the question of the coexistence of these models. We conclude that the policy level has a prominent role to play in enabling this coexistence.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>INRA</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Barbier , M.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Elzen, B.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2012-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/27612/1/Sautereau_2012_BookSISA_Chap2.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sautereau, Natacha and Bellon, Stéphane    (2012) The contribution of conversion to organic food and farming to the analysis of dynamics and governance in transitions towards sustainable agri-food systems.    In: Barbier , M. and Elzen, B. (Eds.)   System Innovations, Knowledge Regimes, and Design Practices towards Transitions for Sustainable Agriculture.  INRA, e-book, pp. 47-68.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/27612/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>