<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>IRM-ORGANIC - Training on improved risk management tools for organic inspectors</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Neuendorff, Jochen</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Technology assessment</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Education, extension and communication</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within the framework of the EU-Leonardo-project IRM-Organic, an analysis of the inspection methods for risk-orientated inspection instruments and the description of the existing training concepts of control bodies in Austria, Germany, Italy and Poland were carried out. Coordinated by R. Setti and R. Maresca (CCPB), additionally expert interviews were conducted in Austria, Italy Germany and Poland. Furthermore, an international online survey with more than 500 participants from more than 20 countries was realized. A SWOT-Analysis was elaborated. S. Bruckner from AGRIZERT, another project partner, compiled a description of the content and methodology of courses for inspectors in private food and feed certification programs and in public food and feed control in Austria, Italy, Germany and Poland. Based on the above-mentioned data a curriculum for train-the-trainer-courses for risk-oriented inspection for improved fraud prevention in Austria, Germany, Italy and Poland was elaborated. The courses concentrated on control methodology oriented towards major risk areas; the concept of critical control points and checks of international trade exchange of organic products including their traceability. Each course was evaluated and used for the development of the final train-the-trainer curriculum.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/22593/7/22593.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Neuendorff, Jochen    (2014) IRM-ORGANIC - Training on improved risk management tools for organic inspectors.       Paper at:   IFOAM Organic World Congress 2014, Istanbul, Turkey, 13-15 October 2014.     [Completed]</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/22593/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>