<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Results from two years of sanitation measures to reduce apple scab in organic orchards</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kelderer, Markus</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lardschneider, Ewald</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Marschall, Klaus</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Scab is still a big challenge for those apple orchards which are managed organically.&#xD;
Inoculum survives during winter in leaf litter, and sporulates in spring when&#xD;
vegetation starts. Different surveys in other regions showed that it is possible to&#xD;
reduce the presence of scab in apple orchards by removing the leave litter from the&#xD;
orchards. Different trials were carried out to understand if sanitation measures would&#xD;
also be of practical interest in organic orchards in South Tyrol. The results varied. In&#xD;
some trials, scab was reduced on the leaves up to 60%, in others no differences&#xD;
were observed. It is therefore not clear if the results justify the expense of cost and&#xD;
time for such measures.</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2004</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14082/1/17_Triloff_87_90.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kelderer, Markus; Lardschneider, Ewald and Marschall, Klaus    (2004) Results from two years of sanitation measures to reduce apple scab in organic orchards.  [Ergebnisse aus einem zweijährigen Versuch durch die Beseitigung des Falllaubes den Schorfbefall in Bioobstanlagen zu reduzieren.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  Ecofruit - 11th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 3rd February to 5th February 2004 at Weinsberg/Germany, p. 86.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14082/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>