<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>EVALUATION OF EFFECTIVE MICROORGANISMS (EM) TECHNOLOGY IN  MAIZE (Zea mays L.) GROWTH, DEVELOPMENT AND YIELD IN MOROGORO TANZANIA</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>SAIDIA, PAUL SABAS</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>CHILAGANE, DAUDI AMOS</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>WOSTRY, ALEXANDER</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>MARO, JANET FARES</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Recycling, balancing and resource management</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm nutrient management</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The field experiment was conducted at Tushikamane Centre  Kilakala, Morogoro Tanzania to investigate the effect of EM technology on maize (Zea mays L.) growth, development and yield. Maize is a major cereal consumed; over 80% of population depends on maize for food in Tanzania. Low soil fertility, insect pests and diseases are among the primary constraints in maize production. This is due to continuous cultivation without fertilizing the soil, poor and lack of proper measures to control pest and diseases. Most farmers in both rural and urban areas of Tanzania are not aware with the use of organic fertilizers especially the EM (Effective Microorganism) technology in agriculture to increase crop yield without the use of agricultural chemicals or artificial fertilizers, the method of farming is inexpensive, capable of producing high-quality products, high yield produces and preserving the environment. Therefore, this research work mainly aimed at studying the efficiency of EM technology on maize (Zea mays L.) crop performance in the field.&#xD;
Five treatments comprising of EM technology EM-Bokashi, Bokashi and EM-A, EM-FPE and EM-5, combination of Bokashi, EM-A, EMFPE and EM5, and absolute control were compared in a randomized complete block design with three replications. Bokashi leaves (3.7%N) at 1851.9kg/ha, 200 mls of EMA mixed with water to make a 2L solution, EMFPE and EM5 were mixed with water at 200mls to get a 2L solution which was sprayed thrice a week scheduled for application. Three weeks were scheduled for application of EM.&#xD;
Application of EM-Bokashi produced an average yield of 3.06 tonha-1, EM-Bokashi and EM-A produced grain yield of 3.24 tonha-1, EMFPE and EM-5 produced 3.11 tonha-1 and, application of all EM-Bokashi, EM-A, EMFPE and EM-5 produced grain yield of 3.51 tonha-1, while absolute control produced 2.12 tonha-1. Application of EM improved maize crop yield.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2010-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Report</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/19472/1/EFFECTIVE_MICROORGANISMS_IN_AGRIC_Saidia_et_al_2010.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>SAIDIA, PAUL SABAS; CHILAGANE, DAUDI AMOS; WOSTRY, ALEXANDER and MARO, JANET FARES         (2010) EVALUATION OF EFFECTIVE MICROORGANISMS (EM) TECHNOLOGY IN MAIZE (Zea mays L.) GROWTH, DEVELOPMENT AND YIELD IN MOROGORO TANZANIA.    .</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/19472/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>