<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Lessons learnt from ORGAP Project – planning, implementation and evaluation of Action Plans for Organic Food and Farming</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schmid, O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolz, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lampkin, N.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeffreys, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dabbert, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eichert, C.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Michelsen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zanoli, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vairo, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gonzalvez, V.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Policy environments and social economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Within the EU funded project ORGAP, a toolbox was developed for the evaluation of the European as well as national action plans for organic food and farming. Also recommendations and a resource manual for policy makers and stakeholders were developed. These were based on the analysis of national Organic Action Plans as well as stakeholder and expert consultation. The analysis showed that several EU member states have emphasised the need to balance supply-push policies with more market-focused demand-pull policies. An integrated approach is required and this has been to differing degrees through the formulation of multi-functional Organic Action Plans (OAPs), which also adress the dual roles of organic farming (from a policy perspective) to provide public goods and satisfy consumer demand. Eight Organic Action Plans, reviewed in the ORGAP project, vary with regard to the elaboration process, targets, objectives and the emphasis of measures on certain areas (e.g. market versus environment orientation). This variation is due to quite different political and socio-economic framework conditions for organic farming in these countries. It revealed that the weaknesses identified in the status quo analysis of the organic sector have only partly been translated to the targets and measures included in the action plan documents. Definition of the priorities for development of organic agriculture must be agreed by all relevant stakeholders. The priorities, and hence the programmes, will depend on correct analysis of the issues (and conflicts) that need to be addressed and clear objectives with measurable outcomes (for effective evaluation). For more information on the project, on the practical project manual and the evaluation toolbox for Organic Action Plans see project website www.orgap.org</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13972/1/schmid-etal-2008-IFOAM-ORGAP-lessons-final_paper.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/13972/2/schmid-etal-2008-IFOAM-OWC-ORGAP-lessons-presentation.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schmid, O.; Stolz, H.; Lampkin, N.; Jeffreys, I.; Dabbert, S.; Eichert, C.; Michelsen, J.; Zanoli, R.; Vairo, D. and Gonzalvez, V.    (2008) Lessons learnt from ORGAP Project – planning, implementation and evaluation of Action Plans for Organic Food and Farming.       Paper at:   16th IFOAM Organic World Congress, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/13972/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>