<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Akzeptanz von Tiergesundheitsplänen bei Landwirten – Ergebnisse einer Befragung bei 60 Betrieben</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Goeritz, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oppermann, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller-Arnke, I.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rahmann, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Schumacher, U.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>March, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Brinkmann, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Health and welfare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In organic farming the ambitious claims in enhancing and keeping animal health are often not realised. The implementation of animal health plans should clear this deficit effectively. Experiences with British and Danish herd health plans showed that the acceptance of plans is an essential part for its successful transfer into practice. But anyhow, this aspect has not been regarded sufficiently. To avoid similar mistakes like done in former institution tests a social study is integrated into German projects that deal with the implementation of animal health plans in poultry, dairy, and pig hus-bandry. To get more information about the acceptance, the study requires farmers’ attitudes to herd health plans, the motivation to animal health and financial and work capabilities as well.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2007</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9621/1/9621_Goeritz_Poster.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Goeritz, M.; Oppermann, R.; Müller-Arnke, I.; Rahmann, G.; Schumacher, U.; March, S. and Brinkmann, J.    (2007) Akzeptanz von Tiergesundheitsplänen bei Landwirten – Ergebnisse einer Befragung bei 60 Betrieben.  [Acceptance of animal health plans – results of a survey at 60 farms.]      Poster at:   Zwischen Tradition und Globalisierung - 9. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Universität Hohenheim, D-Stuttgart, 20.-23.03.2007.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9621/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>