<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>IMPROVING THE YIELD OF Celosia argentea IN ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEM WITH SYSTEM OF CROP INTENSIFICATION</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gbadamosi, R.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>AdeOluwa, O.O.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Farming Systems</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Vegetables</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>A field study was conducted at Teaching and Research Farm boundary of University of Ibadan, Ibadan, Nigeria to investigate the effect of system of crop intensification on Celosia argentea growth and yield performance. The experiment was farmers’ participatory with a group of 8 farmers. Two seeding rates were used; farmers’ traditional seed rate of 26 kg ha-1 (D2) as high seed rate and lower seed rate of 13 kg ha-1 (D1). Observations were made on growth and yield parameters of the crop. The results showed that growth and yield of celosia were significantly (P&lt;0.05) influenced by system of crop intensification. The results of seeding rates‘ effects on number of leaves, stem width and yield showed that low seed rate (D1) performed better than high seed rate (D2). Low seed rate (D1) resulted in higher marketable fresh leaf yield of 12.24 ton ha-1 compared to high seed rate (D2) of 8.82 ton ha-1. The accrued revenue / ha ranged between ₦882,000 to ₦1,224,000 [₦150 = $1 (US Dollar)] for D2 and D1 respectively, subsequently increasing farmers’ income. Overall, this investigation revealed that both growth and yield of Celosia argentea can be improved with low seeding rate that is a component of system of crop intensification.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Rahmann, G.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Aksoy, U.</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2014-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/23311/1/23311%2C%20R.O.%20Gbadamosi%20and%20O.O.%20AdeOluwa%20OWC%202014%20paper%20submission_MM.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gbadamosi, R.O. and AdeOluwa, O.O.    (2014) IMPROVING THE YIELD OF Celosia argentea IN ORGANIC FARMING SYSTEM WITH SYSTEM OF CROP INTENSIFICATION.   In: Rahmann, G. and Aksoy, U. (Eds.)  Building Organic Bridges, Johann Heinrich von Thünen-Institut, Braunschweig, Germany, 3, Thuenen Report, no. 20, pp. 859-862.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/23311/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>