<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nachhaltigkeitskriterien als essentieller Bestandteil einer &#xD;
novellierten EU-Öko-Basisverordnung</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Brunner, George</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Hoffmann, Heide</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Rainer</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Regulation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The main goal of this study was to develop sustainability criteria for the advancement of the EU-Eco-Regulations. To achieve this, the authors analyzed 8 international certification schemes for sustainable aspects which could be transferred to existing regulations. By doing so it was possible to abstract 10 sustainability criteria and in the prozess evaluate their value for future developments of the EU-Eco-Regulations.&#xD;
Sustainability of agricultural systems is of the utmost importance for future development of mankind itself. Since ecological agriculture is the most sustainable System we have that works on a large scale (cf. Pick 2009), it is reasonable to suggest that the outline we use for this kind of agriculture – producing best quality with fewest external inputs – is true for sustainable agriculture itself. This work proofed this conjecture to be true.&#xD;
So although the here found sustainability criteria are only partly adopted in the ad-vancement of the EU-Eco-Regulations it can be said that sustainable agriculture of any kind should involve the criteria found in this work.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Verlag Dr. Köster, Berlin</dc:publisher>
  <dc:date>2014-09-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/26949/1/26949_brunner.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Brunner, George; Hoffmann, Heide and Friedel, Rainer    (2014) Nachhaltigkeitskriterien als essentieller Bestandteil einer novellierten EU-Öko-Basisverordnung.       Paper at:   13. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Hochschule für nachhaltige Entwicklung Eberswalde, 17. - 20. März 2015.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/26949/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>