<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Konventionaliserung: Notwendigkeit einer Bewertung mittels&#xD;
Indikatorensystem, basierend auf den IFOAM-Prinzipien</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Darnhofer, Dr. Ika</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lindenthal, Dr. Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zollitsch, Dr. Werner</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bartel-Kratochvil, Dr. Ruth</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Indicators and other value-laden measures</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Farm economics</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The developments within organic farming and the threat of ‘conventionalisation’ have&#xD;
been debated for over 10 years. This debate mostly focuses on the degree of&#xD;
similarity between organic farming and conventional farming. We argue that whether&#xD;
or not organic farming comes to resemble conventional farming may be less important&#xD;
than whether organic farming practices stay true to the organic principles and values&#xD;
that are its foundation. We thus argue that the conventionalisation debate needs to&#xD;
avoid a narrow ‘back to the roots’ argument and move towards a principle-based&#xD;
assessment of new practices. Once an assessment framework is developed, it could&#xD;
be used by organic farmers and farmer associations and thus make the conventionalisation&#xD;
debate more relevant to practitioners. It would also allow more transparency in&#xD;
farming practices and support the recognition of those farmers not limiting themselves&#xD;
to the minimum requirements as stipulated in the regulations.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/14252/1/Darnhofer_14252.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Darnhofer, Dr. Ika; Lindenthal, Dr. Thomas; Zollitsch, Dr. Werner and Bartel-Kratochvil, Dr. Ruth    (2009) Konventionaliserung: Notwendigkeit einer Bewertung mittels Indikatorensystem, basierend auf den IFOAM-Prinzipien.       Paper at:   10. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Zürich, 11.-13. Februar 2009.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/14252/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>