<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Nitrogen transfer from forage legumes to nine neighbouring plants in a multi-species grassland</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Pirhofer-Walzl, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Høgh-Jensen, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Eriksen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Søegaard, K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rasmussen, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Pasture and forage crops</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Legumes play a crucial role in nitrogen supply to grass-legume mixtures for ruminant fodder. To quantify N transfer from legumes to neighbouring plants in multi-species grasslands we established a grass-legume-herb mixture on a loamy-sandy site in Denmark. White clover (Trifolium repens L.), red clover (Trifolium pratense L.) and lucerne (Medicago sativa L.) were leaf-labelled with 15N enriched urea during one growing season. N transfer to grasses&#xD;
(Lolium perenne L. and xfestulolium), white clover, red clover, lucerne, birdsfoot trefoil (Lotus corniculatus&#xD;
L.), chicory (Cichorium intybus L.), plantain (Plantago&#xD;
lanceolata L.), salad burnet (Sanguisorba minor L.)and caraway (Carum carvi L.) was assessed. Neighbouring plants contained greater amounts of N derived from white clover (4.8 gm-2) compared with red clover (2.2 gm-2) and lucerne (1.1 gm-2). Grasses having fibrous roots received greater amounts of N from legumes than dicotyledonous plants which generally have taproots. Slurry application mainly increased N transfer from legumes to grasses. During the growing season the three legumes transferred approximately 40 kg N ha-1 to neighbouring plants. Below-ground N transfer from legumes to neighbouring plants differed among nitrogen donors and nitrogen receivers and may depend on root characteristics and regrowth strategies of plant species in the multi-species grassland.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2012</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/20613/4/20613.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Pirhofer-Walzl, K.; Rasmussen, J.; Høgh-Jensen, H.; Eriksen, J.; Søegaard, K. and Rasmussen, J.   (2012) Nitrogen transfer from forage legumes to nine neighbouring plants in a multi-species grassland.   Plant and Soil, 350, pp. 71-84.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/20613/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>