<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Wirkung von Quassiaextrakt auf die Apfelsägewespe Hoplocampa testudinea Klug</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kienzle, Jutta</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zimmer, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Maxin, P.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Rank, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bathon, H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Zebitz, C.P.W.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Fruit and berries</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The efficacy of Quassia extract with a standardized content of Quassin was proved in various field trials in different regions during three years. The amount of Quassin of 6 g/ha/m tree height will be recommended to practice. It is not important to have a contact effect on the eggs. The larvae must feed on the product before they enter the fruit. There is a very good efficacy on primaray infestation. Furthermore, there is even an effi-cacy on secondary infestation. Thus, even if due to difficult conditions during application or not optimal ter-mination of the treatment the efficacy on the primary infestation is not entirely sufficient, the secondary in-festation will be controlled better.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Boos, Markus</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2006</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/9028/1/ecofruit_12th_42.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kienzle, Jutta; Zimmer, J.; Maxin, P.; Rank, H.; Bathon, H. and Zebitz, C.P.W.    (2006) Wirkung von Quassiaextrakt auf die Apfelsägewespe Hoplocampa testudinea Klug.  [Efficacy of Quassia extract on the apple sawfly Hoplocampa testudinea Klug.]  In: Boos, Markus (Ed.)  ecofruit - 12th International Conference on Cultivation Technique and Phytopathological Problems in Organic Fruit-Growing: Proceedings to the Conference from 31st January to 2nd February 2006 at Weinsberg/Germany, Fördergemeinschaft Ökologischer Obstbau e.V. (FÖKO), Traubenplatz 5, D-74189 Weinsberg, pp. 239-242.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/9028/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>