<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Artenvielfalt auf biologischen und nicht-biologischen Landwirtschaftsbetrieben in zehn europäischen Regionen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Schneider, Manuel</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lüscher, Gisela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jeanneret, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Arndorfer, Michaela</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bailey, Debra</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Balacs, Katalin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Choisis, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Dennis, Peter</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fjellstad, Wendy</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fraser, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Frank, Thomas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Friedel, Jürgen K.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gillingham, Pippa</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jerkovich, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gomiero, Tiziano</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Jongman, Rob</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kainz, Max</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Moreno, Gerardo</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oschatz, M.-L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Paoletti, Maurizio</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Pointereau, Philippe</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sarthou, Jean-Pierre</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Siebrecht, Norman</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Sommaggio, D.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Vale, Jim</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Wolfrum, Sebastian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Herzog, Felix</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>"Organics" in general</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Biodiversity and ecosystem services</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>One of the aims of organic farming is the protection of biodiversity. In the EU FP7 project BioBio, we studied the effect of organic farming on species numbers at farm level on 169 randomly selected organic and non-organic farms with mostly low to medium intensity in ten European regions. Using a preferential sampling scheme based on habitat mapping, numbers of plants, earthworms, spiders and bees were assessed at farm level. A global analysis across the ten regions shows that organic farms have significantly higher numbers of plant and bee species than non-organic farms. The effect of organic farming on earthworm and spider species numbers are also positive but insignificant. The effects in absolute terms are small and much smaller than the variation between individual farms. Currently ongoing analyses aim at identifying the important driving factors for farmland biodiversity.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21413/1/21413_Schneider.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Schneider, Manuel; Lüscher, Gisela; Jeanneret, Philippe; Arndorfer, Michaela; Bailey, Debra; Balacs, Katalin; Choisis, Jean-Pierre; Dennis, Peter; Fjellstad, Wendy; Fraser, M.; Frank, Thomas; Friedel, Jürgen K.; Gillingham, Pippa; Jerkovich, G.; Gomiero, Tiziano; Jongman, Rob; Kainz, Max; Moreno, Gerardo; Oschatz, M.-L.; Paoletti, Maurizio; Pointereau, Philippe; Sarthou, Jean-Pierre; Siebrecht, Norman; Sommaggio, D.; Vale, Jim; Wolfrum, Sebastian and Herzog, Felix    (2013) Artenvielfalt auf biologischen und nicht-biologischen Landwirtschaftsbetrieben in zehn europäischen Regionen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21413/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>