<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Inoculation affects nitrogen balances of composts and growth, yield and microflora of Phaseolus beans</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Sangakkara, Dr Ravi</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Weerasekera, Mr Danesh</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Attanayake, Mr K B</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Attanayake, Ms A M U</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Composting and manuring</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The impact of organic matter and two types of inoculums on composting and subsequent growth of common beans was evaluated under tropical field conditions. The composts were made of commonly available organic matter with different C:N ratios, and inoculums consisting of  cattle manure slurry, Effective Micro organisms or a mixture of both were added. The  mixture of cattle manure and Effective Microorganisms increased N availability and reduced C: N ratios of compost than when applied individually. Legume green matter enhanced compost quality and growth yields. The nodulation and mycorrhizal populations of roots of beans were increased by a mixture of inoculums and using diverse materials in the compost. The usefulness of inoculums such as EM, which is available in all continents is presented on the basis of this study.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>rtf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/12526/1/Sangakkara_12526_ed.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Sangakkara, Dr Ravi; Weerasekera, Mr Danesh; Attanayake, Mr K B and Attanayake, Ms A M U    (2008) Inoculation affects nitrogen balances of composts and growth, yield and microflora of Phaseolus beans.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/12526/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>