<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Three new systems for recycling of urban organic waste to agriculture</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Møller, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bruun, S.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Magid, J.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Nutrient turnover</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Short-Circuit is an on-going EU-LIFE ENVIRONMENT funded project (KVL is project leader) with the aim of 'short-circuiting' the carbon and nutrient cycle between urban and rural districts by establishing three new systems for source separation, collection and composting of organic waste in the greater Copenhagen area.&#xD;
&#xD;
The project is a collaboration between research institutions (KVL and Küngl. Tekniska Högskolan in Stockholm), and industry represented by the composting firm Solum Ltd. and the Internet-based box scheme business Aarstiderne Ltd.&#xD;
&#xD;
KVL´s part of the activity is co-funded by the Danish Research Centre for Organic Farming, via the CRUCIAL project.&#xD;
&#xD;
These two projects form part of a coherent effort to re-invent urban waste management with emphasis on closing the rural-urban nutrient cycle.&#xD;
&#xD;
The main objectives of the Short-Circuit project are:&#xD;
&#xD;
    * To develop three new full-scale source separation and composting systems designed to optimise recycling of organic urban waste to agriculture by establishing a close relation between the sources, households, and the end users.&#xD;
&#xD;
    * To optimise the systems via technical solutions as well as through increased public participation to improve source separation with minimum amounts of contaminants in the waste.&#xD;
&#xD;
    * To evaluate the environmental impact of the three systems by systems analysis.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2005-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/5857/1/5857.PDF</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Møller, J.; Bruun, S. and Magid, J.   (2005) Three new systems for recycling of urban organic waste to agriculture.   DARCOFenews (1).</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/5857/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>