<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Organic Food and Farming in Kenya</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Kledal, Paul Rye</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Oyiera, Habwe Florence</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Njoroge, John Wanjau</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Kiarii, Eustace</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Africa</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The organic farm sector itself is basically organized around a minor number of large farm enterprises, or various supply organizations, based on purely commercial, community, faith or simply farmer cooperation involved in packaging, domestic or export sales. 35 farm enterprises covered the organic production in Kenya’s eight provinces. More than half are concentrated in the Central Province, where also most of the outgrowers are connected in relation to the labour intensive crop production within horticulture. A total of 1’811 farm outgrowers (smallholders of various sizes) were included to secure the ‘critical mass of supply’ – either for export or national market chains. The total organic area is distinguished between what is agricultural land and what is considered wild and extensive production. The agricultural land consisted of 4’535 hectares, which together with the area for wild and extensive collection reaching 73’851 hectares amounted to a total 78’438 hectares certified organic. The Central province dominates within horticulture, fruits, nuts, coffee and essential oils – five out of the six major organic product categories Kenya produces and exports. Tea is the sixth product, which is produced in the Rift Valley province around the town Kericho.</dc:description>
  <dc:publisher>FiBL, IFOAM and ITC</dc:publisher>
  <dc:contributor>Willer, Helga</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>Kilcher, Lukas</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>2009</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Book chapter</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/17933/1/kledal-etal-2009-world-organic-agriculture.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Kledal, Paul Rye; Oyiera, Habwe Florence; Njoroge, John Wanjau and Kiarii, Eustace    (2009) Organic Food and Farming in Kenya.    In: Willer, Helga and Kilcher, Lukas (Eds.)   The World of Organic Agriculture - Statistics and Emerging Trends 2009.  FiBL, IFOAM and ITC, CH-Frick, D-Bonn and CH-Geneva, chapter 8, pp. 127-132.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/17933/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>