<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Kohlenstoffspeicherung und Treibhausgasflüsse in Böden unter biologischer und konventioneller Bewirtschaftung – Ergebnisse aus zwei globalen Meta-Analysen</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Gattinger, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Skinner, Colin</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Müller, Adrian</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Fließbach, Andreas</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Mäder, Paul</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Häni, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Buchmann, Nina</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Stolze, Matthias</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Niggli, Urs</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Soil quality</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Air and water emissions</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Explorative literature searches followed by meta-analyses were conducted to identify differences in soil organic carbon (SOC) and soil-derived greenhouse gas emissions between organic and non-organic farming systems. Within a total of 74 studies we found significantly higher SOC concentrations, SOC stocks and C sequestration rates in organically managed soils compared to those under non-organic management. Meta-analysis of soil-derived GHG flux data from 19 studies revealed lower N2O emissions and higher CH4 uptake rates in soils under organic management when related to acreage. Due to lower yields in organic farming systems higher GHG emissions from these systems were obtained when the data was related to unit crop yield. The poor availability of farming system comparisons from developing countries, at present, renders the transfer of the obtained results to these extremely vulnerable environments difficult. However, the presented approach is open to regular updates once relevant data from these regions are published.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2013-09-09</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/21581/1/21581_gattinger.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Gattinger, Andreas; Skinner, Colin; Müller, Adrian; Fließbach, Andreas; Mäder, Paul; Häni, Matthias; Buchmann, Nina; Stolze, Matthias and Niggli, Urs     (2013) Kohlenstoffspeicherung und Treibhausgasflüsse in Böden unter biologischer und konventioneller Bewirtschaftung – Ergebnisse aus zwei globalen Meta-Analysen.       Paper at:   12. Wissenschaftstagung Ökologischer Landbau, Rheinische Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität, Bonn, 5. bis 8. März 2013.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/21581/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>