<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Differences between spring wheat cultivars in susceptibility to Fusarium caused seedling blight</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Timmermans, Dr. B.G.H.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Osman, Ir. A.M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Crop health, quality, protection</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Breeding, genetics and propagation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Fusarium spp. present on spring wheat seeds can infect seedlings and cause reduced plant densities and higher wheat infestations. In the current project, variation between commercially available spring wheat cultivars in their tolerance to Fusarium seedling blight was investigated in a pot and a field trail. Additionally, initial growth rates of cultivars were measured to investigate possible relations with tolerance. Preliminary analysis shows presence of  tolerance differences between the spring wheat cultivars in the pot and field experiment. This difference was relatively robust (experiment x cultivar interaction was not significant). Preliminary analysis also showed a relation between tolerance and initial growth rates of cultivars in the field experiment. The presence of robust differences in tolerance and relations with growth rates of commercially available cultivars form good possibilities for future breeding.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2008</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Conference paper, poster, etc.</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>source</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/11945/1/seedlingblightsofar2008aobt.doc</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Timmermans, Dr. B.G.H. and Osman, Ir. A.M.    (2008) Differences between spring wheat cultivars in susceptibility to Fusarium caused seedling blight.       Poster at:   Cultivating the Future Based on Science: 2nd Conference of the International Society of Organic Agriculture Research ISOFAR, Modena, Italy, June 18-20, 2008.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/11945/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>