<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Dietary citrus pulp reduces lipid oxidation in lamb meat</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Inserra, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Priolo, A.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Biondi, L.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Lanza, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Bognanno, M.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Gravador, R.</dc:creator>
  <dc:creator>Luciano, G.</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Feeding and growth</dc:subject>
  <dc:subject>Sheep and goats</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This study investigated the effect of replacing cereal concentrateswith high levels of dried citrus pulp in the diet on lamb meat oxidative stability. Over 56 days, lambs were fed a barley-based concentrate (Control) or concentrates inwhich 24% and 35% dried citrus pulpwere included to partially replace barley (Citrus 24% and Citrus 35%, respectively). Meat was aged under vacuum for 4 days and subsequently stored aerobically at 4 °C. The Control diet increased the redness, yellowness and saturation of meat after blooming (P &lt; 0.01). Regardless of the level of supplementation, dietary dried citrus pulp strongly reduced meat lipid oxidation over 6 days of aerobic storage (P &lt; 0.001), while colour parameters did not change noticeably over storage and their variation rate was not affected by the diet. In conclusion, replacing cereals with dried citrus pulp in concentrate-based diets might represent a feasible strategy to naturally improve meat oxidative stability and to promote the exploitation of this by-product.</dc:description>
  <dc:date>2014</dc:date>
  <dc:type>Journal paper</dc:type>
  <dc:type>NonPeerReviewed</dc:type>
  <dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
  <dc:identifier>http://orgprints.org/25281/1/Inserra-etal-2014-MeatSci-p1498-1493.pdf</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>Inserra, L.; Priolo, A.; Biondi, L.; Lanza, M.; Bognanno, M.; Gravador, R. and Luciano, G.   (2014) Dietary citrus pulp reduces lipid oxidation in lamb meat.   Meat Science, 96 (4), pp. 1489-1493.</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>http://orgprints.org/25281/</dc:relation>
</oai_dc:dc>